94	Life in prison or the death penalty for Boston Marathon Bomber, Dzhokhar Tsarnaev?
252	Following the New York Times reporting that the 2013 Boston Marathon Bomber, Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, has been found guilty on all 30 counts, the question now turns to whether he will be put in prison for the rest of his life or whether he'll be put to death under capital punishment.
532	Which fate would you pick for him, if you could, and why?
690	Following the New York Times reporting that the 2013 Boston Marathon Bomber, Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, has been found guilty on all 30 counts, the question now turns to whether he will be put in prison for the rest of his life or whether he'll be put to death under capital punishment.
970	Which fate would you pick for him, if you could, and why?
1038	Nobody deserves to be murdered.
1144	Death penalty.
1160	The federal government very rarely executes anyone so no doubt he'd be left languishing for a fair while.
1344	the death penalty (if we're assuming he's 100% provably empirically *factually* guilty) would definitely be justified, but then again, I'm not really a death penalty guy because I don't trust the government to carry it out without ending up killing innocent people. but with *this* *******? I wouldn't care if he got tortured to death in theory - so long as he was 100% guilty and not framed/innocent. so, again, I'm not a bleeding heart liberal over the death penalty because I think if they're truly proven guilty then fair enough, let them have it, but I think the government is inefficient in everything it does, so it's dangerous. so I've voted death penalty with caution.
2103	Heart is saying death penalty but that's just knee-jerk and I know it's not the right thing to do.
2203	Head says Life in prison.
2230	Edit: in some twisted way life imprisonment would be worse for that type of 'person' in any case.
2399	In this case, I would make an exception and go for death.
2531	Torn about this, I want this guy to suffer. Suffer big time but ultimately he deserves the death penalty. His mother is deluded as well.
2769	Following the New York Times reporting that the 2013 Boston Marathon Bomber, Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, has been found guilty on all 30 counts, the question now turns to whether he will be put in prison for the rest of his life or whether he'll be put to death under capital punishment.
3049	Which fate would you pick for him, if you could, and why?
3117	I don't support the death penalty, but I don't follow the usual argument of it being 'government-sanctioned murder'. That's as flawed as saying that taxation is 'government-sanctioned theft'. Death penalty advocates could argue that in a similar way to how the money taken from taxation benefits us as the government spends it on public services, the life taken from an execution benefits all of us, because there's one less murderer around.
3560	The reason why I oppose the death penalty (aside from the huge risk the death penalty handed down on innocent people, for example the innocent man who was released after 30 years on death row) is that ultimately, it just isn't the most effective way of making us safer. In my opinion, money spent on executions could be more effectively spent on rehabilitation of inmates during their time in prison and making them useful members of society, instead of them languishing in prison cells only to reoffend upon release.. In any case, money should also be spent on preventing radicalisation and helping poorer communities, as although poor people are certainly not genetically inclined to commit crime, once they have been deprived of opportunities, they are more likely to turn to illicit activities. That's a more effective way of reducing the number of crimes committed in the first place.
4451	What I hate about the death penalty debate is that both sides base their arguments on an appeal to emotion rather than the facts
4651	Life in prison.
4668	Don't give him have the opportunity of becoming a martyr.
4801	Life imprisonment. Was he not going to blow himself up anway? 
4934	Death penalty
4949	he could end up radicalizing more offenders
5067	What he did was outrageous, leaving people dead, with broken legs and making one blind for eternity.
5169	As much as this my contradict my beliefs as a person, i must say the death penalty afterall people come out of prison unchanged.
5299	This may seems harsh but something must be done, countless of lives are being endangered simply because of barbaric people like him.
5530	Death penalty
5545	he could end up radicalizing more offenders
5599	The sort of Prison he would go to would not offer many opportunities for that. Presumably he would be in a super max prison, where he would spend the majority of his time in solitary confinement. Any prisoners he came across would likely also be in for life.
5859	I have to say life in prison. I simply do not agree with the death penalty in any circumstance.
6025	Life in prison. But a very awful prison not one of those cushy ones :rolleyes:
6179	Life in prison is a far worse fate than death.
6304	I don't see the point in the death penalty when Death is his goal.
6482	I don't see the point in the death penalty when Death is his goal.
6559	If he wanted death that badly then he would of killed himself or went out in a blaze of glory, the coward pulled back from the edge and is trying to place the blame all onto his brother but not before he murdered many men. women and children. The sniveling coward deserves to feel the terror and complete absence of hope while lying strapped to the bed crying for help, right before he is put down like the filthy pig that he is.
6990	I hate the argument constantly brought against death penalty of "oh life in prisons much worse anyway" well surely if that is the case then death penalty is more humane and the state should be allowed to do it then? The justice system shouldn't be all about rehabilitation it should be about punishment. I don't buy into the belief that justice, revenge and emotion shouldn't play any part in the Justice System. It should be about Justice, Public Safety &amp; Rehabilitation some people should fall into the first and second categories as they are beyond being rehabilitated.
7568	It doesn't mean that I agree with the US Justice Systems methods or ways as I believe too many people get the death penalty where their guilt is in doubt, I also don't agree with the long drawn out expensive process over there, nor the barbaric methods such as Hanging, Electric Chair and Gas Chamber. 
7872	I would personally allow only the worst criminals to be executed such as serial killers or murder that involves torture etc..., also I would only allow it in cases where there is absolutely no doubt that they are guilty where the evidence is 100%, and where they show no remorse and also where the victim is innocent also. Dzhokhar Tsarnaev fits the bill.
8299	Solitary confinement for the rest of his life.
8457	If he wanted death that badly then he would of killed himself or went out in a blaze of glory, the coward pulled back from the edge and is trying to place the blame all onto his brother but not before he murdered many men. women and children. The sniveling coward deserves to feel the terror and complete absence of hope while lying strapped to the bed crying for help, right before he is put down like the filthy pig that he is.
8897	Well, he was unarmed when he was caught, so I am not sure how he is going out in a blaze of glory. 
8998	Anyway, he is going to care if he dies. He believes his brother is in heaven so I am not sure why he is going to care if he dies.
9198	I'm against the death penalty so I don't believe he should get that. However, life in prison is hardly any better than the death penalty in my opinion, and perhaps worse.
9370	Personally I think he should be treated well and let out again when he's older if he's not deemed a continued threat to society.
