94	Yazidi girls 'raped in public' and sold to Isis fighters before release
252	Ok I don't care how unpopular my opinion is but it seems like you can print any story about Isis and it suddenly becomes gospel, I am not saying this happens but every time I read stories like this there is never a source or its a "local man" etc.
574	yo feminists, wanna do something useful for once and actually DO something about this shit rather than slactivism?
915	I wanna join the military and just kill those fuckers.
1042	Rape is a war crime.
1144	They both have the same god but yet they treat each other with such contempt. Insane and barbaric and primitive individuals.
1270	Where is their god now?
1377	Islam in action.
1474	I don't care. I don't think we should be involved other there. I've been 100% against it from the start.
1658	We cannot let these scum get away with this as so much pain and suffering. The West has supported them for far to long. The trouble is we have used them to fight Communism, giving them weapons and trading when we should have shut the door on them from the days of WW1. Best for one to start learning history. I could show one that Islam had lots to do with both world wars than what you know. Let's start here with this man who has lots to do with lots of world events especially just before WW2 up to today. http://tellthechildrenthetruth.com/amin_en.html.
2296	Prepare to be attacked by fans of always being at war.
2427	prepare to be attacked by people with common sense
2559	Lets fucking go dude. These guys need to be shwacked.
2687	I was wondering when the next sensational headline starring ISIS would come.
2765	PS: This is all fake propaganda
2798	Next Headline: ISIS continues genital mutilation of little girls
2943	The trouble Islam has brought FGM to our door steps.
3069	WTF you think that's cute? I might be late to the post yet my question stands.
3225	Finally someone who sees that too. It's like Emmanuel Goldstein in Orwell.
3375	I'm sorry but this is an organization who is getting away with every atrocity they commit. Our problem or not we can't stand by and let innocents be thrown to the slaughter. We need to help arm and effectively strategize with nearby nations affected, Jordan and Japan included. Come together and wipe these motherfuckers off the map, and rebuild the entire thing from the ground and keep strict regulation on firearms till we can figure this out. I expect to be downvoted out of existence, but someone needs to say something other than "I hope this ends soon." There will never be peace without war.
4055	The trouble is we would have the UN, and all supporters of human rights abuses against us while they get away with so many attrocities. One law for them to get away with attrocities and none for the west. Look at Russia/Afghanistan, Serbia/Bosnia all turned against them when learning about some history they were pushing back Islam and look where we are with the world in a mess in the name of human rights but no rights for the victims of the attrocities done in the name of Islam.
4619	Organizations that get away with every atrocity they commit are, indeed, quite evil.
4780	Just like the prophet muhammad did. Say what you will about ISIS, they are exemplary at following the example of the prophet. Does it alarm anybody else that there are hundreds of millions of people who see emulating shit like this to be the best thing they can do with their life?
5137	Trust me, if Islam had demanded that we rape people, then you'd have 1.2 billion people raping everyone. That's nearly 1/5th of the entire world. So basically, 1 in every 5 humans would be rapists.
5411	I did not say that islam demands that muslims rape people.
5550	I would say sine the days of Muhammad most have in emulating Islam, that females have been brainwashed to accept Islam or face the retribution for not been a good Islamic female knowing to only be a slave. The Western female faces many rapes by Muslim gangs and areas are defineately no go areas. I would prefer a female to dress western than these death rags in Burqas Hijabs etc. Terrible females can becraped, have acid thrown on them just because there Western.
6091	"females have been brainwashed to accept Islam or face the retribution for not been a good Islamic female knowing to only be a slave"
6226	Got a source or are you pulling it out of your arse?
6353	don't spread your Islamophobia you ignorant scum
6478	Did the prophet enslave women captured in battle and distribute them among his men? Yes.
6638	Your comments draw an interesting pattern.
6764	ISIS is the scum of the Earth. They should be stomped out like roaches. Actually, that's an insult to roaches.
6951	"Justifiable on religious ground"
6986	To anyone who uses that as a means to impose your will on others you are in good company.
7147	Religious grounds? Where have I heard that before?
7270	the middle east would be better off without religion...
7399	This is beyond terrible. It is evil to the core. The Yazidi girls have poverty, refugee living conditions, the loss of families, loss of culture, and having to live with this...
7650	I wish I were surprised.
7752	what a great way to convince the kurds that a truce is a solid idea...
7895	So have we found the WMD in Iraq yet?
8013	Nah, just a bunch of empty incubators :(
8129	Rape is wrong in most, if not all, circumstances.
8253	Please elaborate a little
8352	Rape is wrong in any and all circumstances. Yo'. I clear that up for you now bro?
8505	Current apes are about a century ahead of these ones. The middle-east is medieval Eurasia.
8597	It seems as though they honestly just don't understand.
8729	I guess Grand Theft ISIS will be coming out soon, but this will be a hard act to follow.
8902	If a ton of people are like hey what the fuck are you doing... you are probably committing sin. I don't know 2 shits about Islam but I am sure this ain't getting them into heaven or whatever they believe.
9108	I imagine most of these ISIS guys are just really angry and ugly dudes who couldn't get any so they wanted to create their own state where they could legally rape.
9346	So muslims are rapists? Someone quick go tell tumblr .
9479	Phrasing.
9563	So how long before they're pushed out of their hiding holes? Didn't they make a retreat from their central city?
9748	who is ISIS?
9834	Good god damned question. We know who ISIS/isl are.
9887	Tney are going down.
9988	Comes with many names but better as the Muslim brotherhood
10129	This is awful. This and their destruction of historical sites make me just want to not pay attention to any world news anymore.
10337	Islam has destroyed lots more history than any others. Best for one to start learning as one learns one can start to see the real Islam for what it is worth. Good place to start is Nalanda University in India, but there were others as well. Great Library of Alexandra a much more harder one to see who destroyed it. If you look hard enough the final blow came with Islam after it was rebuilt. Ani - City of 1001 churches with 40 gates said to be the size of Istanbul There are plenty more as we see today in the destruction to wipe everything that's not Islam.
10899	Worst is how they are brainwashing our students with doctored truth to suit Islam and leaving out truth of history. Like in this video the mention of Muhammad and Mecca would find the truth in searching the life of Muhammad. How many parents of these students would have fits seeing their children kneel and pray to Islam https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=6qzkSes69Rw
