94	Terrorist Group Confusing Me.
202	Can't figure out if it's me, the govt., the newscasters, or the terrorists themselves, but I'm confused. Every day I see snatches of news reports about this group of terrorists called ISIS. Problem is that sometimes they are called ISIS, sometimes called ISIL and sometimes just IS.
486	Are they all the same group or different groups? Do you start out as an IS and work your way up to an ISIS or ISIL?
603	Or is it like living in Canada where one day you can be a Canadian, but the next day a Canuck?
768	My understanding is that they are basically the same, just depending on where the pieces of crap are operating. ISIS is the islamic state in iraq and syria. The L is libya and IS is the general useless movement. Want to know how I really feel about them? lol
1109	The L does not stand for Libya. It is "the Levant". ( No not Ezra, look it up)
1189	IS is the name the group adopted worldwide
1233	ISIS= Islamic State of Iraq and Syria
1272	ISIL= Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant ( commonly used by US State Department
1355	Essentially they are "Prince' of the terrorist community
1413	"The terrorist group formerly known as........."
1536	Thanks guys. Guess it kinda makes sense as much as any of thier BS makes sense.
1692	they are all a little out there
1798	To simplify:
1812	ISIS = ISIL = IS
1830	3 different names to describe the same demon. Abbreviations are mentioned above.
1988	Couple of years back, they were our heroes, fighting against the "unjust" regimes in Lybia and Syria. Now Assad is not such a bad guy.  Those people bitching about the situation in Egypt, better give their heads a shake. If the Muslim Brotherhood had their way, it would be another Iran. Middle East politics are whacky to say the least. 
2328	Grizz
2401	That is for sure!
2527	Couple of years back, they were our heroes, fighting against the "unjust" regimes in Lybia and Syria. Now Assad is not such a bad guy. Those people bitching about the situation in Egypt, better give their heads a shake. If the Muslim Brotherhood had their way, it would be another Iran. Middle East politics are whacky to say the least. 
2866	Grizz
2882	Looks like someone understands whats going on beyond the 2 ponds... you nailed it...
3086	The L does not stand for Libya. It is "the Levant". ( No not Ezra, look it up)
3166	IS is the name the group adopted worldwide
3210	ISIS= Islamic State of Iraq and Syria
3249	ISIL= Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant ( commonly used by US State Department
3332	Essentially they are "Prince' of the terrorist community
3390	"The terrorist group formerly known as........."
3449	ohh ohhh me me me pick me! Al-cia-da
3557	This should help https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lMUlTSmNu0c
3691	Don't get confused.. Its just one gruop. ISIS
3812	There's a pakastani taliban that differs from the original taliban in afghanistan. Related, yes. Same original group? No. Just offshoots of each other. Like ISIS was "Al Qaeda in Iraq" til the original AQ disowned them and they became ISIS/ISIL.
4162	There's a pakastani taliban that differs from the original taliban in afghanistan. Related, yes. Same original group? No. Just offshoots of each other. Like ISIS was "Al Qaeda in Iraq" til the original AQ disowned them and they became ISIS/ISIL.
4418	All them terrorist groups have 1 thing in common,...can you guess what that is ???.
4575	Csis ?
4679	All them terrorist groups have 1 thing in common,...can you guess what that is ???.
4773	Let me guess....... 
4795	AK - 47?? - NO...
4814	Black uniform? no...
4836	RPG's? Nope again...
5134	This should help https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lMUlTSmNu0c
5421	Oh my, ha, ha, ha, ha.
5646	It's meant to be confusing waterninja. ISIL is real but it stemmed from the illegal invasion of Iraq in 2003 for the most part. Don't believe me? Maybe Obama will explain it better... McCain knew it was coming as well. 
5875	ISIL is a direct outgrowth of Al-Qaeda in Iraq that grew out of our invasion. Which is an example of unintended consequences. Which is why we should generally aim before we shoot.
6065	Oh look, a video of his interview - FF to 11:45
6114	https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2a01Rg2g2Z8#t=745
6165	Now look at the BS in North Africa, Gaddafi in Libya, the overthrow in Egypt. The over throw in Ukraine, the list goes on and on. 
6297	And what is the result of all the crap? Arm sales are gone through the roof. Create an enemy - real and perceived - then monetize it. That's the game. 
6450	Propaganda needs no truth. 
6479	Hermann Goering played the terrorism card very well - and hung for his atrocities. People ask why we don't learn from the past? Because it works and terror laws in Canada are a case in point. Frighten the population and you can do what you want. 
6735	"Why of course the people don't want war. Why should some poor slob on a farm want to risk his life in a war when the best he can get out of it is to come back to his farm in one piece? Naturally the common people don't want war neither in Russia, nor in England, nor for that matter in Germany. That is understood. But, after all, it is the leaders of the country who determine the policy and it is always a simple matter to drag the people along, whether it is a democracy, or a fascist dictatorship, or a parliament, or a communist dictatorship. Voice or no voice, the people can always be brought to the bidding of the leaders. That is easy. All you have to do is tell them they are being attacked, and denounce the peacemakers for lack of patriotism and exposing the country to danger. It works the same in any country."
9093	Wait for bill C-51 to kick in.
9194	This woman can explain
9218	https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFN8ahYN1b0
9370	Can't figure out if it's me, the govt., the newscasters, or the terrorists themselves, but I'm confused. Every day I see snatches of news reports about this group of terrorists called ISIS. Problem is that sometimes they are called ISIS, sometimes called ISIL and sometimes just IS.
9654	Are they all the same group or different groups? Do you start out as an IS and work your way up to an ISIS or ISIL?
9771	Or is it like living in Canada where one day you can be a Canadian, but the next day a Canuck?
9876	It doesn't really matter, for now they our enemy. When Putin ramps up in the Baltic they will change their name again and become our friends the freedom fighters.
10136	This woman can explain
10160	https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFN8ahYN1b0
10214	WOW!!!! What a powerful speech!
10317	ISIS is the same as ISIL
10441	This woman can explain
10465	https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFN8ahYN1b0
