94	Obama hints at Cuba breakthrough as he flies south for Raúl Castro meeting: Havana expected to be dropped from list of state sponsors of terrorism, while John Kerry and Cuban counterpart sit down for highest-level talks in decades
406	The US needs to stop buddying up with terrorist states like Cuba and get back to working with countries that best represent our ideals of freedom and democracy like Saudi Arabia.
661	Apparently the minus voters didn't pick up the sarcasm.
793	Quick make Cuba the 51st state, sorry puerto rico.
921	Despite the horrible things Castro has done this is a good thing. Isolation only hurt the Cuban people who have little choice.
1049	Same with Iran.
1149	Annex that shit obama
1243	It's nice to have adults in the white house.
1364	That Disney ride "Bay of Pigs" was so juvenile!
1487	dont worry John Kerry will be sure to fuck this up.
1616	How long until I can order Cuban Rum on-line?
1747	i'm looking for the cigars on ebay
1858	Can't help but wonder whether this recent expedited process is related to wanting to avoid Cuba repeating history by getting chummy with Russia
2075	Nothing significant has changed since Fidel left and Raul took over I'm guessing that there's pressure from businesses to be allowed to go in and export to new markets.
2318	Florida just lost a lot of business. But since Florida will be underwater i a few years I guess its for the best.
2507	In a world full of uncertainty and violence I'm glad Cuba and the us can finally put a bad past behind them . so glad to see this happening.
2719	I can imagine the kids in 30-50 years time: TIL America and Cuba used to be enemies!
2883	I feel like its good to put the past away but communism shouldn't be trifled with. It was a failed social experiment that led generations of honest human beings into tragic despair. Personal freedom is a human right and necessary for happiness.
3205	Please apply that "standard" to every country then.
3420	Oh wait. The USA being a problem-free democracy was a myth from the very beginning.
3505	Oh wait. Puerto Rico: That sure as fuck was democratic. I'm sure Cuba would have been just as lucky to be colonized, if it wasn't for their larger size and resilient people.
3680	Oh wait. Maybe the concept of an autocratic world police is flawed to it's very core? Maybe international cooperation and local solutions could actually make the world a better place, instead of just pretending to do so?
3977	you must be a fucking hoot at family dinners.
4094	What ever happened to the accusation that a Cuban airline was bombed under US direction?
4265	The CIA agent who did it is living a cozy retired life in Miami.
4404	Cubans are ready.
4423	Cubans are ready for change. A lot of them want to move to Florida still, Tampa or Miami where more than half of all Cubans have family or friends.
4572	For everyone else, they want to setup shops, have normal lives. Most Cubans have an incredibly clear understanding of everything. Shockingly a lot more than many people reading this.
4756	They get that things wont change over night, that a lot of their money will likely end up in the governments hands, that repression will still likely exist 5 years from now, that the insane tourism of Americans will have some negative affects. They get it. But 97% or so are ready. They're excited and they're so very tired of the embargo.
5097	Republicans should understand that the majority of Cubans favor the US president and about half (according to a recent Miami poll from 1,400 respondents ) disapprove of their communist ruler so they aren't complete morons that think Cuba is a communist paradise. That's Congressional bullshit that want Americans to think they're getting the short stick in this deal. You aren't! Nor are Cubans.
5571	It makes me sad hearing that that McCarthy-ist nonsense still has followers over there and yet that generally isn't the Americans I meet. When I visited no one seemed like that. Even the Republicans. Although I was in Iowa and Chicago so...
5894	The McCarthy-ist stuff has largely dropped off the radar of mainstream US politics, those in the US most adamantly against the US improving ties with Cuba are the Cuban expats that fled during the Cuban Revolution. Many of them had their property seized or were attacked by the Castro government and its supporters (e.g. Bacardi Limited).
6311	Yeah, understandably the ex-Pats have a much better reason for hating Castro. Messy.
6471	Idunno. It was pretty bad in 2008.
6588	Compared to the height of the Cold War? People weren't handing out flyers with special numbers to call if you suspected someone of being a "communist sympathizer" so the government could investigate them. In 2008 it was fringe elements pushing it (albeit it was a large and very crazy fringe) and there was little more than empty rhetoric behind it. It was more like at a football game when a group of hardcore fans trash talk the other team. The trash talk and antics were exceptionally bad compared to prior elections, but little came of it beyond talk. Fox News definitely milked it for all it was worth though.
7274	Republicans should understand that the majority of Cubans favor the US president
7356	Don't tell them that, then they'll double down on their anti-cuban efforts.
7507	"Republicans should understand that the majority of Cubans favor the US president and about half (according to a recent Miami poll from 1,400 respondents ) disapprove of their communist ruler."
7702	This makes it sound like your study comes only from Cubans in Miami. I hope that's not what you meant by that because I would like to think that you would understand that there is going to be a difference between the opinions of the descendants of well off conservative Cubans who fled the country worried about their money and the descendents of liberal Cubans who stayed because most had nothing to lose in the Communist regime.
8205	I'm sorry, have you ever lived in Miami? Clearly you haven't because you couldn't be anymore wrong.
8306	Was the first wave of Cubans fleeing the revolution those who were well off in Cuba under Batista? Sure, a lot were. However that is such a minuscule number of the current Cubans in Miami, that to say all Cuban exiles and their descendants are 'well off' is straight up deceitful. Look up the Mariel Boatlift and other mass migrations after the revolution and you can see the vast majority of Cuban immigrants were very poor. I say this myself as the son of Cuban parents who on both sides' families arrived in the US with nothing. The fact is spend any amount of time in Miami and you'll see most Cubans are not well off, and it's a huge misconception some people seem to have here on reddit specifically. Another thing is times have changed, Miami consistently votes Democrat, and a very surprising number of Cubans in Florida actually support ending the embargo, which likely contributed to the Obama administration's decision.
9238	So yeah, sorry to burst your bubble but you should really do your research instead of believing everything that goes around reddit since most of us support our brothers on the island having a better life.
9524	My favorite example is Desi Arnaz. His father was the mayor of Santiago, and they were extremely well off until the revolution, when he was put in jail and everything was confiscated by the government. Desi landed in Miami with his mother (until his father was released and later joined them), and his very first job in America was at a pet store, cleaning bird cages.
9894	He eventually got into show business, playing in Xavier Cugat's orchestra, and went on to completely revolutionize television. Most notably, the three-camera effect you see in everything now, and in the way of claiming syndication rights (which CBS gave up for free), was every bit as smart as Lucas was with his merchandising of Star Wars.
10307	My GF was in Cuba last month. The youths don't give a crap about the revolution nor old ideologies. All they think of are smartphones and social networks, and are annoyed the embargo keeps them from that.
10585	US wants to have Cuba in our sphere of influence to protect Caribbean interests, I'm sure everyone is onboard (except for the who Socialist thing)
10814	I'm not sure Cuba ever truly left the US's "sphere of influence". The sheer number of Cuban expats living in the US and their ties to relatives back in Cuba would have ensured that, along with things like the US base in Guantanamo, and the regular travel of US citizens to and from Puerto Rico and nearby countries like the Bahamas, and Jamaica. US-Cuba ties were definitely strained/weakened during the Cold War, but I'm not sure it would be possible to break them. With the collapse of the USSR decades ago, there really hasn't been any other "spheres" capable of countering US influence on the Caribbean.
11502	The Cubans in Florida were the driving factor of keeping the embargo and sanctions going this long.
11675	It's more of a 'too close for comfort' concern than anything, I'd say, where you don't necessarily fear them, but you lack directly control. Imposing your will also goes against American ideals of freedom and self rule
11974	And what exactly are our Caribbean interests?
12093	Well... the US has always wanted Cuba, assuming we'd eventually get it. But there was the whole "OK Spain, don't give it to anyone but us if you end up giving up control", but then Cuban independence and all that. But it prevents other interests from interfering there (China, Russia, etc)
12384	Sometimes preventing others from having is an interest in and of itself
12535	Viva Cuba LIBRE!
12632	I am exited to see it con mi propio ojos.
12744	The US and Cuba could use more friends.
12861	I can only imagine the reception Obama will get from the public. Do we expect them to kiss his ass after we (USA) have been embargo-ing them for so long?
13093	They'd better seeing as how cuba benefits from this far more than the US does.
13248	80 percent of Cubans say they have a positive opinion of Barack Obama.
13320	47 percent of Cubans say they have a positive opinion of Raul Castro while 48 percent see him negatively. The responses are more positive among older Cubans.
13479	44 percent of Cubans say they have a positive opinion of Fidel Castro. 50 percent view him negatively.
13583	http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/the_americas/poll-shows-vast-majority-of-cubans-welcome-closer-ties-with-us/2015/04/08/6285bfe4-d8c3-11e4-bf0b-f648b95a6488_story.html
13755	Well they like him better then what they currently have.
13896	Could of used a source other then Washington post. But what ever makes you feel good.
14063	why?
14151	You need to stare harder at them gothic fonts. They never lie.
14294	Maybe they could appreciate that he's the first President to improve the situation in 50 years.
14463	Yes! This is a worldly top priority.
14573	What is the impetus for removing Cuba from the list? Were they actually sponsoring terrorism up until recently, or was their inclusion on the list just a case of "Fuck you! Why? Because we can!"?
14852	Obama had the speech in Cairo that led to the Arab Spring. This can lead to another revolution for us.
15030	Cuba was believed to sponsor FARC. There has been no recent evidence of financial support and in late 2011 Cuba allowed the TSA to inspect their airports to make sure that they have security in place to prevent Latin American terrorist groups like FARC from traveling into the USA and it turns out Cuba does have proper security in place. There has been a lot of work behind the scenes between Cuban and American diplomats to ease tensions on both sides. Both sides have had their concerns, but finally they have opened up to each other diplomatically to assuage these concerns.
15689	As far as I know FARC has been severely degraded over the years as well. I don't know that they are even that big a problem for Columbia as they used to be. Maybe in the Darrien Gap.
15950	I was under the impression that they were starting negotiations with the Colombian government since their funding from Cuba and Venezuela has all but ended.
16181	Not only that but Cuba has accepted North Korean ships to dock. That's widely accepted by the international community. Cuba doesn't deny it as they're allied with North Korea.
16358	Example is currently Mexico is holding a North Korean ship and likely will never return it. Several months ago a ship that docked in Cuba was stopped in another Latin American country where it was seized.
16564	They often carry drugs and fake US currency. In fact North Korea is by far the largest producer of fake US currency.
16682	So North Korea alone would qualify them under that list. It's pure political and purely up to Washington as it's it's own list.
16882	That would perhaps be a violation of certain UN sanctions or something along those lines, but it's not nearly the same thing as being a "state sponsor of terrorism." North Korea isn't considered a terrorist organization for obvious reasons, and interestingly it was also removed from that list.
17254	North Korean ships could dock in LA if they wanted to. They'd have to do everything by the books, the ship would have to belong to a North Korean company that's not under sanction, and the exports would have to be cleared first but it could happen. Total commercial exports from the USA to North Korea reached 24 million USD last year.
17674	But when the TPP passes, there are going to be a lot of Cubans thrown in jail for sharing copyrighted content. You can't just unteach people how to share.
17903	Since when is Cuba involved in TPP in any fashion?
17954	Sources?
18039	Since Cuba became a pacific nation in his alternate history book.
18180	Well, you can simply add it to the myriad of mundane bullshit that can get you sent to prison in Cuba. They have almost the same incarceration rate as the USA, but without the war on drugs. Instead of packing people in prisons for petty things like pot possession they imprison people for complaining about breadlines and listening to American radio.
18614	Prove it.
18699	Prove what? Imprisonment rate? Speaking against the government and listening to foreign radio are both covered by Article 103 in the Cuban penal code (http://www.tsp.cu/ley_62_codigo_penal_cuba). If you find this hard to believe then just go and look for yourself around the internet. There are a number of Cuban bloggers that document what's actually going on in the country. Yoani Sanchez is the best known among them (https://generacionyen.wordpress.com/). The fact that the Castro regime jails dissidents is one of the worst kept state secrets after maybe Gaddafi's Amazonian guards and Kim Jung Un's love for Gruyere cheese.
19404	The US government doesn't even think supporting ISIS merits inclusion in the terrorist list so you can be pretty sure that the few who do make it on there are for bullshit reasons just like how Venezuela is supposedly a threat to US national security...
19973	The usual crowd is down voting you for telling the truth. The US has no qualms about protecting it's terrorists:
20087	http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luis_Posada_Carriles
20216	I hope so. The embargo needs to end. It did not have the intended effects and the people of Cuba have suffered for decades as a result. It might have seemed like a good idea at the time but just like the 'war on drugs' it was a failure. Time to begin to set things right.
