94	War with Russia
185	hate to say it but I can't see a way out of this, Putin has never/will never capitulate and NATO have squared up
401	hate to say it but I can't see a way out of this, Putin has never/will never capitulate and NATO have squared up
524	Russia's economy continues to spiral downwards as no one wants to do business with them.
614	Russia is no longer able to pay for its armed forces or pensions.
681	Putins position becomes less and less tenable.
728	.
730	.
754	.
756	.
758	China takes most of eastern Siberia.
796	BBC broadcasts people in Moscow pulling down statues of Putin and hitting them with shoes.
958	best case scenario right there
1062	Oh and if Putin is out, and then some idealist socialists take control like once before, things will turn out great! hehe
1185	This idea that the West can just shove a puppet dictator into power there once Putin is out, and not cause political fractures like we've seen in Ukraine in the last year is just bonkers!
1374	Imagine rebels with control of nuclear weapons... Nice.
1431	Anyone would think the West *wants* ww3!
1473	Dave
1585	Slow escalation is the only possible path for the US to achieve its objectives in the current scenario. The Russians have not "expanded" anywhere in this conflict.
1759	I was suggesting that wrt Russia.
1794	Others allude to Russia being aggressive and warmongering and absolutely wanting war. So why mess around? They'd have been better going all in a year ago and taking all the East European ex Soviet Union territories before Nato could respond conventionally.
2052	Yes, conversely, for the Usa to do their banana republic thing, slow subversive is the only route.
2152	Now the USA has screwed up Ukraind it's back to Syria, Iraq and no doubt Libya, those other recent success stories of Western intervention hehe
2404	Oh and if Putin is out, and then some idealist socialists take control like once before, things will turn out great! hehe
2527	This idea that the West can just shove a puppet dictator into power there once Putin is out, and not cause political fractures like we've seen in Ukraine in the last year is just bonkers!
2716	Imagine rebels with control of nuclear weapons... Nice.
2773	Anyone would think the West *wants* ww3!
2815	Dave
2830	Right better go and get the footings back in for that wall then...
3009	Oh and if Putin is out, and then some idealist socialists take control like once before, things will turn out great! hehe
3132	This idea that the West can just shove a puppet dictator into power there once Putin is out, and not cause political fractures like we've seen in Ukraine in the last year is just bonkers!
3321	Imagine rebels with control of nuclear weapons... Nice.
3378	Anyone would think the West *wants* ww3!
3420	Dave
3435	I'm not one for conspiracy theories, I find them hilarious because they are so far removed from the things people actually should be worried about and I do not think WW3 is on the cards.
3623	That being said the last World War pulled the US out of the depression.
3800	Oh and if Putin is out, and then some idealist socialists take control like once before, things will turn out great! hehe
3923	This idea that the West can just shove a puppet dictator into power there once Putin is out, and not cause political fractures like we've seen in Ukraine in the last year is just bonkers!
4112	Imagine rebels with control of nuclear weapons... Nice.
4169	Anyone would think the West *wants* ww3!
4211	Dave
4226	Why is the choice Putin or Rebel nuclear anialation? Surly the most likely outcome is Russia's existing democratic structure kicks in, and they get politicians who are actually accountable to the people? 
4536	Why is the choice Putin or Rebel nuclear anialation? Surly the most likely outcome is Russia's existing democratic structure kicks in, and they get politicians who are actually accountable to the people? 
4751	Just like in Ukraine, with their recent democratic elections?
4926	I'm not one for conspiracy theories, I find them hilarious because they are so far removed from the things people actually should be worried about and I do not think WW3 is on the cards.
5114	That being said the last World War pulled the US out of the depression.
5196	I'm not one for conspiracy theories either. But I'm also not a subscriber to the idea wars just 'start' by accident through unconsidered posturing and escalation.
5430	Former deputy PM Netsmov, an opposition politician, has been sot dead in Moscow.
5512	Mr Putin's mates do we think?
5646	Former deputy PM Netsmov, an opposition politician, has been sot dead in Moscow.
5728	Mr Putin's mates do we think?
5768	I wouldn't be surprised.
5794	http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-31669061
5910	No way, Putin is bigger than Jesus.
6017	there are two versions and Putin has the problem with both of them
6085	1st : his people are that stupid to kill the opposition leader in front of the Kremlin
6173	2nd(much more probable) : foreign agents are killing people in front of the Kremlin and setting up the false flag
6288	either way - he has the problem
6424	Former deputy PM Netsmov, an opposition politician, has been sot dead in Moscow.
6506	Mr Putin's mates do we think?
6546	He was opposed to Russia's War with the Ukraine and was about to lead a large protest against it.
6645	He recently said "he feared Mr Putin would have him killed because of his opposition to the war in Ukraine."
6755	http://m.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-31669061
6914	Oh and if Putin is out, and then some idealist socialists take control like once before, things will turn out great! hehe
7037	This idea that the West can just shove a puppet dictator into power there once Putin is out, and not cause political fractures like we've seen in Ukraine in the last year is just bonkers!
7226	Imagine rebels with control of nuclear weapons... Nice.
7283	Anyone would think the West *wants* ww3!
7325	Dave
7340	Dave,
7347	The Ukrainian people had a democratic vote.
7392	The Petro Poroshenko Bloc won the most seats (132 seats) in the election (because of its lead in single-seat constituencies) with the People's Front (who gained more votes than the Petro Poroshenko Bloc on the nationwide party list[22]) coming second with 82 seats.[23] 94 independent candidates won a seat in single-seat constituencies, Self Reliance won 33 seats, the Opposition Bloc 29 seats, the Radical Party 22 seats, Fatherland 19 seats, Svoboda 6 seats, Right Sector 1 seat, Strong Ukraine 1 seat, Volia 1 seat, and Zastup also 1 seat.[23] For the first time since Ukraine's 1991 independence Communists have no parliamentary representation.[23][24] The official voter turnout was set at 52.42%.[25] 57% was the turnout in the previous 2012 Ukrainian parliamentary election.[26]
8180	Chocolate man won.
8200	Where were you?
8217	Please note Svoboda only won 6 seats so please don't go down the facist, nazi rant route.
8308	Phil
8416	Former deputy PM Netsmov, an opposition politician, has been sot dead in Moscow.
8498	Mr Putin's mates do we think?
8561	He was opposed to Russia's War with the Ukraine and was about to lead a large protest against it.
8660	He recently said "he feared Mr Putin would have him killed because of his opposition to the war in Ukraine."
8770	http://m.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-31669061
8836	Russia's only real democratic alternative to Putin...
8891	hmmm
8999	there are two versions and Putin has the problem with both of them
9067	1st : his people are that stupid to kill the opposition leader in front of the Kremlin
9155	2nd(much more probable) : foreign agents are killing people in front of the Kremlin and setting up the false flag
9270	either way - he has the problem
9312	EFA
9390	So Putin continues to take Russia further back towards the early days of the cold war, if not beyond.
9493	Russian society must surely be starting to wake up and smell the vodka. There have been that many allegations of election fraud, organised crime connections, and opposition leader 'accidents' during Putin's reign that something has to give. 
9736	They're already in a North Korea type situation where anybody who stands as a critic of Putin (Pussy Riot, Litvenenko, et al) can expect a visit from the Police, or worse, some of his old FSB mates who don't intend taking you back as a prisoner.
9983	He's about as good of an example of a blatantly corrupt dictator as you get.
10173	Dave,
10180	The Ukrainian people had a democratic vote.
10225	The Petro Poroshenko Bloc won the most seats (132 seats) in the election (because of its lead in single-seat constituencies) with the People's Front (who gained more votes than the Petro Poroshenko Bloc on the nationwide party list[22]) coming second with 82 seats.[23] 94 independent candidates won a seat in single-seat constituencies, Self Reliance won 33 seats, the Opposition Bloc 29 seats, the Radical Party 22 seats, Fatherland 19 seats, Svoboda 6 seats, Right Sector 1 seat, Strong Ukraine 1 seat, Volia 1 seat, and Zastup also 1 seat.[23] For the first time since Ukraine's 1991 independence Communists have no parliamentary representation.[23][24] The official voter turnout was set at 52.42%.[25] 57% was the turnout in the previous 2012 Ukrainian parliamentary election.[26]
11013	Chocolate man won.
11033	Where were you?
11050	Please note Svoboda only won 6 seats so please don't go down the facist, nazi rant route.
11141	Phil
11156	Eh?
11161	Ukraine had democratic elections.
11196	They now have civil war.
11222	Perfect example that ousting Putin democratically via Western pressures may fracture Russia into vying capitalist/socialist leaning factions, among many others.
11384	Which is the point I'm making.
11416	Pushing Putin out of leadership may result in a worse Russia.
11479	But hey that is the Western way.
11513	Make any potential opponent or defiant government a shambles so they can be manipulated. Just look at every country the USA has been involved in for the last 40 years.
11682	Fine if that is what they like doing, but Russia has nuclear weapons. Potentially having them fall into the control of rebels isn't ideal. Especially if that then means the USA has to go in to protect the world from rebels with nuclear weapons.
11928	Talk about false flags. It's playing out just like a shallow as a puddle Western spy thriller!
