94	St. Leo University (National): Hillary up 9-16 points
224	http://polls.saintleo.edu/clintons-numbers-slip-but-she-maintains-frontrunner-position/
313	Clinton 47
324	Christie 38
337	Clinton 49
348	Paul 39
357	Clinton 49
368	Bush 38
377	Clinton 50
388	Walker 36
399	Clinton 51
410	Rubio 35
420	So much for all the self-proclaimed political experts who claimed emailgate would doom Hillary.
587	They're a couple points off on Walker and Rubio. But yeah, the emailgate fallout has yet to occur. emailgate needs a smoking gun first - right now it's really just a "I'm too cool to follow tradition" situation, which voters don't really care about.
912	St. Leo University? What do we know about their record? 
1001	http://polls.saintleo.edu/clintons-numbers-slip-but-she-maintains-frontrunner-position/
1133	Clinton 49
1144	Paul 39
1273	So much for all the self-proclaimed political experts who claimed emailgate would doom Hillary.
1379	Eh, I highly doubt those numbers are true. If we dismiss Gravis, we really should dismiss this one, too.
1591	St. Leo University? What do we know about their record? 
1658	From a cursory glance of their site:
1696	Final FL-Gov poll: Crist up 3 (4 point miss)
1742	FL-26: Curbelo up 4 (nailed it)
1775	Their track record is more thin than bad, so better than Gravis, though that's obviously not saying much.
1980	St. Leo University? What do we know about their record? 
2069	From a cursory glance of their site:
2107	Final FL-Gov poll: Crist up 3 (4 point miss)
2153	FL-26: Curbelo up 4 (nailed it)
2186	Their track record is more thin than bad, so better than Gravis, though that's obviously not saying much.
2312	The average error on 2014 polls was bad across the board due to the unpredictably abysmal turnout.
2516	St. Leo University? What do we know about their record? 
2605	From a cursory glance of their site:
2643	Final FL-Gov poll: Crist up 3 (4 point miss)
2689	FL-26: Curbelo up 4 (nailed it)
2722	Their track record is more thin than bad, so better than Gravis, though that's obviously not saying much.
2856	The average error on 2014 polls was bad across the board due to the unpredictably abysmal turnout.
2985	The polls weren't actually that bad, by the standards of recent midterm elections:
3069	http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/03/24/election-polling_n_6932004.html
3143	Quote
3149	The polling misfires of 2014 have greater precedent if we broaden the comparison to include different measures and elections held in the 1990s and earlier. For example, Nate Silver’s initial assessment of average bias— whether polls collectively favored one party or the other—in 2014 found an average four percentage point understatement of Republican Senate margins. However, this calculation also revealed an equally large bias against the Republicans (4.0) in 2002 and an even bigger bias against the Democrats (4.9) in 1998.
3680	Also:
