94	Obama's approval rating at an all time high of 80 percent. Yeah it's in Cuba, but you take what you can get
281	His approval among Cuban Americans is pretty high, too (last I read, something in the vicinity of 54-56%). The younger Cuban-Americans simply don't hold the same anti-Communist antagonism the old Cuban-Americans have and they're turning into Democrats.
618	Well, he is the greatest socialist in the history of history, so it stands to reason
780	In a new NBC poll, he hits a 28 month high.
825	51 percent of Americans approve of how Obama is handling his job, compared with 48 percent who disapprove.
1043	In a new NBC poll, he hits a 28 month high.
1088	51 percent of Americans approve of how Obama is handling his job, compared with 48 percent who disapprove.
1205	and republicans control congress - ALL of congress. they're farked.
1350	Wonder what Ted "My father is Cuban" Cruz is polling at.
1521	Well, he is the greatest socialist in the history of history, so it stands to reason
1616	Why is the term "socialist" so ironically lost on right wingers?
1809	Well, he is the greatest socialist in the history of history, so it stands to reason
1924	Why is the term "socialist" so ironically lost on right wingers?
2009	Well, pretty much everything else* is, so...
2055	/*especially self-awareness
2153	at an all time high
2174	Now I have that horrible Octopussy theme song stuck in my head.
2344	In a new NBC poll, he hits a 28 month high.
2389	51 percent of Americans approve of how Obama is handling his job, compared with 48 percent who disapprove.
2530	and republicans control congress - ALL of congress. they're farked.
2618	Same thing happened during the reign of St Ronald of The Reagan.
2758	Meanwhile, 55 percent of Cubans said they'd like to live in another country, with 52 percent of that group saying their preferred country would be America.
2915	Yeah... I don't think that's exactly a surprising new trend.
3055	So the whole Castro and Communism thing was not so great, then?
3596	Suck it, neocons. Suck it long and suck it hard.
3718	It might be for the same reason that almost nobody hates Santa Claus.
3861	Obama is supposed to meet with Raoul Castro tomorrow in Panama.  They'll at the least have a nice cordial visit.  More likely Obama will score another foreign affairs win with some kind of preliminary agreement relating to the opening of relations with Cuba.  And the GOP will lose their minds again for the umpteenth time since the new congress sat down on their nuts in January.
4347	It might be for the same reason that almost nobody hates Santa Claus.
4427	Almost nobody over the age of 8 thinks Santa exists, or has any kind of opinions on international affairs based on Santa.  Or was your comment a "Ted Cruz-like I was joking" kind of comment?  Conservatives do humor so badly.
5174	Suck it, neocons. Suck it long and suck it hard.
5233	10 cups of coffee in a box? Where's my straw?
5356	It's pathetic that Obama abandoned the embargo when it was so close to the desired goal of toppling the Castros. Ten, maybe twenty years tops and I guarantee that Cuba would have been out from under the thumb of Fidel and Raul.
5687	It might be for the same reason that almost nobody hates Santa Claus.
5767	Obama doesn't exist?
5789	Well... that's a new tack on "empty suit."
5941	It's pathetic that Obama abandoned the embargo when it was so close to the desired goal of toppling the Castros. Ten, maybe twenty years tops and I guarantee that Cuba would have been out from under the thumb of Fidel and Raul.
6179	Most people don't realize the economic boon to Cuba the embargo is.  Where are you going to go for 40s/50s GM, Ford and Chrysler parts and mechanics who know how to install them perfectly?  Lifting the embargo is going to fark them up so bad...
6538	It's pathetic that Obama abandoned the embargo when it was so close to the desired goal of toppling the Castros. Ten, maybe twenty years tops and I guarantee that Cuba would have been out from under the thumb of Fidel and Raul.
6776	This is something we should have done ten or twenty years ago if you ask me. The GOP have been holding on to the Commie Cuba boogie man for far too long to appease a group in south fla that got them into all that trouble in the first place.
7018	Your sarcasm was noted I just had to get on my high horse. Have a Canadian cousin that vacations there and says its near paradise. Yes U.S. canadians are able to vacation there.
7583	Hell on earth according to the GOP just because they cant control it
7761	It's pathetic that Obama abandoned the embargo when it was so close to the desired goal of toppling the Castros. Ten, maybe twenty years tops and I guarantee that Cuba would have been out from under the thumb of Fidel and Raul.
8026	This is something we should have done ten or twenty years ago if you ask me. The GOP have been holding on to the Commie Cuba boogie man for far too long to appease a group in south fla that got them into all that trouble in the first place.
8268	Your sarcasm was noted I just had to get on my high horse. Have a Canadian cousin that vacations there and says its near paradise. Yes U.S. canadians are able to vacation there.
8833	Hell on earth according to the GOP just because they cant control it
8922	There's an embargo from the US, but not from the rest of the world.  We have this myth that Cuba is choking on their own dysfunction because they have no tourism or trade with the US.  We're kind of self-absorbed that way.  But they'll cave eventually and overthrow their commie bosses.
9282	According to an NPR interview, these are from the same people who want Michael Jackson to visit.
9452	His quarterly approval rating doesn't really matter. He has managed to accomplish quite a bit, considering the derp-storm he has sailed through. So much vitriolic derp has been heaved his way, it is hard to keep it all in mind. Do we even remember little details like Michelle and Barack fist bumping on stage during one of the early rallies and one of the pundits called it a "terrorist fistbump"? It is an ocean of stupid these past six years. And still he has managed to check things off the list. Amazing.
10064	His quarterly approval rating doesn't really matter. He has managed to accomplish quite a bit, considering the derp-storm he has sailed through. So much vitriolic derp has been heaved his way, it is hard to keep it all in mind. Do we even remember little details like Michelle and Barack fist bumping on stage during one of the early rallies and one of the pundits called it a "terrorist fistbump"? It is an ocean of stupid these past six years. And still he has managed to check things off the list. Amazing.
10584	Wasn't it "terrorist fist jab"?
10617	Possibly the most utterly racist and crazy of the myriad of bullshiat that the Obamas have had to deal with. It's one of the few times that there is no explanation for why that would be anything other that trying to make a connection between Obama and "terrorists". Fist-bumping is largely a thing in black communities. And not in terrorist ones. I, seriously, to this day, want to punch her in the face for saying that. Just thinking about it makes me angry.
11209	His quarterly approval rating doesn't really matter. He has managed to accomplish quite a bit, considering the derp-storm he has sailed through. So much vitriolic derp has been heaved his way, it is hard to keep it all in mind. Do we even remember little details like Michelle and Barack fist bumping on stage during one of the early rallies and one of the pundits called it a "terrorist fistbump"? It is an ocean of stupid these past six years. And still he has managed to check things off the list. Amazing.
11775	Wasn't it "terrorist fist jab"?
11808	Possibly the most utterly racist and crazy of the myriad of bullshiat that the Obamas have had to deal with. It's one of the few times that there is no explanation for why that would be anything other that trying to make a connection between Obama and "terrorists". Fist-bumping is largely a thing in black communities. And not in terrorist ones. I, seriously, to this day, want to punch her in the face for saying that. Just thinking about it makes me angry.
12288	Yes you are right! Fist jab. They threw everything they had.
12417	You know, it's almost as if the Cuban people are greeting Obama as a liberator.
12565	You know, it's almost as if the Cuban people are greeting Obama as a liberator.
12645	What a cheater! He didn't even invade the place!!!
12774	Wonder what Ted "My father is Cuban" Cruz is polling at.
12831	You mean Rafael "Ted" "My Father is a Cuban" Cruz.
