94	Hillary clinton dramatic lie exposed by CBS
213	https://youtu.be/8BfNqhV5hg4
315	I'm all for Hillary Clinton brandishing her ovaries above her head while she storms the White House, but constantly saying she wants to be the "first woman President" is a bit redundant; we know she's a woman, and that she wants to be President. By taking that angle, her gender could be seen as being to blame if she doesn't win.
717	https://youtu.be/uHVEDq6RVXc
818	i won't vote for her now
946	https://youtu.be/uHVEDq6RVXc
985	oorah
992	this made my day !!
1086	Even if she was telling the truth, it would hardly be "battle tested experience" - it would be "politician endangers the lives of her security team in order to get a photo shaking hands with some people who have just lived through a war".
1405	Wasn't this revealed years ago?
1508	I question how we can call the US a democracy when lobby groups and rich billionares influence the media and really who candidates are selected.
1654	It's merely a choice of Hillary vs a ipac-lobbyist republican if we believe the media. No choice of other parties, other groups etc. Barely 'democracy' if you only really have one option.
1913	She almost is over qualified to be president.
2038	Clintons are as much criminals as Bush and Obama.
2165	"Hillary Clinton and her husband are evil satanists and they are using ID politics (look up who invented that and you will see who rules over us) to control the female vote.
2340	She is not pro-female, she is anti-female.  Pro-abortion, pro-gay marriage.
2417	A real female leader would look to build stronger traditional marriage and not abort babies."
2512	Pro-female means giving women the freedom to have control over their own bodies and their own lives, hence the pro-abortion. What has the relationships of other people got to do with female empowerment
2786	So killing unborn babies empowers women? What empowers any one is being able to get a good job and live a decent life.
3016	https://youtu.be/8BfNqhV5hg4
3055	F*** me Quds force puppet.
3083	That news story's about ten years old.
3123	How many gays has your beloved country hung from Cranes this week?
3299	So killing unborn babies empowers women? What empowers any one is being able to get a good job and live a decent life.
3428	Being able to receive a safe, sanitary procedure to end cells growing in your own uterus which you will then have to give birth to and bring up for the next 18 years is empowering. It is extremely psychologically painful having the knowledge and physical evidence of something growing inside of you which you don't want. In places where abortion is illegal, back street abortions involving sticking needles into the vagina and drinking poison are commonplace. Being pro-choice means wishing to bring hygiene and safety to desperate women, as opposed to leaving them to drastic, dangerous resorts.
4026	Since when is having a good job mutually exclusive to abortion? You can have both..
4182	Listen I don't want to go into the abortion debate but saying that abortion empowers women is completely ridiculous. It gives women more options but does not empower them.
4462	Listen I don't want to go into the abortion debate but saying that abortion empowers women is completely ridiculous. It gives women more options but does not empower them.
4644	Giving women more options' is by nature giving them more power over their own bodies and lives, hence 'empowering' them.
4837	Empowering is the wrong word in my opinion.
4989	Empowering is the wrong word in my opinion.
5043	empower
5052	ɪmˈpaʊə,ɛm-/
5066	verb
5072	gerund or present participle: empowering
5114	give (someone) the authority or power to do something.
5170	"members are empowered to audit the accounts of limited companies"
5238	make (someone) stronger and more confident, especially in controlling their life and claiming their rights.
5422	So....he did not have sexual relations with that woman, and she did run under fire at the airport.
5522	God certainly made and matched them.
5666	So....he did not have sexual relations with that woman, and she did run under fire at the airport.
5766	God certainly made and matched them.
5813	The scary thing is we have an option:
5852	1. Her and her husband as president
5889	2. A republican AIPAC pro-war neocon.
5928	The media has taken a complete blind eye to all the other democratic potential presidents. Why can't we have another democrat instead of Hillary ? If someone can have amnesia or lies like that, it really worries me they will be in charge of America.
