94	Hillary Clinton as the next leader of the damned?
221	One thing I think is clear, worst case scenario is she does just as terrible as the long line of fools we've had as recent presidents.  Would be interesting to see whether or not she can do better though.
504	She will make the worst POTUS ever in the history of the United States. By the end of her term, she will make the country bankrupt by indulging in unnecessary wars all around the world. First, she will attack Iran. Once that is done, the next will be North Korea. Venezuela and Bolivia might be the next targets. The ultimate target will be Russia.
964	She will make the worst POTUS ever in the history of the United States. By the end of her term, she will make the country bankrupt by indulging in unnecessary wars all around the world. First, she will attack Iran. Once that is done, the next will be North Korea. Venezuela and Bolivia might be the next targets. The ultimate target will be Russia.
1323	I think you mean 'more' bankrupt, but who's counting.  The wars, do you mean she will do as exactly as we've already been doing. I don't believe she has expressed any such agenda.
1614	I think you mean 'more' bankrupt, but who's counting.  The wars, do you mean she will do as exactly as we've already been doing. I don't believe she has expressed any such agenda.
1804	Hillary's foreign policies are much more "hawkish" when compared to Obama. Remember that she almost single-handedly triggered the invasion of Libya. Also, she has advocated for US ground forces in Ukraine, to fight against the Russian-backed separatists. Her role in the NATO interventions of Bosnia, Serbia, Kosovo.etc should not be forgotten.
2257	I think you mean 'more' bankrupt, but who's counting.  The wars, do you mean she will do as exactly as we've already been doing. I don't believe she has expressed any such agenda.
2475	Hillary's foreign policies are much more "hawkish" when compared to Obama. Remember that she almost single-handedly triggered the invasion of Libya. Also, she has advocated for US ground forces in Ukraine, to fight against the Russian-backed separatists. Her role in the NATO interventions of Bosnia, Serbia, Kosovo.etc should not be forgotten.
2840	ugh thats all we need, to mettle in other countries business.
2903	guess we need more debt, trillions isnt enough.. lets build up zillions of $$ of debt.
3098	I think you mean 'more' bankrupt, but who's counting.  The wars, do you mean she will do as exactly as we've already been doing. I don't believe she has expressed any such agenda.
3316	Hillary's foreign policies are much more "hawkish" when compared to Obama. Remember that she almost single-handedly triggered the invasion of Libya. Also, she has advocated for US ground forces in Ukraine, to fight against the Russian-backed separatists. Her role in the NATO interventions of Bosnia, Serbia, Kosovo.etc should not be forgotten.
3681	No doubt, people have to have blinders on or not paying attention to see what she's been up to and how she'll continue to proceed if elected. All major policies are the same when it comes to the establishment types like her, Bush and the entire neocon ilk.
4011	People vote with their hearts not with their minds. They vote for the person not the policies. She'll win because most women will vote for her on the mere fact she's a woman alone.
4193	They voted Obama because they wanted to see a black man win. In a way I was glad to see it too, but it hasn't really panned out too well has it. Oh well, give the broad a try...
4372	Anyway, there's better broads out there. Hillary is corrupt as hell. At least she is menopausal so she won't start WWIII when she gets PMS
4626	She will make the worst POTUS ever in the history of the United States. 
4709	It has been the rule for decades now that each president has to be worse than the last. The worst possible evil "wins" because they count the votes.
4971	People vote with their hearts not with their minds. They vote for the person not the policies. She'll win because most women will vote for her on the mere fact she's a woman alone.
5153	They voted Obama because they wanted to see a black man win. In a way I was glad to see it too, but it hasn't really panned out too well has it. Oh well, give the broad a try...
5332	Anyway, there's better broads out there. Hillary is corrupt as hell. At least she is menopausal so she won't start WWIII when she gets PMS
5481	I agree somewhat, a female president is inline with the current liberal zeitgeist pervading much of the US (from an outsiders view).
5721	People vote with their hearts not with their minds. They vote for the person not the policies. She'll win because most women will vote for her on the mere fact she's a woman alone.
5903	They voted Obama because they wanted to see a black man win. In a way I was glad to see it too, but it hasn't really panned out too well has it. Oh well, give the broad a try...
6082	Anyway, there's better broads out there. Hillary is corrupt as hell. At least she is menopausal so she won't start WWIII when she gets PMS
6261	I agree somewhat, a female president is inline with the current liberal zeitgeist pervading much of the US (from an outsiders view).
6414	That may be true, but it does not apply to Hillary.  She ceased being female long ago.  She is now Uber Zombie WarWitch of the Inner Scrotum of Thieverville.
6679	People vote with their hearts not with their minds. They vote for the person not the policies. She'll win because most women will vote for her on the mere fact she's a woman alone.
6861	They voted Obama because they wanted to see a black man win. In a way I was glad to see it too, but it hasn't really panned out too well has it. Oh well, give the broad a try...
7040	Anyway, there's better broads out there. Hillary is corrupt as hell. At least she is menopausal so she won't start WWIII when she gets PMS
7219	I agree somewhat, a female president is inline with the current liberal zeitgeist pervading much of the US (from an outsiders view).
7385	That may be true, but it does not apply to Hillary.  She ceased being female long ago.  She is now Uber Zombie WarWitch of the Inner Scrotum of Thieverville.
7573	Lesser evil and all that sounds like the description of a saint in the day and age comparatively.
7747	HILLARY CLINTON TAKES HIT IN WSJ POLL, GOES 24 DAYS WITHOUT TALKING TO MEDIA
7825	The fact that Hillary Clinton – the likely Democratic presidential nominee – hasn’t addressed the controversy over her private email server and the fundraising controversy surrounding the Clinton Foundation in an interview or with the public seems to be causing the former Secretary of State to take a hit in the polls.
8146	A new Wall Street Journal/NBC poll finds that although Democrat support for Clinton remains strong, the percentage of people who view Clinton negatively has increased six percent since last month’s poll, as controversies swirl around the former First Lady.
8404	Last month, roughly 36 percent of individuals surveyed said they viewed Clinton negatively, but now that is up to 42 percent. The Wall Street Journal reports only 25 percent of voters say they think Clinton is honest – which is down more than 10 percent from a poll last summer.
8684	It has been 24 days – more than three weeks – since Clinton announced her bid for president, yet she still has not spoken to national media about her campaign or to address the controversies she is facing. Breitbart News previously reported this is a record for presidential candidates in recent history.
8990	http://www.breitbart.com/big-government/2015/05/05/hillary-clinton-takes-hit-in-wsj-poll-goes-24-days-without-talking-to-media/
9194	http://www.politico.com/story/2015/05/hillary-clinton-2016-andrea-mitchell-117647.html
9282	It’s Andrea Mitchell, host of “Andrea Mitchell Reports” on MSNBC, a top correspondent for NBC News, and a veteran of the Clinton beat who will spearhead the network’s Clinton coverage for 2016 — years after driving coverage on big stories like Whitewater, Bill’s impeachment, and Hillary’s first forays as a candidate.
9602	Mitchell, 68, is back on the trail, acting more like a cub reporter hungry for her first scoop than a star television journalist with her own show or a Washington insider married to former Fed chair Alan Greenspan. She’s one of the most senior reporters covering the race, and one of the most outwardly aggressive, calling Clinton out, chasing her down, asking her questions — and occasionally getting a roundabout answer. Some sources suggest she’s getting under the Clinton camp’s skin, a rope-line irritant constantly shouting after the former secretary of state to answer questions. For Mitchell, it’s second nature.
10224	Read more: http://www.politico.com/story/2015/05/hillary-clinton-2016-andrea-mitchell-117647.html#ixzz3ZJmByD1G
10412	Hillary Clinton rejects Bill’s immigration crackdown, vows lenient approach
10489	Bill Clinton was the strictest president in modern political times when it comes to immigration, signing bills cracking down on both legal and illegal immigrants — but it’s unlikely that record will infect his wife, Hillary Rodham Clinton, who has promised a more lenient approach as she makes a push for Hispanic voters in her presidential bid.
10836	The former first lady and secretary of state already earns relatively high ratings from Hispanics and is moving quickly to head off problems, with her team reaching out to Latino leaders to take the temperature of the community.
11066	On Tuesday Mrs. Clinton will be in Las Vegas to talk immigration with young voters her campaign says are “personally affected” by the issue — a signal, coming this early in the campaign, that she is determined to capitalize on an issue that could produce tremendous payoff in a general election matchup.
11371	Read more: http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2015/may/4/hillary-clinton-rejects-bill-clinton-immigration-c/#ixzz3ZJuBiZfv 
11572	Hillary is the favorite among millionaire voters: Survey
11630	Hillary Clinton is the favorite U.S. presidential candidate among millionaire voters and would win a head-to-head contest with former Florida Governor Jeb Bush, according to the third CNBC Millionaire Survey conducted in March that was released today.
11883	The survey, which polls 750 Americans with a net worth of $1 million or more, found that 53 percent of millionaires would vote for the Democratic ex-Secretary of State, compared with 47 percent for the GOP presidential hopeful, in a hypothetical general-election match-up. Clinton had the support of 91 percent of Democratic millionaires, 13 percent of Republican millionaires and 57 percent of Independent millionaires.
12305	More...http://www.cnbc.com/id/102650475
12423	Cronyism confirmed.
