94	cuba to lose notorious designation...
209	http://www.cnn.com/2015/04/07/politi...ist/index.html
754	"Our expectation" is that Cuba will be removed from the list, the official said. But the official cautioned the Obama administration has yet to make any formal announcement. While that announcement from the State Department is not expected Tuesday, it could come as early as Wednesday.
1116	Yeah, enrich the Castro regime. The embargo was working perfectly. 
1185	Obama is an idiot.
1313	Yeah, enrich the Castro regime. The embargo was working perfectly. 
1382	Obama is an idiot.
1592	RiL is right.
1607	Here, enjoy. (NSFW - gangsta)
1709	LOL...Castro still in some Americans heads.
1858	LOL...Castro still in some Americans heads.
1912	particularly in the older generations...
2024	I wonder if we got anything in return for this? Like maybe the release of Alan Gross or maybe the release of some long term political prisoners.
2273	I wonder if we got anything in return for this? Like maybe the release of Alan Gross or maybe the release of some long term political prisoners.
2428	Extremely doubtful. Obama negotiates about as well as an 85 year-old senile grandmother at a used car lot.
2643	Yeah, enrich the Castro regime. The embargo was working perfectly. 
2712	Obama is an idiot.
2741	LOL the embargo has only worked to impoverish the Cuban people. Liberating Cuba is but another foreign affairs feather in Obama's cap.
2982	Extremely doubtful. Obama negotiates about as well as an 85 year-old senile grandmother at a used car lot.
3099	And yet Obama and Kerry have negotiated two historic foreign affairs triumphs in a row: liberating Cuba and preventing Iran from going nuclear.
3357	LOL the embargo has only worked to impoverish the Cuban people. Liberating Cuba is but another foreign affairs feather in Obama's cap.
3502	If you think this is a feather in Obama's cap (I don't), then this is about the only feather there. He has been a failure at almost every turn. Bin Laden was killed under his watch, but that was conducted by others far more competent and willing than he.
3871	And yet Obama and Kerry have negotiated two historic foreign affairs triumphs in a row: liberating Cuba and preventing Iran from going nuclear.
4126	Ok, clearly we're dealing with a true believer here.
4283	And yet Obama and Kerry have negotiated two historic foreign affairs triumphs in a row: liberating Cuba and preventing Iran from going nuclear.
4437	Are you Brian Williams?
4535	y'all realize George Bush removed North Korea from this list back in 2008?
4688	I think Cuba's continuing designation as a State Sponsor of Terrorism should hinge on whether they are continuing to be a state sponsor of terrorism. There is very little evidence that they are. They've provided safe haven to a few fugitives to a couple of revolutionary type groups, neither of which is directly in conflict with the United States. They have not provided weapons or training to any terrorist groups for a very long time.
5127	If Cuba is compared to groups like Iran, Sudan, and Syria, the only other three countries of the list, it's clear that Cuba doesn't belong. If Cuba is compared to countries that are not on the list, like Pakistan and Sri Lanka, it's equally clear that Cuba doesn't belong on the list.
