94	PM Benjamin Netanyahu to address Congress
211	No she is a good sign that not all Yanks a brainwashed Israel nuthuggers.
286	Like other western nations.
385	Bibi Using Congressional Address In New Campaign Ad, Just As Critics Warned
461	Posted: 03/12/2015 1:38 pm EDT Updated: 03/12/2015 2:59 pm EDT
525	WASHINGTON -- When House Speaker John Boehner (R-Ohio) announced he had invited Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to address a joint session of Congress just a few weeks ahead of an Israeli election, he was criticized for giving Netanyahu a platform to boost his campaign.
807	The United States has a policy of not meeting with foreign leaders in advance of elections, so as not to appear to be tilting the electoral balance. But Netanyahu insisted that his motivations had nothing to do with the election, and that the timing of the speech was demanded by the urgency of the Iran nuclear negotiations. There was simply no time to waste.
1169	Already, however, Netanyahu is using his speech as a prop in a campaign commercial back in Israel, where the prime minister is shown basking in the applause of members of Congress who did not boycott his speech. 
1383	Read more at:
1398	http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/03/12/bibi-campaign-ad_n_6856826.html
1547	Cotter said: "You are defined by your written words."
1602	---So?? Then?? Are you a liar or just ignorant?
1651	Both, it is no secret that Jew haters use the word "Zionist" as a code word to disguise their anti-Seminism.
1761	They conveniently forget how the last stoush in 2014 was started by Hamas firing Iranian supplied rockets into Israel for no other purpose than to kill Israeli citizens and when casualties were confirmed they had street parties to celebrate.
2004	They conveniently bring up the myth of the Israelis being land grabbers, but fail to acknowledge that the Israelis withdrew from the Gaza Strip in 2005 after the PA agreed to not use that land to launch rocket attacks against Israel. The Israelis were deceived of course and effectively traded land for terror.
2316	The nutters claim that Israel is a genocidal regime, but don't ever produce any evidence to back up that claim and in the meantime fail to recognise that 20% of the Israeli population are actually Muslims so if they were genocidal why do they not kill those Muslims?
2584	The last Miss Israel was a Muslim, why didn't they kill her?
2646	The PA leaders wife regularly attends a hospital in Israel for treatment, why don't they kill her?
2746	They fail to acknowledge that since 1993 Hamas has conducted 100's of suicide bomb attacks right across Israel, killing and maiming innocent civilians and when the deaths are confirmed they have street parties to celebrate.
2971	As they fail to acknowledge stuff like the above it confirms that they are in fact Jew haters and hence Hamas supporters.
3164	Don't worry some would like to.
3197	The same way Arabic Israeli football players are threatened.
3259	Whats your dog in the fight? hamas firing rockets into Victoria?
3394	LMFAO 
3402	One of the Senate's biggest boobs is now scheduled to go see BN. 
3469	I suppose it's so he can pat BN on the back for revealing how racist he is. Boy oh boy ... I bet he really wishes the "Arab" Israelis weren't allowed to vote.
3629	Ole Mr. Zionist in chief will get an extra "atta boy" from our "orange" guy for admitting he never wanted a two-state solution and he will see to it that it never happens.
3876	Congratulations on your landslide election victory, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu! Bravo!
3971	The United States of America and all of her citizens share in the joy of your well-proven leadership. 
4075	May our two countries continue to be fantastic allies against the vicious evildoers in that volatile region.
4289	One of the Senate's biggest boobs is now scheduled to go see BN. 
4365	He going there to get his marching orders
4408	The same guy who questions Obama's patriotism
4455	...................
4475	poster 106 says:,
4494	The United States of America and all of her________ citizens share in the joy ...
4577	You don't speak for me; I'm a free thinking citizen
4630	please insert the word 'neocon' in the above blank.
4760	Herzog gave his concession speech &amp; his Zionists conceded to Netanyahu.
4837	Lots of people/parties ran against Netanyahu, even some Americans.
4905	Netanyahu is still waiting for Obama &amp; his opposition party to give a concession speech.
5074	Now that Netanyahu has said a two state solution is out, I wonder how he's going to sell the two state solution he's been pushing for since first elected..
5302	correct again Eric. ALL patriotic Americans can rejoice over the landslide victory of Mr. Netanyahu. Bebe knows that the radical muslims who oppose an Israeli State understand only one thing and that is strength and power. whereas the golfer thinks that if we delay the Iranians from getting a nuke for 10 years he can persuade them to be nice. the FOOL!
5658	the community golfer has shown his true colors by delaying his congratulatory phone call to the protector of Israel.
5776	he wanted the dove to win so they would both be in sync. now like a little child he pouts that he didn't get his way and puts off the right thing to do. 
6192	but nooooooo. he sulks in a corner and puffs on a cigarette peeking around to make sure Michelle doesn't catch him smoking. he's a weakling, our worst president of modern times.
6442	when Hussein finally DID call BN he told him he had to "reassess" his Israeli policy. 
6530	what the hell does that mean??
6672	Netanyahu is still waiting for Obama &amp; his opposition party to give a concession speech.
6775	You said Herzog gave a concession speech and then you said the Netanyahu's opposition didn't? Lol!! 
6877	Here's a hint: If you're not in a race, you don't concede. You actually have to be in a race to be defeated. Just look at the 2014 election. All the Republicans were back-slapping and partying over what they thought was a defeat for the President. A week later he stuck the finger in their face with his immigration policy. Pen-slapped their hopes for Keystone. He showed that Republicans didn't win squat except the country's focus on their incompetence at leading. 
7346	BN didn't defeat Obama either. He has merely isolated Israel from America. He's going to find out that his childish stunt will have consequences. He's got to remember that Republicans don't have much control over American diplomacy. That ball is in the President's court. I see a bunch of neocons bowing down to Netanyahu, but this president isn't going to. Obama rightfully didn't even call to congratulate that disrespectful flip-flopper.
7897	when Hussein finally DID call BN he told him he had to "reassess" his Israeli policy. 
7985	what the hell does that mean??
8026	That was Obama's version of a "concession speech". Obama lost that election, despite his monumental effort to oust Netanyahu &amp; install the Zionists. He made the call, but being the sore loser he is, he couldnt bring himself to do the right thing. He had to go full-nut narcissist.
8312	But see, Obama cant believe he lost, so he thinks he knows better than a majority of Israelis, &amp; also thinks he knows better than a majority of Congress , therefore he must show all of them how "wrong" they are &amp; how "right" he is LMAO. What a self serving d!ckhead.
8660	BN has done the not-so-savvy political move of making American-Israeli relations a matter of politics rather than that of an ally. Our support for Israel used to be bipartisan. Now the Republicans want to frame the issue as a wedge issue. BN doesn't realize how badly he hurt his country by dividing America and making his country a pawn in the Democrats vs. Republicans struggle. 
9043	Republicans are only harming Israel by pitting Obama vs. Netanyahu. They want Obama to kiss their master's ring. They're all butt hurt that he's not going to do that. Republicans should back off their efforts to divide America against Israel.
9365	Obama should be tried &amp; hanged for meddling in the Israeli elections. He went out on a limb in support of the liberal Zionists' effort to oust Netanyahu. Nothing like imposing your own selfish agenda on another country &amp; its majority.
9609	American liberal racists who march in lock-step with Obama tried their darndest to install their preferred Israeli liberals....you know...the white European Israelis. The true Middle-Eastern Israelis represented by Netenyahu won. American liberal racism against Netanyahu &amp; the dark-skinned Middle-Eastern Israelis who support him glares so brightly it is blinding.
10093	Netanyahu is still waiting for Obama &amp; his opposition party to give a concession speech.
10196	Obama give a concession speech to BN??????
10240	you gotta be joking of course!
10272	........................................................
10365	Now that Netanyahu has said a two state solution is out, I wonder how he's going to sell the two state solution he's been pushing for since first elected..
10531	He's never been for it to begin with!
10570	he simply lied and said he was for it; just to get the Centrist &amp; Liberal votes in the past
10667	and now he's showing his true colors 
10706	in order to maintain the orthodoxy's support
10752	```````````````````````````````````````````
10827	when Hussein finally DID call BN he told him he had to "reassess" his Israeli policy. 
10915	what the hell does that mean??
10956	What is O'reilly telling you it means?
10996	Well here is what it REALLY means!
11032	It simply means that Obama is not gonna get on his knees and kiss BN's azz like Bohner is doing, and taking directives from him!
11162	..........................................
11243	Obama lost that election, despite his monumental effort to oust Netanyahu &amp; install the Zionists. 
11356	By doing what?
11372	Unless you are expelling oral flatulence; would you mind putting up a VALID source for this statement!
11476	PS: Fox News is not a valid source.
11550	American liberal racists
11585	^ a dis-congruous label
11610	If it wasn't for the so-called 'liberals' we'd still be living within a quasi-apartheid state that was in place in the US for the 1st half of the 20th century. Look up the Johnson-Reed act of 1924 (and who signed it into law) just to give one example. 
11901	The true Middle-Eastern Israelis
11944	LMAO, big time!
11961	Do you know what a logical fallacy is? 
12002	If you do, then you clearly don't know about the " Any true Scotsman fallacy" .
12083	If you don't know what a logical fallacy is then stop watching Fox news and get educated.
12280	PS: Fox News is not a valid source.
12326	you're right.
12341	in the future ALL valid reference points must be approved by MS(MESS)NBC, Rachel Madcow and Lying Lawrence O'Donnell.
12460	it must then be OKed by every viewing member of that cable news network.
12534	*************************************************************************
12608	all 127 of them.
12727	he told him he had to "reassess" his Israeli policy. 
12782	what the hell does that mean??
12848	It simply means that Obama is not gonna get on his knees and kiss BN's azz like Bohner is doing, and taking directives from him!
12997	I might mean that we have to go back and re-think our behavior in the UN ... with all those "of course" vetos when the Zionists have resolutions and sanctions being thrown at them left and right. 
13195	It was bound to happen sooner or later since now the Palestinians have the ICC working with them. We'd look like huge fools to keep giving BN a break when the ICC is going after the greedy killer Zionists.
13437	Now that Netanyahu has said a two state solution is out, I wonder how he's going to sell the two state solution he's been pushing for since first elected..
13628	He's never been for it to begin with!
13667	he simply lied and said he was for it
13725	Yeah well, that's nothing new. 
13758	Actions speak louder than words and his actions have been shouting "NO TWO-STATE SOLUTION ... E V E R" for a long time.
14176	The world would be a better place if the United States currently had a President with the same clarity, fortitude, and direction as Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. Israeli citizens wisely saw President Barack Hussein Obama was against their best interests so the logical decision was to vote against his views for the betterment of their home.
14595	correct Eric.
14610	I only wish the American voter were as intelligent as the Israeli voter.
14684	Maybe the Kardashian Society voters can be overcome in 2016.
14746	congratulations to Benjamin Netanyahu for seeing the Iranian threat for what it really is - the desire to kill and irradiate America and Israel with nuclear weapons. 
14914	Mr.. Netanyahu is a hero to all good people of the world and an enemy of evil.
15106	Maybe the Kardashian Society voters can be overcome in 2016.
15177	Maybe these societal poxes can be overcome. Maybe even those who mention the society in every other post can be somehow made to realize this.... That they really seem hung up on the Society of Kardashians. Maybe a illustrative poem would help??
15423	It's a Kardashian Society.. When your main notoriety, is having a hefty set of hams.
15509	But when your hams surround your ears... And your brain ignores all that it hears. And your logic succumbs to your fears.....
15636	Well, if this is the case, and everyone is out to get you then it's time to pull out your heads and take a few deep breaths.... What you're smelling is the world longing to breathe free.....
15827	our country can be destroyed in two different ways - from outside by Iranian nukes, radicals or any number of other ways.
15950	what I fear is that America will be destroyed from WITHIN.
16010	this is why I rail against the Kardashian Society. I've lived long enough to see what used to be a great country and what we have now. I've seen what the ME GENERATION has done to undercut and chip away at what was once a solid fairly united country to where we are now - sinking like the Titanic.
16309	the KS has made the importance of the INDIVIDUAL of greater importance than the country as a whole. it has come in small insignificant ways that are meaningless by themselves such as odd and strangely spelled first names, some of them many of us cannot pronounce or bizarre pink and green hair color. things of this unimportant nature, the desire to be unique and different than the rest is what I call The Tracks or Pawprints Of The Lion. these prints in the soil BY THEMSELVES cannot harm us and by themselves are nothing. but when the KS elects representatives and presidents who can make policy to change America in enormously dangerous ways is what I see as coming FACE TO FACE WITH THE LION. those meaningless tracks LEAD US to the lion.
17054	the Democrats and especially the liberals and ultra liberals have brought face to face with the lion or imminent danger to the longevity of our country. it's easier to be and to vote democratic. they give things away and are looking out for the individual to the detriment of the country. it's easier to say "we'll take from the rich and give to all you poor people".
17423	this resonates with the Kardashians and as more generations come and go their numbers will continue to swell, especially in a recession such as we are in.
17579	so when I speak about the Kardashian Society I speak about those who have the ability to destroy us from within.
17795	so when I speak about the Kardashian Society I speak about those who have the ability to destroy us from within.
17918	And when someone reads your profile and then your forum posts, they see that you are either a hypocrite or someone who is stupid enough to support political parties and candidates that represent the very things you claim to hate.
18149	Or is your cosmetic surgeries, obsession with tanning and your clams of wast wealth just a ruse?
18320	The U.S. "administration" that is seen as being against the election of Nat has been and still is interested in seeing an end to the conflict not because of the poor Palestinian's being targetted but because Israel is the west's fortress and arms storage area. Obama may talk tough against Nat in he next while but he isn't nor has he done anything to stop Nat's war crimes. Talk is cheap, if or when he stops vetoing the inquiry, then maybe he will show the world that he is against war crimes. I doubt this will happen as the U.S./nato is guilty as shit themselves.
18889	Nat does not want a 2 state solution, never has. His plans are to control MORE territory and bombing is the way he wants to do it. 
19022	Pay attention because Nat has another ace up his sleeve (to delay/try to stop the U.N. inquiry). He'll boycotte the inquiry, he'll claim conflict of interest, anti semistism and anything else to avoid the inquiry. He'll pledge that the 2 state solution will not be off the table if Hamas is ousted first. He might even start his own "U.N." that will find him not guilty.
19394	The REAL powers that be (not the puppets) will also be starting a campaign/coup in Palestine to convince the people that getting rid of Hamas would be the end of the conflict and open the door to a two state solution. They will also claim that they will work with Fatah but you will not see a coalition in the real sense of the word. Having a dictator is the quickest way to grab more territory and that is Nat's cronies plan, hence the continues expansion backed by bombing Gaza.
19876	I wonder if anyone will remember that Nat never keeps his promise and if/or as soon as, Hamas is out, Nat. will up his war crimes against the people trapped in his apartheid system?
20059	The people who voted for Nat have fallen for the fear mongering as well as proved themselves to be hypocrites when they expect everyone to remember the Holocaust (most people do) and feel for them when they have no pity for the people of Palestine. How soon they forget when their backyard isn't being segregated fast enough for their liking.
20403	Was the election "rigged"? When 1 in 7 Palestinian's are allowed to vote, it's a valid question. 
20502	https://www.middleeastmonitor.com/articles/debate/17460-10-facts-about-israels-elections-and-the-palestinian-vote
20724	our country can be destroyed in two different ways - from outside by Iranian nukes, 
20819	Is that what FOX Entertainment is saying these days? It's only 7,239 miles from Iran to the US. Iran has no missile close to traveling that far. Perhaps an Iranian terrorist will strap a nuc to his/her back and cross the southern boarder along with all those other illegals.
