94	Kenya - Al-Shabaab holds Christian students hostage 15 dead
226	Surprised this hasn't been mentioned yet - Al-Shabaab militants haver stormed Garissa University College, 120 miles from the Somalian border in Kenya, they gone through the students &amp; released the Muslim students, only 280 out of 800 students have been accounted for.
499	http://www.theguardian.com/world/201...-eastern-kenya
554	http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worl...sity-live.html
609	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/arti...niversity.html
764	Surprised this hasn't been mentioned yet - Al-Shabaab militants haver stormed Garissa University College, 120 miles from the Somalian border in Kenya, they gone through the students &amp; released the Muslim students, only 280 out of 800 students have been accounted for.
1037	http://www.theguardian.com/world/201...-eastern-kenya
1092	http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worl...sity-live.html
1147	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/arti...niversity.html
1211	I have been watching the story developing. The extremists really don't like education do they?...I hope the Kenyans manage to kick their hairy butts out their Country...do you know if this was the Russians doing this there would be public outrage.
2292	I think its a matter of Al Shabaab not being viewed as proper Muslims following the Islamic ideology...big mistake. These are the crack pots that Lee Rigby's murderers were very attracted to.
2585	I have been watching the story developing. The extremists really don't like education do they?...I hope the Kenyans manage to kick their hairy butts out their Country...do you know if this was the Russians doing this there would be public outrage.
2843	The uneducated are far easier to control. 
3251	Sadly, I think it's a bit of both.
3396	I think its a matter of Al Shabaab not being viewed as proper Muslims following the Islamic ideology...big mistake. These are the crack pots that Lee Rigby's murderers were very attracted to.
3598	Not to mention our very own 'white widow' Samantha Lewthwaite.
3789	The uneducated are far easier to control. 
3833	Sadly, I think it's a bit of both.
3878	BIB So very true. How many Jihadi's could they hold onto if they knew for a scientific fact the world was not flat?
4297	Surprised this hasn't been mentioned yet - Al-Shabaab militants haver stormed Garissa University College, 120 miles from the Somalian border in Kenya, they gone through the students &amp; released the Muslim students, only 280 out of 800 students have been accounted for.
4570	http://www.theguardian.com/world/201...-eastern-kenya
4625	http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worl...sity-live.html
4680	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/arti...niversity.html
4744	Well let's be honest, the cowardly arsewipes can't actually fight. All they can do is take hostages and murder innocent people. Killing, murder and mayhem is what this particular branch of Islam is all about.
5387	It'd been noted on here before African atrocites tend to be at the bottom of most people's radar. I'm not sure it's an African thing or a race thing, if there was a similar atrocity in Burma/Nepal/Cambodia it would probably be similarly low on the attention scale. Saying that if it did happen in a 'white' country it probably would get more attention, so maybe it's a combination of race &amp; distance involved.
5802	France 24 reporting death toll may rise significantly, one survivor saying she stepped over at least 100 bodies.
5993	Reports of them using chainsaws to kill people.
6042	They're savages.
6137	It's now being reported that at least 70 people were murdered.
6276	According to an Al-shebaab spokesman the terrorists are releasing Muslims and killing Christians
6374	http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32169080
6423	So who's going to be first to deny this is an act of barbaric religious bigotry committed by Muslims?
6526	It's not the fault of Mossad, Or America. Or capitalism. There are no grey areas here. There is no nuance. There are no "yeah-but-whatabouts". These people want a religious war.
6816	According to an Al-shebaab spokesman the terrorists are releasing Muslims and killing Christians
6914	http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32169080
6963	So who's going to be first to deny this is an act of barbaric religious bigotry committed by Muslims?
7066	It's not the fault of Mossad, Or America. Or capitalism. There are no grey areas here. There is no nuance. There are no "yeah-but-whatabouts". These people want a religious war.
7254	Have the police apologised for this atrocity yet?
7380	According to an Al-shebaab spokesman the terrorists are releasing Muslims and killing Christians
7478	http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32169080
7527	So who's going to be first to deny this is an act of barbaric religious bigotry committed by Muslims?
7630	It's not the fault of Mossad, Or America. Or capitalism. There are no grey areas here. There is no nuance. There are no "yeah-but-whatabouts". These people want a religious war.
7808	It's happening all over the Muslim world, unfortunately. Christians have recently been targeted by Islamists in Syria, Iraq, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya and now Kenya.
8085	It's happening all over the Muslim world, unfortunately. Christians have recently been targeted by Islamists in Syria, Iraq, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya and now Kenya.
8258	Strange that Muslims and their apologists always complain about so-called 'Islamophobia' in secular Western democracies (who provide them with everything possible to lead a good fulfilling life) and yet they never mention how people other faiths and none are treated in Islamic countries (badly at best, slaughtered at worst).
8586	The silence is totally deafening.
8621	Hypocrisy in action.
8720	It's happening all over the Muslim world, unfortunately. Christians have recently been targeted by Islamists in Syria, Iraq, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya and now Kenya.
8883	Islamists aren't real muslims!
9019	It'd been noted on here before African atrocites tend to be at the bottom of most people's radar. I'm not sure it's an African thing or a race thing, if there was a similar atrocity in Burma/Nepal/Cambodia it would probably be similarly low on the attention scale. Saying that if it did happen in a 'white' country it probably would get more attention, so maybe it's a combination of race &amp; distance involved.
9434	France 24 reporting death toll may rise significantly, one survivor saying she stepped over at least 100 bodies.
9557	It comes down to who people identify with.
9601	9/11 shocked the western world because the vast majority of people recognise themselves going to work in the morning in a big office building, commuting. living in an advanced society, living in a developed, orderly city, ect, and if not themselves, people around them.
9872	When those poor girls were kidnapped by Boko Harem, their lives (or what we see of their lives) are so removed it's hard to imagine yourself in the same circumstances. Things like the reports from the few who escaped about running into the jungle and hiding for days.
10141	It is like hearing about something from another planet. The world has got smaller because of mass media, but it's still very big.
10272	How does it happen that a truck load of terrorists can drive into a school and kidnap children, and get away with it?
10460	Almost 150 now reported as being murdered. Their barbarism knows no bounds. Sickening, totally sickening.
10816	How does it happen that a truck load of terrorists can drive into a school and kidnap children, and get away with it?
10944	In that case, in Nigeria, there is huge corruption, so much so that the soldiers on the ground have had to buy their own ammunition &amp; uniforms (hence they don't match, leading to confusion). Of course there probably weren't any on duty at that school anyway. And it seems there were only two armed guards at this university of 800 people in Kenya, how could that possibly be the case when they knew of threat &amp; there had been attacks in that very town? You have to suspect corruption again sadly, the money from taxes is not getting to the people &amp; services to the people but in pockets of those in influential positions.
11579	Now confirmed, at least 147 murdered.
11688	NOW is it a war between religions?
11792	Kenya's off my holiday list. That's most of africa now.
11946	Kenya's off my holiday list. That's most of africa now.
12012	Was that your first thought?
12119	Something a read the other week, Christians are persecuted around the world in Islamic countries but you don't see terrorism aimed at Muslims. Due to our foreign policy some Muslims feel violence against the West is justified.
12347	Last month a bomb attack in Pakistan killed 14 Christians and destroyed their church, this week you 150 people dead by Boko Harem.
12479	In less than a month there has been almost 200 people, mostly Christians killed by Islamic terrorism.
12582	That doesn't include those recently captured on Syria.
12708	It's my experience that many people in the UK (and Europe generally) don't differentiate countries in Sub-Saharan Africa all that much. We've been reading/hearing about one group murdering other similar groups for as long as I can recollect and it just becomes one more tragedy on top of an endless number. People are inured to it. I'm not sure how else it can be as it seems no amount of concern or aid makes much long term difference.
