94	Default No Surprise: Piles of US Taxpayer $$$$ from the CIA Ends Up in ISIS Hands
254	Besides which there is no evidence in the NY Times article that any of the CIA cash went to ISIS. There WAS a part of ransom money paid from that cash to Al Qaeda years ago, probably before ISIS came into existence, and three other countries ponied up to save a certain important individual. Al Qaeda is not ISIS. There may still be cash going to Afghanistan from the CIA, but no evidence that that money is going for anything other than corruption or its intended purposes which were to pay off warlords and fund local police.
783	It may be going to ISIS or it may not. I'd guess probably not,, since the warlords would probably want to keep as much as possible.
916	The thread title is pure propaganda and a huge twist on the reality laid out in the NYTimes story.
1090	I think the take away is implied: if the cash can so easily end up in the hands of Bin Laden, it can just as easily end up in the hands of ISIS. It's only a matter of time until the next article confirms that. 
1302	We fund one side in the usual "the enemy of my enemy is my friend" scenario and we pump money and arms into that side. It's not too long after that when the current "friend" IS the enemy and it is as well armed and monied-up as we have made it. 
1549	That's exactly how AQ was born: with American arms and funds.
1612	Anyone who thinks Karzi was anything but a blood sucker for his own interests is dreaming.
2031	G.
2112	I suspect that the "intelligence" agencies of the free world have been doing the equivalent since the Russian Revolution, if not earlier. European nations have been probably doing it much longer.
2309	You would think that one day these "intelligence" agencies would realize that a friendship you have to buy is essentially worthless, and do forward planning for when these so-called friends end up turning against us as they so often do.
2619	This is an interesting tidbit from the NYTimes article dated 3/15/2015
2691	Al Qaeda stockpiled weapons using covert CIA cash funneled to the murderous terrorist group by Afghan officials as part of a $5 million ransom for a hostage diplomat.
2859	The U.S. intelligence agency remained clueless that some of its money went directly to the terrorists behind the 9/11 attacks on New York and Washington, The New York Times reported Saturday. At the time of the spring 2010 ransom deal, the CIA was delivering as much as $1 million cash each month to officials in Afghanistan.
3186	Those payments continued through 2014, according to the newspaper.
3254	Letters discussing the 2010 payoffs were found during the raid one year later where Bin Laden was killed by Navy SEALs
3374	Interesting. again, under who's watch was this under? Panetta? Petreus? but the buck stops with the president whether it was Bush and/or Obama. 
3520	If, as the article states, the CIA was unaware, assume the WH and DoD were also unaware, it is concerning we are negotiating anything with Iran other than tightening the sanctions belt.
3778	Originally Posted by CanadianTrotter
3816	I found this thread informative and will continue to read any worthwhile replies.
3899	Yes, but would you recommend it to your niece?
4054	Originally Posted by CanadianTrotter
4092	I found this thread informative and will continue to read any worthwhile replies.
4175	Yes, but would you recommend it to your niece?
4232	WIN!
4311	Here's a Reuter's story which summarizes the situation. 
4369	http://www.nytimes.com/reuters/2015/...-cia.html?_r=0
4424	The NYTimes story seems to not be available on the NY Times website. I did read it Saturday, and it was much longer.
