94	Hey did you hear? Joker Tsarnaev was found guilty
216	:lol:
222	 
224	Now tell us something we didn't know
261	 
263	We all knew he was guilty.
290	 
292	All that has mattered since day 1,  is whether or not he will get the death penalty
455	 He and Hernandez should share a needle. 
604	 He and Hernandez should share a needle. 
656	Joker killed and wounded many, many innocent people.
781	No one in Mass has been put to death since 1947, or so the wikipedia of knowledge tells me. If there had been more deaths, I think it would be more possible, but with 3 deaths, I doubt this kid gets it. Life in prison, no parole. 
1084	he'll get the death penalty, he should get tortured for life 
1246	No one in Mass has been put to death since 1947
1304	are you not counting the 3 killed with he and his dirtbag brother's bombs?
1452	As young as he is, he's looking at 60 years in SuperMax. That's worse than prison and worse than death. 
1658	As young as he is, he's looking at 60 years in SuperMax. That's worse than prison and worse than death. 
1773	That's an interesting question.
1805	 
1807	Where will he spend his life? what prison?
1950	are you not counting the 3 killed with he and his dirtbag brother's bombs?
2035	:rolleyes: Easy there Captain America
2073	 
2075	he'll get 3 consecutive life sentences for the 3 deaths, and 150 years or something like that for all the other charges.
2298	That's an interesting question.
2330	 
2332	Where will he spend his life? what prison?
2385	I don't think there's any question. All domestic terrorists go to Florence Colorado's SuperMax... Kazinski, underwear bomber, John Walker, etc. 
2631	:rolleyes: Easy there Captain America
2669	 
2671	he'll get 3 consecutive life sentences for the 3 deaths, and 150 years or something like that for all the other charges.
2802	Just saying.
2815	 
2817	He didn't mind putting people to death, he should get the same
2986	No one in Mass has been put to death since 1947, or so the wikipedia of knowledge tells me.
3088	Mass does not have the death penalty but this is a federal case, still your point is a good one. 
3187	Can citizens of this state put someone to death if they don't believe in it?
3265	Isn't there an American Deserter out there that we can trade this kid for? He certainly is not as dangerous as the five terrorists we gave up for Bergdahl. 
3524	Mass does not have the death penalty but this is a federal case, still your point is a good one. 
3623	Can citizens of this state put someone to death if they don't believe in it?
3701	Isn't there an American Deserter out there that we can trade this kid for? He certainly is not as dangerous as the five terrorists we gave up for Bergdahl. 
3868	because the state doesn't have the death penalty, the citizens don't believe in it? :wacko:
3960	 
3962	As a rule I like to see there is solid evidence. For christ sakes, there is video of him placing the bomb. 
4144	I am categorically opposed to the death penalty.
4194	They should lock this piece of sh1t up for the rest of his life. Put him in solitary "for his own protection." 
4307	Day in and day out for decades almost never leaving your cell or ever talking to another human being. A fate worse than death. He will wish with every ounce of his soul that he had a bedsheet or a shoelace or a belt with which to hang himself.
4552	Conversely if you execute him he gets a quick and easy death as a martyr. No way, that's way too good for him.
4737	Should put him in that ultra cool prison in face off 
4893	I am categorically opposed to the death penalty.
4943	They should lock this piece of sh1t up for the rest of his life. Put him in solitary "for his own protection." 
5056	Day in and day out for decades almost never leaving your cell or ever talking to another human being. A fate worse than death. He will wish with every ounce of his soul that he had a bedsheet or a shoelace or a belt with which to hang himself.
5301	Conversely if you execute him he gets a quick and easy death as a martyr. No way, that's way too good for him.
5422	:thumbsup:
5433	 
5435	but you know this will never happen.
5574	:thumbsup:
5585	 
5587	but you know this will never happen.
5634	Why not? He sure as sh1t won't ever get parole if that's what you're saying 
5784	Focker probably wants the death penalty, to be with his 1,000 virgins or whatever it says in his backwards religion.
5902	Life in prison, no parole. :cheers: 
6012	Even if he gets the death penalty, it'll be 20 years before it's carried out, with all the attendant appeals and cost of keeping death row inmates. Capital punishment is a stupid waste of resources.
6313	Why not? He sure as sh1t won't ever get parole if that's what you're saying 
6400	I'm saying he will never be treated like that
6556	Even if he gets the death penalty, it'll be 20 years before it's carried out, with all the attendant appeals and cost of keeping death row inmates. Capital punishment is a stupid waste of resources.
6765	They should just dig a hole out back of the courthouse and put a bullet in his head.   Cheap, easy, and fast.
6977	I'm saying he will never be treated like that
7033	I'd be surprised if he wasn't 
7140	I am against the death penalty but I have no problem with this dude staring at a wall for the rest of his existence.
7333	just found out that f&amp;cker automatically gets changed to dude
7470	Franknbeans is a dude.  
7596	Franknbeans is a dude.  
7631	:angry:
7738	Franknbeans is a dude.  
7773	Nicely played
7897	Franknbeans is a dude.  
7932	 Touch his ears and see. 
8031	I don't care if he gets the death penalty or not.  But when he goes to prison, I don't want us giving him any special attention.   Simply open thew doors and say "Here you go.  Good luck".    I'd love to see him get the Jeffrey Dahmer treatment.
8350	they should stick him in s room and blast his legs with thousands of ball bearing
8433	then life in prison 
8555	they should stick him in s room and blast his legs with thousands of ball bearing
8638	then life in prison 
8669	:thumbsup:
8754	People hate him and want to him to suffer, because he hated Americans and made them suffer. Ironic. 
8961	People hate him and want to him to suffer, because he hated Americans and made them suffer. Ironic. 
9072	how is that ironic? he blew an 8 year old child up, got a link to any of his haters doing the same? 
9275	People hate him and want to him to suffer, because he hated Americans and made them suffer. Ironic. 
9386	wow.
9465	I understand the bloodthirsty desire for vengeance. But that's an emotional reaction rather than an intelligent one. 
9689	People hate him and want to him to suffer, because he hated Americans and made them suffer. Ironic. 
9800	i see comments like this all over social media sh;t nowadays. wtf is even your point???
9888	 
9890	i weep for america :(
9985	"Americans" has little to do with it for me... it's the  "children and families" that he hurt that bothers me so much.
10104	 
10106	And I guess it breaks down like this:
10144	 
10146	If anyone should ever be punished by death, this is the person. I don't think that is debatable.
10244	The debate is simply the age-old death penalty debate. Should we kill the worst humans in the name of justice?
10461	People hate him and want to him to suffer, because he hated Americans and made them suffer. Ironic. 
10572	Ironic? Or obvious? If someone killed someone in your family, others in your family would want him dead. 
10783	i see comments like this all over social media sh;t nowadays. wtf is even your point???
10871	 
10873	i weep for america :(
10905	I do too...so much talk of vengeance.
10944	I get the guy is scum...but its sad how quickly people here throw out the constitution of this country to get revenge on someone.
11175	i see comments like this all over social media sh;t nowadays. wtf is even your point???
11263	 
11265	i weep for america :(
11297	one of the reasons I had to deactivate my facebook.
11349	 
11351	Focking liberals man :mad:
