94	Hillary Clinton Room Post. Chris Matthews is reporting Hillary will announce Sunday.
256	Hillary Clinton Room Post.
284	The moment is here and it is time to savor it.
410	1. Yeah I am hearing it is very close....her team has been told to prepare....
562	2. I can't wait to see her on the campaign trail.
691	3. I cannot wait to watch a certain group of DU'ers heads explode....
834	5. Well that Hillary DU operatives post made me put a few on ignore.
982	7. Yep I am using "ignore" a whole lot more than I used to....
1118	10. It works well.
1138	I think one person I might rethink but the others I won't miss anytime soon.
1295	29. I just added another one to Ignore. They can talk to each other.
1365	They have absolutely nothing of importance to say about Sec Hillary, from here on.
1449	Everything about Hillary I read or post will be right here in the Hillary Room where it belongs.
1546	They have nothing constructive to add anyway so they have no place on my DU Screen.
1630	POOF They're Gone!!!
1652	What a great exciting year we will have.
1693	And it starts this Sunday.
1721	God speed Hillary, see you in the Oval Office 2016
1846	8. And Republicans
1866	She will make the candidates crazy.
1982	11. Its going to be great!
2083	12. Of course. They know that she can beat them.
2133	Going to be fun to watch the gop squirm.
2252	4. Would someone please post me a link of her speach, will be out on a weekender
2334	No news, no radio, no tv, will only have phone access. I knew this might happen.
2489	6. Sure but it might be low key.
2523	But yes we will post it in this room.
2639	9. Thank you so very much.
2738	13. Chris Matthews just said it was this Sunday
2787	I'm glad. Maybe some of the mis-information about her and her record will calm down.
2946	14. Great. I will change the title.
3063	15. Sunday via video. Then she will talk agenda &amp; policy through her tour.
3143	Yaaaa. Can't wait!!!
3164	Finally
3246	16. I feel like ringing out some bells.
3361	22. glad you posted those joyous bells here also.
3485	23. lol I seem to be posting them all over.
3610	24. Most Appropriate. Ringing of the Bells!
3655	I am so happy tonight
3751	25. And people were so sure she wasn't running.
3874	28. Wishful thinking.
3977	17. She will get her message out thru Social Media &amp; her tours.
4046	She can get her actual message to millions directly via social media rather having her agenda filtered &amp; opined by MSM.
4170	Her Team of savvy professionals will handle her campaign as it should be.
4244	What people hear will be her own words. Not the RW owned media's version.
4392	18. This is smart. She learned from the 2008 mistakes.
4519	19. Can you imagine the excitement if this happens?
4572	http://www.democraticunderground.com/1251402337
4694	20. I don't think the gop can beat a Hillary/Castro ticket.
4835	30. Clinton/Castro would blow up Jeb's dream of aligning with the Hispanic voters.
4919	I love Castro for everything he represents.
4963	So will the 2016 voters.
5062	21. More bells.
5153	26. The day I have been waiting for!
5264	27. A joyous moment.
5366	31. Me too William769. This is a Really Big Deal isn't it. Finally!!
5436	Hey I hope you are feeling well. Rest up cuz The Big Game is about to begin!
5513	Wooohoooo**
5599	32. I checked out a related thread
5635	in GD not too long ago. There were a few posters who expressed a lack of enthusiasm for the announcement, yet they bothered to view (and comment) on the page. It's stupid.
5881	33. They know thwt they likely can not stop her and they are frustrated by it.
6035	34. Come on our Gal!
6137	35. Business Insider: Rubio is to announce this weekend, however he will be overshadowed in the media by
6243	Hillary Clinton. Also saying Rubio will not enjoy the benefit of free press that others like Rand &amp; Cruz had at their Pres race announcement.
6389	Poor Marco. A day late &amp; a dollar short.
6434	Overshadowed again.
6528	36. Lol! I bet he moves the day.
6642	37. He'll be playing that marco...polo game for press time.
6703	.........marrrco. polo
6727	..................................marrrrco
6771	..polo.
6780	( softly now) marrrrco.
6804	..(all together now) P O L O.
6908	38. Freaking hilarious!
7013	39. Ha.. Humor will be our greatest weapon
7057	We are gonna be just fine in the Hillary Room this year.
7114	Waaaay more fun than GD.
7139	We Rock the Hillary Room man!!
7244	40. I think you are right.
