94	How come ISIS is still around?
201	Considering how many forces are united against ISIS how come ISIS is still around? I would have thought with such strong military technology backing them that the ground forces would have been able to stop ISIS dead in its tracks, but recently ISIS has captured a new province in Iraq, Ramadi as well as a town in Syria, Palmyra.
604	Because jet fuel can't melt steel beams
712	Because you cannot win a war with air power and the army on the ground falls to pieces in every conflict. 
902	The Syrian Government Forces at this stage--though not facing defeat--seem unable to advance.
997	ISIS can take advantage of the petty anarchic factional nature of the Syrian rebellion.
1086	The Iraqi "army" is, I dunno. Apparently none of the U.S. equipment and training managed to instil anything akin to courage under fire.
1223	Maybe nobody wants to fight and die for the Iraqi government I dunno.
1294	Kinda sad how 200 IS fighters managed to chase out a much larger Iraqi force. Pathetic.
1460	with hindsight, actually bush n blair had the right idea
1590	Because ISIS have no morals or no issues doing what needs to be done to achieve what they want. On the flip side, if the USA and UK just carpet bombed the entire regions into oblivion there'd be an international outcry for killing innocent women and children. Also, the people dying for ISIS believe they're on a mission working for their God with nothing to lose. The military does have a lot to lose and therefore will do risk assessments before every strategic move. ISIS are advancing because they're essentially a virus with no remorse.
2204	I think the thing stopping them from winning is the lack of common goal for those fighting ISIS. There are a lot of people fighting them but many of them are enemies with each other and so won't be coordinating any strategies.
2500	What the western media doesn't tell us is that they have massive support in the region there's no way they could take that much land without it.
2724	They're worried about the hostages that they keep
2846	On some fronts, ISIS have actually been driven back. The Kurds in Iraq have forced them out of most of the Kurdish areas, and the Syrian Kurds have made similar progress (though they're held back a bit by not having many heavy weapons).
3084	This isn't the case everywhere though. The Syrian army is overstretched at the moment. While ISIS was attacking Palmyra, Syrian troops were (and still are) fighting to defend what they still hold of Idlib province, as rebels advance there. That's probably why ISIS were able to succeed in taking Palmyra - Syrian troops (plus equipment and supplies) are needed in other places as well. In Iraq, the national army is pretty weak and not as competent as it should be.
3551	So, I would say ISIS still exists because there isn't a strong and competent fighting force to fight them on the ground and force them from their territory
3808	What the western media doesn't tell us is that they have massive support in the region there's no way they could take that much land without it.
3963	You mean in the same way that Nazi Germany had massive support in France, Poland, Greece and Russia?
4165	You mean in the same way that Nazi Germany had massive support in France, Poland, Greece and Russia?
4276	I don't know much about them
4410	What the western media doesn't tell us is that they have massive support in the region there's no way they could take that much land without it.
4565	This is akin to George Galloway's comments in Parliament where he suggested that the civilian populations of the areas taken by the Islamic State were partially to blame (by effectively saying that they 'support' the Islamic State).
4799	Contra Galloway, I believe it is the reign of terror associated with the Islamic State that gives the illusion of a satisfied civilian population under Islamic State rule. They behead their own members for smoking and have butchered children and innocent civilians in their thousands.
5085	Unless you can provide evidence to the contrary, I think the above is the more convincing view as to how the Islamic State are able to control such vast territories.
5355	Considering how many forces are united against ISIS how come ISIS is still around? I would have thought with such strong military technology backing them that the ground forces would have been able to stop ISIS dead in its tracks, but recently ISIS has captured a new province in Iraq, Ramadi as well as a town in Syria, Palmyra.
5695	Because the west lacks the resolve to put troops on the ground and conquer both Syria and Iraq while ISIS will behead any non-believers. The Iraqi army are cowards and the Syrian army is still having to divert forces to fight the rebels in the north west of the country. 
5968	As has been pointed out elsewhere, while we have the technology to wipe out every ISIS town the rules of a Just War forbid it.
6199	Because the west lacks the resolve to put troops on the ground and conquer both Syria and Iraq while ISIS will behead any non-believers. The Iraqi army are cowards and the Syrian army is still having to divert forces to fight the rebels in the north west of the country. 
6472	As has been pointed out elsewhere, while we have the technology to wipe out every ISIS town the rules of a Just War forbid it.
6609	Thing is if we put troops down we wipe em, but then they'll just regroup. The major weakness of american troops is that they are really expensive to maintain. I'm just wondering even for less well trained troops how come they can't advance when they can call in an air strike at any time. Its like playing war on easy mode. I have to commend the bravery at least of ISIS troops.
7067	Because whilst the left wing media tell us all how peaceful Islam is and there are only a few bad eggs, the fact of the matter is that ISIS are inundated with volunteers and are swelling in numbers every week.
7278	So much so, that there are now waiting lists to become suicide bombers.
7460	Because whilst the left wing media tell us all how peaceful Islam is and there are only a few bad eggs, the fact of the matter is that ISIS are inundated with volunteers and are swelling in numbers every week.
7671	So much so, that there are now waiting lists to become suicide bombers.
7753	Pretty sure some right wing people have been saying that as well, including people high up in the Conservative party. David Cameron has used the "religion of peace" line if I remember correctly.
7949	Don't try to turn this into a left wing vs right wing issue. It's a lot more complicated than that.
8122	From what I've seen on liveleak
8155	Both sides fire haphazardly in "general" direction of the enemy (including amateurish nonsense like one handed fire of M16s, AKs and RPKs, putting barrel in the dirt etc from all sides).
8343	ISIS tactics in the video they published on Ramadi seems to be a really unrefined version of fire and maneuver where they saturate a building/target with bullets so soldiers/suicide bombers can get close enough to through grenades/blow themselves up.
8595	Also the fact is that ISIS is not a purely untrained mob. Jihadi groups in Syria and Iraq use Chechnyan and Dagestani merceneries/Jihadis  as shock troops. These guys potentially have decades of experience in urban combat fighting the Russians in the Caucasus
8856	Iraqi Army runs, ISIS gain ground.
8963	They are very far away and we have limited resources (mainly air) which are simply not sustainable for long assaults, furthermore I imagine ISIS are exploiting tensions on the ground and the air strikes that are harming civilians is giving them more legitimacy since most of them hate the US with a passion. ISIS is brutal and has managed to maintain its territory through very public control and severe punishments for minor crimes. It's also both a grass roots and centralised movement, ISIS is attracting lots of attention from both random groups and the highly centralised leadership which is making it difficult to target.
9694	Pretty sure some right wing people have been saying that as well, including people high up in the Conservative party. David Cameron has used the "religion of peace" line if I remember correctly.
9890	Don't try to turn this into a left wing vs right wing issue. It's a lot more complicated than that.
10000	By most standards the Conservatives are of left of centre, certainly more than their American counterparts.
