94	OFFICIAL: Chris Kyle Trial - GUILTY!! - Now with testimony video
240	Tag
965	Yet so many ARFCOMMERS think that Kyle is a lying POS, so we got that going for us.
1085	No,many Arfcommers are simply able to differentiate between his stellar performance in Iraq and his need to tell tales. One can be separated from the other and you are not finding anyone calling him a "lying POS",you are simply seeing people who think he had a proclivity towards telling sea stories. That has absolutely nothing to do with his murder in any way,shape or form. 
1464	As I said in the other thread,his legacy will not have anything to do with Jesse Ventura or car jackers any more than the first thought of Pappy Boyington is an irascible drunk. History has a habit of being kind in that manner.
1722	Actually, those sort of things have been said in this site.
1853	Texan News Service: 
1875	Lieutenant Michael Smith is called to the stand by the prosecutor. He served on the department for twenty years. Smith got a call on Feb. 2, 2013, by a retired Detective Shavera, because he was concerned about his house and family. Detective Shavera lived right next door to Routh. 
2159	Texan News Service: 
2181	Smith says that Shavera got a call from Routh's sister to check on Routh at his home. He and Smith checked Routh's home after he received the call. They knew that if Routh's dog was in the home, then Routh would be there. They saw the dog was still in the kennel out back, so they knew Routh wasn't home. Shavera and Smith were both off duty and went to the scene in unmarked vehicles. 
2569	Texan News Service: 
2591	Acording to Smith, the officers were at Routh's house when Routh arrived and pulled to the curb of his house. Smith and Shavera got out of their vehicles to speak with him. Officer Logan had a body camera on his lapel and has footage of that night. Shavera was talking to Routh through the window of the truck while Smith was listening to their conversation. Smith said that Salazar and another officer were on their bellies, trying to place sticks to flatten his tires. 
3158	Pictured is an image from Salazar's dash camera. 
3209	Texan News Service: 
3231	According to Smith, Shavera said to Routh, "Eddie! Eddie, turn it off [referring to the truck]. It's not worth it." Smith said Shavera was trying to get Routh to talk to them and trying to get Routh to roll the window down. 
3457	Texan News Service: 
3479	Smith added that Shavera said, "I don't want to hurt you, Eddie. We all grew-up together. Throw me the keys out here, and don't take off while they get down here. We are here, because we have to be. And we aren't going anywhere. As a friend and as a neighbor, you can always come to talk." 
3771	Texan News Service: 
3793	This is all information recorded from Logan's lapel camera. 
3855	Texan News Service: 
3877	Smith said that during this event, Routh asked, "Why can't you get in the truck with me?" 
4039	Texan News Service: 
4061	In the footage, Routh also asked, "Is this about me walking on Earth right now?" And Shavera replied, "I don't know what you mean." So, in the recording, Routh asked again, "Like, is this about me walking on Earth?" 
4279	Shavera was still trying to get Routh to leave the truck. Shavera said, "Remember what we talked about? Don't worry about what you can't control. Worry about what you can control." 
4462	In the footage, Salazar and another officer are still trying to put sticks down. 
4545	Shavera then tried to call Routh's mom so that she could talk to him while he is still in the truck with the window rolled-up. Shavera put Routh's mom on the speaker to talk to Routh through the window. 
4750	Shavera told Routh's mom, "He will come out of the truck if you can come to him." But Routh's mom was in Abilene. Routh's mom told him that she would come see him if he would get out of the truck. 
5019	Texan News Service: 
5041	In the footage, Routh asked, "Do y'all have any guns?" 
5098	And Shavera replied, "Yes, we do. It's our job. 
5148	Routh said, "Well, I do too." 
5253	body cam view as cops try to talk Routh out of truck 
5378	Texan News Service: 
5400	In the footage, Routh turned on the car after talking for a few more minutes. He then turned it back off and said, "I want to take a nap." Shavera replied, "How about you take a nap somewhere else?" Then, Smith said to Shavera that Shavera should tell Routh that he will get in the truck only if Routh rolls the window down and let's him look around before getting in the truck with him. 
5790	In the video, Shavera said, "Do me a favor, Eddie. Keep your hands up the way you've been doing so we can all relax." 
5910	Routh then turned the truck on again and took off down the street, 'peeling-out.' 
5994	Smith's duty was to review all the footage from that evening. 
6058	Smith (back on the stand) said that he was in the second vehicle in the chase and wasn't sure what car Logan was in. 
6518	Texan News Service: 
6540	The truck that Routh was in eventually stopped, because it was disabled. 
6615	In the video, after the chase ended, Routh said to Shavera, "Everyone wants to barbeque by ass right now. I'm making the decision to stay in this truck, because my soul is on this side of the glass and so is my high." 
6835	Sgt Logan had body cam
6929	Texan News Service: 
6951	Routh's lawyer is asking Smith if these quotes by Routh in the video are correct: 
7035	"I don't know if I'm going insane." 
7073	"Is this about, like, Hell walking on Earth right now?" 
7131	"I don't even know what peace and law and order is about." 
7192	"Is the apocalypse on too?" 
7222	"I can't keep sitting here, watching these cats scurry by while they keep fucking walking, running around me." 
7335	"I can feel everyone feeling on my soul, and that was not good." 
7402	Smith replied that all of the quotes from Routh are accurate. 
7568	Texan News Service: 
7590	Routh's lawyer is asking Smith if these quotes by Routh in the video are correct: 
7674	"I don't know if I'm going insane." 
7712	"Is this about, like, Hell walking on Earth right now?" 
7770	"I don't even know what peace and law and order is about." 
7831	"Is the apocalypse on too?" 
7861	"I can't keep sitting here, watching these cats scurry by while they keep fucking walking, running around me." 
7974	"I can feel everyone feeling on my soul, and that was not good." 
8041	Smith replied that all of the quotes from Routh are accurate. 
8114	Batshit crazy and legally insane are not the same thing, fortunately.
8290	Texan News Service: 
8312	Routh's lawyer is asking Smith if these quotes by Routh in the video are correct: 
8396	"I don't know if I'm going insane." 
8434	"Is this about, like, Hell walking on Earth right now?" 
8492	"I don't even know what peace and law and order is about." 
8553	"Is the apocalypse on too?" 
8583	"I can't keep sitting here, watching these cats scurry by while they keep fucking walking, running around me." 
8696	"I can feel everyone feeling on my soul, and that was not good." 
8763	Smith replied that all of the quotes from Routh are accurate. 
8857	Batshit crazy and legally insane are not the same thing, fortunately.
8947	Guessing he was once again high as fuck on that formaldehyde weed
9081	aren't crazy people pretty remorseful after the hurt someone during "an episode"?
9262	aren't crazy people pretty remorseful after the hurt someone during "an episode"?
9354	Probably too many different kinds of crazy to accurately give a general answer to that. Some people probably would be, and some people who are really (legally) insane would probably think they didn't do anything wrong. Office I was in prosecuted a guy who stabbed his infant daughter to death in her crib because he thought she was possessed by demons. I'm not sure if he ever realized he did something wrong.
9836	Texan News Service: 
9858	Barnard did the autopsies for both Littlefield and Kyle. 
9917	Barnard is now looking at Chris Kyle's autopsy report and pictures, which Barnard said shows that Kyle was shot six times. 
10042	Barnard notes that Chris Kyle was 6'1" and 216 pounds. 
10099	He said that Kyle had tattoos on his upper left arm, which was a cross and eagle and another one of a frog skeleton on his upper back. 
10236	Barnard said that Kyle had one substance in his system, which was venlafaxine, an anti-depressant 
10336	Barnard said he believes the first shot was the one on Kyle's right side of his face, the jaw area, which Barnard believes caused injury to Kyle's back-side of his spinal cord. 
10586	Texan News Service: 
10608	Barnard said the number-two-shot was to the shoulder but never exited the body. 
10690	What Barnard believes was the second shot is what he thinks killed Kyle. He said that bullet bounced around his whole body, from his right to left, hit his heart and arteries, and hit both lungs. 
10888	Barnard added that the third and fourth gun shots broke his right arm and exited the underside of his arm. 
10997	Barnard said that one of the two bullets that exited his arm superficially penetrated his abdomen. He added that bullets one and two were rapid-ally, fatal injuries. 
11165	Barnard said that bullets five and six were also rapidly fatal wounds. 
11860	Texan News Service: 
11882	Dr. Barnard is talking about Littlefield now. He is looking over a photograph and pointing out Littlefields tattoos: the face of Jesus on his right upper arm, the name "Morgan" on the right side of his upper arm, and a tattoo on his ankle that was not described. 
12147	They are now showing pictures from Littlefield's autopsy 
12206	The first bullet wound to penetrate Littlefield was on the top of his head. The second entered the left side of his face by the nose and under his eye and traveled down and exited by his left shoulder. He was shot seven times. 
12435	Shot three was through the neck and back of the head. Shot four was through the right upper shoulder. Shot five was through the chest and exited the middle of the back. Shot six was through the lower back and exited the right upper chest. Shot seven entered the front of his left palm and exited the back of his left hand. 
12760	They were shot with two different types of guns. 
12811	Barnard said the neither Kyle nor Littlefield had a chance of survival. 
12956	Just a note on the numbering of the bullet wounds - usually, they're numbered on autopsy reports just so each individual wound can be distinguished from the others. The numbering may not actually reflect the order in which the shots were delivered. On Littlefield, the last one they describe was probably one of the first ones delivered, since it seems like it'd be a wound delivered with the hand up, palm out in a defensive gesture. Not likely he would be able to do that after the shot to the head.
13568	Just a note on the numbering of the bullet wounds - usually, they're numbered on autopsy reports just so each individual wound can be distinguished from the others. The numbering may not actually reflect the order in which the shots were delivered. On Littlefield, the last one they describe was probably one of the first ones delivered, since it seems like it'd be a wound delivered with the hand up, palm out in a defensive gesture. Not likely he would be able to do that after the shot to the head.
14080	Thank you for the clarification. I was confused on the timeline based on that.
14231	Tagged. Hope for speedy trail for families.
14349	The wounds are only numbered sequentially; most pathologists start at the top and go down in sequence. The numbers have nothing to do with which wound occurred first.
15138	This whole thing just makes me sad and confused. 
15189	What happened?
15205	How did they let their guard down?
15241	Now the text msg's about them thinking he was nuts and they didn't keep him in front.
15328	What went wrong?
15346	I'm so sad over this it sucks.
15378	Did he have his own gun they were not aware of?
15496	I haven't been following this story very closely. Has it been determined how this POS doper who apparently was high at the time got the drop on 2 seasoned war veterans? If they were shot with the same gun I guess I could see how he could have wheeled around and shot them both but unless he was holding both guns, how did he shoot both before 1 or the other stopped him? I would think that since they both texted that the guy was a little wacky on the way to the range supposedly, they would have kept a pretty close eye on him.
16126	I haven't been following this story very closely. Has it been determined how this POS doper who apparently was high at the time got the drop on 2 seasoned war veterans? If they were shot with the same gun I guess I could see how he could have wheeled around and shot them both but unless he was holding both guns, how did he shoot both before 1 or the other stopped him? I would think that since they both texted that the guy was a little wacky on the way to the range supposedly, they would have kept a pretty close eye on him.
16665	All really good questions, but we'll probably never know the answers to. 
16740	Also, just to clarify, Chad never served. He was just good friends with Chris. 
16924	I haven't been following this story very closely. Has it been determined how this POS doper who apparently was high at the time got the drop on 2 seasoned war veterans? If they were shot with the same gun I guess I could see how he could have wheeled around and shot them both but unless he was holding both guns, how did he shoot both before 1 or the other stopped him? I would think that since they both texted that the guy was a little wacky on the way to the range supposedly, they would have kept a pretty close eye on him.
17463	If you get the drop on someone it doesn't matter what credentials they hold. If anything a false sense of security may have been instilled from his military training which is in many ways extremely different from civilian self defense training. 
17780	That's what gets me is how it all happened. 
17826	I just hope justice is served. It's too bad he can't get the death penalty. I'll be very shocked if he gets off though. Dude was high on drugs which is no excuse for anyone. Not an excuse for a drunk driver and shouldn't be an excuse for him. 
18071	Another thing is how do lawyers defend someone like this guy? I know they want to make a buck but it's sickening.
18262	Can some things get clarified a bit? 
18301	The Ranger said that Kyle's pistol was empty ( not the loaded one on him) so I assume that he had fired at least a magazine from some handgun before the attack? Perhaps this was the moment that he chose,both of his victim's hands occupied loading or unloading? 
18564	It also seems,but again I could be wrong,that Kyle was shot front to back and Littlefield shot back to front so that points towards waiting for an opportune moment rather than a rash and random action. That suggests to me at least some degree of premeditation. 
18827	Of course,I never expect that cretin to tell the truth and I am positive that his defense has counseled him to be as effusive,dim witted and so forth as possible to portray the part of damaged PTSD victim/incompetent. It sure sounds like the overall reason was actually pretty simple: he was a violent creep high on drugs and did something a violent creep high on drugs would do. 
19209	One thing I hope for,that I'm doubtful will happen,is that he will be locked away in anonymity rather than be allowed to give interviews and so forth. There is the horrible risk that this asshole will become the poster child for vets,especially those with PTSD, regardless actual conditions. Maybe I'm just a little too cynical but I can see some filth championing him as "a tragic victim of a needless war" . 
19691	I thought both were shot in the front? Littlefield was shot in the hand which went through and struck him again. Makes me think he knew it was coming aka he was shot sfter Chris Kyle was? 
19881	Maybe I am wrong and need to re-read the autopsy.
20046	Can some things get clarified a bit? 
20085	The Ranger said that Kyle's pistol was empty ( not the loaded one on him) so I assume that he had fired at least a magazine from some handgun before the attack? Perhaps this was the moment that he chose,both of his victim's hands occupied loading or unloading? 
20348	It also seems,but again I could be wrong,that Kyle was shot front to back and Littlefield shot back to front so that points towards waiting for an opportune moment rather than a rash and random action. That suggests to me at least some degree of premeditation. 
20611	Of course,I never expect that cretin to tell the truth and I am positive that his defense has counseled him to be as effusive,dim witted and so forth as possible to portray the part of damaged PTSD victim/incompetent. It sure sounds like the overall reason was actually pretty simple: he was a violent creep high on drugs and did something a violent creep high on drugs would do. 
20993	One thing I hope for,that I'm doubtful will happen,is that he will be locked away in anonymity rather than be allowed to give interviews and so forth. There is the horrible risk that this asshole will become the poster child for vets,especially those with PTSD, regardless actual conditions. Maybe I'm just a little too cynical but I can see some filth championing him as "a tragic victim of a needless war" . 
21414	I believe I read that the weapons on the bench were empty, but both Kyle and Littlefield had loaded pistols in their wastes with the safties on. The were caught by surprise. 
21590	ETA: Here http://www.ar15.com/forums/t_1_5/1716259_OFFICIAL___Chris_Kyle_Trial_Thread___Latest_coverage_in_linked_blog.html&amp;page=5#i52006722
21841	Can some things get clarified a bit? 
21880	The Ranger said that Kyle's pistol was empty ( not the loaded one on him) so I assume that he had fired at least a magazine from some handgun before the attack? Perhaps this was the moment that he chose,both of his victim's hands occupied loading or unloading? 
22143	It also seems,but again I could be wrong,that Kyle was shot front to back and Littlefield shot back to front so that points towards waiting for an opportune moment rather than a rash and random action. That suggests to me at least some degree of premeditation. 
22406	Of course,I never expect that cretin to tell the truth and I am positive that his defense has counseled him to be as effusive,dim witted and so forth as possible to portray the part of damaged PTSD victim/incompetent. It sure sounds like the overall reason was actually pretty simple: he was a violent creep high on drugs and did something a violent creep high on drugs would do. 
22788	One thing I hope for,that I'm doubtful will happen,is that he will be locked away in anonymity rather than be allowed to give interviews and so forth. There is the horrible risk that this asshole will become the poster child for vets,especially those with PTSD, regardless actual conditions. Maybe I'm just a little too cynical but I can see some filth championing him as "a tragic victim of a needless war" . 
23237	I believe I read that the weapons on the bench were empty, but both Kyle and Littlefield had loaded pistols in their wastes with the safties on.
23402	Pretty sure you have it correct. 
23706	Can some things get clarified a bit? 
23745	The Ranger said that Kyle's pistol was empty ( not the loaded one on him) so I assume that he had fired at least a magazine from some handgun before the attack? Perhaps this was the moment that he chose,both of his victim's hands occupied loading or unloading? 
24008	It also seems,but again I could be wrong,that Kyle was shot front to back and Littlefield shot back to front so that points towards waiting for an opportune moment rather than a rash and random action. That suggests to me at least some degree of premeditation. 
24271	Of course,I never expect that cretin to tell the truth and I am positive that his defense has counseled him to be as effusive,dim witted and so forth as possible to portray the part of damaged PTSD victim/incompetent. It sure sounds like the overall reason was actually pretty simple: he was a violent creep high on drugs and did something a violent creep high on drugs would do. 
24653	One thing I hope for,that I'm doubtful will happen,is that he will be locked away in anonymity rather than be allowed to give interviews and so forth. There is the horrible risk that this asshole will become the poster child for vets,especially those with PTSD, regardless actual conditions. Maybe I'm just a little too cynical but I can see some filth championing him as "a tragic victim of a needless war" . 
25102	I believe I read that the weapons on the bench were empty, but both Kyle and Littlefield had loaded pistols in their wastes with the safties on.
25276	Pretty sure you have it correct. 
25502	Yep, that's how I read it too. I think the blog/reporter got a little confused, which I imagine is easy to do when you're trying to listen, document, and post all at the same time. 
25758	Any info on the murder weapons? Who they belonged to?
25885	TAG
25994	Any info on the murder weapons? Who they belonged to?
26058	It was a 9mm pistol that appeared to be issued by the SEALs based on the engraving. Chad was killed with it. And a .45 pistol that was used to kill Chris. That's all I know at this point. 
26318	Just speculating, but it seems POS was standing to Chris' right when POS started shooting Chris. From the report, it looks like Chris was hit all on his right side which may suggest a rapid string of fire. This sequence startled and caught Chad by surprise. It seems like Chad had his hands up and was probably begging for his life when POS shot him straight on. POS put a few more rounds into Chad's body as he laid on the ground.
26823	Is the trial in recess today?
26957	Is the trial in recess today?
26997	No, just not a lot going on. Plus I've been kind of busy. 
27057	I did find the house Eddie was living in at the time this happened. That's his red beetle back there in the driveway. 
27177	https://goo.gl/maps/CiwGE 
27308	Is the trial in recess today?
27369	No, just not a lot going on. Plus I've been kind of busy. 
27429	I did find the house Eddie was living in at the time this happened. That's his red beetle back there in the driveway. 
27549	https://goo.gl/maps/CiwGE 
27596	Dude had a Beetle painted like a ladybug? Maybe he was insane.
27731	Opening statements can be watched here: 
27773	http://bit.ly/1B6Gir4
27867	Some pipes, marijuana and a grinder were found inside a Hershey's tin container in Routh's guest bedroom- testifies TX Ranger 
27995	Routh's fridge. On top are prescription pill bottles with his name on them. 
28073	Police found #ChrisKyle's name and phone number on a note stuck to Routh's fridge. 
28158	Murder suspect Eddie Ray Routh's house - police photos shown to jury in 
28232	Pictures inside Routh's home in Lancaster, TX 
28280	Police found "an assortment of firearm ammunition" inside Routh's guest room closet w door closed. 
28381	On Routh's desk Tx Rangers investigators found a Hershey's tin containing marijuana, pipes and grinder. 
28487	TX Ranger investigator Armstrong shows Hershey's tin holding drugs/paraphernalia found on Routh's desk 
28663	There were no guns found in Routh's home; they only found ammunition.
28805	Defense emphasizes antipsychotic meds found in home- Risperidone, used to treat schizophrenia, bipolar disorder.Cops photo'd, didnt seize em 
28948	Testy exchange btw TX Ranger &amp; defense attorney as ranger reveals that house smelled of marijuana. He didnt include that in his report tho. 
29094	Defense never received cops handwritten notes from search, only report. Cop insists he gave to DA. DA say they provided defense w everything 
29315	The live blog seems to be reenforcing the confusion over the order of the gunshot wounds: 
29407	11:51 
29414	Comment From Guest 
29434	Is Chad's hand wound a "defense" wound? Indicating he was at that point aware of Routh attempting to kill him?
29546	Texan News Service: All we know about that wound is that of the seven times Littlefield was shot, that was the seventh place he was shot. 
29822	The live blog seems to be reenforcing the confusion over the order of the gunshot wounds: 
29914	11:51 
29921	Comment From Guest 
29941	Is Chad's hand wound a "defense" wound? Indicating he was at that point aware of Routh attempting to kill him?
30053	Texan News Service: All we know about that wound is that of the seven times Littlefield was shot, that was the seventh place he was shot. 
30202	Sounds like they're just assuming that the numbering of the shots in the autopsy report is actually a chronology of the shots.
30404	Sounds to me like he was high, but still sane enough to realize he was in big trouble (appreciate his actions) and sane enough to have waited for both men to in a prime position to kill them. 
30598	Whatever happened I don't think PTSD was at play now at all. If he had any kind of mental issue it sure as hell wasn't PTSD.
30794	@wfaajdouglas: #snipertrial Routh's uncle, James Watson, says "We're a God fearing family." Says Routh has sense of morality. 
30922	@wfaajdouglas: #snipertrial "does he know right from wrong?" "Yes." "Does he believe in God?" Yes
31095	They going to call Ron Paul? 
31289	Schizophrenic either taking medicine or not and self medicating with drugs.
