94	Presidency Silent On Patience Jonathans Whereabouts
224	http://www.punchng.com/news/presidency-silent-on-patience-jonathans-whereabouts/
380	She is too ashamed to show her face after being disgraced out of aso rock by the same northern children she insulted. Those "born troway" pikins dem for Kano have done Mama P a strong thing ooo... chai! grin 
694	She is too ashamed to show her face after being disgraced out of aso rock by the same northern children she insulted. Those "born troway" pikins dem for Kano have done Mama P a strong thing ooo... chai! grin 
913	Learn to be civil bro. Thanks.
945	http://www.nairaland.com/2215960/warri-south-constituency-ii-chief
1084	P baby is recounting her losses. Feel so sori fr her though. This one na from fame to shame.
1255	Are you people missing mama piss or why are you looking for her after refusing to vote for her husband
1463	Learn to be civil bro. Thanks.
1495	http://www.nairaland.com/2215960/warri-south-constituency-ii-chief
1572	Though she is the most uncivil and uncouth first woman Nigeria ever had, I will be the bigger person and edit appropriately.
1767	Learn to be civil bro. Thanks.
1798	Was she civil when she made those hateful utterances against northern ppl and stoning APC supporters?
1901	She deserves what's coming to her; I have no pity for either her or her husband - the thousands of innocent lives lost, maimed, destroyed and families brutalised cannot be easily forgotten or forgiven.
2172	Mama Peace don run for her live! smiley she no wan go jail.
2301	"I don't want to take food to my husband in jail" - Patience.
2436	I'm happy that lady shrek is off my tv screen.
2559	Never again will Nigeria have a first lady/president like you ma'am.
2705	you guys should leave this people alone na
2819	This woman lost her most prized asset(don't think her husband is a substitute)and you expect her not to withdraw and lick her wounds in private.
2965	Mama P needs to come out of her self imposed hibernation though before Amaechi takes Rivers as well as Aso rock from her before its too late.. smiley
3187	Nigerians already missing her even before handing over
3315	Its not easy to be a victim..already we are missing ds woman from otuke..she is one funny woman dt wen u think of her grammar u wl laff not matter d stress of d day.A lesson to the rest in power post, its not forever try to b civic wen in position. Mama peace pls drop one bomb shell for us bfo leaving finally on may 29...history wl remember u eida good or bad..chai diaris God o.I kno its now dawning on u too dt na only u waka come.Wishing u well in all ur future endeavors.
3864	the almajiri have send her into political exile
4018	Those "born troway" pikins dem for Kano have done Mama P a strong thing ooo... chai! grin 
4119	This is one of the most disturbing and disgusting statements I've heard someone so highly placed make, all in the name of canvassing support/votes.
4268	I can wager my annual income she hadn't a shred of doubt her husband was gonna win being the incumbent. She underestimated the will of the Nigerian people. Well, she got served and I really don't bloody care where she is at this moment or what is happening to her.
4534	Ps: regarding the Oba's scandal, I think we should soft pedal a little. A lot of folks are still bitter from the experience of March 28 and might wanna cease any opportunity to ensure the transition never takes place. They (politicians) just might kill a couple of South Westerners in the SE prompting a reprisal in the SW and before you know it, we get a serious sectarian crises in our hands, and then everything else the likes of Orubebe and Asari had desired would follow.
5012	As long as Buhari has yet to be sworn in, we aren't out of the woods yet.
5087	#SayNoToEthnicBashing.
5216	This is one of the most disturbing and disgusting statements I've heard someone so highly placed make, all in the name of canvassing support/votes.
5365	I can wager my annual income she hadn't a shred of doubt her husband was gonna win being the incumbent. She underestimated the will of the Nigerian people. Well, she got served and I really don't bloody care where she is at this moment or what is happening to her.
5631	Ps: regarding the Oba's scandal, I think we should soft pedal a little. A lot of folks are still bitter from the experience of March 28 and might wanna cease any opportunity to ensure the transition never takes place. They (politicians) just might kill a couple of South Westerners in the SE prompting a reprisal in the SW and before you know it, we get a serious sectarian crises in our hands, and then everything else the likes of Orubebe and Asari had desired would follow.
6109	As long as Buhari has yet to be sworn in, we aren't out of the woods yet.
6184	#SayNoToEthnicBashing.
6217	Well said. Noted.
6307	The shame is quite much. I never knew she could be this humble. If she was this calm since she assumed the first lady,Jonathan's problems would have been halved.
6543	Missing mama piss like kilode
6643	Is she still crying and inconsolable? May God comfort her and give her heart to bear the loss. Amen
6817	She on terminal leave
6914	Honestly I'm missing her English lines with those heavy Ijaw accent. Gov. Amaechi who laughs last laughs best. Amaechi my role model.
7119	I was left in tears when i read President Goodluck congratulatory message to Gen. Buhari I was not crying because i felt like crying, i was not crying cause i supported him and he lost, but i cried cause his words arrested my emotions. He wished his opponent a good administration ahead, he congratulated him and accepted defeat. I could remember by this time in 2011, Buhari never accepted that he lost, he promised Jonathan that he will make his administration ungovernable for him and he later fulfilled his promise. His supporters took to the streets and slaughtered innocent Nigerians but he never stopped the killings. But today, he has won that same man that defeated.him in 2011 but got a congratulatory message instead of threats. He has wished him success and not promising him an ungovernable tenure. Few weeks to the election, the people we call our leaders were busy sending threats to themselves and leaving the poor masses gripped with fear. Some people left the country with fear of the aftermath of the election. But today you'v restored peace by accepting defeat peacefuly..Oh! Jonathan, you've shown us that you'r a good man. You'v shown African leaders the true definition of democracy. You wished not to influence the elections with your powers, you wished not to cancel the election when you can do it and nothing will happen. Posterity will never forget you where ever you go. I am still your fan for life. You'r a good and gentleman but surrounded by ingrates and fools that care for their pockets alone. Oh Jona! You lost the election but won my heart....
8773	r
8849	Now she has gone hiding. Just few days ago she was acting like she is GOD. 
8926	She comported herself as though she was more powerful than the sissy of an husband she has ( or is it had sef? ). It is all lesson to everyone us. There is no such thing as absolute power. Take note. When in power, thread careful, the situation may change
9250	Mummy p is a powerful woman....she's annoyed with Nigerians women , they really disappointed her.
9419	lipsrsealed Mama Peace first to bolt/flee.Bode G next,FAyose to follow suit.Mama P,come back home oo,Ur shildren dey look for U grin
