94	Do British Muslims embarrass us internationally?
222	When you hear foreigners talking about the UK, it's not uncommon to hear them talk about our Muslim population and how frighteningly radical they are.
374	Young British Muslims are going abroad in droves to fight and young British Muslim women are even going abroad to become the fighters' brides.
518	Many terrorist plots have been foiled where British Muslims either helped plan or carry out the attack - Richard Reid, the shoe bomber, and Umar Farouk Abdulmutallab, the underwear bomber, are just two recent high profile examples.
751	Probably the most prominent Islamic terrorist in the world right now, Jihadi John AKA Mohammed Emwazi, is British-raised and has brutally executed innocent people of various nationalities whilst spewing hate in a British accent.
981	Groups like CAGE actively defend people like Jihadi John who was called a "beautiful young man" by one CAGE activist.
1100	High profile hate preachers like Anjem Choudary and Abu Hamza have made the UK their home and are free to say disgusting things knowing they're protected by our free speech laws.
1280	There is a huge amount of anti-semitism amongst UK Muslims with 39 percent of attacks on Jews in the UK committed by "Asians" or "Arabs" (Muslims).
1429	Polls have shown huge amounts of support amongst British Muslims for disgusting things like the execution of apostates, homosexuals and adulterers - especially amongst younger Muslims.
1615	When this is the way British Muslims are seen around the world, should we as a country be embarrassed?
1798	I don't feel embarrassed. They're not my fault.
1961	I don't feel embarrassed. They're not my fault.
2019	I just can't help feeling a little bit embarrassed. :/
2144	Nah the non Muslim population do a good job of that themselves. 
2210	And for your information, CAGE do not support Jihadi John. He was called 'beautiful' before he turned into the person he now is. 
2341	So get your facts right. 
2468	Nah the non Muslim population do a good job of that themselves. 
2534	And for your information, CAGE do not support Jihadi John. He was called 'beautiful' before he turned into the person he now is. 
2665	So get your facts right. 
2701	I doubt, given the extreme levels of psychopathy demonstrated, that there has actually been a huge transition in this person's personality. He was probably always a psychopath and a "beautiful" one at that.
3014	Groups like CAGE actively defend people like Jihadi John who was called a "beautiful young man" by one CAGE activist.
3142	Was the CAGE activist Afghan by any chance?
3261	I think Britain has embarrassed itself enough with the atrocities committed all around the world throughout history and in modern times.
3472	As a British Muslim, the radicalised ones embarrass us even further. Being 20, at uni, brown and Muslim, I'm seen as a potential radical thanks to these guys -_-
3635	(I can't do much, I'm not in an influential position, and not involved in the wider British Muslim community)
3850	Nah the non Muslim population do a good job of that themselves. 
3916	And for your information, CAGE do not support Jihadi John. He was called 'beautiful' before he turned into the person he now is. 
4047	So get your facts right. 
4083	They kinda do. Asim Qureshi called him “extremely kind, extremely gentle and the most humble young person I ever knew”, blamed his radicalisation solely on the intelligence services (as opposed to his religion which, obviously has nothing at all to do with it) and generally painted an extremely sympathetic picture of a guy who is a cold-blooded murderer.
4522	I think it's only the ones who voice their radical views publicly. Most Muslims are perfectly nice people.
4736	Was the CAGE activist Afghan by any chance?
4790	No idea. 
4834	As a British Muslim, the radicalised ones embarrass us even further. Being 20, at uni, brown and Muslim, I'm seen as a potential radical thanks to these guys -_-
4997	(I can't do much, I'm not in an influential position, and not involved in the wider British Muslim community)
5117	Yeah, it has to suck being a moderate Muslim when you have a very vocal minority making you all look like extremists. :/
5314	hahahaha, Britain and many other countries have committed so many barbaric acts in the past, should we not feel embarrassed by those? Think it's important to realize that by having this sort of mindset where you're generalizing an enormous group of people as a result of the (inhumane) acts of others, the problem isn't going to be solved any time soon
5781	When you hear foreigners talking about the UK, it's not uncommon to hear them talk about our Muslim population and how frighteningly radical they are.
5933	Young British Muslims are going abroad in droves to fight and young British Muslim women are even going abroad to become the fighters' brides.
6077	Many terrorist plots have been foiled where British Muslims either helped plan or carry out the attack - Richard Reid, the shoe bomber, and Umar Farouk Abdulmutallab, the underwear bomber, are just two recent high profile examples.
6310	Probably the most prominent Islamic terrorist in the world right now, Jihadi John AKA Mohammed Emwazi, is British-raised and has brutally executed innocent people of various nationalities whilst spewing hate in a British accent.
6540	Groups like CAGE actively defend people like Jihadi John who was called a "beautiful young man" by one CAGE activist.
6659	High profile hate preachers like Anjem Choudary and Abu Hamza have made the UK their home and are free to say disgusting things knowing they're protected by our free speech laws.
6839	There is a huge amount of anti-semitism amongst UK Muslims with 39 percent of attacks on Jews in the UK committed by "Asians" or "Arabs" (Muslims).
6988	Polls have shown huge amounts of support amongst British Muslims for disgusting things like the execution of apostates, homosexuals and adulterers - especially amongst younger Muslims.
7174	When this is the way British Muslims are seen around the world, should we as a country be embarrassed?
7287	They should be embarrassed about themselves. I have nothing but contempt for ***** like Abu Hamza.
7496	No idea. 
7507	Yeah, it has to suck being a moderate Muslim when you have a very vocal minority making you all look like extremists. :/
7638	the worst is when people who hate Muslims expect you apologise for them. I don't even follow the same sect as them, and don't know them, what the hell?! :/
7894	Nah the non Muslim population do a good job of that themselves. 
7969	Yeah, Agreed.
7984	The Brits are quite good at doing that themselves, regardless.
8161	They should be embarrassed about themselves. I have nothing but contempt for ***** like Abu Hamza.
8270	Agreed. Nice goal on Monday btw mate. :yy:
8418	Yeah, Agreed.
8433	The Brits are quite good at doing that themselves, regardless.
8506	People having...... FUN?!?!?! That is embarassing!
8628	Terrorists are not Muslim,you forget the fact that these terrorists have killed more Muslims than any other race or religion through suicide bombings and school massacres in their own country .
8823	Then we go in with America and not expect a backlash.
8878	We killed almost millions of civilians in their countries and some (American soliders)even took pictures of dead childrens bodies in burning cars
9025	We supplied arms to isis when ASAD was gasing his own people.
9088	A better question would be
9116	Should we feel embarrassed that we blindly followed America into those countries on US intelligence that was blurred and then killed more innocent people in the crossfire?
9289	Yes
9294	Should we feel ashamed by British Muslims ? 
9340	No,the majority don't take the Quran that literal 
9392	Lets look at it from another perspective if their was a bully at school who just terrorizes the weaker kids just for the fact his father told him"You either be the bully or get bullied" and his mother said the complete opposite.Who would you blame if the child violently beat up another child The bully ,the bully dad or both parents.​Or all of them?
9821	To be honest I'm more embarrassed about our country's role in going to war in Iraq and Afghanistan and successfully destabilising the region and leaving it more dangerous than it was before. Now that my man is embarassing
10145	I doubt, given the extreme levels of psychopathy demonstrated, that there has actually been a huge transition in this person's personality. He was probably always a psychopath and a "beautiful" one at that.
10362	That's not true. Psychopaths were once normal people. Sometimes it only takes one event to completely change a person's life around. 
10531	They kinda do. Asim Qureshi called him “extremely kind, extremely gentle and the most humble young person I ever knew”, blamed his radicalisation solely on the intelligence services (as opposed to his religion which, obviously has nothing at all to do with it) and generally painted an extremely sympathetic picture of a guy who is a cold-blooded murderer.
10898	No they don't. 
10915	If you read my previous post I said those comments praising him was before he started all these beheadings. 
11025	Family and friends of murderers all the time paint a nice picture of someone who they once knew as a nice, kind person etc. This really isn't an uncommon thing. 
