94	Isn't it ironic that KDF is protecting other people in foreign land?
237	Isn't it ironic for KDF to be protecting other people in foreign land and is the same reason we are being butchered at home? It is time for our gorvenment to make some sense out of this. KDF should be withdrawn to guide our borders and the police force strengthened to flush out and deal with the terrorists and their sympathisers already living herein. 
593	It does not matter if Al-shabaab gains some millitary strength in Somalia, as long as they do not find a way into Kenya. Besides, if they (the shabaab) strengthen, KDF will have a chance to face them in a more millitary way instead of them slaughtering us with every opportunity they get.
883	#MyTake
962	The finger of blame here should point at the police dept and our intelligence agencies for failing to identify and thwart the plots of these terrorists in time.
1124	The KDF is doing its work just fine,(not perfectly though). For having debilitated the activities of the alshbb within Somalia, thus preventing the crisis from snowballing into a Boko Haram or even worse, the ISIS kinda situation is commendable. The KDF deserve to be celebrated for fostering the relative peace and stability within this region.
1538	it is easier to negotiate with a woman on period than a terrorist.#nonegotationwithterrorists
1733	The finger of blame here should point at the police dept and our intelligence agencies for failing to identify and thwart the plots of these terrorists in time.
1895	The KDF is doing its work just fine,(not perfectly though). For having debilitated the activities of the alshbb within Somalia, thus preventing the crisis from snowballing into a Boko Haram or even worse, the ISIS kinda situation is commendable. The KDF deserve to be celebrated for fostering the relative peace and stability within this region.
2251	Our intelligence agencies and the kenya police still haven't learnt (and they will never). If they had, earlier smaller attacks and the westgate massacre should have been a lesson enough for them. We have to look at other alternatives and withdrawal of troops out of somalia to be deployed along the border makes sense alot.
