94	Calling Hillary Clinton Supporters On DU "Operatives" Is Ugly
235	Insinuating that her current or future supporters are paid shills is divisive.
315	Doing so helps create an overall atmosphere of distrust. It breeds a sort of McCarthyism.
406	IMO, it shouldn't be encouraged because it ends up being a form of personal attack in a flimsy attempt at concealment.
526	There are a few Hillary supporters posting here whom I respect highly. Differ with primary choice of candidate, but that's normal.
658	Going forward I am going to make an effort to focus my commentary on the actual politicians and their history/positions and try to stay away from talking about supporters of any candidate. Unless some advocates for a candidate really cross a line.
907	I may not always live up to that goal. But it's a goal worth trying for.
1061	1. Remember
1074	When some of us were accused of being paid Obama shills too?
1210	5. Also, paid Wes Clark shill. Actually, according to some, Wes Clark ran to siphon votes from Dean
1311	to save the nomination four years later for Hillary.
1434	84. HOLY CRAP!
1450	No WONDER we Clarkies heard that DU was an unwelcome place (and I didn't 'join' til later.)
1625	86. I was a Wes Clark delegate
1657	I'm still waiting for my check. That and my George Soros check.
1788	92. Oh yeah, Like some around here kept bullying ProSense that she was a "paid shill".. I cannot count
1892	how many times I answered those stupid accusations.
1945	Aloha, PLD
2029	95. I wonder what's taking him so long to disburse my check. nt
2167	2. Yes.  While I am not keen on Hillary Clinton I can see why other people would be
2252	There's no value to making that sort of accusation unless you genuinely want DU to be more of an "Agreement Board" than a "Discussion Board."
2395	Bryant
2474	3. So is calling those who do not care for Hillary rat-fuckers, right-wingers, trolls, etc.
2567	Those words are not insinuated, they are the words used.
2624	So pot, kettle, etc.
2718	4. Don't forget
2735	"haters". One of my personal favorites.
2776	But frankly I agree with the OP. Although I'd like to actually see who is running before I decide who I would support in the primaries.
2985	8. Oh, yes, I forgot - anyone who disagrees with what we can make out of Hillary's policies
3078	is automatically a hater.
3180	12. how is calling someone who supports Hillary an operative talking about her policies?
3270	I don't like some of her policies.
3306	Don't like what Bill Clinton did to weaken Democratic infrastructure across the entire country.
3403	There probably are a few thin-skinned Hillary supporters who call everyone who point out their problems w/her record "haters".
3531	But that clearly isn't prevalent in GD.
3644	16. What I am pointing out is how some HRC supporters call anyone who does not support her
3736	a right wing operative or troll. Already happened in this thread.
3875	21. Then perhaps you should start a thread about it, rather than attempting ...
3956	to hi-jackthisone. The OP made a point. Instead of responding to it, you went for the deflection via the "Oh yeah? But other people do THIS!" route.
4105	Shit, for a moment I thought I was at Discussionist.
4232	40. Then perhaps you should start a thread about it
4285	Why is that?
4299	How is that unrelated to what this thread is about?
4352	And how soon would someone in this other thread point out that some people call pro-Hillary folks "operatives"?
4537	51. Too much logic there, AlbertCat.  But thanks!
4659	29. My favorite, too.
4757	6. When DU'ers post right wing garbage against her- they very well might. You don't see the difference?
4862	Says more about your own inability to distinguish between cookware.
5001	9. +1 Couldn't agree more!
5101	11. "Right wing garbage" seems now to include anything about Hillary that anyone does not care for.
5202	I feel that labeling anything negative as right wing garbage is/was supposed to get us all to circle our wagons around Hillary. Too early in the game for that.
5362	Still waiting for her to clarify what, exactly, her positions and policies ARE. Looks to me like this was supposed to be a done deal with no messy positions and policies, just her turn, and SCOTUS!!!!! and lists of things she has said over the years.
5689	15. Well, I resent the stupid anti-Hillary garbage posted here cause it forces me to defend her.
5787	And I've seen other posters say same.
5826	And I'm still waiting for her to state her positions too. The primary hasn't started yet. Here on DU, Hillary is no favorite.
6026	66. "Stupid anti-hillary garbage" to some, includes any question about her past record
6114	or policy statements. So I decided to enumerate the different types of comments which may or may not, constitute this anti-hillary garbage.
6255	Questions about "emailgate" may or may not be anti-hillary garbage.
6324	Questions about her vote for the IWR definitely are not.
6382	Questions or comments about the thinly disguised racist primary campaign the clintons waged in 2008 are not.
6492	References to her disloyalty to President Obama over Syria are not.
6561	Comments regarding her personal veracity ("I came under sniper fire in Bosnia" "We were dead broke when we left the white house") aren't anti-Hillary garbage.
6721	Comments about her expressed admiration for war criminals (Kissinger) and regular criminals (Goldman Sachs et al) are not.
6845	Comments about Monica Lewinsky, Vince Foster, Whitewater, or any other scandals from the Clinton presidential era are probably anti-Hillary garbage. Unless they are true, in which case they may not be.
7048	If she wants to be defined by her own words and/or actions, she should announce her candidacy and tell us in very specific terms, why she wants to be POTUS and what she proposes to accomplish if elected. And deal with the criticism that follows. Otherwise, she is going to continue to be defined by others. And those others may not always be so kind as we here on DU are so she needs to toughen up.
7517	17. This.  Disagreeing with Hillary on policy is the same as hate to many of her supporters. n/t
7694	52. Haven't seen much of this "disagreeing on policy" you speak of.... because Her POLICIES
7787	(and she has quite a public record for all to fact check against) are being mischaracterized and exaggerated beyond recognition! Its unbelievable how many downright myths and distortions are allowed to stand when they are so easily proven false with FACTS! I read a lot of rhetoric and read a lot of bullshit that is allowed to stand...but do not see a lot of backing that shit up with EVIDENCE! We are all just supposed to ACCEPT it because they say so! As if repetition is how you create perception...if people just get worn down..having to prove things a myth or urban legend often enough and over and over and over over "it do get tiresome after a while". So when people just stop opposing that because they are just bored with doing so ...it means that now everyone just accepts it as reality! Afterall "no one's complaining anymore" so it must be true! The old George Bush "we have to catapult the propaganda" technique of "politickin'"
8803	63. She helped write the TPP and has spoken in favor of it.  There have been links to this posted many
8907	times. I am against the TPP, because it is a corporate takeover. Is that plain enough for you?
9082	65. so has Obama....but lets see your evidence of her transgression...what you just said is EXACTLY
9183	what I am talking about....Because YOU say so! Is that plain enough for you???
9263	By the way...all that proves is she is no worse than President Obama....like I said..."exaggerated beyond recognition"!
9456	68. Her "transgression"?  Word salad time, I guess.  I do not support any politician who supports
9555	Fast Track and the TPP or TTIP. My evidence? We go through this once a week, it seems, and there have been links posted to Hillary's speeches about how great the TPP and how proud she is of helping architect it. Not playing this game with you.
9799	Oh, and I do not like it that Obama is pushing the TPP, either.
9943	69. Here let me do it for you...
9977	Q: What would you do differently than a Pres. Obama would when it comes to the economy?
10066	A: I would agree with Obama a lot, because it is the Democratic agenda. We are going to rid the tax code of these loopholes &amp; giveaways. Were going to stop giving penny of your money to anybody who ships a job out to another country. Were going to begin to get the tax code to reflect what the needs of middle class families are so we can rebuild a strong &amp; prosperous middle class. The wealthy &amp; the well-connected have had a president the last 7 years, and its time that the rest of the US had a president to work for you every single day. We will have a different approach toward trade. Were going to start having trade agreements that not only have strong environmental and labor standards, but also a trade time-out. Were going to look and see whats working &amp; whats not working. Id like to have a trade prosecutor to actually enforce the trade agreements that we have before we enter into any others.
10997	Source: 2008 Democratic debate at University of Texas in Austin , Feb 21, 2008
11149	73. That is also word salad.  Those who have read the TPP say that there are no actual enforcements.
11251	That all sounds like campaign blather, when what has been leaked about the TPP says that corporations can sue if environmental laws hamper profits. Special prosecutor? The ISDS will be in charge of prosecution - corporations against sovereign countries and municipalities. No appeal. Secret corporate courts. What was said in 2008 does not hold true in 2015. But I am eagerly awaiting Hillary's platform.
11736	70. By the way...still no evidence.....otherwise it is still just rhetoric!
11885	74. What you posted - is merely actual campaign rhetoric.  But we shall see soon how Hillary plans to
11988	do things, right?
12080	60. If Fox News or Limbaugh is running with it...
12131	...should we care for it?
12230	61. If Hillary is for the TPP, for example, and I am against the TPP, and Fox or Limbaugh is against the
12336	TPP, does that mean I need to be FOR the TPP? I don't like the TPP. I don't care about Clinton gossip or any of that other crap. I was for Hillary her first shot at this, and voted for her in Florida. Pointless vote, but I was happy to do so.
12580	Now, I am looking more closely at things, and Corporatism and Third Way policies are things I do not like. How Fox or Limbaugh feels about them is totally irrelevant.
12821	67. Not at all.
12838	You can be against something but not running the right wing narrative of the day. How about waiting to talk about it until another day? It's certain that the TPP has been talked about a lot here. Why must the right wing be allowed to run a given narrative on a given day?
13111	If they are running a narrative on their sites and it shows up here I have no problem considering it ratfucking. I can't prove the people posting the information is a ratfucker themselves, but somehow the media narrative is making its way to a liberal site and the only conclusion I can have is that some astroturfer somewhere somehow is pushing a narrative to come here. It's not necessarily a conspiracy, but just people being exposed to media PR dissemination (it could be three ways removed from the original post; literally a fox news article, posted on fb, edited and changed, posted as a graphic on a liberal fb picture posting page, then picked up and posted here).
13786	I get so tired of our crappy, shitty, checkbook, clickbait journalism in this country that is literally causes me to zone out and completely ignore it. It's beyond tiresome.
14033	71. Actually, the right wing loves the TPP.  McConnell said it is the one thing he can certainly work
14136	with Obama on. And NOW is the time to speak out against Fast Track. Obama is running around pushing it.
14240	Better tell the liberal Dems in Congress to sit down and shut up too, you know.
14320	And I do not ever click on RW sites. I have no idea what their narrative is about the TPP, and I see no reason to care.
14441	What right wing narrative, exactly, am I running? Or anyone is running? Are her corporate ties, for example, a right wing invention? Are we supposed to shut up during the primaries?
14697	76. Take the ISDS TPP revelations.
14733	The very day that the revelations came out, leaked by Wikileaks, Fox News was running a story about how it would let foreign companies sue the US, etc.
14886	Now, Elizabeth Warren had wrote about ISDS a few weeks prior, and it garnered a whole one thread. One thread! Like ahalf dozen of responses. Most of which were me even!
15056	Fast forward to the "revelations." Same exact information, absolutely identical information. "TPP uses ISDS." Dozens of threads spawned. Dozens.
15202	This is just the first page of Google:
15242	http://www.democraticunderground.com/10026440549
15291	http://www.democraticunderground.com/10026415083
15340	http://www.democraticunderground.com/10026357276
15389	http://www.democraticunderground.com/10026417822
15438	http://www.democraticunderground.com/10026422709
15488	We are driven by mainstream media, not by civics, not by duty, but by a media environment that literally motivates our own actions. It is beyond incredible how easily fooled human beings can be when they drive into these mass mainstream narratives.
15810	78. I have been posting against the TPP for over a year.  I don't need right wing sites to get info
15911	about it.
15921	Oh, and I posted in that thread.
16027	80. Ran a search - looks like I have been posting about the TPP since 2013.
16104	Not MSM driven. At all.
16202	89. Oh and let's no forget "Rand Paul clowns"
16249	Really some HRV supporters (not all) cant stand any dissent
16382	64. What, exactly, is the right wing garbage that DUers are posting?  Can I have an example?
16476	Or is anything not for her classified as garbage?
16602	75. If someone is breathlessly quoting the Benghazi committee and/or right wing sources
16691	like Washington Examiner, Fox News, The Daily Tucker Carlson etc it is right wing garbage. It isn't that hard to understand.
16889	77. I would understand it if I read that stuff.  I honestly do not remember any DUers believing
16986	the Benghazi crap. And I have never quoted any right wing stuff - I merely do not like the corporate ties, the trade agreements, fracking. In fact, the things that I am against, I think the GOP like.
17262	81. Yes there are many legit issues one can criticize HRC for.  That is why it disturbs me to see RW smears
17371	used here.
17455	83. Yes.  And it disturbs me when legit issues are dismissed as RW smears, too.
17536	Are the RW smears used, or just brought over and quoted?
17662	10. Rest assured
17680	There are plenty of right wing trolls here who hate Hillary as much as the far left. Fortunately DU is only an echo chamber and their efforts are pretty much wasted.
17920	59. If it rat fucks like a rat fucker it's a ratfucker.
17977	Ratfucking is using dirty tricks, right wing sources, to spread hate and lies. If you search "FOX News" and "news story" and there is a crossover, it's likely ratfucking or someone being mislead (perhaps posting something from FB over here without knowing that they're being manipulated by some media PR astroturfer somewhere).
18306	Here's a good definition of what it looks like:http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Ratfucking
18394	It is a very real phenomena and it is almost always targeted at the left. The reason it is still used is it is very very effective. The Democratic Party is not a unity party, it is a very diverse and big tent party. The best way to fuck the Democratic Party over is to divide and conquer. Set it against itself. That's what the PUMA's attempted to do. And we're seeing that sort of shit with pledges to not vote for Clinton if she's the nominee. It's the same damn thing.
18867	Don't post stories here that come from the Moonie Times, Fox News, Breitbart, Drudge Report, or any other open editorial site like OpEdNews (and present it as news). Doing that constitutes carrying water for the right wing and is indeed ratfucking.
19117	More on ratfucking here:http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ratfucking
19252	62. Not "caring for" someone is not equivalent to the kind of garbage that gets posted regularly abt HRC
19358	There are any number of potential candidates I personally "don't care for," but I would never post Right Wing trash about them while refusing to name who I am actually in favor of (aside from someone who has said about a hundred times that they are not running).
19622	But if you can't see the difference, I can't explain it to you.
19687	Who am I supporting? No one yet. I am looking forward to a robust and challenging primary season so everyone gets a chance to be tested and vetted.
19910	79. + a kabillion. nt
20001	7. yes it is.  and dumb as hell.
20035	I vigorously oppose her, but that is NO reason to assume those that vigorously support her here, are "operatives". It's despicable to lable them as such.
20272	13. They can call me what they want. I don't give a rip.
20330	You are civil to me. I will be civil to you. That's how I conduct myself in real life and on this board.
20436	You troll me...I will troll you back exponentially...
20562	14. Recommended
20649	18. No surprise here...
20674	Ugly Я Us these days..
20698	There's been enough of it going around, and juries let a good deal of it stand.
20849	19. Haters, ratfuckers, trolls  and a few other names that Non Supporters are
20928	also called are rather ugly too.
21038	20. Should Hillary become our nominee, I'll immediately become
21102	and/all of the following (without apology)-
21146	Advocate
21155	Hillbot
21163	Operative
21174	The horrible possibility of Jeb or any of the other Republiclowns becoming leader of the free world is unthinkable.
21365	22. I have no problem being called a "paid operative" for Hillary
21432	I am still waiting for that check though.
21545	23. The truth is: There ARE paid antagonists who post on DU
21606	Whether you are or not? ... I don't know, but let's not pretend it is a false claim - it is true
21777	24. No such thing exists
21803	Can you honestly believe otherwise?
21918	35. DU is so miniscule in the grand scheme.
21963	I know there is a such thing as paid trolls and paid supporters, but they tend to stick to places like reddit, facebook, and news comment sections. Not small, mostly unknown message boards like DU. Keep in mind that DU doesn't represent the mainstream of the Democratic party, and those here that DO represent the mainstream are the ones who are generally accused of being paid shills.
22422	42. Present some evidence.
22524	44. Nah....the NSA used to pay for posting here, but given DU's traffic,
22598	you make more posting at kos or reddit.
22710	25. Kitty, I agree completely and see the attacks as an attempt to make people uncomfortable
22804	As a longtime member of the John Kerry group, there was a time when all of us in that group were accused of being paid Kerry Shrills - which was absolutely not true. The purpose - as it is now - seemed twofold - to discredit any arguments we were making AND to render us "others - ie not true blue DU members.
23115	In essence, what it was and is - is bullying. You, along with many others, should be completely immune to this type of attack as you have posted for years and your name should be familiar. That does not make it more pleasant. It also is not meant to say that someone just joining DU as someone excited for the Clinton run to start should be suspect. There are many here now who started posting as the 2008 contest started - especially in 2007 and 2008.
23569	If it makes you feel better, consider what one of my fellow JK group posters once said to me -- after denying it, we should take it as a compliment. After all, what we are accused of is really being considered effective enough that a sitting Senator would have hired us AND kept us on his payroll for years. (Our bank accounts will show this is not the case.)
23930	Not to mention, it was very obvious that some (likely Russian) posters were not who they said they were. In posting, people tend to give enough of themselves away that you get kind of a picture of who they are. In there case, between language not sounding "right" and not seeming to have the shared experiences that they would have if they were who they said they were. The ONLY account here that I think is a paid shrill is ALAN GRAYSON - which is almost certainly one of his staffers - as all he does is drop canned fund raising messages with many blue links.
24493	As to you and other Clinton supporters, it is stunning that some here think that HRC needs to pay people to post in her favor on a Democratic board -- when every poll shows that over half the Democrats want her to be the nominee.
24799	31. I am not, nor have I ever been, a Hillary supporter. Don't like her. Don't want her. And that
24898	And that is what is so ironic. the stupid crap that gets flung at her has me ending up having to defend her.
25009	And the reason for that is, she might very well end up being the nominee. And if she is the nominee we're all going to have to suck it up and look for her good points and shoot down the garbage.
25283	36. I have this same issue...
25314	I don't usually like to let bullshit and RW talking points go uncontested. You repeat a lie often enough, it becomes truth. Especially if that lie goes uncontested.
25480	I'm not a Hillary supporter. Seeing as NO ONE has dropped their hat in the ring yet, I don't know who I'm going to support in the primary. Last time around, it was Kucinich (my wife, who hails from OH also loved Kucinich, but she knew he had a snowball's chance and put her money behind Richardson). If Bernie switches parties and actually runs, I'll probably throw my support behind him. But the reality is that Hillary will most likely end up the nominee (at least as things stand today). When that time comes, I'll be sucking it up with you.
26026	:cheers:
26107	46. Same here for the same reasons
26143	She may very well be the nominee and you are right that most of us will try to emphasize where she is better than the alternative. (I HOPE if she is the nominee that the real negatives will be lost in the noise of all the faux garbage that is thrown at her.)
26403	I did though want to make the other points (even though) that it is bullying and really obnoxious to attack ANYONE rather than just discuss the issue at hand.
26563	PS I recognized your name, but was too lazy to look back to see if you were for or against anyone for 2016. Sorry for assuming - if you want I will delete it, but I think it does make the point I want to make.
26844	72. I'm on that spectrum, Kitty, though probably not as strongly as you. Here I am defending her record
26949	...against people who bring RW sources here against her, and it is aggravating as hell to me. The animosity against Hillary is beyond belief at a "Democratic" board. There are so-called sources that should be flat-out banned at this board, in my opinion, and the posters who persist in using them.
27248	I'm still waiting for the primary to open up for the Democrats. I await it with eager interest. I have not yet made up my mind.
27377	Yet I am so pissed off at the bloody-minded stupidity of the attacks on a good Dem woman that I have participated in the "I'm a secret operative with a decoder ring" mockery for the sheer relief of it, and I will do so again.
27604	DU is making itself irrelevant, and that's a damned shame.
27737	43. the attacks as an attempt to make people uncomfortable
27797	that obviously works.
27891	45. Believe me, I know - because I know how intimidating it was to me
27962	-- and that was even though the JK group was among the most cohesive groups there was on DU - so there was support.
28146	93. Key word is absolutely "bullying", karyn.   And, what I saw wasn't subtle bullying, either.
28317	26. Well said &amp; thank you.
28419	27. It's a lazy tactic used by both her supporters and her detractors.
28491	It's a lot easier to call someone a paid shill than to actually address their argument. So both supporters and detractors of Clinton use that argument.
28718	28. I Totally Agree
28739	Hell, I signed up almost a full day ago and haven't gotten apennyso far!
28887	30. Would you prefer moles?
28916	Sleeper cells?
28932	5th Column?
28945	(I'm joshing you if you can't tell.)
29053	32. I'm not a paid shill for anyone or anything ...
29106	... and I will support Clinton if she is the nominee.
29234	33. I am still waiting for Hillary to sign my check.
29288	Where the hell is my check?
29388	37. I am also waiting for the check to be signed
29520	38. I just recieved my five figure check for one weeks work...
29584	lol@you
29667	56. 5 figure?????????????
29694	Darn you! You buy the next round of pizza and beer!
29829	58. And I'm only a mid level internet operative./NT
29952	88. Mine hasn't come, either.
29983	I was so hoping to buy a bag of Doritos with it.
30107	34. I think it's easier to compile a list of people here who aren't allegedly paid shills for somebody
30211	or some industry.
30308	39. K&amp;R!
30393	41. I don't mind.  I think it sounds kind of dashing!
30448	"Well, I'm an engineer by day, but by night, I'm an operative...."
30516	Sounds kinda sexy!
30611	47. Not Operatives or Minions
30642	Just BIG fans.
30735	49. I agree.  I don't support Hillary much.  But let's not demean
30802	each other over who we're backing.
30838	Any Democrat is going to be better than any Republican. We can all agree on that.
30988	50. Boris and Natasha disagree!
31099	53. How does it compare to
31127	calling FDR Democratsratfuckers?
31161	Just wondering.
31251	54. Well, having been told that my lack of desire for a Clinton presidency makes me a Paulbot...
31349	And that a desire to see Sanders run makes me an "idiot leftist..."
31418	I'm not really worried about the feelings of Clinton supporters.
31560	96. Or told repeatedly that Warren isn't running so don't even think about a Warren candidacy
31655	But if we don't like Hillary, we should find-- and fund-- our own candidate. But relying on grassroots funding ain't gonna win elections, so forget about that because Hillary already has the huge bucks and is inevitable anyway, and she's guaranteed to win the presidential election because all of her opponents are Dumber Than Dubya
32062	55. No worse than what people opposed to Hillary are called here.
32203	57. this is what I wrote in response to the "operatives" post
32266	The term "Hillary operative" sounds interesting and all,
32323	but baseless accusations are not to be confused with actual proof. Facts should compete with facts. I am not a supporter of HRC, but if she best represents my position in the election she will have my vote. As would whomever else the Democratic party decides on.
32587	And I stand by that. Name calling accomplishes nothing other than lowering the level of conversation.
32765	85. Meh
32774	Does this include posts that actually are from paid shills?
32835	Actually the reason to cock an eyebrow about this posts is Hillary supporters constantly heap much uglier names on people who refrain from getting on board with their bandwagon: freeper, rw troll, conspiracy theorists....usually reaching for labels that might have jurying or banning power. The onslaught has been constant and obviously strategic since this is a high profile Dem forum, and Hillary supporters want to create a picture of party unity behind Hillary and only a "not even Democrat" fringe against.
33348	But the best they can do is try to paint that picture, and they haven't been very successful because there is, frankly, not overwhelming support for Hillary here. It seems about half and half.
33542	That said, you Hillary supporters are just embarrassing yourselves when you try to cover your behavior with: "Well you called us X ugly name, too." Who do you think is going to throw a pity party for you? Posts like this just point up that *by your own standards*, your name-calling tactics have been uncivil and should be called out as worse.
33961	87. Agreed!
33974	K &amp; R
34058	90. well re the nagative comments about HRC...
34106	I have no seen any DUers criticizing her on Benghazi, Foster or anything of the lies created by GOP.
34207	Let me be clear.
34224	We critocize her on her taste of secrecy and the Clintons lean to dirty politics. All what we state are proven facts.
34342	its proven that she cozies wis WS and criminal such as Kissinger.
34408	Its is true that Bill and Hillary cares and run only for themselves.
34477	it is true that in 2004 Bill praised Bish while officially "supporting Kerry " while both Clintons stabbed him in the back with "Hillary 2008" in mind.
34629	It is true yhat Hillary Clinton atvStatevdidnt took much risk.
34693	But that do not stop me meanwhile, to AGREE that Hillary was wonderfull on issues re women right and that Bill did good re economy while serving as President.
34926	91. Perhaps if she is the nominee Skinner will let us have stars for free? n/t
35087	94. Posters get called all kinds of names and nasty shit on DU.
35152	It sucks. Sometimes I think that if it wasn't for ad hominem, some folks here wouldn't be able to add at all.
