175	Originally Posted by LongCat
204	So if a trial depends on DNA evidence, should the Defendant be tried by a board of state-approved DNA experts? Should the Enron guys have been tried by 12 state-approved finance experts? Should Darren Wilson have been tried by 12 state-approved police procedure experts?
476	There are legitimate arguments to support ending the jury system and using trial by state-approved expert. But the US decided against that plan a long time ago.
637	If DNA is involved then I hope to God the Houston cops/prosecutor haven't engaged in their fraud to screw things up. 
756	If you're white and haven't killed a war hero then Texas juries are great.
909	I need some Shag attorneys to weigh in with legal definitions.. Despite the 'mental illness' of this guy, the jury decided he understood what murder was and that it was wrong - right? Therefore, regardless of whether he thought the guys at the range with him were purple headed monsters, he still knew it was wrong to kill them (just using that as an example).
1271	Not all mental illness is equal. I assume that a large percentage of mentally ill understand what murder is and that it's against the law.. and that there are consequences.
1445	I did not follow this case closely, I really don't have an opinion. But I've found that there is a lot of logic to our legal system and there is a reason attorney's have a doctorate in the law. I have no idea the legal definitions at play nor the instructions presented to the jury.
1729	I do think it's kinda lazy to look at this case and then make general aspersions against Texas' juries. 
1835	I also think it's dangerous to think that 'state appointed experts' are a better, more infallible approach then 'a jury of your peers'.
2047	The killer was also a vet, right? 
2083	We owe our vets better than this. 
2119	That's what pisses me off the most. We send these guys over there to fight, maybe even "for their country" (whatever that may mean in our current state of affairs), and ask them to pay a great sacrifice then this is how we treat them? 
2356	Chris Kyle was a hero-kind of guy, but his hero status doesn't outweigh the rights of the other guy. 
2459	Bottom line: we owe our vets better than this.
2617	I need some Shag attorneys to weigh in with legal definitions.. Despite the 'mental illness' of this guy, the jury decided he understood what murder was and that it was wrong - right? Therefore, regardless of whether he thought the guys at the range with him were purple headed monsters, he still knew it was wrong to kill them (just using that as an example).
2979	Not all mental illness is equal. I assume that a large percentage of mentally ill understand what murder is and that it's against the law.. and that there are consequences.
3153	I did not follow this case closely, I really don't have an opinion. But I've found that there is a lot of logic to our legal system and there is a reason attorney's have a doctorate in the law. I have no idea the legal definitions at play nor the instructions presented to the jury.
3437	I do think it's kinda lazy to look at this case and then make general aspersions against Texas' juries. 
3543	I also think it's dangerous to think that 'state appointed experts' are a better, more infallible approach then 'a jury of your peers'.
3689	The other thing to understand is that the defense likely presented an expert psychiatrist/chologist(s) who opined that he was insane and didn't know the difference between right and wrong and the state put on an expert(s) who testified to the contrary. The jury had to pick which one they believed, not necessarily on an understanding of psychology, but based on the credibility of the expert and their respective assumptions and theories. Generally speaking, juries are pretty good at collectively deciding who is believable and who is not. Occasionally, though, demagoguery on the part of the prosecution or defense gets the better of them and they make a wrong decision.
4475	The killer was also a vet, right? 
4511	We owe our vets better than this. 
4547	That's what pisses me off the most. We send these guys over there to fight, maybe even "for their country" (whatever that may mean in our current state of affairs), and ask them to pay a great sacrifice then this is how we treat them? 
4784	Chris Kyle was a hero-kind of guy, but his hero status doesn't outweigh the rights of the other guy. 
4887	Bottom line: we owe our vets better than this.
4944	While we owe our vets a ton, it doesn't excuse murder in the slightest. The guy deserves to be in a mental hospital for a long, long time.
5154	Originally Posted by Johnny Sack
5187	"Both sides hire experts to explain the mental health issues to the jury.
5262	I didn't follow the Chris Kyle trial closely, but thinking about it had me wondering about this even before I saw this thread. I'm sure that both sides presented testimony from psychiatrists and experts to back their version of the story. My assumption is that if you talked to enough psychiatrists, you'd be able to find one to say that any given person is sane or insane. It's an inexact science, is my point. But all the jury sees is one expert from the prosecution saying Routh is sane, and one from the defense saying he's insane. They don't know if the defense had to talk to 500 different psychiatrists before finding one that thinks he's insane, or vice versa."
5933	I'm trying to wrap my head around how I would approach this as a juror deciding a man's fate. If Dr. So-and-so from Harvard tells me he examined Routh and believes him to be insane, I'd tend to believe that. But the next day, Dr. Such-and-such from Yale says he found Routh to be perfectly sane. And a juror is supposed to just go with whatever they find most believable I guess? It's not like they can present the jury with a poll of 10,000 psychiatrists saying it's 90%-10% in favor of insane.
6430	The phrase "reasonable doubt" looms large in my mind. As long as the defense can find one appropriately-credentialed expert to testify that Routh is insane, it would seem to me that constitutes "reasonable doubt" as to whether or not he's guilty as charged.
6689	Any shaggy lawyers or legal experts care to explain how this works in the real world? Maybe my thinking isn't quite right.
6813	edit: while I was typing this out, TwiceHorn touched on pretty much the same thing. I would add that I'm not assuming anything nefarious on the part of either side's expert witness. Suppose a two well-credentialed experts truly and honestly came to different conclusions about Routh. It's not a question of who the jury will find believable, because in my hypothetical each expert truly believes himself to be telling the truth.
7354	While we owe our vets a ton, it doesn't excuse murder in the slightest. The guy deserves to be in a mental hospital for a long, long time.
7503	Who said anything about excusing murder? 
7546	You equate an insanity defense with excusing murder? 
7601	A lot of people do.
7727	Originally Posted by Johnny Sack
7760	"Both sides hire experts to explain the mental health issues to the jury.
7835	I didn't follow the Chris Kyle trial closely, but thinking about it had me wondering about this even before I saw this thread. I'm sure that both sides presented testimony from psychiatrists and experts to back their version of the story. My assumption is that if you talked to enough psychiatrists, you'd be able to find one to say that any given person is sane or insane. It's an inexact science, is my point. But all the jury sees is one expert from the prosecution saying Routh is sane, and one from the defense saying he's insane. They don't know if the defense had to talk to 500 different psychiatrists before finding one that thinks he's insane, or vice versa."
8506	I'm trying to wrap my head around how I would approach this as a juror deciding a man's fate. If Dr. So-and-so from Harvard tells me he examined Routh and believes him to be insane, I'd tend to believe that. But the next day, Dr. Such-and-such from Yale says he found Routh to be perfectly sane. And a juror is supposed to just go with whatever they find most believable I guess? It's not like they can present the jury with a poll of 10,000 psychiatrists saying it's 90%-10% in favor of insane.
9003	The phrase "reasonable doubt" looms large in my mind. As long as the defense can find one appropriately-credentialed expert to testify that Routh is insane, it would seem to me that constitutes "reasonable doubt" as to whether or not he's guilty as charged.
9262	Any shaggy lawyers or legal experts care to explain how this works in the real world? Maybe my thinking isn't quite right.
9386	edit: while I was typing this out, TwiceHorn touched on pretty much the same thing. I would add that I'm not assuming anything nefarious on the part of either side's expert witness. Suppose a two well-credentialed experts truly and honestly came to different conclusions about Routh. It's not a question of who the jury will find believable, because in my hypothetical each expert truly believes himself to be telling the truth.
9825	I think that you have to look at the whole picture, there were a lot of othere pieces of evidence presented besides just the psych evals, there was documented behaviors by the defendant that a juror could look at on their own to help make an informed decision as to sanity.
10210	Who said anything about excusing murder? 
10253	You equate an insanity defense with excusing murder? 
10308	A lot of people do.
10338	Most people do, actually. It's what makes it so damned hard to do.
10406	Routh was insane.
10425	But he also did a really $#@!ty, bad, evil thing. And we instinctively want to punish that, at least by making a declaration that he is "guilty."
10572	That's why the solution I've proposed is introducing a new possible verdict -- GUILTY by reason of insanity. That way, a jury gets to find the defendant guilty, but then the court gets to determine where he will be confined, treated, etc. And a dangerous person is off the streets. 
10856	It doesn't satisfy ALL of the concerns addressed by a "not guilty by reason of insanity" plea, but it's more achievable and closer to real justice than just booting the not guilty plea because it just doesn't sit right with us.
11187	Who said anything about excusing murder? 
11230	You equate an insanity defense with excusing murder? 
11285	A lot of people do.
11315	what pisses me off the most is when morons don't have a clue what the $#@! they are talking about, but just keep hammering away at the keyboard. it's painfully obvious you didn't follow a minute of the testimony, or you'd understand why the killer didn't get off by reason of insanity. 
11603	what pisses me off just a hair less than that is jackasses who try to use someone's status as a "vet" as some mythic status. the dude never saw action.
11756	He joined the Marine Corps in June 2006 and served four years as a small arms repairer/technician, a job that primarily involves working in an armory on rifles and other weapons. He served in Iraq between September 2007 and March 2008, aboard the amphibious assault ship USS Bataan from May 2009 to December 2009, and then in support of earthquake relief operations in Haiti from January through April of 2010.
12168	Routh did not receive the Combat Action Ribbon, the Navy Department decoration that recognizes those who “directly and actively participate in ground or surface combat,” as the Navy and Marine Corps Awards Manual indicates. Marines and sailors can get it a variety of ways, including engaging in a firefight, facing direct exposure to an improvised explosive device detonation, and participating in a clandestine mission in which they are restricted in their ability to return fire even though it is likely that they will be attacked.
12801	the dude never saw action.
12838	So PTSD or no PTSD?
12961	what pisses me off the most is when morons don't have a clue what the $#@! they are talking about, but just keep hammering away at the keyboard. it's painfully obvious you didn't follow a minute of the testimony, or you'd understand why the killer didn't get off by reason of insanity. 
13249	what pisses me off just a hair less than that is jackasses who try to use someone's status as a "vet" as some mythic status. the dude never saw action.
13411	I am glad that you can discern the ultimate truth about this situation and you can determine which vets deserve our support. I freely admit that I am unable to do this. I give the benefit of the doubt to most vets. 
13628	Was this guy just a loser? Maybe. I don't know. But we owe him something.
13807	I didn't follow the Chris Kyle trial closely, but thinking about it had me wondering about this even before I saw this thread. I'm sure that both sides presented testimony from psychiatrists and experts to back their version of the story. My assumption is that if you talked to enough psychiatrists, you'd be able to find one to say that any given person is sane or insane. It's an inexact science, is my point. But all the jury sees is one expert from the prosecution saying Routh is sane, and one from the defense saying he's insane. They don't know if the defense had to talk to 500 different psychiatrists before finding one that thinks he's insane, or vice versa."
14478	I'm trying to wrap my head around how I would approach this as a juror deciding a man's fate. If Dr. So-and-so from Harvard tells me he examined Routh and believes him to be insane, I'd tend to believe that. But the next day, Dr. Such-and-such from Yale says he found Routh to be perfectly sane. And a juror is supposed to just go with whatever they find most believable I guess? It's not like they can present the jury with a poll of 10,000 psychiatrists saying it's 90%-10% in favor of insane.
14975	The phrase "reasonable doubt" looms large in my mind. As long as the defense can find one appropriately-credentialed expert to testify that Routh is insane, it would seem to me that constitutes "reasonable doubt" as to whether or not he's guilty as charged.
15234	Any shaggy lawyers or legal experts care to explain how this works in the real world? Maybe my thinking isn't quite right.
15358	edit: while I was typing this out, TwiceHorn touched on pretty much the same thing. I would add that I'm not assuming anything nefarious on the part of either side's expert witness. Suppose a two well-credentialed experts truly and honestly came to different conclusions about Routh. It's not a question of who the jury will find believable, because in my hypothetical each expert truly believes himself to be telling the truth.
15797	Neither side is going to be privy to how many experts the other side contacted before finding the "right" one. But if one expert or the other has a minority opinion in view of the science, you can be sure the jury will be so informed through cross examination. The "system" works pretty well at revealing biases and fabrications. I mean the prosecution always has Park Dietz, who apparently has never encountered an insane person in his career.
16323	You know, I'm probably gonna get negged for this. I'm sorry the guy died trying to help veterans. That was noble as hell. I take offense that he is being glorified as the American sniper. He did his job. Well. Thousands of other veterans did their job well without a thank you or whatfor. I don't get the glorification of this guy. I admire his marksmanship, but he's no more a war hero than anybody else who served and excelled at their job. Is that wrong?
16895	You know, I'm probably gonna get negged for this. I'm sorry the guy died trying to help veterans. That was noble as hell. I take offense that he is being glorified as the American sniper. He did his job. Well. Thousands of other veterans did their job well without a thank you or whatfor. I don't get the glorification of this guy. I admire his marksmanship, but he's no more a war hero than anybody else who served and excelled at their job. Is that wrong?
17363	Nope. Ive had the same thought, not that that makes it right or wrong. Same thought I had watching the end montage of Lone Survivor, which does a good job of reminding that Marcus Luttrell isn't the only "hero." I really thought Berg knocked that out of the park.
17730	I am glad that you can discern the ultimate truth about this situation
17811	it's a legal situation, nothing more. you're a $#@!ing moron because you can't tell the difference. well, that and you won't shut the $#@! up about it. 
18000	and you can determine which vets deserve our support. I freely admit that I am unable to do this. I give the benefit of the doubt to most vets.
18154	there's a wide range of "vets" and you're trying to act like some kid who never saw combat "deserves" something simply because he wore a uniform for a couple of years. he deserves exactly what he got - a conviction on capital murder charges. the thought that he's owed something more after killing two men in cold blood - also vets, by the way - is asinine.
18513	those who serve this country do deserve more from us as a nation, but that doesn't mean that the legal system makes exceptions simply because someone once wore a uniform.
18798	Nope. Ive had the same thought, not that that makes it right or wrong. Same thought I had watching the end montage of Lone Survivor, which does a good job of reminding that Marcus Luttrell isn't the only "hero." I really thought Berg knocked that out of the park.
19072	Exactly. The guy driving a bulldozer under fire in WW2 building an airstrip isn't any less. Less glamorous. Not less faithful nor dutiful.
19318	he's no more a war hero than anybody else who served and excelled at their job. Is that wrong?
19423	some kid who serves 4 years in fort sill in the motor pool is equal to a combat soldier w/ multiple deployments? 
19538	a soldier who completes the highest level of training, executes the highest level of warrior proficiency and saves american lives as his primary job, is the same as a supply chain clerk at fort riley?
19846	it's a legal situation, nothing more. you're a $#@!ing moron because you can't tell the difference. well, that and you won't shut the $#@! up about it. 
20000	there's a wide range of "vets" and you're trying to act like some kid who never saw combat "deserves" something simply because he wore a uniform for a couple of years. he deserves exactly what he got - a conviction on capital murder charges. the thought that he's owed something more after killing two men in cold blood - also vets, by the way - is asinine.
20359	those who serve this country do deserve more from us as a nation, but that doesn't mean that the legal system makes exceptions simply because someone once wore a uniform.
20540	Jt don't get your judgement clouded. Chris had a $#@!ty job to do and he did it extremely well. The guy that killed him was wrong, addled by whatever, and above all it sucks that they were trying to help him post combat. That's completely admirable. And it makes a good story. I think a lot of people just bristle at why a sniper gets any more attention than a regular infantryman who does his job to the best of his ability. That's all. There aren't many movies made about the regular grunt. Those are the ones who number ptsd in the thousands.
21193	some kid who serves 4 years in fort sill in the motor pool is equal to a combat soldier w/ multiple deployments? 
21308	a soldier who completes the highest level of training, executes the highest level of warrior proficiency and saves american lives as his primary job, is the same as a supply chain clerk at fort riley?
21519	That wasn't what I was saying at all. I'm saying in the service everyone has a job, well defined, to do. One persons job is no more meaningful, intrinsically than the other. If the Great American Sniper gets no ammo, what good is he? No food? No water? The dude isn't just out there by himself for years sniping people. He has a $#@!ing spotter for gods sake. If your idea of chivalrous war is to shoot a $#@! from over 1000 yards while he's not suspecting it is cool. Ok. That has to be done sometimes. This guy did it. It's taxing mentally. Other than that, how hard is it?
22162	you're the one painting broad strokes judge. not all who wear the uniform are the same. they don't fill the same roles, and even among those who do, some truly excel and some fail miserably. i'm not talking about kyle specifically, but your assertion that all who serve are heroes is straight $#@!ing bull$#@!. some are heroes, some are cowards and a whole lot fall somewhere in the middle.
23269	I get what you're saying, but I'm pretty sure that particular skill is pretty $#@!ing hard.
23435	Originally Posted by Zathras@B5
23467	Was it really necessary to close ramps and cause massive traffic disruptions for this? Up around Parmer/Braker it was a cluster$#@! as police shunted traffic onto the feeder road before Braker, and blocked onramps.
23683	Negrepbumped
23807	I get what you're saying, but I'm pretty sure that particular skill is pretty $#@!ing hard.
23909	Yeah but is it any harder than trying to say put up a building while under constant rocket and small arms fire? I dunno. I haven't been there. I do think laying this guy next to Sam Houston and those guys is a little much. One made Texas. The other shot insignificant $#@!s that $#@!ed with oil prices. You decide.
24335	I get what you're saying, but I'm pretty sure that particular skill is pretty $#@!ing hard.
24437	I'll give you a head start. That's what my brother used to tell me. Half a mile. You forget I'm here. I could hit you 9 out of 10 times. Back up,another half mile. What is noble about just shooting a bastard that isn't shooting back? That's bravado? No that is marksmanship. Ain't a bit of humanity in it. It's just killing. If that's your job, well, you signed up for it and you banged it.
24949	I'll give you a head start. That's what my brother used to tell me. Half a mile. You forget I'm here. I could hit you 9 out of 10 times. Back up,another half mile. What is noble about just shooting a bastard that isn't shooting back? That's bravado? No that is marksmanship. Ain't a bit of humanity in it. It's just killing. If that's your job, well, you signed up for it and you banged it.
25350	And you died from what you threw, right?
25472	I'm irritated because he got a grave near true texas heroes, who fought on our own soil for freedom. Not against some bull$#@! overseas for money.
25731	I need some Shag attorneys to weigh in with legal definitions.. Despite the 'mental illness' of this guy, the jury decided he understood what murder was and that it was wrong - right? Therefore, regardless of whether he thought the guys at the range with him were purple headed monsters, he still knew it was wrong to kill them (just using that as an example).
26093	Not all mental illness is equal. I assume that a large percentage of mentally ill understand what murder is and that it's against the law.. and that there are consequences.
26267	I did not follow this case closely, I really don't have an opinion. But I've found that there is a lot of logic to our legal system and there is a reason attorney's have a doctorate in the law. I have no idea the legal definitions at play nor the instructions presented to the jury.
26551	I do think it's kinda lazy to look at this case and then make general aspersions against Texas' juries. 
26657	I also think it's dangerous to think that 'state appointed experts' are a better, more infallible approach then 'a jury of your peers'.
26803	We do have a Shag attorney with a NGBROI verdict, which are very rare, to chime in, if he wants to......
27022	I'm irritated because he got a grave near true texas heroes, who fought on our own soil for freedom. Not against some bull$#@! overseas for money.
27179	Who gives a $#@! why he was there. He fought for his brothers.
27354	Yeah but is it any harder than trying to say put up a building while under constant rocket and small arms fire? I dunno. I haven't been there. I do think laying this guy next to Sam Houston and those guys is a little much. One made Texas. The other shot insignificant $#@!s that $#@!ed with oil prices. You decide.
27679	There are also 13 governors, 5 lieutenant governors, 5 state house speakers, 3 senators, 6 congressmen, 4 state first ladies, 5 authors, 9 confederate generals, and 1 baseball player in that cemetery. Are they worthy of being buried there, or should they be exhumed?
27947	And unless Chris Kyle was buried in Huntsville, he's not anywhere near Sam Houston's grave.
28120	The ironic thing is you shoot at what the voices tell you to. One gets credit, one gets life.
28285	Dude, take a deep breath. Pretty sure he didn't have much to do with the location of his burial spot. And you said it yourself, he was just doing his job, he wasn't doing it for overseas money, where the $#@! is that coming from. I was simply countering your assertion that a 1000yd shot, in a war zone, wasn't hard.
28714	There are also 13 governors, 5 lieutenant governors, 5 state house speakers, 3 senators, 6 congressmen, 4 state first ladies, 5 authors, 9 confederate generals, and 1 baseball player in that cemetery. Are they worthy of being buried there, or should they be exhumed?
28982	And unless Chris Kyle was buried in Huntsville, he's not anywhere near Sam Houston's grave.
29084	You didn't read the post about the kids who went to the state cemetery and all they could talk about was the American sniper? Really?
29330	I'm irritated because he got a grave near true texas heroes, who fought on our own soil for freedom. Not against some bull$#@! overseas for money.
29487	There are three Medal of Honor winners in the cemetery. None fought on our own soil for our freedom. One fought in a police action that we didn't even win. That guy certainly doesn't deserve to be honored alongside the real heroes.
29831	You didn't read the post about the kids who went to the state cemetery and all they could talk about was the American sniper? Really?
29975	So are you upset that he's being honored alongside people who fought in the state of Texas or are you upset because people are talking about him too much? I'm having trouble following.
30271	Dude, take a deep breath. Pretty sure he didn't have much to do with the location of his burial spot. And you said it yourself, he was just doing his job, he wasn't doing it for overseas money, where the $#@! is that coming from. I was simply countering your assertion that a 1000yd shot, in a war zone, wasn't hard.
30598	It's hard, it isn't exceptional. I know lots of guys that have killed people from 20k ft and more. Just drop them. Heroes? I guess that's the point. Are you heroine killers? If so I have a long, long line of bad asses. Most of them would kick Chris Kyles ass. Jack Hayes? Big foot Wallace?
31000	So are you upset that he's being honored alongside people who fought in the state of Texas or are you upset because people are talking about him too much? I'm having trouble following.
31195	Im upset because he lost his life as a civilian, has nothing to do with texas freedom or statehood, has a movie and pop culture featured around him in a war that has nothing to do with texas, and gets planted next to people who actually created this state, rather than ones who perpetrated the drug war by sniping afghan citizens.
32242	If it was easy, Kyle wouldn't be in such singular company. And I don't understand why you think celebrating Kyle as a hero prevents you from celebrating anyone else as a hero. You don't have to tear someone down to prop someone else up.
32584	There are three Medal of Honor winners in the cemetery. None fought on our own soil for our freedom. One fought in a police action that we didn't even win. That guy certainly doesn't deserve to be honored alongside the real heroes.
32826	Are you saying a CMOH winner (from Texas) in Korea doesn't deserve to be honored alongside real heroes?
32931	The $#@! is going on in this thread?
33049	I think the difference is one was for texas independence. The other is for some bull$#@!, well bull$#@!. Give me some compelling reason that Chris Kyle was defending or furthering texas freedom or anything related to Texas.
33377	Are you saying a CMOH winner (from Texas) in Korea doesn't deserve to be honored alongside real heroes?
33482	The $#@! is going on in this thread?
33529	I think he was trying to show others that fail to qualify under JRBB's reasoning for wanting to exclude Kyle.
33753	Im upset because he lost his life as a civilian, has nothing to do with texas freedom or statehood, has a movie and pop culture featured around him in a war that has nothing to do with texas, and gets planted next to people who actually created this state, rather than ones who perpetrated the drug war by sniping afghan citizens.
34094	Why does it matter where he died? If your criteria are having something to do with Texas freedom or statehood or creating this state, there would be no more burials?
34261	Exhume Street and DKR because they weren't on the field when they died? Didn't fight at the Alamo?
34400	I think the difference is one was for texas independence. The other is for some bull$#@!, well bull$#@!.
34515	Are you answering my question? I hope not
34671	Why does it matter where he died? If your criteria are having something to do with Texas freedom or statehood or creating this state, there would be no more burials?
34838	Exhume Street and DKR because they weren't on the field when they died? Didn't fight at the Alamo?
34938	Are you answering my question? I hope not
34990	I didn't bring DKR into this you dumb$#@!. If you want to glorify some dry gulching back shooting $#@!head then go right on. Sniper means back shooting $#@!wad. If that's what america wants to go with then more power to ya.
35325	I didn't bring DKR into this you dumb$#@!. If you want to glorify some dry gulching back shooting $#@!head then go right on. Sniper means back shooting $#@!wad. If that's what america wants to go with then more power to ya.
35559	Not sure what is so offensive about Kyle to you, but I think he had more kills with a regular 5.56 than he did "sniping" from a hide.
35804	Not sure what is so offensive about Kyle to you, but I think he had more kills with a regular 5.56 than he did "sniping" from a hide.
35948	Yeah but was that right? Why was he killing those people? In furtherance of our state?
36111	I like the extremes of this thread:
36148	"So what if Routh murdered people? He's a vet and America owes him."
36218	and then:
36229	"Chris Kyle doesn't impress me and never did anything to help Texas. Why is that guy buried in the Texas State Cemetery?"
36352	-----
36359	I think shaggy has a mental illness.
36517	Yeah but was that right? Why was he killing those people? In furtherance of our state?
36614	We're your children and live stock at risk from the afghanis stealing them from 15000 miles away? Certainly.
36839	I like the extremes of this thread:
36876	"So what if Routh murdered people? He's a vet and America owes him."
36946	and then:
36957	"Chris Kyle doesn't impress me and never did anything to help Texas. Why is that guy buried in the Texas State Cemetery?"
37080	-----
37087	I think shaggy has a mental illness.
37134	Wtf does this person have to do with Texas history other than being a killer? Really.
37301	Yeah but was that right? Why was he killing those people? In furtherance of our state?
37388	Right? He was doing his job, following lawful orders, what exactly is wrong about that? And again, I'm trying to understand what your specific beef with Kyle is, because you've been all over the map on this.
37670	Go to bed judge, you're drunk. Really drunk.
