94	The main suspect in the murder of Nemtsov says he confessed under torture
254	I cannot wait for the US government to condemn Russia's use of torture.
399	Meanwhile Ramzan Kadyrov, the man who most probably organized the killing, get decorated with the order of honor from Putin himself :
534	http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/russia-sends-a-very-clear-message/2015/03/11/d02ffdfe-c813-11e4-aa1a-86135599fb0f_story.html
737	That sounds about right
833	Putin murdered Nemtsov.
936	So Dick Cheney is working for the Russian government?
1063	Undercover Mentoring.
1160	Torture is ventriloquism.
1259	There better not be a single US politician making a fuss about this.
1407	What kind of barbaric government tortures people?....is what I would have said pre-Bush era.
1571	It's not like you have to look at Guantanamo. Police departments have been coercing and fabricating false confessions for about as long as there have been Police. When you see "Convicted man exonerated" in the news, how often do you hear about a false confession? Even people who have been proven innocent are often convinced to plead guilty under threats in order to protect the record of the prosecutors.
1979	The only difference here is that it's a high-profile case. The police wouldn't just round up the nearest black guy and say he killed the opposition candidate to cover for the politician's hitman (though they would probably just say it was an accident or a suicide).
2322	But America tortures brown people!
2432	Nah, just the black ones.
2531	No, you're forgetting the sand people.
2644	Joke: Russian KGB officer with his crew looking for a fugitive elephant. Few days later the crew brings up a shackled, battered camel. The officer shouts at his men:-WTF you brought me a camel for?! We are looking for an elephant! One of the crew members pull on the chains of the camel. The camel freaks out and drops on the floor screaming: -I am an elephant, I am an elephant!!...
3101	There's an OLD joke about the KGB/FSB:
3141	FBI, MI5, and the KGB had a contest at who's the best at catching suspects. To make it fair, they decided they would let a rabbit run into a forest and time how long it would take the various teams to catch the rabbit.
3361	The FBI was first. They used high tech equipment and helicopters, and within 12 hours they caught the rabbit.
3472	MI5 was next. They used hunting dogs and expert hunters to get catch the rabbit in 6 hours.
3565	The KGB was last to try. Two fat cops armed with night sticks walked into the forest. Within 15 minutes they emerged dragging a bear. The bear said, "OK, OK, I'm the rabbit, just stop hitting me please".
3980	Bear was obviously guilty of species treason, and should be tried with the rabbit swine it makes it's home with.
4094	That forest doesn't deserve to have it's native Russians tortured by these godless rabbits.
4258	I thought precedent was established at the Nuremburg Trials that confessions under torture are 100% valid?
4443	Back to Stormfront with you.
4544	I dont know what the hell Stormfront is
4657	Stormfront is filled with neo Nazi white supremacists. They commonly try to paint genocidal groups like the Nazis as "good guys" and "misunderstood."
4807	And while in the Nuremberg trials they may have used torture there is still countless pieces of evidence pointing to the crimes of those convicted.
5033	Begone from the earth vile redneck!
5142	No shit.
5226	Let's be clear people, it's not torture, it's enchanced interrogation.
5374	It's only enhanced interrogation when we do it.
5502	"We tortured some folks"
5603	Enchanted interrogation, is that a level 5 spell?
5727	Enchantment shaman. Every time someone said that, I killed a baby rabbit. The only way you can be an enchantment shaman is if your profession is enchanting.
5955	“We cannot confirm that he was tortured as we are not investigators but we did find numerous wounds on his body,” said Babushkin, who was swiftly rapped over the knuckles by investigators for meddling in their probe.
6173	The fuck?
6257	who was swiftly rapped over the knuckles by investigators for meddling in their probe.
6345	I nearly died of laughter reading this part... that shit's funny! :)
6493	It's getting more and more evident that Chechens are heavily involved in this and some high-ranking people from Ramzan Kadyrov's inner circle probably organized the assassination.
6674	According to Novaya Gazeta, the newspaper that published Putin's Crimea annexation plans a couple of weeks ago, the main suspect (Dadaev) is actually a red herring and they forced him to confess. Their sources claim that the man behind the assassination is a major from Ramzan Kadyrov's personal guard named Ruslan (they withheld his last name in accordance with presumption of innocence).
7065	And what's more important is that as it turns out, Nemtsov was under those Chechens' survelliance for several months. This goes against the official version that shows his murder as a response to his position on Charlie Hebdo.
7370	It wouldn't surprise me at all if Kadyrov was behind it, with or without orders from Putin. He's a bloody-handed bastard, and Putin's loyal pet warlord.
7599	The relationship between Putin and Kadyrov is fascinating to me, and I'm really curious to see how the future will pan out for Kadyrov. He's much more than just a loyal pet warlord: he's charismatic, ambitious, savvy, totally ruthless, and oddly relevant... he keeps popping up again and again in places you wouldn't expect, he seems to come in handy quite a lot.
8037	I posted this yesterday and it kind of ties everything together rather succinctly. When you consider the deaths of Putin's major rivals and critics.
8187	Two weeks before his poisoning, Alexander Litvinenko accused Vladimir Putin of ordering the assassination of the Russian journalist Anna Politkovskaya and stated that a former presidential candidate, Irina Hakamada, warned Politkovskaya about threats to her life coming from the Russian president. Litvinenko advised Politkovskaya to escape from Russia immediately. Hakamada denied her involvement in passing any specific threats, and said that she warned Politkovskaya only in general terms more than a year ago.[71] It remains unclear if Litvinenko referred to an earlier statement made by Boris Berezovsky, who claimed that Boris Nemtsov, a former Russian Deputy Prime Minister, received word from Hakamada that Putin threatened her and like-minded colleagues in person. According to Berezovsky, Putin uttered that Hakamada and her colleagues "will take in the head immediately, literally, not figuratively" if they "open the mouth" about the Russian apartment bombings.
9162	All 4 of those people have been murdered for political reasons. That's not a conspiracy theory that's a fact. It's also a fact like you said that Putin has Kadyrov on a short leash and he wouldn't do something this high profile without approval. Now while the apartment bombings connection might not be true what is true is that Putin has utilized Chechens under Kadyrov for a number of high profile killings.
9651	I agree that Putin or high-ranking FSB members killed Litvinenko, but for a different reason.
9746	As for Kadyrov, he only has two responsibilities. To keep separatists/islamists at bay and to make sure that Putin gets 146% of votes in Chechnya. Apart from that, he's free to do whatever he likes. If he was Putin's pet he would've never killed Yamadaev brothers, who were super loyal and valuable to Kremlin. Another example, when Medvedev appointed Alexander Hloponin Plenipotentiary Envoy of the President to the North Caucasian Federal District, Hloponin started raising concerns over huge dotations Chechnya was getting. He called for an investigation into spending these dotations, claiming that most of the money was ending up in Kadyrov' pockets. A week later two suicide bombers blew themselves up in Moscow Metro. And the whole investigation thing simply died down.
10524	And do you honestly think that Berezovsky was murdered? The guy was found hanged in his bathroom with a scarf around his neck.
10652	From Wikipedia:
10669	Berezovsky had fallen into debt after losing a protracted lawsuit against Roman Abramovich, and had spent the final few months of his life selling his possessions to cover his court costs. Berezovsky was also said to have recently been depressed and to have isolated himself from friends. He reportedly suffered from depression and was taking antidepressant drugs; a day prior to his death he told a reporter in London that he had nothing left to live for.
11127	Politkovskaya was digging deep into Kadyrovs' shady dealings in Chechnya. And Ramzan Kadyrov actually unsuccessfully tried to sue her a couple of months before the assassination. All people involved in her assassination were Chechens, what a coincedence.
11383	Nemtsov heavily criticized Kadyrov and went as far as publicly calling him batshit crazy, plus he claimed that he had evidence that Kadyrov's personal guard, the so-called Kadyrovsty, was fighting in Ukraine and he was going to publish it. And the fact that members of Kadyrov's personal guard are involved in his assassination kinda speaks for itself.
11810	Nemtsov heavily criticized Kadyrov and went as far as publicly calling him batshit crazy, plus he claimed that he had evidence that Kadyrov's personal guard, the so-called Kadyrovsty, was fighting in Ukraine and he was going to publish it. And the fact that members of Kadyrov's personal guard are involved in his assassination kinda speaks for itself.
12164	A war started by Putin with Kadyrov's men fighting on behalf of Putin. Or are you trying to state that Chechens just decided to go fuck shit up in Ukraine for no reason? It's very clear that they're are there because Putin wants them there. Putin is very much in control over Kadyrov, the FSB has killed a number of Chechen leaders if they didn't like him he'd be dead.
12535	The Chechens have been doing Russia's dirty work since before the Russian-Chechen war. Putin has obviously co-opted Chechen extremism and put it to work for himself.
12780	Yamadaev brothers assassinations and those metro bombings prove that Kadyrov can act on his own.
12878	are you trying to state that Chechens just decided to go fuck shit up in Ukraine for no reason?
12975	No, of course not. Kadyrov's old enemy, Isa Munaev, was leading the Dudaev Battalion that fought the separatists in Ukraine.
13174	Yeah it's amazing how Kadyrov just happens to do all this stuff that benefits Putin all on his own with no coordination between the two of them. If you believe that I have a real estate on the moon going for a good price.
13475	How did Putin benefit from Yamadaev brothers assassinations and metro bombings? It all happened in 2003 and in 2009-2010, his actual ratings were high and there was no organized opposition movement.
13748	Kadyrov does have some will of his own but to pretend that the Chechen soldiers in Ukraine fighting the Ukrainian forces aren't there with Putin's knowledge and blessing is ridiculous. That all of Putin's rivals just happen to die at the hands of Chechens. Putin runs Kadyrov and uses him for the jobs he doesn't want to get caught doing.
14166	Of course Putin knows they're there, but he has no control over them. He only controls Russian SpecOps and Russian "vacationers" that fight in Donbass, and he approves arms deliveries as well.
14360	All those people killed by Chechens over the last 15 years (namely Politkovskaya and Nemtsov) happened to piss off Kadyrov the most. I don't think that's a coincidence.
14530	And the only case that is 100% FSB job is Litvinenko's death.
14666	I'm not even sure that's figurative. They actually caned him for it.
14814	We don't believe you, you need more people.
14931	sarcasm - noun The use of irony to mock or convey contempt.
15065	And torture has been shown to produce unreliable information, false confessions so....
15224	Shocked ? It's Russia...
15322	They torture people as well ?..i am shocked !!
15442	Oh my god i'm so completely shocked.
15555	Nah. Putin would never confess. I doubt he was tortured.
15842	Yeah you'd have be absolutely out of your mind to think all of Putin's critics dropping like flies over the years is just a coincidence.
16064	And you'd be an idiot to think I said anything about any assassination besides this one.
16229	Whether you mentioned them or not, they're relevant.
