94	President Obama and President Castro of Cuba spoke by phone in the first known conversation between leaders of the two countries in over 50 years.
324	"Sup."
332	"Not much. Chillin."
427	Whasaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaap
517	Que pasaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
612	YO!
699	Quiero taco bell
790	Klok papi.
883	Dimeaver manin
969	 'bla kro mnol
1061	DIMELO TIGUERE
1159	Manzana
1245	Eyy, hombre, hit me up with some of those cigars
1364	It's funny because I don't think Obama would actually talk like that
1510	I know right? A lot of people forget that he is from the middle east (Hussein).
1674	He's not from the middle east. Hussein is an Islamic name, from his Indonesian Dad. Err, wait, secret muslim manchurian candidate. That's it. Totally.
1896	Two dictators.
1996	He's from America, actually.
2099	Pretty sure they are making a joke.
2220	Well. Whoosh for me.
2320	Middle name! Middle east! It's all coming together now!
2456	My god this is the start this is what JRRT meant. Middle earth is happening.
2604	Thanks, Obama.
2696	Jet Fuel Can Melt Steel Feels! Cheney and Biden are reverse vampires!
2848	Except he's not. He's from Hawaii
2963	"Uuuuuh...I think, that. Some of those cigars...would be good!
3026	...
3030	So could you uuuuh...send some over"
3140	Wagwan Jamaica.
3227	Did you see the video from Obama's trip to Kingston? He started the speech in patois -- "Whaa gwan Jamaica". It was surreal.
3430	I was reading in cigar aficionado that the quality of the cigars isn't what it once was. Partly due to the older generation not passing the skills down as there was no (foreseeable) future in their sales
3716	A lot of them also moved to other Central American countries after the embargo.
3873	I hear Nicaraguans are supposed to be the new best.
4003	This is the better answer - the reason Cubans were the best was that other markets were nascent or not that great.
4119	Fortunately non-Cuban cigars are now excellent and much cheaper. I still love Cubans but if you want to have great cigars you still have plenty of great options from $5 to $50 without having to go Cuban.
4400	Dat Priva Ligada T-9
4496	Alot moved to the DR with seeds right when Castro took power. It was the closest to Cuban soil and sunlight. Thus why you have cigar companies with the same names as the Cuban equivalent.
4754	Wine is priced often proportionately to how well it's rated by "distinguished" judged, but when the judged are blinded cheap and pricy stuff aren't distinguishable. Is there any "blind" study on cigar judges, as far as you know..??
5068	And the whole Communism thing. Doesn't tend to keep quality control high.
5220	Whatcha doin?
5235	Nothin just presidential stuff.
5344	Same here. How's Michelle?
5441	She's good, just munchin' on some carrots.
5561	Cool story bro.
5578	Dude, did you see Putin's suit last week at the meeting? That guy has no style. Whoever chose that tie for him deserves the gulag.
5788	I liked it when your American Show about the card house made fun of him!
5938	Ikr? The only difference is that Michelle would leave him in the floor crying for mommy and a bottle of vodka.
6128	Tired. How's Beyonce?
6220	Did Michelle make it home safely this morning?
6343	Chillin, killing.
6438	True, true.
6703	Ah, yes. I know what you mean. I got some robots for that now.
6845	"When is Pac coming home?"
6950	TUPAC ALIVE #1 NUMBER KNE IN CUBA
6985	REMOVE PAELLA from the premises you will get caught. You are worst spaniard
7135	So that's why we were trying to get Elian Gonzalez, leverage.
7276	"How far you think the Bulls go this year?"
