94	15 dead in attack at Kenyan University
752	They went around asking who was Christian and who was Muslim and shot the Christians. It is believed to be Al Shabab. 800 students were believed to have been inside 280 accounted for. I wonder what will be the reaction of the Kenyan government to this. There has been harassment and deportation of Somalis in Kenya and this could well be stepped up.
1175	Rip.
1255	These Wahabi salafists really hate Christians.
1303	Meanwhile America is helping Saudi Arabia, the home of Wahabi-ism, to bomb the houthis of Yemen.
1474	A murderous attack carried about by Jihadi's.
1521	The Free Syrian Army will be happy with their ''brothers'' work.
1690	Rip.
1705	Is that weasel acronym the best you can do in the face of yet another outrage carried out in the name of a certain rancid religion/political ideology ?
1972	Is that weasel acronym the best you can do in the face of yet another outrage carried out in the name of a certain rancid religion/political ideology ?
2134	carpet bomb kenya? what do you want done?
2286	These Wahabi salafists really hate Christians.
2334	Meanwhile America is helping Saudi Arabia, the home of Wahabi-ism, to bomb the houthis of Yemen.
2431	A murderous attack carried about by Jihadi's.
2478	The Free Syrian Army will be happy with their ''brothers'' work.
2553	Neither Saudi Arabia or the Free Syrian Army is linked with Al Shabab.
2739	carpet bomb kenya? what do you want done?
2791	I wouldn't dignify that excretion with an answer.
2910	The "religion of peace" strikes again. And no surprise to see the lunatic Parry on here blaming Murica for this. What that gobshyte fails to remember is that the US is bombing Al-Kebab in Somalia. What the fukk is his own country Russia doing to stop Islamic barbarians?" Sweet FA that's what!
3314	Neither Saudi Arabia or the Free Syrian Army is linked with Al Shabab.
3395	The ''Free Syrian Army'' is nothing more than an umbrella term for a bunch of jihadist factions.
3493	Islamist terrorists, just like Al Shabab.
