94	Obama and Castro shake hands as U.S. and Cuba seek better ties.
243	I'm still confused as to why so many people see this as a bad thing. What's the drama with building up good relations with a neighbouring country? Yes, they were former enemies, but it doesn't mean that has to continue into perpetuity. Look at the relationship the US has with Germany and Japan.
612	I have heard that it has to do with Cuban-Americans that are opposed to the Cuban government. I don't know how true this is, but the idea goes something like this:
777	There are many Cuban-Americans who escaped Cuba and who hate its government. These Cuban-Americans hate the Cuban government so much that they oppose any motion to better relations between the US and Cuba, because they feel that the Cuban government needs to be kept down and punished and that lifting embargoes and such is basically equivalent to letting them (the Cuban government) win. They basically hate the Cuban government so much they feel that anything the US can do to hurt it is justified and worth it even if it ends up hurting ordinary Cubans living on the island. The idea being that the only way to end what they feel is an oppressive regime, is to continue hurting it economically until it falls and Cubans on the island are free from it.
1533	It is apparently for this reason that US politicians rarely touch up on the issue. Because if they say that they will better relations with Cuba because it's about time we do, they could suddenly lose the support (and votes) of many Cuban-Americans. So for a lot of them, it's not worth amending relations if it's going to cost them votes.
1874	This is the popular idea/theory/whatever that gets passed around Reddit whenever someone asks your question. It makes some sense to me, but I am not the most knowledgeable when it comes to this issue so I'd rather not treat it as my own opinion.
2121	EDIT: Spelling and such.
2229	Well, Obama has no more elections to win, so he gives zero fucks about pandering to old and bitter geriatric Cubans, mostly in south Florida.
2445	old and bitter geriatric Cubans
2478	Well, if Cuba is currently doing bogus shit still(not that I know if they are or not), then whether or not they are old and geriatric doesn't matter.
2629	Edited for clarity.
2725	There is a huge generational divide in thinking on this. If you're over 60, were born in Cuba and had to flee chances are you hate the Cuban government no matter what happeneds; Not until the Castro brothers die and the nation is capitalist and untied to this 50 year temporary revolution. If you are young and didn't flee, didn't live through the Cuban missile crisis then chances are you don't really care, even though your parents have told you since birth that they are evil bastards who stole a homeland, young people are interested in visiting the island their parents obviously hate and love so much.
3406	Bingo.
3485	happeneds
3496	I think you invented a new verb tense. "Whatever happends" could mean, "whatever has, will or could happen."
3681	Funny, obviously it was just a typo, but strangely it works better than what I'd meant to write.
3850	a word in a quantum juxtaposition! I never thoughtds that I would live to see one!!
4007	The bogus shit they do, is it any different than many of our other allies? I've not been informed to believe so.
4121	So it seems like this is more of a lingering pile of shit that needs to be wiped away and diplomatic efforts restored.
4241	Why not embargo China if we embargo Cuba? Trade, really. So why allow this to become a feigned moral dilemma?
4420	The main bogus shit that they got pissed off about was taking land and property from land/property owners, to use for the public good, which you sort of can only do once...
4594	The geriatric/influential members of the Cuban-American community mostly are those former Cuban property owners.
4708	They also have descendants involved in politics, and there are also newer Cuban migrants, but those migrants tend to have moved with less resentment: They got their free educations and wanted to earn more 50x the income with it. If the newer imports got seriously sick, by-and-large they would move back for the healthcare immediately.
5045	If you can live the best of both worlds, a free education and free catastrophic healthcare coverage, while earning a much much larger income with no real risk of deportation due to the political situation, why wouldn't you?
5346	They are.
5436	It's not just "bitter geriatric Cubans" that are opposed to the Castros. They make up the largest piece of the opposition, but there are plenty of younger Cubans and Cuban Americans that still hold a grudge against the Castro regime.
5671	Look at Marco Rubio and Ted Cruz. They're both Cuban American Presidential candidates under the age of 50 that vehemently oppose the Castro government. Yes, it's true that they're partially pandering to their bases (Cruz with "anti-commie" old timers, Rubio with Cuban expatriates in Florida), but part of their animosity is certainly genuine given their familial backgrounds.
6049	Some young Cubans are willing to let bygones be bygones. But others still want to get rid of the Castros and their system of government, and many of those people are in positions of significant power. This impending deal could very well crumble if guys like Rubio and Cruz aren't placated to some extent.
6428	Both Rubio and Cruz have Cuban roots and are influenced by those same bitter geriatrics - they were raised by them.
6545	Some hatreds are passed from generation to generation - doesn't make it rational or appropriate.
6723	I'm not Cuban, fuck the castro regime.
6839	You don't think disapproving of the Cuban government is rational?b
6987	There's a large difference between disapproving of the Cuban government and not wanting to normalize relations. You're sensationalizing the issue.
7135	I disapprove of the Iranian government, but I'm still glad an agreement with them is being reached and sanctions will be lifted.
7338	Well, considering Castro is a mass murdering piece of shit, I'm going to go ahead and say that these people have justified hatred of the Cuban government.
7574	Yet every other nation in the world has normal relations with that government that's run by a mass-murdering piece of shit, and we have normal relations with a dozen other countries that are run by similar (or worse) men. You're also sensationalizing the issue. People can hate Fidel Castro all they want and they're perfectly justified for it, that's beside the point.
8018	How is it sensationalizing it when someone is a mass murderer and people don't like him for it?
8195	Rubio and Cruz don't give a flying fuck about the Cuban government. They care about pandering to their base.
8383	What's kind of curious is Rubio's family actually came to the US before the revolution in Cuba, and he spent a lot of his formative years in Nevada and elsewhere.
8627	Honestly the Castro remind has made life harder on themselves and they deserve no appeasement. I have family there one uncle who was in prison for 4 years for taking 2 steaks from his job on Christmas. Other family members who are surgeons and can't even afford a car. I support opening embassies and working towards a better future but approving of the Castros and painting them as good guys is misleading and lets them instill their hand picked future cronies To run the regime.
9182	Other family members who are surgeons and can't even afford a car.
9250	That's happened because the USA places sanctions on everyone willing to sell cars (or anything else except food and medicine, since 1962) to Cuba, and consequently all the cars there are at least 50 years old - still-working cars have become extremely scarce, and extremely expensive as a result. They're literally using horse-pulled buses there.
9598	Say what you like about Cuba, but the reason why people can't afford things is that decades after the war has "ended", the USA is still doing everything it can to cripple Cuba, both economically (by not letting anyone sell them stuff) and politically (with various covert operations). There are still US anti-Cuba operations as of 2012, and yet people are surprised that the Cuban government are afraid of dissent - well of course they are, the CIA is quite happy to encourage and manipulate it for the purposes of screwing with Cuba rather than forcing the government to fix its inadequacies (which is what we actually want dissent for).
10313	I thought that Ted Cruz was a Canadian...
10426	His mother was American and father was Cuban.
10548	Being born in Canada makes you a Canadian. Like how being born in Mexico makes you a mexican.
10712	Yes but he was born to an American which also makes him American. And just in case he gave up his theoretical Canadian Citizenship.
10920	Being born in Canada isn't a theoretical citizenship. It's a real thing.
11063	Yes I understand that but Cruz never thought about it and I think he was suprised to find out about it.
11243	He never saw his long form birth certificate?
11360	Marco Rubio and Ted Cruz...LOL.. tip of the iceberg of the 'McCarthy era socialist witch hunt' ideology that is against any pragmatic progressive principles.
11589	Funny, I literally just met 4 Cubans who are ages 21-26 who all fled Cuba's extreme and opressive government. You clowns will justify anything a democrat does.
11830	yes but he needs congress to lift the sanctions, so politics is still important.
11986	old and bitter geriatric Cubans, mostly in south Florida.
12045	that's so unbelievably condescending lol
12168	Tell us how you dealt with having tour relatives thrown in jail and your land and assets confiscated by the guy currently running Cuba. You seem to be so level headed.
12404	That's a reason to punish average citizens of Cuba? Have you ever gave a thought to the idea that if they weren't so heavily embargoed and were allowed to enter the global economy that maybe their government wouldn't need to rule with an iron fist to keep the populace from revolting?
12690	Isn't the goal here to make Cuba a better place, a more free place where the population isn't ruled with an iron fist? You're not going to do that by punishing their government officials. They're not the ones who suffer anyways. They live like kings through sanctions and embargoes while the average citizen wallows away in squalor.
13105	They trade with the whole world except for the US. They can buy all the Chinese crap they want, just like we do. The difference is their economic system is a pathetic communist joke, and the people aren't even allowed to open their own businesses in any meaningful way. Most money goes straight into the pockets of the rulers.
13504	Also most of those Cuban-Americans and Cubans who escaped Cuba had their assets, properties, and land took by force by the Cuban government. I'm not Cuban but I would understand the hatred that everything you have is owned by the government.
13815	The other side of that coin is that the Batista was a corrupt thug who was in bed with the Mafia.
13914	No doubt the Cuban revolution, like all revolutions, had too many victims. And I suspect that the world will be a better place when the Castro brothers are gone. But anyone with close ties to Batista who ended up in Miami deserves very little sympathy.
14241	So anyone that had their property seized was in bed with batista and that makes it ok?
14405	He said it in a way that if they were to close to Batista AND had their stuff taken.
14491	Not that confiscated property = close to Batista
14609	No. But more than a few were. And to be seriously wealthy in Havana in the late 1950s meant that you had to have certain...understandings, if not outright connections to the mob.
14789	No doubt there were innocent victims, as I made clear in my initial post. But let us be honest here. The revolution in Cuba happened for good reason, even if the end results were unfortunate. Batista and his supporters were not people that history is going to show any great sympathy for. And they are only players now because of Florida politics and the Electoral College.
15235	Well the Cuban people certainly thought so, with something like 90% approving of executions for Batista's thugs. I've never lived under a brutal dictatorship, so I'll leave the moral decisionmaking to those who actually did it.
15544	Cubans are still living under a brutal dictatorship.
15669	Source? Dictatorship maybe, but brutal? I haven't seen a shred of evidence to classify Cuba as brutal in comparison to the rest of the world.
15892	Yea, arresting people and keeping them in jail for disagreeing with the government is really nice.
16063	Trying to find a source for this. Seeing protesters arrested. Not what I'd call brutal. Protesters are arrested especially in the US and I wouldn't call it brutal.
16308	Yes you are right. Cuba is a communist paradise.
16433	Not anything close to brutal when you consider the dictatorships that the US supported in Central and South America (hell, the dictatorships that the same group of Cuban Americans supported)
16625	Most Cuban Americans who oppose Castro do not do so because they oppose dictatorship, they're just upset that its not their dictatorship.
