94	Anonymous released 9,200 ISIS supporter Twitter account names to apply pressure on Twitter for suspending them
286	Couldn't they just make another account?
403	we wanna hear what they have to say. they will always communicate. we can't stop that. so let them do it where all can see. i'm a fan of anonymous. but i wonder if they've thought this through enough.
675	Aim for the stars little guys.
781	Anonymous rules :) isis naaah --_--
892	I feel much safer with anonymous now so fuck Isis big time :)
1024	Twitter suspended my account that I barely used and I don't even know why. Maybe if I was a blood thirsty terrorist they would let me have one. 👹
1254	Lol at people that still think Anonymous is a group. Rather than literally fucking anybody. From an activist to an organised intellegence agency. Anybody can fall under the Anon banner if they please.
1525	Anonymous before top response - "Yeah, take that one, ISIS!"
1587	Top response - "this could be a bad move because government uses these accounts to track ISIS"
1683	Anonymous after top response - "Oh.... Well uhhh.... We are Anonymous. We are Legion. We do not forgive. We do not forget. Expect us."
1896	About fucking time.
1992	Anonymous wants internet freedoms so that they, a notorious organisation which is often associated with terrorism, can continue to enjoy freedoms, and what do they do?
2161	Publish the details of members that support a notorious organisation which is often associated with terrorism.
2273	It wasn't so long ago that Anonymous had members being targeted by intelligence agencies and were spitting fire about members being exposed on the grounds that they were a notorious organisation which is often associated with terrorism.
2511	I guess when the shoe is on the other foot, it is more comfortable for them.
2666	did you just compare Anon to ISIS?
2851	Anonymous thinks small. They think the government isn't equipped to shut down some user accounts? They keep them up because then they know exactly what they are saying, what moves they are making, and who they are contacting. Why would they pay for information that it's almost guaranteed they have? The military invented tor, the NSA is more advanced than you can imagine. Seeing and tracking your targets is the smart way to do things, if they disappear from online, the govt. is fucked. Just like when the Taliban broke off and started communicating on paper again.
3497	What happened to freedom of speech... this is not anonymous its just a stooge...
3654	do people really use their real names and details when they register???
3803	And 90% of them turn out to be FBI accounts
3927	I'm sure the CIA would take unkindly to suspending so many on their payroll.
4075	I've got a good idea for a game using this data set. A space invaders like game but each block you have to destroy would be a little tweety bird linked to a different one of these twitter names and every time they get destroyed a bot would tweet the "you've been killed or something to the twitter handle. could be a fun way of spamming them while keeping other people amused.
4532	Since when is Anonymous getting involved in wars? This is dumb.
4670	What does releasing account names achieve? I'd assumed Anonymous had tracked them down and got their real names and addresses. But no. Seems like entry level "hacking" to me.
4919	Um, I support ISIS.
5014	Edgy.
5097	Suisisidal.
5184	Anon is the CIA.
5277	Here's the thing. If they're just sympathizers and not actual members of ISIS then I think they have the right to freely express their support under free speech. It's terrible and absolutely disgusting to support those monsters, but at the same time it's speech.
5541	Now, paying money or participating in their operations is something else.
5689	It might be more helpful to farm images ISIS posts for GPS coordinates.
5838	Was Kanye West one of them? He's been terrorizing award shows for a while now.
5987	Twitter hasn't done anything because the US Gov doesn't want them to, regardless of Twitter's preferences. For the same reason governments manipulate foreign politics to place known individuals in charge: it's better to have a known and understood evil in place than an unknown or misunderstood one.
6372	Seems kind of moot, when it only takes 30 seconds to set up a new Twitter account.
6534	All of this blocking of ISIS/ISIL data is hurting, not helping, the intelligence agencies fighting against them. It reduces the electronic trails to the sources to get to the root of the problem It's like how OBL stopped using cellphones, it made it much tougher to find him. I agree that it's repellent that they're using social media to recruit but consider how turning off the information spigot will impact the intelligence community.
7046	Congrats dipshits, you just destroyed 9,200 sources of information for the FBI.
7206	Yes, because I'm sure that "CoolISISlolcat777" was going to be a great source of information on terrorist activities.
7397	maybe not one, but 9,200 is a biiig number.
7517	Would they even care about a twitter account...
7640	Yeah! Got em! Now they have to make new twitter accounts!
7768	I don't see how this will have any effect whatsoever.
7900	Am I the only one going "FUCK YEAH ANONYMOUS!!!" ?
8024	yeah, because now that 9,200 inside sources on ISIS for the FBI and the CIA (who can actually do something with the information) now destroyed thanks to some neckbeard vigilantism
8282	"Inside sources" implies that these Twitter accounts were actually working for the feds. As a social scientist I can tell you that research on social media is embarrasingly far behind the developments in the field, and I find it very hard to believe that FBI or CIA have come up with some CSI tech to track, trace and triangulate anyone based on Twitter handles.
8646	I think these hackers are doing what most of the planet would like to do. Smack ISIS in the face and say 'fuck you'.
8836	ok then expert
8924	inb4: Anonymous = NSA.
9020	Guys guys... we cannot go on with the fighting because our twitter accounts were hacked..............................
9212	Anonymous no longer exists. Everyone associated with lulzsec was busted. There is simply no way that the government isn't using 'Anonymous' for their own agenda.
9375	The final boss of the internet is the NSA. There is no anonymity.
9512	Why are we defending get ISIS? Too many people want their heads cut off
9660	Twitter is most likely under pressure by several government agencies not to suspend them. The more these people talk the more information they devulge. It is a statistical situation that has to balance out the threat of isis recruiting against the prospect of gaining actionable intelligence with no effort expended.
9978	I tried to make this comment sound as thought out and well spoken as possible as I am currently taking a shit.
10166	Isn't that called self-compromise?
10278	“If the United States is struggling to counter the Islamic State’s dispersed, rapidly regenerative online presence, why not turn to groups native to this digital habitat?"
10451	I'm not sure most readers are prepared for the actual answer to this question.
10611	Anyone have a Death Note?
10714	Interesting. Glad to hear the groups are collaborating.
10771	Question, though. I watched a documentary saying that Anonymous as a collective group was disbanded years ago. Was that just the original members?
11001	Wow they outed their handles, that outta throw a wrench in their spokes. The war's over guys, the terrorists twitters have been found out.
11223	Let me start this by saying I find ISIL abhorrent. But should Twitter be making determinations on who may use it as a medium. In this decade, both the internet and derivatively social media, have become public goods. I.E. The reason netizens are so pro-net neutrality is the because of the philosophy that the connections created between individuals online should only be regulated in the same way we would regulate interactions between individuals in a public square. The question I ask is, given such a framework ought public forums (such as twitter as well as reddit) be in the business of determining who may use their channel for what speech?
