94	Dear Hillary Clinton Supporters To-The-Core DUers.
222	This discussion thread was locked asoff-topicby Sissyk (a host of the General Discussion forum).
320	As Hillary Clinton is expecting to announce after tommorow I certainly understand your excitement.
419	Nontheless although I know how hard you wilk work for her and to avoid a Reich Winger enter Oval Office after Barack Obama I woulf like to ask to you..
572	Please accept DU comlunity members dont share your wiews and your wish to see her elected. Accept critics and advises. Accept the fact that not all Dems are expecting her as the Only One Viable. Every primary candidates has his/her streghths and weaknesses
830	Please act a little bit less harsh to those who diss Clinton now-overhelming lead.
913	Convention is way months ahead.
945	The battle of the primary has to bre real and equal for the sake of good and fair political process.
1125	1. Let the battle royal commence.
1160	Gentlemen and Lady, on your mark!
1194	Get set!
1203	Go!
1277	4. Did you mean, "Let the hyperbole commence"?
1403	20. I decided to use an obvious and intentional exageration after reading the OP.
1555	42. Well done.  I'm here in my undisclosed location hiding out from the evil HRC supporters.
1721	2. Some of the kindest posters here support Clinton.
1775	They have received nothing but ire, like this post.
1828	Go to the Clinton group. The names I see there are some of DUs best posters. There is one I even envy due to their patience and kindness. I don't understand how they do it.
2002	So I really don't know where this is coming from.
2120	5. you think this op is "ire"?  strikes me as a respectful post
2185	and who and who isn't "du's best posters" is entirely subjective.
2325	16. Cali, you flat out know this wasn't posted in honest. nt.
2455	26. what the heck are you talking about?  How is it not honest?
2594	31. History.
2608	When this poster makes claims against Clinton that are so laughable that they delete their own posts, it is clear. If Clinton takes populist stances during the campaign are you going to jump up and down and say yes? No, you aren't. Neither will I. Why? History. Yet op with a history like this get a free pass.
2988	38. I am not familiar with his/her posts.
3110	27. It occurs to me that a post written using a teabagger/right wing dictionary may have bee intended as
3216	an attempt at a subtle attack.
3248	But I let it pass.
3341	6. Really?  This post counts as 'ire'?
3454	9. They see what suits their agenda.
3565	14. "only one viable"
3588	You use coded language pretending to be informative.
3642	The whole post comes off as condescending.
3686	Hillary supporters have been getting "criticism" for years, what happens between now and when she announces changes nothing for them.
3894	33. I agree with this...
3920	and I'm not even a big fan of Hillary.
3960	The non stop hammering of her supporters is crazy. As if the people they support (with one exception Bernie) don't have a few bones in their closet. Who needs the pukes we beat each other up better than they ever could.
4181	We can have policy discussions without all the name calling--or wait--apparently we can't.
4273	Again...not a big fan of Hillary.
4381	36. As far as Im cincerned..
4411	My OPs xritics Clinton Supremacy.
4445	I am not in anyway "hammering"
4476	supporters
4487	Or if so... well please accept my apology.
4531	When I say she is too much frienfly towards Kussinger , for instance.... I doesnt mean I label Clinton supporters as Kissinger lovers or somewhat.
4752	35. Sorry, have to disagree.....
4786	if you're too gentle, then you're 'condescending'? So poster should have been more confrontational?
4959	3. I second that!
5049	7. Dear mylye222,
5068	Could I ask the same of you?
5098	Could we have fewer posts about other DUers and more about policy differences?
5178	Yours,
5185	Nancy
5265	17. +1
5343	18. +1
5351	At a minimum.
5434	22. This
5515	23. Agreed
5600	25. +1
5608	Just a tad obsessive, IMO...
5711	8. Be wary.
5724	The purge will come. No reasoned thinking or less than glowing approvals will be allowed. Yield to the machine or be gone.
5921	10. Exact.
5933	And I have been told it was the same tactics in 2008.
6061	11. When people spread obnoxious lies about Hillary, they will be called out, harshly.
6149	Sorry, no kid gloves from me.
6252	12. Extra butter on mine, please.
6361	13. Playing innocent is fun isn't it? lol nt.
6481	15. And what am I guilty of please???
6520	OH yes. Not following the majority....
6634	19. That's it. nt.
6727	28. Oh really?
6743	So wishing someone lefftyer, less WS friendly candidate ( my dream would be Sanders) is making me "guilty"?
6851	Guilty of not aknowledging to what seems to me more like a motoriety based candidacy than a one when candidate needs to convince?
7052	37. How's politics in France these days?You say you are a "Dem" which means registered to vote in the US
7158	....more or less, but as you are, if I recall correctly, a French national, that is not precisely possible.
7267	We welcome most opinions here, from all countries. As you well should know. It makes the conversation not only more interesting but more informative.
7418	However, when a person has only one tune to play (Hillary is all things bad), slips into RW terms (Queen Hillary), and offers no actual policies or other candidates to talk about ....
7603	So I ask again, as I have before this, how's things where you are aside from the Le Pens? I understand there's a growing tide of anti-Semitism in France just now, for starters.
7854	43. Politics in France now are shittt
7893	I am a progressive supporting the lest wing of Socialist party ( social democrats)
7976	I voted for Hollande but whished a more prigressive. Now our govt is continuing austerity crap. Sarkozy us a corrupted crook. And Le Pens are frightening.
8202	44. Uh huh
8289	21. This is how you followup your "Hillary Supporters control DU" and Clintons control the Party OPs ???
8395	http://www.democraticunderground.com/?com=view_post&amp;forum=1002&amp;pid=6480369
8479	http://www.democraticunderground.com/10026468809
8528	----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
8630	How about some more truth in advertising? I could have respected you a lot more if you had written:
8739	"Well, I've already got some of my bombthrowing in against Hillary and her supporters and I will probably throw some more, but please don't throw any back and treat me with kid gloves."
8935	At least that would have been accurate.
9047	24. Dear anti-Clinton crowd,
9077	Hillary will now be officially running for president. It might upset some of you, but then that's life. She has the right to run just as much as any other registered Democrat who wishes to enter the race.
9283	If anything, the poor sportsmanship has been exhibited by the rabid anti-Hillary posts that I have read here ever since before Obama even became president, some of them using RW talking points. That's why many Hillary supporters have left this site for friendlier pastures.
9558	Therefore, personally, I don't give a flying fig about anyone's opinion about Hillary on this site. Vote for her, don't vote for her, your choice. I will certainly not waste my time trying to convince folks who would rather sit on their hands than cast a vote for her. I will be far too busy volunteering for her campaign.
9882	I do know one thing though, I will be damned if I don't vote for the Democratic candidate in 2016, be it Hillary or someone else. The stakes are far too high. The rest of you can do whatever you want.
10152	30. She absolutely has the right to run.  Has any DUer suggested otherwise?
10300	34. Plenty here act as if she were the anti-Christ, it got tiresome a long time ago.
10386	No one is forcing anyone to support her during the primaries, but a pox on those who have repeatedly said that they will refuse to vote for her if she's the party's nominee. I would vote for any Democrat over the pile of manure who will be the Republican nominee.
10724	41. + 100
10809	29. Yeah!  Be nice to those who diss Clinton!...
10859	Sid
10938	32. When the mud starts flying...
10973	I will probably disappear again. The primaries fights get very ugly around here.
11129	39. No mud here.. just lovely...
11237	40. Ofercrissake... grow up.
11337	45. Locking.
11351	Please the SOP of General Discussion, and the pinned thread. Thank You!
11424	Discuss politics, issues, and current events. Posts about Israel/Palestine, religion, guns, showbiz, or sports are restricted in this forum. Conspiracy theories anddisruptive meta-discussion are forbidden. For more information, click here.
11738	46. Written with absolutely no sense of irony
11785	In other words, leave the insults and berating to the anti-Hillary crowd.
