94	Anti-Defamation League Urges Benjamin Netanyahu To Cancel Congress Speech
250	http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/0...n_6636420.html
379	Do you really think the PM cares? He's got an audience and a platform.
526	I thought he would have cancelled it by now and told Beanhead to suck eggs!
603	I still expect him to cancel the speech.
719	Ego! mHe's got the curtain and the stage. He's happy. If I thought bonehead had a brain...Oh well, never mind!,
905	Most will view this through their already politically tainted eyes. Here, the GOP will think it's the best thing Boehner has ever done. Obama supporters view it as a snub. I have no idea how it actually plays among the voters in Israel.
1143	From that standpoint, can he afford to cancel? Can he afford not to cancel?
1220	I do remember not long ago the people here leaning right telling us the "office" of president deserves a certain amount of respect, but they changed that opinion when Obama got elected.
1479	A senior Israeli official suggested on Friday that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had been misled into thinking an invitation to address the U.S. Congress on Iran next month was fully supported by the Democrats. [...] 
1702	"It appears that the speaker of Congress made a move, in which we trusted, but which it ultimately became clear was a one sided move and not a move by both sides," Deputy Israeli Foreign Minister Tzachi Hanegbi told 102 FM Tel Aviv Radio on Friday.
2025	if the dems boycott his speech, as well they should; i do wonder if any republicans will do so as well. . .
2133	what is AIPAC's position?
2267	A senior Israeli official suggested on Friday that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had been misled into thinking an invitation to address the U.S. Congress on Iran next month was fully supported by the Democrats. [...] 
2490	"It appears that the speaker of Congress made a move, in which we trusted, but which it ultimately became clear was a one sided move and not a move by both sides," Deputy Israeli Foreign Minister Tzachi Hanegbi told 102 FM Tel Aviv Radio on Friday.
2749	Well, they have finally figured out that Bonehead is an idiot. Too bad the reps haven't.
2913	Shouldn't all threads like this be titled as leading questions? 
2979	(Yes, I'm just screwing around).
3122	Most will view this through their already politically tainted eyes. Here, the GOP will think it's the best thing Boehner has ever done. Obama supporters view it as a snub. I have no idea how it actually plays among the voters in Israel.
3360	From that standpoint, can he afford to cancel? Can he afford not to cancel?
3437	I do remember not long ago the people here leaning right telling us the "office" of president deserves a certain amount of respect, but they changed that opinion when Obama got elected.
3633	I agree. 
3644	I suspect that the people of Israel would have a mixed reaction since they are drawn from a spectrum of opinions. The place where Israelis are wholy unified is in their belief that they face an existential threat, especially from Iran. No matter how liberal Israelis are, they will almost always agree on that. 
3957	It remains to be seen how they will view all this, but one thing is sure: they are far more tuned in to our politics than we are to theirs. Israel is historically always governed by a coalition. This era is no different.
4251	Saw a brief of an article that mused whether a Democratic boycott of his speech would push Jewish votes to the Republicans.
4376	I call that wishful thinking.
4481	one wonders, which vote is boehner courting - the jewish vote, or that of the fundamentalist christian zionist?
4669	He's trying to be the "man" and to tell the Repubs he's in charge.
4849	A senior Israeli official suggested on Friday that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had been misled into thinking an invitation to address the U.S. Congress on Iran next month was fully supported by the Democrats. [...] 
5072	"It appears that the speaker of Congress made a move, in which we trusted, but which it ultimately became clear was a one sided move and not a move by both sides," Deputy Israeli Foreign Minister Tzachi Hanegbi told 102 FM Tel Aviv Radio on Friday.
5493	if the dems boycott his speech, as well they should; i do wonder if any republicans will do so as well. . .
5601	what is AIPAC's position?
5637	I would think Tea Partiers would stay away. They're isolationists and they despise Boehner - not as much as Obama, whom they hate, but why not sneak in a jab when you can?
5916	one wonders, which vote is boehner courting - the jewish vote, or that of the fundamentalist christian zionist?
6038	I believe you ask this rhetorically but it is a very good question especially inasmuch as Boehner is a pragmatic, compromising establishmentarian who is not a hardline conservative and does not personally need to court either type of voter. There is no question that Boehner's move has put the Democrats in a difficult position, which I think it the real reason for the invite, that is, to make trouble for Democrats rather than so much base shoring or vote courting by Republicans. After all, it isn't like the Christian Zionists are in play any more than the "Jewish vote" is.
6618	Also, Lew makes an important point about coalition government in Israel, to which I would simply add that whether Netanyahu is Prime Minister (or not) is unlikely to mark any substantive change in Israeli policy on the Palestinian question (as history has already shown us). There may be a tweak or two, a softening of rhetoric, perhaps some minor policy changes, but in the end, Israeli policy will likely remain unchanged in substance irrespective of who holds the Prime Ministership.
7106	The Democrats can win this one, I think, by sitting it out en masse. If they can show spine and agree to do this and convey that agreement backchannel to the Israeli government, Netanyahu will be forced to cancel the engagement rather than suffering the rebuke and showing the leader of the Israeli government to be the divisive force that he actually is. The alternative is to show up and politely clap and do the dog and pony, which is precisely what Boehner is counting on. 
7585	Boehner has in fact presented an opportunity for Democrats, if only they would call his bluff. Such a rebuke would provide cover for much more strident criticism of Israeli policy here in the US.
7857	He's catering to HIS own party members who challenged him for his position. The Dems in a tough bind? I don't agree. The Israeli PM is also in a bind.
8084	New look for the GOP
