94	U.S. expected to remove Cuba from state sponsors of terrorism list.
244	I suppose that Cuba should reciprocate.
285	How many times did the CIA try to kill Castro?
333	Down votes? Here's 10 http://m.mentalfloss.com/article.php?id=30010
481	I think you are getting downvoted because it seems like you are saying that Cuba should try to kill the president?
597	Interestingly enough, lots of people think Cuba had something to do with killing JFK.
761	I was trying to say Cuba should remove the US from their State sponsored terrorist list.
851	Seems obvious to me...
954	Doesn't read that way, seems like people are having hte same issue.
1232	There, that's a lot less ambiguous and less assassinate-y while remaining succinct
1393	Some people think it was actually the cia
1518	i think the only person who hasn't been blamed is Jackie O, and even she would have been blamed had she not been filmed picking pieces of her husband's head off the back of the presidential limo
1788	Nah she's been blamed. They say she orchestrated the hit because JFK gave her the clap.
1877	Their proof being that she married so soon afterwards.
2007	I'm firmly of the opinion that if it was a conspiracy (which is unlikely, honestly) it was LBJ.
2104	A conspiracy by Cuba could be outed pretty easily without much real consequence to the integrity of the US government, finding out that a sitting vice president killed a current president and then plowed the US straight into Vietnam, however, would cause a severe crisis of trust for roughly half of the US. That's the sort of secret conspiracy I could understand keeping secret.
2562	? never heard that EVER. sounds like youre talking out your ass
2700	638+ times
2784	Is the US on its own list?
2890	Can't Cuba have a list? Course it's probably not very long.
2951	1. USA
3031	Don't see why not. Just saying that we should be on our own list.
3176	It's our own list.
3196	From our perspective the CIA are not terrorists. According to the Government they're the good guys. They spread freedom through subterfuge.
3413	Things are really looking up for defrosting Cuba relations. Maybe I'll be able to take a vacation there without jumping through 50 state department hoops one day.
3655	Interesting, do they just plop any country they happen to dislike on the terror list?
3813	yes.
4044	You can argue about any specific country but the overall answer to your question is Yes. That list should not be taken at face value at all.
4264	Yes.
4351	No, despite what everyone else is saying. Any given person might not agree with the reasoning, but it wasn't just because we don't like them.
4494	http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_Sponsors_of_Terrorism#Cuba
4557	According to Country Reports on Terrorism 2010: August 18, 2011:[4]
4626	Designated as a State Sponsor of Terrorism in 1982, the Government of Cuba maintained a public stance against terrorism and terrorist financing in 2010, but there was no evidence that it had severed ties with elements from the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) and recent media reports indicate some current and former members of the Basque Fatherland and Liberty (ETA) continue to reside in Cuba. Available information suggested that the Cuban government maintained limited contact with FARC members, but there was no evidence of direct financial or ongoing material support. In March, the Cuban government allowed Spanish Police to travel to Cuba to confirm the presence of suspected ETA members. Cuba has been used as a transit point by third-country nationals looking to enter illegally into the United States. The Government of Cuba is aware of the border integrity and transnational security concerns posed by such transit and investigated third country migrant smuggling and related criminal activities. In November, the government allowed representatives of the Transportation Security Administration to conduct a series of airport security visits throughout the island. Regional and International Cooperation: Cuba did not sponsor counterterrorism initiatives or participate in regional or global operations against terrorists in 2010.
5984	It was added because Cuba has a history of funding and arming organizations like FARC. And before anyone replies "BUT SO DOES AMERICA," which is reasonable... that's not an argument for taking Cuba off of the list, but changing America's behavior and/or including it on the list, if you believe that America does such things.
6311	It was because they fund(ed) terrorism and we don't like them.
6375	But that looks like it's changing (they're looking to broker a peace deal rather than funding FARC), so... it looks like their status on the list might change, too.
6621	that may be true, but also Saudia Arabia funds terrorism, but since we like them, they're not on the list. It also depends on what "terrorism" is, since the US sponsored several coups that could be considered terrorist in nature, thus putting the US on the list.
6885	At best it's not a comprehensive list, and at worst it's an arbitrary list used for propaganda purposes.
7072	I'm going to go out on a limb and assume you stopped reading after the quoted material?
7237	Neither. The list is a means to use America's global reserve currency as a way to sanction countries without formally sanctioning them. Conducting international commerce in currencies other than $US is less efficient and limits access to commodities markets. Putting someone or some country on this list means the Treasury gets to freeze dollar-denominated assets wherever they are found, to include banks in countries who like to cooperate with the US.
7773	The US is currently housing a terrorist who killed over a 100 people in a plane bombing in Cuba BTW. The US refuses to extradite and the Cuban 5 were arrested for spying on him and other anti Cuban terrorists housed in Miami. Jose Posada Carrilles.
8094	Yes. But given the USA's track record they should also be on their own list.
8242	bravery/10. edgy++
8262	how's the 9th grade going?
8368	Eglin is that you?
8466	lol? the air base. I love those conspiracy theorists.
8521	If it is true the US government is completely retarded. Why do that on a military base? you can do it anywhere in the country.
8727	Not sure, flyboys are pretty patriotic and don't perhaps, ask many pesky questions. Perhaps decent office space, good coffee, jets, big posters of us flag underwear wearing, caped eagles? I really don't know actually. Its no conspiracy theories though many countries do it, I don't think the us is that incompetent not to have such an agency, the cia will practically choke someone to death if they didn't allocate funds for it in this day and age.
9257	Israel does it, the US did so in Operation Mockingbird also.
9389	for a large number of those countries, they'll say that this group or that group sponsored terrorists. this explanation fails to mention the sheer frequency that in the decades before that, the US was there too, funding and training and enabling the "terrorist supporters" in the first place.
9755	To some extent, but Cuba was legitimately placed on the list for their support of FARC. What is actually harder to do is to get off the list once one is on the list if one is disliked.
10014	The US isn't on it, so you know it has to be taken with a grain of salt.
10171	Maybe I'll be able to take a vacation there without jumping through 50 state department hoops one day.
10447	I thought you couldn't do that? Becuase if you get your passport stamped or have any travel record to Cuba, you can get into some big trouble.
10672	Cuba doesn't stamp American passports for just that reason.
10807	I learned something new today
10914	It's not true. I'm a American who traveled to Cuba through my university. They still stamped my passport
11091	Isn't that one of the few legit ways to visit though? Education or Media?
11235	There's 12 legal ways to visit:
11267	Family visits
11281	Official business of the U.S. government, foreign governments, and certain intergovernmental organizations
11388	Journalistic activity
11410	Professional research and professional meetings
11458	Educational activities
11481	Religious activities
11502	Public performances, clinics, workshops, athletic and other competitions, and exhibitions
11592	Support for the Cuban people
11621	Humanitarian projects
11643	Activities of private foundations or research or educational institutes
11715	Exportation, importation, or transmission of information or information materials
11797	Certain export transactions that may be considered for authorization under existing regulations and guidelines.
11982	8 Support for the Cuban people
12014	Is that one a trap or something?
12129	I read it as: Its ok to support the people just not the government.
12269	11. Exportation, importation, or transmission of information or information materials
12356	Bring a tourist guide back with you (importation of information materials). Now your trip is 100% kosher.
12540	Yeah that's how you end up in a Cuban prison.
12657	No, not at all. You get a free trip to Bahía de Cochinos.
12798	We call it Giron.
12897	But you have to walk since air support isn't provided.
13024	1. Guantanamo Bay
