94	Governorship Polls: Jonathan Warns Against Intimidation Of Nigerians
243	http://leadership.ng/news/423798/guber-polls-jonathan-warns-against-intimidation-of-nigerians
408	When he and his wife were forming Rambo in Rivers, Bayelsa, and Ekiti States, imposing thugs as Governors, recklessly interfering with the powers of a duly elected governor, playing politics with the unbridled butchery of thousands of hapless Nigerians, and his pathetic wife constituting herself into an unmitigated political nuisance, He never deemed it fit to give us this 'Salvation Army' speech undecided
819	Now that the shoe is on the other foot, GEJ has suddenly metamorphosed into Pope Jonathan Paul, preaching peace, tolerance, and fairness everywhere he goes angry
982	Yes, Nigerians understand the need for peace and fairness in the upcoming elections. ... But we don't need a chameleon like GEJ to tell us that. .. And no, APC won't act all 'fair and just', and allow blood-hounds like Fayose and Agbaje remain or get into power angry .....
1257	CHANGE MUST BE TOTAL !!! angry
1362	Say no to intimidation.......nice one from the agent of peace my amiable GEJ
1440	All l know is APGA for imo state.......captain ihenacho is the best man for job
1521	APGA for Abia.......Alex otiti is the man
1564	APGA for Nasarawa.......labaran maku victory shall be yours
1625	APGA onye a ha na nwanne ya cheesy cheesy cheesy cheesy
1682	Kokoronko....chi efuo grin grin grin
1789	Nice one from Mr President. cool
1896	If Jonathan didn't spend the past 6 years getting high on alcohol while Fayose, Koro, Wike and Shepopotamus were running amok creating confusion we wouldn't get here.
2064	Was he deaf dumb and mute when Arthur Eze was calling people Amala Ppl in his presence 2 years ago. 
2166	Just pack your load, Buhari would correct every misrule
2292	Apc party should listen to Mr President and stop causing trouble in Ekiti, lagos and Rivers state
2462	I hope he is also going to personally warn nyesom wike and patience jonathan because they are causing nuisance in rivers state....
2662	Well said, Mr. President.... cheesy cheesy
2706	#votenotfight
2790	Hmm.....
2874	Is Jona still a President? Things have been quiet around him lately.
3018	Igbos are the Jews of Africa....
3052	Any Naija State without the Igbos is dead economically....
3188	Better
3272	Did the "Super hero" suddenly grew brains? Why didn't he said this when his wife made the "Stone them" statement? Let me just keep mute on Fayose, Wike, Asari, Koro, Eze etc...Let's just focus on your wife, after all charity begins at home.
3544	When he and his wife were forming Rambo in Rivers, Bayelsa, and Ekiti States, imposing thugs as Governors, recklessly interfering with the powers of a duly elected governor, playing politics with the unbridled butchery of thousands of hapless Nigerians, and his pathetic wife constituting herself into an unmitigated political nuisance, He never deemed it fit to give us this 'Salvation Army' speech undecided
3955	Now that the shoe is on the other foot, GEJ has suddenly metamorphosed into Pope Jonathan Paul, preaching peace, tolerance, and fairness everywhere he goes angry
4118	Yes, Nigerians understand the need for peace and fairness in the upcoming elections. ... But we don't need a chameleon like GEJ to tell us that. .. And no, APC won't act all 'fair and just', and allow blood-hounds like Fayose and Agbaje remain or get into power angry .....
4393	CHANGE MUST BE TOTAL !!! angry
4434	Lol... He gats to act like an elder statesman, do you want him to lose his "Super hero" title cheesy.
4609	Honestly, I tot our President was on sabbatical all these while after the election. Now he remembers he's still the President till at least May 29th. We need him to be active now than before, no matter what. Am not his govt fan, but I think we need him now.
4940	Doing/ saying the right thing at the wrong time... When he, his wife and his cohorts were harassing Amaechi and those they saw as enemies, where were this thoughts?? Adieu President Emeritus... It's obvious people tend to reason well and turn good when they lose power.
5281	This where this man so fits well: peace and conflict resolutions, not presidency. 
5365	Scratching to hear PEJ. Its been a long while.
5484	Ok
5560	that's nice of him, poo!
5697	If Jonathan didn't spend the past 6 years getting high on alcohol while Fayose, Koro, Wike and Shepopotamus were running amok creating confusion we wouldn't get here.
5865	Was he deaf dumb and mute when Arthur Eze was calling people Amala Ppl in his presence 2 years ago. 
5967	Just pack your load, Buhari would correct every misrule
6033	Stop dreaming and typing rubbish
6146	Now, let the battle begin
6247	K
6323	k
6401	...
6406	special forces in Lagos needed.... maximum cctv on this oba guy
6542	My amiable president, Nigerians have heard your warning, it is loud and clear
6694	good cool
6784	Now, let the battle begin
6810	Battle of kini?
6897	Politicians in States like Rivers, Imo and Lagos should be kept under surveillance...The way they play politics in those states is horrible
7108	Jona
7190	K
7262	Let's all come together in peace and vote our choice. No candidate imposition would work.
7353	APC for Lagos though.
7452	Did the "Super hero" suddenly grew brains? Why didn't he said this when his wife made the "Stone them" statement? Let me just keep mute on Fayose, Wike, Asari, Koro, Eze etc...Let's just focus on your wife, after all charity begins at home.
7693	Mind your grammar sir before you abuse someone publicly
