94	Jury Finds Dzhokhar Tsarnaev Guilty In Bombing Of Boston Marathon
240	Now comes the death penalty trial. Having lived and been in Boston during the bombings makes this whole saga emotional for me. Glad to see police and due process have done their job. I don't envy the jurors having to make the death penalty decision.
563	The jury gets to decide whether it's life or death? I always thought the jury just decided guilt then the judge decided the punishment?
771	The jury can recommend the death penalty or not. The judge can impose the death sentence if the jury recommends it, but does not have to. The judge cannot impose the death sentence if the jury does not recommend it.
988	edit: Apparently this is not always the case, and exceptions exist, see posters below.
1156	That is not true in all states. In Alabama and a few other states, a judge can impose a death sentence even when a jury recommends life.
1367	This is a federal trial, though - Massachusetts law does not allow for the death penalty at all.
1539	Slightly off topic question:
1569	Then why are all the jurors from the area? If it's at a national level shouldn't the jurors be from around the nation?
1689	Edit: I know the logistics of that is hard but is there any other reason
1836	Federal courts have geographic jurisdiction. This trial is taking place in US District Court for the District of Massachusetts, which sits in Boston. The jury pool consists of people who live in Massachusetts.
2047	EDIT: This is also why the 9/11 trials had to be in NYC.
2181	Regarding your edit, the other day I asked the lawyers sub about why so many terrorism trials (not just 9/11-related) happen in NYC. Learned some interesting info!
2346	https://www.reddit.com/r/law/comments/317lfw/why_are_terrorism_suspects_tried_in_new_york/
2517	Another interesting fact, any federal crime that involves a financial transaction can be tried in NY.
2697	Oh? Why?
2787	When you have a crime, like a conspiracy, when an act in furtherance of that conspiracy/crime takes place in another state, that state can establish venue. This is all for federal crimes though. All financial transactions are routed through NY.
3107	Well that's fucking terrifying.
3214	Not really, that ruling will be countered real quick with a appeal.
3357	Well, one would hope it would be overturned, but an appeal isn't a guarantee. But I still think it's awful for a judge to be able to overrule the jury in that way.
3596	If one dude in the Jury was not for it and all the others did, plus the crime was terrible, I could care less. This is why most cases get appealed, very few stick because the high volume of appeals. Take this case. All 17 counts of death penalties of guilt will get appealed. This is why the stats say appeals do not work.
3994	To be fair, I'm staunchly anti-death-penalty, so my opinion on this is pretty biased from the get-go.
4171	I am what is ever cheaper for the tax payers....So I guess I am with you until they find a different system. I have not read anywhere the death penalty is cheaper in the US.
4420	Which is generally unsuccessful.
4887	Appeals in general...Yea. Appeals that a judge overturns from the jury is a different story all together. If just one dude said no and 11 other people wanted the death penalty, I can see why the judge could rule the way he did and the appeal was overturned, but this would not be a normal; appeal man.
5264	That's not what we're talking about, though. Read my edit - as many as one-third of the people on death row are there because a judge wanted to impose the death penalty against the jury's will. There is no evidence that would suggest that a judge-imposed death penalty is more likely to be overturned on appeal than a jury-imposed death penalty.
5685	First off the premise is wrong. The jury makes a recommendation, then the judge makes a decision. The judge is not overriding the jury. The judge is the key element in the deciding factor period. The jury just makes a recommendation.
5920	That is like saying The President overrides his staff on his decisions because he did not follow there recommendation. After they gave him permission to judge.
6081	The Jury gave the judge the power to decide. Hell some courts do not even have a Jury when in the sentencing phase.
6272	How in the hell are you coming up with that? I don't even...
6408	What is the Judge overruling legally? The Jury gives there recommendation, The prosecutor, and the defense.
6517	When the Jury said the individual is Guilty with a Max/Min sentencing it is now up to the Judge to decide the mans fate. It is his decision. 3 different institutions give there recommendation. The decision is not the Jury, nothing they say is getting overturned. Not a hard concept to understand.
6889	Not overruling, overriding.
6918	And the jury never gave the judge permission to do a damn thing.
7058	We will just agree to disagree. 3 institutions gave there recommendations. The Judge does not overrule or override anything. The Jury legally gave authority to the Judge, to judge the individual they, the jury, found guilty. It is how the system works. The Judge cannot sentence a individual until the Jury gives legal authority to do so.
7398	3 institutions give there POV. Then the Judge well OMG...He Judges.
7542	A judge can always overrule a jury on "sentencing" (within the bounds of acceptable sentences given the crime the defendant has been convicted of). A jury can decide guilty or not guilty.. sentencing, regardless of jury recommendation, is the judges final decision.
7890	That is blatantly false in the case of the death penalty. Different states have different statutes and a judge cannot overrule a jury recommendation of life in many of them.
8140	"within the bounds of acceptable sentencing"... If a jury decides on life, then "death" is no longer within these bounds. The judge can still set the terms of the sentence.
8386	I often wonder how I would handle that if I were on a jury.
8447	It's very easy for me to sit back at my computer right now, drinking a latte, saying "Yup, give him the death penalty." ... but I don't know how I would handle it if I were one of the jurors.
8640	Not an enviable position by any means.
8751	ive been listening to a lot of updates about the trial since I live in new england. apparently all of the jurors stated that they believed in the death penalty. seems like you wouldn't have been passed on if you didn't (i think anyways)
9069	To be seated on this jury, the judge had to feel that you were willing to impose the death penalty, but also that you hadn't made your mind up before the trial started.
9308	I am not usually a proponent of the death penalty, but I imagine that the jurors will have a hard time giving him life in prison after seeing the pictures of what the shrapnel did to 8 year old Martin Richard's body. There is video of him placing the backpack right next to an 8 year old boy and his sister. If that doesn't deserve the death penalty, then I don't know what does.
9762	I live in Boston, and I do not want this excrescence given the death penalty. I want him to live a long, long life behind bars, with no hope of ever getting out. I want him to have all the time in the world to think about what he's done, the many people he hurt, the lives he's ruined, including his own. I want him to feel regret and remorse.
10183	the death penalty will also make him a martyr.
10304	excrescence
10317	I agree with your point, and I appreciate you teaching me a new word.
10462	Agreed. I do believe that he was a young man with a bright future who got dragged into some terrorist shit and brainwashed by his brother into committed an evil and unforgivable act. As a big brother myself, after this I couldn't help but wonder what crimes I could have talked my young and impressionable brother into committing.
10794	I think that, if he's given life in prison, he will end up speaking out against terrorism and Islamic extremism in the future. I think he could end up being a huge influence on other young and confused Muslims and hopefully, some good will emerge from him after many years of contemplating the evil act he committed.
11112	I also lived in Boston, moved out right before this happened. I lived in Dorchester, where that poor little boy lived, and my sister in law was classmates with the college girl who died.
11300	I hope that Tsarnaev thinks about that little boy every single day for the rest of his life. I am sure he will.
11493	Also a Bostonian and was there during the attacks. I couldn't agree more. Let him rot and wither in the worst prison he can be in, treated like a dog in a cage and devoid of all contact and comfort, for the rest of a long life. Don't let him be a martyr for his cause.
11835	That was almost "to the pain."
11949	If you believed he should get the death penalty, and he did get it, but committed suicide beforehand, would that anger you? It is pretty interesting psychologically how someone could get upset that someone that is slated to die, does it themselves and that in turn causes anger and comments like "he took the easy way out". I am not sure hanging yourself or bleeding out is an easier way out than a lethal injection that may or may not work right the first time. Pretty interesting topic to think about.
12536	I have to agree with you here buddy. I think putting him in general population for his entire sentence would be far worse than the death penalty.
12755	Maybe an LA prison then? Butt raped on the daily?
12883	I am morbidly curious to see this
13142	Death penalty will make him a martyr and potentially endanger the lives of future innocent Americans. Let's not be naive here and use our heads
13359	Would he care about your family? Would he care about you? He will sit in a max faculty for atleast 20 years while he waits through appeals.
13580	Death penalty seems like it would be a mercy depending on which prison he would be sent to.
13743	It will most likely be Supermax in CO
13854	I recommend superjail
13956	So the death sentence?
14052	Multiple death sentences
