94	Hillary Clinton expected to announce presidential run this weekend
237	"WASHINGTON — Hillary Clinton is expected to announce her campaign for the Democratic presidential nomination in 2016 as early as this weekend, facing no substantial competition but needing to get her organization in place for the long battle to come.
490	A variety of sources in the Clinton orbit said they were anticipating an imminent announcement but would not confirm a report in the New York Daily News that the announcement was expected on Sunday.
690	Clinton is likely to make her intentions known through a social media announcement followed by campaign travel. This focus on digital communications is an attempt to connect with young voters, who Clinton needs to become American's first woman president.
946	The Guardian newspaper reported that Clinton would make her announcement on Twitter at noon eastern time on Sunday while headed to the early voting state of Iowa, followed up by email and video announcements."
1157	http://www.nytimes.com/reuters/2015/...nton.html?_r=2
1212	http://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2...to-iowa-source
1338	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
1531	I am not excited to have to choose between Hillary and whatever chucklehead wins the GOP nomination.
1709	Doesn't look like anyone in the Dem party wants to run against her. She's got a straight path to the nomination, tho Bernie announcing could make things interesting for a while (he has no chance).
1983	Any idea who will be her running partner?
2133	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
2266	Why wouldn't they?
2393	Why wouldn't they?
2422	Because conservative voters are very strong willed, and democrats are kinda wimpy.
2613	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
2746	if Texans were able to elect a Liberal Woman Democrat for Governor then for sure Americans can vote for an establishment Woman Democrat for President
3004	Because conservative voters are very strong willed, and democrats are kinda wimpy.
3097	I'd say the same applied when Obama was running for president. I think you are talking more about voters being retaliatory towards Hillary after Obama's presidency, but I don't think there'd be enough of those voters to make a difference.
3439	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
3572	Elephant? I though she was part of the democratic party! 
3631	In all seriousness, it would interesting to see if a woman as a president would be any different.
3807	Yay 19 months of the media ignoring real news for election BS.
3871	Not that it hasn't already been happening the previous 19 months.
4044	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
4177	well, speaking honestly, it feels like this is Hillary's election to lose.
4253	unless she fucks up majorly, or some act of god candidate shows up,
4434	if Texans were able to elect a Liberal Woman Democrat for Governor then for sure Americans can vote for an establishment Woman Democrat for President
4594	Davis didn't win? Although you might be thinking of our mayor in Houston but that's a more liberal city in general.
4711	Unless that was sarcastic.
4810	I get the impression a lot of conservatives like Hillary looking at her like the next Thatcher.
4979	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
5102	I don't see why not.
5124	Having the women voter block is a major advantage. And I think the block of people who won't vote for a woman (no matter the person) has to be shrinking.
5279	And she's remarkably centrist. She can be appealing to all walks of life, even some moderate Republicans.
5457	I get the impression a lot of conservatives like Hillary looking at her like the next Thatcher.
5553	They only gave positive coverage to Hillary at first because they hate Obama more because he actually became President. If Hillary had won, we would've had seven years of, "look, we could've dealt with somebody like Obama who talked about there not being a red and blue America, instead of the disuniter in chief, Hillary Rodham Clinton."
6005	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
6138	white woman president yes
6165	Latina yes
6177	Black woman no
6270	Benghazi
6280	Benghazi
6290	Benghazi
6412	Davis didn't win? Although you might be thinking of our mayor in Houston but that's a more liberal city in general.
6529	Unless that was sarcastic.
6775	Benghazi
6785	Benghazi
6795	Benghazi
6814	Medusa head on me like I'm 'luminati
6961	Will the American voters allow a woman president directly after a black president though? That's the elephant in the room.
7094	Hillary is such a known quantity that her being a woman feels like something of a non-factor at this point.
7308	Davis didn't win? Although you might be thinking of our mayor in Houston but that's a more liberal city in general.
7425	Unless that was sarcastic.
7462	Probably means Ann Richards
7710	Derp
7716	Just wasn't thinking of her given the time frame in which she was elected and the modern comparison he used.
7903	American politics is at such a low point
8055	Any idea who will be her running partner?
8107	Well Warren DID only say she wasn't going to run for "president..."
8247	It sounds like some Hillaryous times ahead.
8368	for voters who remember rosier positive economic times during the latter half of the 1990s in times of relative peace, associate it to the Clinton name.
8522	Hillary will do well
8656	for voters who remember rosier positive economic times during the latter half of the 1990s in times of relative peace, associate it to the Clinton name.
8810	Hillary will do well
8841	I get the impression (anecdotal anyways) that she'll pick up pretty much all the Hispanics who were happy with Bill's presidency too. Their kids (and everyone else's) should get off their asses and vote too.
9125	I'm not from the US. Can someone explain me what makes them question whether Hillary will be a good president?
9307	Not sure how electable she is. Lot of potential issues - Benghazi, emails and the biggest of all, Bill. Will be popular among the Democratic base and the frontrunner for the nom, no doubt, but if the Republicans somehow manage to actually get their shit together she will be in trouble.
9700	Well Warren DID only say she wasn't going to run for "president..."
9778	That would be a huge waste of her influence.
9932	I get the impression (anecdotal anyways) that she'll pick up pretty much all the Hispanics who were happy with Bill's presidency too. Their kids (and everyone else's) should get off their asses and vote too.
10474	Not sure how electable she is. Lot of potential issues - Benghazi, emails and the biggest of all, Bill. Will be popular among the Democratic base and the frontrunner for the nom, no doubt, but if the Republicans somehow manage to actually get their shit together she will be in trouble.
10771	Bill is going to be a huge asset to her. Banghazi just isn't going to stick, they've been trying since the day it happened... It'll be 3 full years of failing to make it into something this fall. The emails also turned into nothing.
11110	That would be a huge waste of her influence.
11165	I don't know, maybe she'll end up being GIFable like Biden!
11330	Not sure how electable she is. Lot of potential issues - Benghazi, emails and the biggest of all, Bill. Will be popular among the Democratic base and the frontrunner for the nom, no doubt, but if the Republicans somehow manage to actually get their shit together she will be in trouble.
11627	are we under the assumption it wasn't hillary's own camp who released the info to minimize its effect during the election run?
11859	Not sure how electable she is. Lot of potential issues - Benghazi, emails and the biggest of all, Bill. Will be popular among the Democratic base and the frontrunner for the nom, no doubt, but if the Republicans somehow manage to actually get their shit together she will be in trouble.
12156	Yes, Bill "73% approval rating" Clinton is an issue. Bill Clinton would be on 7th term by now if he was allowed. :)
12378	I don't know, maybe she'll end up being GIFable like Biden!
12448	Nobody is more GIFable than Biden. That's his true calling. He should be VP again!
12639	American politics is at such a low point
12690	Normally I completely and utterly disagree with everything you say Schatt... but yes.
12777	This is the worst presidential year I've been alive to experience. Maybe I'm just salty coming off the amazing Obama years.
12974	Isn't she just assumed to have this one in the bag already? Current republican frontrunners are complete jokes, and swing voters are going to swing her way no problem, they'll choose a boring "remember how sweet the 90s were!?" over any whackjob republican wanting to outlaw the moon or some shit.
13273	I'll be voting for her...because who else is there?
13434	Not sure how electable she is. Lot of potential issues - Benghazi, emails and the biggest of all, Bill. Will be popular among the Democratic base and the frontrunner for the nom, no doubt, but if the Republicans somehow manage to actually get their shit together she will be in trouble.
13731	lol
13736	First off, nobody outside the republican base thinks about Benghazi and the email thing was introduced so early in this cycle to where it barely produced a hickup and will be taken care of by the time next year comes around.
13962	Honestly I think that her own camp released that shit to get it out of the way, considering it was released the same day Bibi was speaking at the white house and that whole clusterfuck.
14218	Will not support!
14343	Isn't she just assumed to have this one in the bag already? Current republican frontrunners are complete jokes, and swing voters are going to swing her way no problem, they'll choose a boring "remember how sweet the 90s were!?" over any whackjob republican wanting to outlaw the moon or some shit.
14642	I'll be voting for her...because who else is there?
14704	Jeb Bush might understandably give her issues.
14752	he has a lot of pull in Florida, and he can fool a large percentage of the hispanic vote due to the fact he speaks spanish. put him on a national podium and have him speak an essay in spanish, and watch the pendulum swing hard his way. no joke.
15103	Not sure how electable she is. Lot of potential issues - Benghazi, emails and the biggest of all, Bill. Will be popular among the Democratic base and the frontrunner for the nom, no doubt, but if the Republicans somehow manage to actually get their shit together she will be in trouble.
15400	You mean the same Bill that won Obama the 2nd term among hundreds of other things?
15594	Doesn't look like anyone in the Dem party wants to run against her. She's got a straight path to the nomination, tho Bernie announcing could make things interesting for a while (he has no chance).
15801	If the Dems want to win though, they need people to actually run to have a field. If this looks like the Dems are just coronating their nominee it's not going to look good.
15975	Strategically it's also poor since it would let the Republican candidates all attack hilary instead of them having to talk about each other.
16195	Honestly, this election comes down to this for me. 
16248	Does this person believe in a anthropomorphic climate change, and will they continue to build off of Obama's executive actions in reducing emissions? 
16400	Which means the entire republican field just got thrown out the window.
16576	If the Dems want to win though, they need people to actually run to have a field. If this looks like the Dems are just coronating their nominee it's not going to look good.
16750	Strategically it's also poor since it would let the Republican candidates all attack hilary instead of them having to talk about each other.
16901	Nobody cares about the primaries but the fringes.
17029	She isn't going to be president.
17063	Everyone should ready themselves for President Jeb Bush now.
17237	I get the impression (anecdotal anyways) that she'll pick up pretty much all the Hispanics who were happy with Bill's presidency too. Their kids (and everyone else's) should get off their asses and vote too.
17455	Jeb is potentiality the Repuplican the most apt at attracting as many Hispanic voters as brother W. did or even better than W. 
17584	Jeb's Spanish speaking skills are exponentially better than W.'s and Jeb isn't afraid to speak it.
18022	Can't read it.
18071	Jeb Bush might understandably give her issues.
18119	he has a lot of pull in Florida, and he can fool a large percentage of the hispanic vote due to the fact he speaks spanish. put him on a national podium and have him speak an essay in spanish, and watch the pendulum swing hard his way. no joke.
18374	I believe he can fool the swing voters, but anyone who voted for Bill Clinton is going to need more than an essay or promises that his party's base are vehemently against.
18547	The republicans also need A LOT more than Florida to hit 270. I look forward to seeing them battle for dear life in Virginia, Pennsylvania Indiana AND Ohio.
18705	Edit: Damn, Penn has gone blue for a while. Reagan is a God (or the Devil for some others, I guess).
18842	Jeb is potentiality the Repuplican the most apt at attracting as many Hispanic voters as brother W. did or even better than W. 
18971	Jeb's Spanish speaking skills are exponentially better than W.'s and Jeb isn't afraid to speak it.
19080	Things must be pretty different out west and in Florida. Must be my experience as a New York Hispanic coloring my expectations.
19315	Nobody cares about the primaries but the fringes.
19375	That's what Hillary thought in 2008.
