94	What's the Difference Between Hillary Clinton
218	The choice is clear for 2016. Vote for a conservative Republican. Vote for Hillary Clinton.
311	https://www.lewrockwell.com/2015/03/...-like-hillary/
366	I wonder if Hillary had a (R) after her name, would the left despise her and the right proclaim the obviousness of her superiority?
764	I will vote for a Republican over a democrat every time.
904	 think you missed half of your comparison.
948	The title should be. What is the difference between Hillary and Limburger cheese. Not much, they both stink and leave a terrible after taste
1167	i refuse to vote for either. They both suck.
1213	I'd like to see them suck muffler fumes.
1360	I will vote for a Republican over a democrat every time.
1427	And what will change? Will the government become more limited? Will there be more individual liberties? Will the state stop stealing your money?
1573	Of course not. 
1590	You'll keep rooting for your team because that's what fans do.
1761	And what will change? Will the government become more limited? Will there be more individual liberties? Will the state stop stealing your money?
1907	Of course not. 
1924	You'll keep rooting for your team because that's what fans do.
1997	Tell you...stay home, don't do anything, just bitch and bitch and bitch some more because you will accomplish so much that way. Don't dare get involved in any Party and try to work from within.
2269	You're right.
2284	There is no difference.
2309	Neither advocates LEGAL POT; and neither advocates anarchy.
2370	So...there's no choice there.
2401	...if your worldview is so compressed and deluded...
2562	Tell you...stay home, don't do anything, just bitch and bitch and bitch some more because you will accomplish so much that way. Don't dare get involved in any Party and try to work from within.
2766	No, I wouldn't get involved in any party... I don't believe that any form of government benefits human civilization in any way. In fact I strongly believe it's detrimental. If I were to get involved in selecting a ruler, I'd be a hypocrite.
3008	I'll let the sheep choose their master and laugh at their quandary... then I'll suffer from the same state they believe they control.
