94	"Food on the floor, Physicist catnaps" The inside look at the Iran negotiations
249	nekom: Marcus Aurelius: Next, maybe we can get Israel to allow IAEA inspections and sign the NPT.
348	It's time for some sanctions on their rogue nuclear program.
410	That 800lb gorilla is always going to be there, just sitting in the room.
485	[blog.ctnews.com image 534x300]
518	Some gorillas can dance and sing.
620	dwrash: udhq: dwrash: They don't care about keeping control of their country... their religion dictates that they start Armageddon.
753	Today I learned that Iran is apparently run by evangelical Christians.
825	Not all evangelical Christians want Armageddon.... only the dispensational nutcases want that to happen.
931	As far as the shiites... Armageddon is closely linked to the coming of the 12th Mahdi.
1019	That's Sunnis.
1035	Shia believe the 12th imam to be the Mahdi, and that he's just been in hiding for the last 1000 years.
1208	lilplatinum: dwrash: Not all evangelical Christians want Armageddon.... only the dispensational nutcases want that to happen.
1335	Armageddon is necessary for the rebirth of Christ, any Jesus freak who takes the magic book as literal truth (which is definitionally all Evangelicals) wants Armageddon to happen ASAP as that means their holy zombie comes back.
1564	Evangelicals all think Israelis are going to hell as much as Muslims, they just need them to kickstart the apocalypse.
1684	You need to broaden your horizons a bit....  Evangelicals only say they take the scriptures literally... but they don't.  There are two verses that blast their end times beliefs to smithereens and they have done some pretty impressive gymnastics to try and explain them away.
1961	1.) Jesus said that some of the people witnessing his preaching would still be living when all prophesy was completed.... they are all dead now.
2107	2.) John wrote that the visions he saw in Revelation were to happen 'soon'.  You cannot equate soon with 2000 years by any stretch of the imagination.
2259	For me... Revelation is a apocalyptic book about the end of the favoritism and promises in Judaism culminating with the destruction of the temple in AD70.  A temple that will never be rebuilt (the Dome of the Rock stands on the old temple foundation).. good luck tearing that down and rebuilding the temple... the Muslims would rather see Jerusalem nuked.
2616	Anyhow, the majority of Christianity do not believe in the rapture and all the other new age interpretations that came out of the 18th and 19th centuries.
2772	Christians should be involved in doing what they are mandated to do... helping the poor and needy first, then preaching.. and treating others with the same respect that Jesus treated everyone, regardless of their behavior.... instead the Dispensationalists live on rumor mongering and trying to shoe horn current events into their end times... they are trying so hard to force the scenario that they believe will force God to return....  but it ain't going to happen that way.
3250	Some Muslims feel the same way about forcing the last Mahdi to return.... they will do whatever they can with such a religious fervor to try and force it... but they will be disappointed.
3439	There is no "get out of loving your neighbor as yourself' card for anyone... they are an embarrassment to the rest of us who call ourselves Christians.
3696	For me... Revelation is a apocalyptic book about the end of the favoritism and promises in Judaism culminating with the destruction of the temple in AD70.
3861	Or the hallucinogenic ravings of a guy who accidentally ate the wrong kind of mushrooms.
4020	Dr Dreidel: nekom: Marcus Aurelius: Next, maybe we can get Israel to allow IAEA inspections and sign the NPT.
4131	It's time for some sanctions on their rogue nuclear program.
4193	That 800lb gorilla is always going to be there, just sitting in the room.
4268	Part of me wonders if that isn't a consideration for Bibi/Likud/Israel, possibly THE biggest unspoken reason they're publicly against any nuke deal with Iran. If Iran's rogue program can be brought to heel by the P5+1, all the more reason for Israel's to be held to account by the same group.
4562	// by 2025, we might see Israel allowing an IAEA inspection or two, maybe even a permanent inspection regime (as a show of good faith, perhaps); but I doubt they sign the NPT
4737	// because Israelis are pig
4766	unleavened bread-headed that way
4800	/passover peeve
4921	Or the hallucinogenic ravings of a guy who accidentally ate the wrong kind of mushrooms.
5020	Look at it as a type of political cartoon of its day.  Everyone once in a while I'll see a political cartoon from the early 1800's and wonder what the heck its trying to get at.  You end up having to go back and hit the history books to understand the context.
5282	The same applies to Revelation... it wasn't much more than a political cartoon of its day... the Apocalypse of Peter is pretty much the same thing.
5535	You need to broaden your horizons a bit....
5589	I did, I moved out of the south away from Evangelicals.
5646	  Evangelicals only say they take the scriptures literally... but they don't.  There are two verses that blast their end times beliefs to smithereens and they have done some pretty impressive gymnastics to try and explain them away.
5880	Well yes, if you actually try to take the bible at face value it is not only downright evil (old testament stuff like advocating slavery, murdering your disobedient children and selling your daughters to rapists), but self contradictory. 
6120	Anyhow, the majority of Christianity do not believe in the rapture and all the other new age interpretations that came out of the 18th and 19th centuries.
6276	Something like 40% of Americans believe that Jesus is coming back to Earth in the next 40 years, and a huge amount believe in Young Earth Creationism.  There is a huge block of nutters in this country that believe this nonsense, and they, sadly, vote in larger numbers than rational people.
6568	A good deal of the right wing inherent kow-towing to Israel is based on Evangelical nonsense (and the rest is based on the deep coffers of their political advocates).
6808	Giltric: lilplatinum: dwrash: I'm of the camp that thinks that Iran is just playing us for chumps and getting us to take their obsolete equipment and stockpiles off their hands so they don't have to dispose of them... and that they have new clandestine underground facilities that the west does not know about working on creating a bomb.. and will continue to work in spite of this proposed treaty.
7208	If they have magical secret underground areas capable of hiding from our satellites, then they are going to be working regardless of what we do, so it's a moot point.
7376	Eventually we are going to have to realize that keeping 70 year old technology away from everyone we don't like is going to be more and more of an uphill battle....
7542	They do according to dissidents/defectors.
7586	I think there was a coincidental order placed for a more robust bunker buster at the time the underground facility was exposed by one of the defectors.
7739	Let me introduce you to the guy who was "informing" us on Iraq...google curveball.
7896	I remember the last movie based on the "international inspectors are being fooled by cunning Middle Easterners" plot line. The ending sucked.
8143	They don't care about keeping control of their country... their religion dictates that they start Armageddon.
8263	That is a stupid thing to say and you should feel bad for saying it. You don't get to climb to governance of any Middle-East country if you don't care very,very much about controlling it. And also, no, their religion does no such thing.
8605	I remember the last movie based on the "international inspectors are being fooled by cunning Middle Easterners" plot line. The ending sucked.
9044	They don't care about keeping control of their country... their religion dictates that they start Armageddon.
9188	That is a stupid thing to say and you should feel bad for saying it. You don't get to climb to governance of any Middle-East country if you don't care very,very much about controlling it. And also, no, their religion does no such thing.
9445	Really?
9454	http://en.islamtoday.net/node/1575
9594	I remember the last movie based on the "international inspectors are being fooled by cunning Middle Easterners" plot line. The ending sucked.
9972	You mistake me for a supporter of Bush.... yup, that sucked on so many levels.  All we have been successful doing is creating another couple generations of people that want to kill us even more.
10271	They don't care about keeping control of their country... their religion dictates that they start Armageddon.
10415	That is a stupid thing to say and you should feel bad for saying it. You don't get to climb to governance of any Middle-East country if you don't care very,very much about controlling it. And also, no, their religion does no such thing.
10682	Really?
10691	http://en.islamtoday.net/node/1575
10756	I didn't see a single thing there about them having to start it. Can you quote the relevant part?
10960	They don't care about keeping control of their country... their religion dictates that they start Armageddon.
11104	That is a stupid thing to say and you should feel bad for saying it. You don't get to climb to governance of any Middle-East country if you don't care very,very much about controlling it. And also, no, their religion does no such thing.
11371	Really?
11380	http://en.islamtoday.net/node/1575
11445	You dismiss the widely held belief amongst Evangelicals that Armegeddon is coming soon and that it is something to look forward to as a simple misunderstanding, but a website proves that all Muslims are working towards accelerating the apocalypse from a political standpoint?
11722	The reality is, that like most religious leaders, the "Mullahs" have found that religion is a good tool to control and consolidate power, and all of them want to hold onto that power and not be incenerated in a nuclear war.
11947	Pakistan's ownerships of nukes is far, far more worrisome (you know, the guys who were sheltering Bin Laden), and even they haven't used them yet.
12095	Intervention in the Middle East has done nothing but trouble (hell, this regime in Iran is a direct result of us propping up the Shah), time to step back and quit wasting my tax dollars in that hellhole.
12400	They don't care about keeping control of their country... their religion dictates that they start Armageddon.
12544	That is a stupid thing to say and you should feel bad for saying it. You don't get to climb to governance of any Middle-East country if you don't care very,very much about controlling it. And also, no, their religion does no such thing.
12811	Really?
12820	http://en.islamtoday.net/node/1575
12890	You dismiss the widely held belief amongst Evangelicals that Armegeddon is coming soon and that it is something to look forward to as a simple misunderstanding, but a website proves that all Muslims are working towards accelerating the apocalypse from a political standpoint?
13167	The reality is, that like most religious leaders, the "Mullahs" have found that religion is a good tool to control and consolidate power, and all of them want to hold onto that power and not be incenerated in a nuclear war.
13392	Pakistan's ownerships of nukes is far, far more worrisome (you know, the guys who were sheltering Bin Laden), and even they haven't used them yet.
13540	Intervention in the Middle East has done nothing but trouble (hell, this regime in Iran is a direct result of us propping up the Shah), time to step back and quit wasting my tax dollars in that hellhole.
13784	/High five!
13876	udhq: On the Sunday shows, it was clear the new talking point was "Obama is an antiwar president" and all I could think is that I can't believe I share a country with people who think that's a bad thing.
14081	Well, war IS good to people who have a lot of their money tied up in companies that feed the MIC.  So endless war is very profitable to them.
