94	ISIL's nuclear weapons
195	Various media reports state that ISIL now controls the output of many refineries in Iraq and Libya. It wouldn'r be too much of an assumption to believe that ISIL now have plenty of cash for all sorts of purposes, including the purchase of nuclear weapons and a means of delivery.
476	What would this mean for the world in general and the West in particular ?
622	It makes me wonder why these sites haven't been reduced to rubble.
793	the purchase of nuclear weapons and a means of delivery.
860	That may be the critical factor John...who, if anyone would sell ISIS/ISIL nuclear weapons? Even some of the States that the West once thought of as "rogue" must wonder whether selling nuclear weapons to ISIL might be a step too far. Sure, the weapons might first be used against the "old Enemies" in the West, but ISIL may one day turn them back on the states from whom they first purchased them. 
1260	Even if States who might potentially sell nukes to ISIL currently practice Islam, unless they are as 'fundamentalist' as ISIL, then they must see that they too may well find themselves on opposing sides to ISIL in the longer term, not leats because Islam seems so full of sub-factions who seem to think "their way" is the only "right" way?
1935	Leaving aside exactly what resources they do have let's suppose you are right and that they were in the market. I wonder how many potential suppliers would actually be prepared to supply? I am not sure that ISIS has any allies so equipped, does it? Their intentions and actions are dangerous and unpredictable so I am not sure who would risk the sale for fear of where they might be used.
2401	I don't think we have to worry about ISIS / ISIL too much; Saddam Hussein dedicated the whole resources of an oil-rich Iraq for decades to getting a nuclear capability and he failed miserably.
2668	ISIL are committed to the establishment of a world wide caliphate (government) - eventually. It is the means by which they bring that about within a reasonable time frame that, in part, supports the original question.
2887	ISIL appears to be supported and maintained by young activist men and young activist men are always in a hurry to bring about change. Such appears to be the strength of their ideology and the depth of their convictions, best illustrated by the recent murders of innocent civilians that, I believe they are capable of acquiring or, even designing - on some future occasion - weapons of mass destruction with the intention of using those weapons at the earliest opportunity. Remember, they do not have to be nuclear.
3403	Far fetched ? Let's hope so.
3536	That may be the critical factor John...who, if anyone would sell ISIS/ISIL nuclear weapons? Even some of the States that the West once thought of as "rogue" must wonder whether selling nuclear weapons to ISIL might be a step too far. Sure, the weapons might first be used against the "old Enemies" in the West, but ISIL may one day turn them back on the states from whom they first purchased them. 
3936	Even if States who might potentially sell nukes to ISIL currently practice Islam, unless they are as 'fundamentalist' as ISIL, then they must see that they too may well find themselves on opposing sides to ISIL in the longer term, not leats because Islam seems so full of sub-factions who seem to think "their way" is the only "right" way?
4546	Paul, I think that money, especially a lot of money doesn't so much talk as shout !
4707	I think we have to be very cautious about assigning too much potential to ISIL!
4788	Yes, they have expanded enormously in the last couple of years but that has only been possible in the power-vacuums that operate in states seriously weakened by civil-war and internal sectarian struggle; hold a gun to somebody's head and give them a choice between death and joining ISIL and they'll join ISIL!
5100	Yes, some followers of ISIL have the 'conviction' to murder civilians in terrorist attacks. These generate enormous publicity but do not really represent a genuine threat to any western nation (although obviously they represent a threat to personal safety if you are unlucky enough to become a victim of an attack). Would ISIL even need to stage these publicity-generating attacks if they had any real power? It begs the question: are these attacks part of some grand strategy or are they just isolated attacks by 'wannabe' groups jumping onto the ISIL bandwagon?
5665	Massacring a few unarmed civilians with a AK-47 is one thing...
5730	...obtaining even the crudest of nuclear devices is quite another.
5872	They will go with a 'dirty' bomb.
5907	Easy to make, easy to transport, easy to utilise.
5958	Will cause havoc in a city.
5987	Baz
6061	Yup totally agree, detonated on an underground and allow the trains push the contaminates around the city.
6169	I also agree you are totally over estimating the resources they have available, as said Saddam couldn't do it with his resources. If they ever did use them it would be the last act because they would be eradicated from the planet toot sweet
6486	I doubt their ability to acquire the components for a dirty bomb or their intention to use one. 
6584	As stated above it would end their aspirations for a Caliphate instantly - they would have no ally and would be obliterated.
6710	They might be a band of gullible zealots lead by homicidsl fanatics with a purpose but I doubt the leadership is stupid.
6906	Tony T
6914	"eradicated from the planet?"
6945	But only after they had created mayhem !
6987	Re 11
6994	There is an example from history: The Japanese were persuaded into surrender by the dropping of two atomic weapons. It might be even easier for ISIL to intimidate the West.
7243	Well that is indeed relevant but only if you believe firstly that ISIL would be able to source the weapon and the capability to use it and secondly that they would actually see any benefit from so doing. I do not think either is credible.
7560	There are radiation detectors at major ports and airports in the United Kingdom plus at either end of the Channel Tunnel; even a 'dirty bomb' requires difficult to obtain nuclear material and a lot of explosive to be effective and the United Kingdom would certainly never 'surrender' to ISIL even if they did detonate one here.
7889	Honestly, they way the media talk about ISIL you'd think they were Nazi Germany or the USSR!
7983	If there was anybody to stand up to ISIL they'd virtually all melt-away and their 'support' would evaporate. Don't forget that Iraq has been at war, mainly with itself, for nearly twenty-five years; I'll wager that most of the population are just thoroughly sick of conflict, including the Iraqi Army, trained at great expense (and a few lives) by the West. As soon as somebody turns up looking for a fight, like ISIL, everybody else (including the Iraqi Army) just rolls-over and goes along (as I probably would under the circumstances); with nobody to stand-up to ISIL they 'conquer' vast territory and seem very powerful but are they?
8622	The 'West' could rout them utterly in a matter of weeks but it would require huge resources (which the West has), vast expense and (most importantly) the lives of our Armed Forces; there simply is no appetite for this any more after Iraq and Afghanistan. Plus, why should we bother? The last two campaigns in Iraq and Afghanistan, to rid these regions of the current 'terror' were (initially) highly successful but what good did it do us (or anybody else); the West got no thanks from anybody and drew huge quantities of criticism, (IED) bombs and bullets...
9182	...every anti-West voice in the world spoke-up about the West being where it was not wanted and highlighted the harm the West was doing (while conveniently forgetting any good that was done), result: sort-out your own problems in Iraq, Afghanistan, Syria, Libya, Egypt...
9455	...but then 'ISIL', or some wannabe group, reach-out to strike the West (tourists)!!! I wonder why???
9632	Let us have a look at the credibility/believability of my suggestion. We know that they have the idealogical fanaticism in abundance to motivate any kind or type of attack. We know that they have seized huge funds. We know that their ideology means that they will destroy themselves to achieve their objectives.
9945	But, acquiring the nuts and bolts of weapons of mass destruction ? That's a step too far. That's crazy. That is preposterous. That will never happen - will it ?
10107	If, fifteen years ago, I had sat at my keyboard as a writer with a rather inventive turn of imagination and written that I can imagine that some fanatical group of terrorists with a chilling agenda, will high jack two commercial airliners packed with innocent passengers and fly them into two skyscrapers in New York City which will ignite and burn to the ground murdering almost 3000 people comprising most nationalities, the howls of laughter would have drowned the traffic noise outside my window and I would have been dismissed as a loonie and a fruitcake.
10746	Fair points, but ISIL aren't stupid.....and they are certainly aware of their own limitations.
10842	And what happened to those behind 9/11, those that planned the attack, their 'organisation', their ideology and those (made) guilty by (an engineered) association? Why don't we hear anything about Al Qaeda these days?
11136	Well that's one of the reasons our boys died in Afghanistan so it was not all in vain as most would have us believe.
11328	CD 16
11335	I rather had the impression that they had morphed into ISIL?
11397	17.
11402	Charlie, I have a slight advantage being former military but not staff. I believe that the Allied presence in Afghanistan was like a pebble thrown into a pond and creating a transitory ripple effect - it shows and then is gone in seconds.
11642	All we have to show for around 300 years of political and military interference is the building of the odd bridge and stretches of highway. The prevailing mindset in that country - as far as I can judge - is and always will be tribal and medieval.
11966	On the contrary al Qaeda high command has strongly denied any connection whatsoever in Syria, Iraq or anywhere else. 
12085	I accept your general points about the various expeditions there over the centuries but in this latest adventure the objective has been successful. What the future brings is another story of course.
12396	I rather had the impression that they had morphed into ISIL?
12467	Well, in some respects I think you are correct. ISIL didn't clone 200,000 'fighters' overnight; some will have already given their allegiance to the Iraqi government, Al Qaeda previously, and Saddam Hussain before that!
12688	I agree with what was achieved by British / Allied Forces in Afghanistan; a temporary, and far too costly, interruption to the normal state of affairs: tribalism, corruption and the law of the gun (to whatever fundamentalism is in fashion).
13039	On the contrary al Qaeda high command has strongly denied any connection whatsoever in Syria, Iraq or anywhere else. 
13158	I accept your general points about the various expeditions there over the centuries but in this latest adventure the objective has been successful. What the future brings is another story of course.
13367	You haven't won if you haven't defeated the enemy. To win, you have to kill the enemy in sufficient numbers as to persuade them that they no longer have credible forces. You have to dusrupt and destroy their communications, supplies and intelligence.
13619	You can't do that with regular forces opposing irregular forces as the Americans discovered in Vietnam. We most decidedly have not achieved our military objectives at a considerable cost in lives and treasure.
13938	It makes me wonder why these sites haven't been reduced to rubble.
14015	Sorry, I missed this.....it is an excellent question; why haven't 'surgical strikes' been made against oil targets?
14207	You can't do that with regular forces opposing irregular forces as the Americans discovered in Vietnam
14311	You can if you have disciplined forces and a clear political will to achieve it -the prime example being Operation Firedog.
14510	I don't know Operation Firedog.
14543	The only way that I imagine you might be able to do it is by adopting the methods of your enemy. Eg. Malaya, Cyprus, Borneo. These theatres were relatively small scale, even so, we used air assets at at least two of them to assist. Our enemy didn't have that luxury.
14885	One or two commentators either inferred that I was being a bit tough on ISIL and they weren't quite the threat that I made them out to be.
15025	Well, here are some more thoughts from no less than renowned author - tho' not to everyone's taste - V.S. Naipaul. He says (report, D. Tel. 23rd) that ISIL can be likened to a latter day Fourth Reich. He goes on to write that they believe in their own racial superiority and have wiped out whole civil populations of certain regions.
15360	Naipaul continues that ISIL offer the most serious and potent threat to the world since the Third Reich. ISIL are dedicated to a contemporary Holocaust. It has pledged itself to the murder of Shias, Jews, Christians, Copts and Yazidis.
15597	The Nobel prize winner, said that ISIL is a totalitarian State, absolute in its authority.
15689	Useful info for the Doubting Thomas'
15802	A fine novelist but that does not make his views on ISIL any more relevant than anyone else's. And there will be much debate around the assertion he makes in the third paragraph.
16093	One or two commentators either inferred that I was being a bit tough on ISIL and they weren't quite the threat that I made them out to be.
16242	The point I was trying to make was that we should not overestimate the capability of ISIL as a threat to the United Kingdom.
16368	I do not doubt the inclination of ISIL to exterminate anybody that doesn't bow to their ideology but there is a big difference in the threat of ISIL depending on whether you live in the United Kingdom of whether you are a virtually defenceless Yazidi!
16621	What concerns me is that United Kingdom defence policy seems to be increasingly skewed towards the 'threat' of ISIL at the expense of our more traditional (and much more capable) enemies. Plus our (however well intentioned) interference in the region has been turned against us and led to accusations of imperialism or even religious crusade; now that ISIL are terrorising the whole region there have been, of course, calls for the west to 'do more'. We're damned either way!
17172	Nothing there with which I'd argue CD. What does concern me and others who give some thought to these matters, is the apparent level of covert support in this country for these rascals.
17359	The fact tht we can't control illegal immigration means that many who are our enemies find our borders completely porous. We now read that illegals are being exported out so that they can return at a time of their choosing co-incident with whatever beneficial welfare changes are in the offing !
17656	The threat of ISIL is necessarily a covert threat. They cannot move large armies across the Channel but, they could, given our lack of control over our coastline, infiltrate piecemeal and merge successfully into a receptive and visually identical section of the population.
17931	There, to assemble over time, very dangerous toxins of a bacterial or viral nature and capable of causing huge casualties and perhaps more importantly widespread panic among a population that to my understanding, does not have the resilience or mental and physical toughness of the wartime generation.
18234	Yes, let us overestimate the capabilities of ISIL and be prepared.
18376	Charlie,
18386	He's nobody's fool. He's written extensively on the subject of Islam. He's informed and I respect his opinion.
18573	John 
18580	Of course he is not and my intention was not to suggest he was. Merely that across the Islamic world there is a breadth of opinion and he falls into the more extreme camp by making the comparison he does. It is one which is not shared by other equally respected figures.
