94	Al Shabaab terrorists murder 150 students at university
231	http://www.theguardian.com/world/201...-on-university
286	Unbelievable. Revolting.
312	It reminds me of the Taliban attack on the Pakistani school that killed hundreds of children a couple of months ago.
430	Islamist terrorists have no solutions, they have nothing to offer the world, no vision for the future, except death and oppression
633	For the love of God.
763	For the love of God.
794	And I just think... why students? I mean, if they attacked a Kenyan Army base, I wouldn't support it but I'd think they were attacking combatants.
942	But university students? Wtf?
973	The Kenyan government also has questions to answer given the Australian government warned late last week than an attack was imminent
1215	And I just think... why students? I mean, if they attacked a Kenyan Army base, I wouldn't support it but I'd think they were attacking combatants.
1363	But university students? Wtf?
1394	The Kenyan government also has questions to answer given the Australian government warned late last week than an attack was imminent
1537	They fear education. 
1560	Ignorance is the preferred option and attacks like this will help enforce ignorance.
1715	Islamists never attack anybody who will ever fight back.
1773	Hence they target so many schools and un-armed establishments. Pretty disgraceful the way the Kenyan government handled this, they had evidence of an attack similar to this in the works and only had 2 armed guards?
1989	Tragically the two guards both died bravely trying to defend the students, but surely if an attack was to happen how was 2 guards ever going to be enough?
2215	Horrible news - it goes without saying. A very sad state of affairs and my thoughts go out to all the families of those killed and injured. What a barbaric act of terrorism.
2465	We have people on TSR happy about it too http://www.thestudentroom.co.uk/show....php?t=3238493
2667	Islamists never attack anybody who will ever fight back.
2725	Hence they target so many schools and un-armed establishments. Pretty disgraceful the way the Kenyan government handled this, they had evidence of an attack similar to this in the works and only had 2 armed guards?
2941	Tragically the two guards both died bravely trying to defend the students, but surely if an attack was to happen how was 2 guards ever going to be enough?
3106	Good comment, well said.
3209	great to see the good religion is apparently doing these days.
3344	We need to start destroying and calling out these subhuman jihadist scum rather than engaging in moral relativism all the time.
3543	Islam is just a nuisance everywhere in the world. It makes me so mad.
3723	Islam is just a nuisance everywhere in the world. It makes me so mad.
3803	I wouldn't say it's the religion. It's the few crazy individuals who follow that particular religion. Also note that there are insane people all over the world who aren't Muslim though we tend to focus on one particular group
4144	I wouldn't say it's the religion. It's the few crazy individuals who follow that particular religion. Also note that there are insane people all over the world who aren't Muslim though we tend to focus on one particular group
4380	You list all the other religious murders around the world and I'll list all the Islamist/Muslim ones. 
4484	Give a minute though, I'm going to need a bigger pen.
4614	It is utterly shocking just how far down the running order most media outlets are posting this, even allowing for the fact it is happening to Brown people in a far off land.
4789	In one a spat between Gove and Burnham is more important.:eek:
4922	Absolutely disgraceful. What was upsetting is I was following the story from pretty early on, and they were initially reporting there were around 15 deaths. Then I went out and came back to see the death toll had risen tenfold, was speechless.
5284	I wouldn't say it's the religion. It's the few crazy individuals who follow that particular religion. Also note that there are insane people all over the world who aren't Muslim though we tend to focus on one particular group
5520	It's the religion too.
5544	The most explicit of all the Abrahamic religions in advocating the takeover and expulsion/conversion of natives and usurping of all lands.
5684	It's mandated in the Qur'an to keep fighting indefinitely.
5744	Hence why we won't see an end to this. Just periods of calm which are also mandated in the Qur'an, where Muslims are instructed to only offer temporary peace deals when they are in a position of weakness.
5950	When they are in a position of strength, they're mandated to wage war.
6022	Hence why when Hamas are being pummeled by Israel, they offer what's called a 'Hunda'. A temporary ceasefire but not a long lasting peace.
6162	The maximum length of a Hunda I believe is 10 years. 
6217	So in theory any peace for example with Hamas, would only last for 10 years and then they're religiously obliged to wage war against Israel again.
6479	You list all the other religious murders around the world and I'll list all the Islamist/Muslim ones. 
6583	Give a minute though, I'm going to need a bigger pen.
6647	What's the difference? Murder is murder!
6806	It's the religion too.
6830	The most explicit of all the Abrahamic religions in advocating the takeover and expulsion/conversion of natives and usurping of all lands.
6970	It's mandated in the Qur'an to keep fighting indefinitely.
7030	Hence why we won't see an end to this. Just periods of calm which are also mandated in the Qur'an, where Muslims are instructed to only offer temporary peace deals when they are in a position of weakness.
7236	When they are in a position of strength, they're mandated to wage war.
7308	Hence why when Hamas are being pummeled by Israel, they offer what's called a 'Hunda'. A temporary ceasefire but not a long lasting peace.
7448	The maximum length of a Hunda I believe is 10 years. 
7503	So in theory any peace for example with Hamas, would only last for 10 years and then they're religiously obliged to wage war against Israel again.
7660	http://www.channel4.com/news/palesti...criminal-court
7715	I wouldn't blame Hamas for that one! Watch the video attached
7850	this is utterly revolting. to murder Christians at any time is appalling, but at Easter is beyond belief. these terror scum must be destroyed.
8104	We need to start destroying and calling out these subhuman jihadist scum rather than engaging in moral relativism all the time.
8242	That won't do anything... People need to understand that islam is at the root of evil. As long as we don't admit it, nothing will change.
