94	Trouble in the land of Barry's birth
209	Given the circumstances, he's probably OK with it:
261	Al-Shabaab reportedly claims responsibility for deadly attack on Kenyan college
411	They attacked Kenyon College?
519	Hopefully, the violence didn't spill over into the boxes HUSSEIN'S family lives in.
714	Hopefully, the violence didn't spill over into the boxes HUSSEIN'S family lives in.
808	That could cause catastrophic losses in the dollars.
961	They attacked Kenyon College?
1001	Full of aspiring constitutional scholars, I'm sure.
1126	Over 70 Christians dead, workplace violence in the fatherland!
1261	So Al-Shababb, Boko Haram, Al Queda, and ISIS are all joined together and slaughtering Christians or Non-Muslims. Obama and Kerry are willfully giving the Persians the Bomb. The Middle East is in flames and Israel is being backed into a corner and will have to make preemptive strikes...
1550	I got money that says Barry is glued to ESPN and won't miss a minute of the Final Four with his buddy Al...
1765	They attacked Kenyon College?
1805	I'm sorry, but I just laughed out loud in the office...  Big Grin
1983	Hopefully, the violence didn't spill over into the boxes HUSSEIN'S family lives in.
2100	That could cause catastrophic losses in the dollars.
2173	Possibly in the dozens!
2276	Death toll may be up to 150.....
2310	http://www.foxnews.com/world/2...arissa-attack-kenya/
2434	Of all the stupid reasons to kill someone or be killed, religious pissing matches have to be right up there as the most ridiculous.
2669	Of all the stupid reasons to kill someone or be killed, religious pissing matches have to be right up there as the most ridiculous.
2811	So if someone invades you in the name of religion, you shouldn't resist? Like all those Yazidis in Iraq?
3015	Of all the stupid reasons to kill someone or be killed, religious pissing matches have to be right up there as the most ridiculous.
3180	So if someone invades you in the name of religion, you shouldn't resist? Like all those Yazidis in Iraq?
3305	Of course you should! Killing an invader or someone threatening your life is in no way stupid. The original premise for the invasion on the basis of religion is VERY stupid.
3580	Of all the stupid reasons to kill someone or be killed, religious pissing matches have to be right up there as the most ridiculous.
3722	I agree. "My imaginary friend is better than your imaginary friend."
3792	F'in whackos
3904	Of all the stupid reasons to kill someone or be killed, religious pissing matches have to be right up there as the most ridiculous.
4067	I agree. "My imaginary friend is better than your imaginary friend."
4137	F'in whackos
4170	Well, to some, it is far more important than "imaginary". I don't have a problem with it until they start killing to impose their beliefs on others.
4396	I'm a simple person and I believe our military is there to smite evil. This is pure evil.
4563	Obama released a statement about the massacre that did not mention Islam, Muslims, or even Christians. It was just some unfortunate massacre that occurred due to some unknown reason.
4747	https://www.whitehouse.gov/the...ege-terrorist-attack
4802	Michelle and I join the American people in expressing our horror and sadness at the reports coming out of Garissa, Kenya. Words cannot adequately condemn the terrorist atrocities that took place at Garissa University College, where innocent men and women were brazenly and brutally massacred. We join the world in mourning them, many of whom were students pursuing an education in the pursuit of a better life for themselves and their loved ones. They represented a brighter future for a region that has seen too much violence for far too long. We also commend the heroism of the responders who lost their lives in the selfless protection of the students and faculty. 
5472	I know firsthand the extraordinary resilience and fundamental decency of the people of Kenya. So I know that the people of Garissa and all of Kenya will grieve, but their determination to achieve a better and more secure future will not be deterred. And neither will the resolve of the United States. We will stand hand-in-hand with the Kenyan Government and people against the scourge of terrorism and in their efforts to bring communities together. This much is clear: the future of Kenya will not be defined by violence and terror; it will be shaped by young people like those at Garissa University College – by their talents, their hopes, and their achievements. This is a message I will relay to the Kenyan people when I visit Kenya in July. Even at this difficult hour, the Kenyan people should know they have an unwavering friend and ally in the United States of America.
6427	I understand on Easter Sunday Obama took the opportunity to comment on "less than kind Christians".
6599	Obama is a fraud in so many ways.
6714	Zippy said:
6726	the Kenyan people should know they have an unwavering friend and ally in the United States of America.
6830	hoo-boy they are screwed now. they should have kept it on the DL.
