94	Boris Nemtsov Assasinated Near Kremlin
215	Putin's loudest critic Boris Nemtsov was shot near the steps of the Kremlin, days before a march against Putin's economic policies. The march which was to be held today is now a memorial march for Nemtsov.
422	Thousands March in Moscow in Memory of Boris Nemtsov
475	http://www.wsj.com/articles/thousand...sov-1425223254
530	Investigators say there are no suspects in the murder of the opposition leader, who was shot dead steps from the Kremlin
652	Fear Envelops Russia After Killing of Putin Critic Boris Nemtsov
717	http://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/01/wo...in-russia.html
772	Boris Nemtsov's 'ghastly' murder could hurt Putin: Alexander Downer
840	http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/nati...01-13s4z3.html
895	Russians march in memory of murdered Putin critic
945	https://uk.news.yahoo.com/russians-m...1.html#oXNzSKZ
1000	I was watching an interview with Garry Kasparov this morning:
1063	http://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-pres...russia-n315141
1118	and he described the fear critics had even before Nemtsov's murder. If the name Garry Kasparov sounds familiar then you were chess aware in the 80s. Kasparov was one of the youngest world champion chess phenoms ever and became famous for his chess game against the IBM computer Deep Blue. It also cost his chess organization it's major sponsorship from Intel as IBM was their biggest rival at that time.
1523	I am saddened that this assassination is just another example of people dying for justice at the hands of cowards. I'll say it over and over again, those whose truth isn't good enough, or strong enough will act out by lying or even violence because they are a coward that isn't mature enough to handle reality.
1912	Not surprising if it's true. Scapegoating has become the sport of presidents and kings.
2001	Kelly McParland: Putin finds a convenient scapegoat for Nemtsov killing, while admitting he lied about Crimea
2112	No one in Russia believes the official explanation for Boris Nemtsov's murder
2190	http://www.businessinsider.com/the-r...#ixzz3TzcMy5Qq
2245	Nemtsov murder: Yashin sceptical of Russian arrests
2297	http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-31792844
2413	Same as that White House aid that riled Ms Clinton? Vince Foster? Witnesses came forward that LBJ had at least 6 people rubbed out.
