94	10 doctors ‘shot dead’ after refusing to treat ISIS militants
239	Wow, debunked as war propaganda. New York Post willingly ran misattributed pictures.
404	I would like to take a moment here and point out that the picture used in this article as proof of this terrible story is not true, and has been used in articles dating back to June of 2014, at least.
909	I didn't think doctors were supposed to have political boundaries. I thought doctors were supposed to help people that are ill regardless of what that person believes. But, it is ISIS, and I fucking hate ISIS and the retards that compose its membership, so fuck ISIS for killing doctors.
1272	These are the heroes, lads.
1371	muslims at their best...yea right...
1480	It is better to die on your feet, than to live on your knees.
1615	I salute those doctors. They knew the risk they faced not treating those terrorist assholes, but faced death bravely. They deserve all the virgins those asshole suicide bombers think they'll get in heaven.
1899	I guess next time they're better off treating them... badly. "I just need to give you this needle to put you asleep [forever]". idealy, ricin, so the death is delayed.
2146	I read somewhere that there is a breakout of leishmaniasis in syria...right where ISIS currently is holed up. The problem with this disease is being holed up with the sandflies that transmit the infection. Poor hygiene and sanitation make perfect vectors. Oh, and doctors and meds are needed to fix it.
2519	There is every good reason to have the whole world cooperate to eliminate these ISIS people. Death is too good for them.
2715	I am the 666th comment!!! 1! 11!!
2827	Source that isn't a shitty tabloid?
2939	There isn't enough content here for me to be able to judge if I'm looking at propaganda or not. However I like the idea that they are having problems with leishmaniasis.
3178	Becoming a doctor = smart Being near Isis = not smart
3312	Sounds like ISIS is with the HMOs. amarite?
3426	Eh, what kinda doctor wont treat a patient in need regardless of who they are!? Its not a doctor's job to judge and play god, or separate the bad from the good.
3588	I wish the article had something more to go on about the details of the circumstances(?), if there were other patients that required more immediate attention(?), anything else that would let the reader know more about the actual story. Based on the facts presented, those doctors should really have just treated them like any other patient.
4007	Because fuck them, thats why.
4113	Good thing we're letting them run around and do that. I mean since doctors grow on trees these days.
4284	I thought they didn't want to be treated. Isn't there some sort of face disease running rampant through their camps?
4473	Seriously docs. Treat them, but leave a little something behind so they die slowly later.
4564	You're better off to the world alive than dead. Don't die for these fucks.
4711	I admire their bravery
4806	Heros. All of them.
4909	So we can we just tell the Mexican cartel they made fun of there mom's or something?
5075	Hold up...
5087	How can a doctor refuse treatment?
5123	Doctors aren't supposed to judge or see sides... they treat the sick and injured. End of story.
5220	To everyone saying, "What bravery..." it's crap.
5270	We're no better than savages if our doctors won't treat our enemies.
5340	These doctors violated any number of oaths they took by refusing treatment to a patient. Let's cite this one http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Declaration_of_Geneva
5501	"I will not permit considerations of age, disease or disability, creed, ethnic origin, gender, nationality, political affiliation, race, sexual orientation, social standing or any other factor to intervene between my duty and my patient;"
5813	In theory yes, doctors shouldn't deny care to anyone who needs it.
5881	In practice these people rape, massacre, behead and burn people alive. Can't really deny people care if they're not human.
6078	Why are ISIS fighters going to be treated anyway? They were obviously stricken by disease in combat, they should accept the fate Allah has decided and die as martyrs.
6315	I would have treated them but I sure would not be sanitary about it!
6456	Article referring to a source, that refer to another source, that refer to another source. Yep, that's modern news.
6643	good thing Israeli doctors never refuse to treat ISIS militants.
6786	I'm not pro-ISIS or anything, but aren't doctors supposed to help anyone? Hippocratic Oath and all that? Or is that just a movie thing?
6995	They're meant to yes, but that's just in theory.
7045	ISIS though rape 1000s of women and children, burn people alive and behead innocents. In my books, every fewer member they have is a good thing.
7268	ITT: Idiots advocating murder.
7300	I'm glad you all have such high opinions of yourselves that you think it's not a big deal to be trusted with the power of life over death, and be able to consciously choose to condemn someone to die.
7501	These ISIS guys aren't faceless demons. Quit buying into everything the news tells you.
7665	I would have just pretended to treat them and just let them die.
7804	Yeah, turns out, they're not really a nice group...duh.
7938	Some would say they violated their vows of medical ethics. Some would say a doctor should treat anyone in need, regardless of creed or beliefs. Even enemy combatants receive medical care, for instance.
8141	Of course, ISIS militants aren't so much "enemy combatants" as they are rabid dogs. So I'm not saying the doctors should have necessarily treated them.
8364	It was a good chance to show compassion that was wasted.
8497	that'll sure change their minds
8601	Why dont they just ask Allah to heal them?
8721	Seriously?
8733	The New York Post citing The Daily Mail is the journalistic equivalent of a dog gobbling up another dog's diarrhoea
8921	That's an impossible situation on so many levels. On the one hand, you have ISIS, who if saved would continue their rampage of terror and murder. On the other hand, you have the threat against your life and the Hippocratic Oath to proserve and heal all injured. It's a terrible choice to have to make.
9301	This isn't the first time they've done something scummy like this. They blew up/shot up a hospital and took out tens of Drs and nurses in Afghanistan. Fucks
9539	Truth is, those assholes might have killed them afterwards anyway. I say, treat the injuries, leave infection causing bits inside, let Allah sort them out.
9766	Part of me thinks --- Can we just please unleash the fucking BoDog Drone apocalypse on these fuckers already? There's gotta be back log of DARPA stuff they haven't had a chance to test out yet. The other part of me reflects that ISIS is part of the hangover from our prior adventures in foreign policy. Still, these guys are reaching caricature levels of violence.
10208	My SO insists ISIS has been misrepresented by the media. They are just militant resistance fighters fed up with American interference.
10522	Well... if you believe that there's a grand conspiracy between the government, media (which always lies), and military to control the US populace and fund more wars it's not a completely idiotic conclusion.
10730	To be clear I do think the above is mostly incorrect.
10861	It's possible...It's possible that these wars are fought "to defend and continue our American way of life."
10970	As in...we need fuel for energy, right? We gotta get it cheap from somewhere...and OPEC is making that difficult....
11088	Haha, I can play both sides...But really, I don't bother with politics. It's all a joke in the end right? I'm no activist.
11288	Like I said, most of the stuff I posted above I consider unrealistic.
11359	The part I consider partially accurate is regarding the media, but that's mostly because it's in their interest to report what people will pay attention to, regardless of accuracy, and not with malicious intent.
11572	Edit: And yes, I do agree with you that wars are fought to continue our way of life. I do think it's sometimes immoral to do so to the extent that we push it.
11808	Definitely immoral but most Americans are comfortable, busy and entertained so we don't realize or care.
11986	whats that gif from if you don't mind me asking ?
12113	That's comedian/actress is Janeane Garofalo.
12159	I don't know where the specific gif came from though.
12214	Edit: It's from "The Cable Guy".... wtf, I watched that movie 1k+ times as a kid and I didn't remember her.
