How the Wives of ISIS Are Attracting Western Women to Syria
Women are joining ISIS at an ever-growing rate. Could online recruitment by
current jihadi wives be a factor?
“You can find shampoos soaps and other female necessities here, so do not
stress if you think you will be experiencing some cavewomen life here. …And
lastly for the married sisters or soon to be married, bring makeup and
jewellery from the West because trust me there is absolutely nothing here.
…Unless you plan on looking like a clown ting.”
These are the words Umm Layth published on her Tumblr, “Diary of a
Muhajirah,” meaning one who has made the “hijrah,” or journey to the
Islamic State. Umm Layth is a blogger from the north of Britain who is now
living in the Syrian town of Manbij. She is one of a growing number of Western
women who have gone to Syria to pledge their lives to ISIS—and the men of
ISIS. Manbij, her new home, is a small town in the Aleppo governate, where
images show squat concrete buildings adorned with the extremist group’s
black-and-white logo. ISIS has controlled the town since January 2014.
Sometimes Umm Layth’s posts are more philosophical:
“We are created to be mothers and wives—as much as the western society has
warped your views on this with a hidden feminist mentality.”
Another woman, who goes by the name of Umm Muawiyah, arrived in the area
controlled by ISIS on Oct. 8, tweeting:
“Alhamdulillah [thank God]. I have made it to Dar al-Islam and am finally
living under the shade of the Sharia. Join me my brothers and sisters.”
Prior to the first photo from her travels into Syria, her Twitter timeline was
a mixture of discussion about ISIS and jokes about having to study “the
stages of a break up” for her A-levels, exams British students typically
take when they reach 18 years old. On Sept. 21, she tweeted:
“Psychology a2 is so buff, guys.”
ISIS has proved to be adept at using social media, and the group’s female
followers, particularly those from England, are no exception. Glancing at
assorted tweets, Tumblrs, Instagram, Ask.fm pages and Facebook accounts of
ISIS supporters, it’s initially tricky to distinguish between the online
white noise of 15-year-olds in Wigan, an English town, who want to seem edgy
by supporting the group, and genuine followers on the ground.
A closer look, however, shows a cadre of real ISIS followers who have made the
hijrah and are leaving an online account of the day-to-day workings of life
under ISIS. By adopting a more everyday, accessible approach to their posts,
the women have carved out a social media niche, composing listicles like “10
Marriage Facts From the Islamic State,” which was published by a blogger who
goes by “Bird of Jannah,” referring to the Islamic name for heaven. The
list includes details such as how the Euphrates is every newlywed’s favorite
date spot, and how married mujahideen are given seven days off, and a gift of
$700 by ISIS.
The women broadcast their realities through social media much like anyone of
their generation, using the platforms to make sense of their lives by sharing
personal details and reflections in public. Their ability to be relatable has
made these women a crucial part of the ISIS media machine. And just like their
male counterparts, the women are fighting a running battle with the Twitter
police, who frequently suspend their accounts.
