Death threats and a late night dinner before Russia's Nemtsov was shot dead
It was near closing time on Friday at the upscale Bosco restaurant that looks
out onto the illuminated red-brick walls of Moscow's Kremlin. Boris Nemtsov
and his young, dark-haired girlfriend were finishing dinner.
A political reformer who had fallen foul of Russian President Vladimir Putin,
Nemtsov had been preoccupied for weeks with details of an opposition march
planned for Sunday.
Dinner at Bosco - dishes include beef with rocket salad and balsamic sauce or
duck liver with wild berries - had been interrupted by telephone calls, a
waiter told a Russian newspaper. Nemtsov also broke off for an interview with
a Ukrainian radio station eager for the details of the rally.
Hopes were high that the demonstration, to condemn Putin's economic and
foreign policies, would rekindle the flames of the street protests that in
2011-12 posed the first public challenge to Putin's more than decade-long
rule.
The pair were among the last to pay their bill in the restaurant with its high
airy ceilings and large windows. At around 11 p.m. Nemtsov, 55, a tall
athletic figure with a mop of curly brown greying hair, escorted his
girlfriend of some three years, Anna Duritskaya, more than 30 years younger,
out onto Red Square.
Opposite them, across the cobbles stood the marble tomb that still bears the
body of Bolshevik leader Vladimir Lenin, whose communist economic order
Nemtsov helped dismantle after the 1991 collapse of the Soviet Union.
Nemtsov's apartment was a half hour walk away at a leisurely pace. The couple
turned left, passing to their right the candy-coloured onion domes of St
Basil's Cathedral. Beyond that, soared the Kremlin's Spassky Gate topped with
glowing crimson five-pointed star, another reminder of the Soviet past.
Further down the slope, they walked onto the Great Moskvoretsky Bridge; but
Nemtsov never made it across.
Less than three hours later, policemen were washing his blood from the masonry
and onto the banks of the Moscow River. He had been shot four times in the
back and head in one of the worst shootings Moscow has seen in years.
Nemtsov had enemies politically and personally. Even among the opposition, his
outsized character pulled some into his orbit and pushed others away, at times
polarising the fractious team of oppositionists.
But for Nemtsov, the biggest opponent sat in the Kremlin.
Only hours earlier, Nemtsov had given one of his last interviews, criticising
Putin, comparing his rule to the Nazi Third Reich and promising an uprising
from the streets.
"We need to work as quickly as possible to show the Russians that there is an
alternative, that Putin's policy leads to degradation and a suicide of the
state. There is less and less time to wake up," Nemtsov told a correspondent
for the Polish edition of Newsweek.
"PUTIN AND WAR"
There was a time when Nemtsov's own sights were set on the country's top seat
of power. Amidst the chaos of the 1990s, president Boris Yeltsin had marked
out Nemtsov, then a young, reform-minded deputy prime minister who had made
fast friends with the country's richest and most powerful oligarchs.
Yeltsin had considered handing him the reins of power, but ultimately ceded
the presidency to a little known ex-KGB officer: Vladimir Putin.
Photographs from Nemtsov's political career as a deputy prime minister and
opposition lawmaker show very formal interactions with Putin, the two shaking
hands at a distance with fixed smiles.
But in recent years Nemtsov had become a greater thorn in Putin's side,
compiling reports on sensitive topics - one that tried to expose the scale of
corruption at the 2014 Sochi Winter Olympics.
Nemtsov's friends said his latest effort was to expose the presence of Russian
troops in eastern Ukraine, where NATO, Kiev and Western governments say Russia
has sent soldiers and weapons to support an armed uprising there.
Moscow has denied the accusations repeatedly.
"Boris Nemtsov received threats in the past, mostly anonymous ones. That was
the nature of things," said Nemtsov's fellow opposition leader Ilya Yashin.
While Nemtsov received threats, law enforcement sources said he never went to
the police to ask for protection. But as time passed, his worries grew. In an
interview on Feb. 10 with lesser known Internet outlet Sobesednik, Nemtsov
said that his mother had started to worry that Putin could have Nemtsov killed
for his opposition politics.
The journalist asks: "After such conversations with your mother did you begin
to worry that Putin could kill you either personally or through an
intermediary?"
Nemtsov: "You know, yeah... a little. Not so much as mama, but still."
SURVEILLANCE
Investigators say the killers drove past Nemtsov and Duritskaya in a white
Ford as they turned from Red Square onto the bridge, firing six bullets from a
Makarov pistol, the kind used for years by Soviet and Russian police officers.
Four of the bullets hit their mark in Nemtsov's back and head, killing him
immediately.
In the minutes leading up to the shooting, a law enforcement source told
Russian news agency Interfax that a spotter for the attackers watched the pair
turn onto the bridge before giving the signal to attack - proof that the
killing had been planned.
Opposition leader Alexei Navalny, whose star had eclipsed Nemtsov's in the
years that followed the 2011-12 street protests, met with Nemtsov on an
infrequent basis, and usually just to discuss logistics of protests, as they
did several weeks previously.
Navalny wrote on his Facebook page on Saturday he knew people were following
the leaders of the demonstration, which planned to protest against the
political and economic policies the opposition says are leading Russia to
ruin.
Weeks previously he had met in private with Nemtsov only to have the former
governor later recount to him in a phone call how he was later called by a
pro-Kremlin reporter to ask about the details of the secret meeting.
"We all saw many times the publication of (video and voice recordings) of
Nemtsov," wrote Navalny.
"I practically exclude that surveillance was not being carried out on Boris
Nemtsov last night," he wrote.
It was a ten minute car drive to Bosco from the radio station facilities of
Echo Moskvy, one of Moscow's last independent minded media outlets, where
Nemtsov did an on air radio interview right before dinner.
Following news of Nemtsov's death, Echo Moskvy editor in chief Alexei
Venediktov tweeted a photo of himself and Nemtsov.
"Today ahead of broadcasting, Boris asked me 'aren't you afraid of having me
on air?' It wasn't me who should have been afraid."
