Monica Lewinsky’s story needs to begin a new chapter: Timson
I still don’t know what to make of Monica Lewinsky.
The former White House intern whose name, at 24, became worldwide shorthand
for, as she said recently, “tramp, tart, slut, whore, bimbo and of course
That Woman” after her sexual relationship with then President Bill Clinton
resulted in his impeachment (spoiler alert, he survived nicely) is now 41,
back in the spotlight, and saying some wise things.
“Insist on a different ending to your story,” Lewinsky said last week in a
universally acclaimed TED Talk condemning “public shaming as a blood
sport.”
Describing herself as “patient zero” in internet shaming — there was no
social media in 1998, but news of her affair with Clinton as a young woman
first broke on the gossipy online Drudge Report — Lewinsky called for a
revolution in “compassion and empathy”.
She described how humiliated she had been when salacious details became
public: “I lost my reputation, my dignity, I almost lost my life.”
Those details included snapping her thong at the pathetically weak-willed
president to get his attention, administering oral sex to him beneath his desk
as he talked to congressional leaders, and that infamous blue dress stained
with his bodily fluids that made its way into rap songs
She was fat shamed — one paper called her “the portly pepper pot” —
slut shamed, and portrayed as an opportunistic sexual predator — albeit one
who snagged the biggest predator of all.
Lewinsky’s TED Talk was beautifully rendered, as was her earlier essay in
Vanity Fair magazine in which she had a sharp message for feminist thought
leaders who were so desperate to keep a Democratic president in office they
formed a mean girls club of their own, cackling about everything from her
“third stage gum disease” to whether other men would go after what Bill
Clinton had enjoyed: “I sorely wished for some sign of understanding from
the feminist camp ... Given the issues at play — gender politics, sex in the
workplace — you’d think they would have spoken up.”
Lewinsky did lose much of her life. With a graduate degree from the London
School of Economics, she seems not to have achieved any of the personal or
professional milestones a smart, personable woman of her age normally would
have—no career, no permanent relationship, no family of her own.
She puts it down to the outpouring of ridicule and opprobrium that first
paralyzed her, and then to the ongoing prurience that never let people see her
as a real human being.
Yet 17 years is a long time to wander in the wilderness of shame. I know women
who have recovered from deep personal trauma and gone on to have productive
lives. Why not Monica Lewinsky?
Thankfully, she does not paint herself totally as a victim—she laments her
“poor choices”.
But she is disingenuous in saying her big mistake was “I fell in love with
my boss.” That makes her sound like everywoman in an office, instead of what
she was—attention seeking, foolhardy, and very proactive in pursuing what
she calls “a consensual” relationship with a powerful man whose roving eye
was well known.
I’ve never understood why she kept that incriminating blue dress, stained
with the semen of the most powerful man in the world. She testified that her
“frenemy,” government employee Linda Tripp, who ultimately outed her,
“told me that I should put it in a safe-deposit box because it could be
evidence one day. And I said that was ludicrous because I would never — I
would never disclose that I had a relationship with the president.”
She was forced to do just that under oath by very scary men, including odious
prosecutor Ken Starr, who admitted he “loved the narrative” of shame he
had uncovered. The result was a moral and political cataclysm in America.
And now, just as Hillary Clinton, who in wifely frustration once called her a
“narcissistic loony tune,” is embarking on her presidential bid, Lewinsky
is back, declaring she has been “stuck” for too long, and it’s time to
“bury the blue dress and move forward.”
Timing is everything. Would people have paid this much attention if the
Clintons were not still dominating the news cycle?
Here’s a startling thought. Monica Lewinsky may ultimately be credited as
the catalyst for the first female American president.
In Carl Bernstein’s excellent 2007 Hillary Clinton biography, A Woman in
Charge, he argues it was shortly after the devastating Lewinsky scandal, that
Clinton made up her mind to separate herself from her husband’s agenda and
run for the Senate. Without her successful tenure as a senator, Clinton could
not run for president.
Hah. F. Scott Fitzgerald got it seriously wrong when he argued there were
“no second acts” in American life. The Clintons and now Monica Lewinsky
are having spectacular second acts.
But I hope for her sake that Lewinsky, after contributing profoundly to an
urgent conversation about how badly we treat each other online, can stop using
her beleaguered past and get on with living a life complete with meaningful
work and relationships.
Lewinsky can’t change or deny the past but the really triumphant ending she
should insist on would be in not letting it—in bad or even good
ways—define her one second longer.
