Netanyahu Says He Didn’t Mean Any of It, Loves America, Could Maybe Be OK With a Palestinian State 
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has wasted no time in trying to walk back the rhetoric used in the closing days of his ultimately successful re-election campaign. Tellingly, he chose to do so in the American media, telling NBC’s Andrea Mitchellthat America has no greater ally than Israel and Israel has no greater ally than the United States.”
This comes after a campaign that included a commercial arguing that Israel wouldn’t exist if it always listened to America, an allegation that U.S. money was driving high Arab turnout, and, of course, a speech to the U.S. Congress that infuriated the Obama administration and many Democrats. President Obama has not yet called to congratulate Netanyahu on his victory, and White House officials say Netanyahu’s campaign comments, which included a disavowal of Palestinian statehood, could lead to a “reassessment” of the U.S.-Israeli relationship.
Read more @: http://www.slate.com/blogs/the_slatest/2015/03/19/netanyahu_…e_didn_t_mean_any_of_it_loves_america_could_maybe_be_ok.html
Read more @: Netanyahu Says He Didn’t Mean Any of It, Loves America, Could Maybe Be OK With a Palestinian State 
Blah blah. Again. 
What he is saying now is entirely consistent with what he said before. 
And he was right before. And you are still wrong.
Blah blah. Again. 
What he is saying now is entirely consistent with what he said before. 
And he was right before. And you are still wrong.
What words? Quote pls.
Bibi said America has no greater ally than Israel. Israel is a staunch ally of the US but that comment alone just shows Bibi's arrogance and ignorance of other Countries relationship with the US. 
My Country remains the only country to have served loyally alongside the United States in every major conflict since WWII. Netanyahu needs to get over himself. His Country is no more a greater Ally to the US than mine has ever been.
What words? Quote pls.
Did someone not read the article?
Did someone not read the article?
Post the quote.
What words? Quote pls.
Israel's PM Netanyahu: No Palestinian state on my watch - CNN.com
Israel's PM Netanyahu: No Palestinian state on my watch - CNN.com
That's not a quote.
Did someone not read the article?
Can someone not pull quotes to back up his own claims?
