Poll on Pistorius: If it was not Reeva behind the door?
and it was in fact an intruder, would you have had expected him to walk free from Court? 
I have read number of user comments on case articles online and in the newspaper this morning and a good number of people have expressed their belief that irrespective of whether or not it was Reeva in the cubicle, the fact that Pistorius knew a human being was in there when he fired the four shots means that for them the five year sentence was too lenient. 
Did it not matter that it was Reeva in the cubicle for the purposes of conviction and sentencing?
Update: Just to clarify I am not wanting to know the legal position I just want your personal desire/opinion on this. If it turned out to have been an intruder would you still want to see Pistorius jailed and if so, for five years or less than five years?
My opinion is that the moment someone decides to break into someone else's house and steal or hurt them, they lose all their rights. While I don't condone killing them, if it had been an intruder inside his bathroom, I would have been OK in him spending no time in jail.
There are few legal systems that try cases on the basis of possibility or supposition. There is a very good reason for this. Even poor legal standards, still require the test of actuality and evidence in reaching their findings. People are convicted on the basis of what they did... not what they might have done. 
To turn legal process into some sort of X-Factor form of legal justice, would be disastrous for any collective understanding. Even the most irresponsible, violent and radical regimes in history... have never done that. Why?... because if a court (any court) starts to bend the facts... it ignores the truth. 
What happened that night, is what happened. It undeniably was Reeva behind that door. If her family accept that... then maybe we should too. 
Other than the possibility of an appeal, based upon the failure of the 'prosecution' to secure a murder conviction... the matter is resolved, and international standards of law and process have been observed. 
Unless you want legal findings to be based upon 'gossip', inference and the whims of the media?
Depends what the law is in South Africa on defending your property. Obviously in the UK you cannot just shoot someone unless it is in self defense, whereas in Texas a home owner is allowed to shoot intruders to defend their property (so I am led to believe). But if the law is the same in South Africa as in the UK I would expect him to go to prison. 
I do not believe that he did not think there was at least a strong possibility that Reeva was the other side of the door and thus he deserved prison. 
EDIT I do not support the right of people to act as Judge Jury and executioner and to shoot to kill with no warning. The only reason for killing someone, in my opinion, is self defense or defense of another. He knew when he shot at that door there was a good chance he would kill who was on the other side and as far as I am aware he issued no warnings. So yes he does deserve prison.
He knew it was no intruder when she was not in the room with him.I think he got away with murder because he may not spend any time in actual jail.
