What are the terrorists after?
I've always been wondering why groups like ISIS and Al-Shabaab do what they do, and how can they recruit so many people?What are they trying to accomplish? 
People I've discussed this with say it's all about just throwing their weight around and murdering for fun all while saying it is for religion. What are they trying to do? What do they stand for? 
My mom explained it as that being radical comes with being Muslim and we got into a horrible argument about terrorism. She kept claiming that being Muslim is bad and that it makes someone a terrorist. After all, what are these groups trying to do? Make Islam better. I disagreed.... 
Why are these people attacking innocents? Do they really believe they have something to say, or is it just killing on another level?
It's not that they are Muslim, because there are terrorists of every religion including christian terror groups. It is not so much the religion but because they are extremists. People will always do almost anything for their beliefs, and when you put a crazy extremist in charge of a lot of other crazy extremists that all have the same  religion and belief system they tend to decide their belief should govern the world. Then some will want to be part of the "in crowd" As more people join, even more will decide to as well. Every religion believes they are right and the others are wrong. Many people say they are abused by other religions, but that is because they are just as abusive to the other religions. I hate to hear my fellow Christians talk about how they are the only saved ones and that the other denominations are false and evil, and say they are always abused when they do the most abusing to other sects. That is not what Christ taught, yet they still do it, just like the leaders of the other religions did not teach violence, yet these other groups still try to impose their will on others.
Terrorism is a criminal act intended to influence or effect people beyond it's immediate victims. Say I am a person who believes the United States is a great evil in the world who harms others. At this point, that belief doesn't have to be true. I don't need evidence for my argument. Everybody I tell about my belief, in fact laughs at me. So I plant a bomb that hurts and kills Americans. The Americans react harshly because they want to protect their own people and revenge their deaths. Within a week, U.S. jets bomb a village where they believed little ol'me was hiding. I go to that village and tell them how evil the Americans are as a country. I point out the bombed buildings and dead bodies as proof the Americans are evil. Now others believe me. They may have been convinced by my arguments or they just want revenge for their dead family members and friends, but now I have followers. So we give ourselves a name and start planting more bombs and killing more Americans. The Americans bomb more villages, towns, and cities, and I go and collect more followers. Pretty soon I have a small army of followers and with them I can do considerable damage to the Americans and the countries that support them. As long as the Americans over react to my attacks, I get new followers. My followers consider me a leader, a person of foresight, because I saw the evil of Americans before they showed it themselves. Over the years, if I play my cards right and actually avoid being killed by the Americans, their allies, or my own ambitious subordinates, I'll have enough people to take over a country. When that happens, I get real money and real power.
You, and me, basically, as members of the developed and secular world. They want to drag humanity back to their own brand of superstition and barbarism. That's why we have, in the last instance, to annihilate jihadism. Not Islam - liberal Islam, which does exist, is basically no worse than Catholicism. Bad, but perhaps amenable to gradual education. Jihadism, on the other hand, delenda est.
Most Terrorists 99% are Muslims 
a world run under Sharia I have Lived in 3 Muslim Countries and they all tried to make me Convert and many abused me because i was a Christian 
and Many refused to talk to me But being a Guest of the Government Kept their distance 
and Not one Muslim has ever made a Kind Gesture to me no matter what good i did for their country because i was an Infidel and an Unbeliever
Extremist Muslims are in a war of their own making for total world domination
Power. They use religion as a tool to dupe followers into doing anything they want.
The land of milk and honey + all the virgins they want. Other than this, I have NO IDEA. Thugs for the sake of thuggery - in the name of religion?
-Attention; Headlines, &amp; MORE Followers. And SO Far; That's EXACTLY what They're Getting. :(
They are after our heads, and anyone who will not conform to thier evil religious ideology. Now you know why they must be crushed with out pity.
they want to take over the world and impose their version of Islam on everyone.
