Clinton trumpets income inequality message in wake of Warren push
Clinton trumpets income inequality message in wake of Warren push
Source: http://www.cnn.com/2015/03/23/politi...obe-editorial/
Well, at least she(Hillary) is somewhat trying to attract the left...
She's less undesirable than the available alternatives, that's for sure.
If she just happened to pick Warren as a VP, that'd be a nice turn of events. But fucking swings states.
Bernie "Mothafuckin'" Sanders for Prez 2016
Like I said in another thread:
Quote Originally Posted by Naxere
I can't wait to see Hillary try and tout her populist appeal. It'll be good for a laugh at least.
Like with a lot of issues, wealth inequality is a balance problem. Which means those who are advantaged by the current system must be comparatively disadvantaged by any attempt to correct the injustices of that system. 
What we need to realize, as a society, is that unless your household income is over a half-million $US or so, you are not one of those who is being advantaged by the current system. If you're under that mark, you'll be better off if we redress the wealth inequality, and it's in your best interests to get on board. If you're over, well, I really don't see why I should give your complaints that much credence; you're the ones benefiting from the current unjust distribution, and you've got more than enough wealth (and will continue to) to assuage any negative impacts that result just fine. It's not like addressing wealth inequality means rich people go to the poorhouse. It just means that maybe they don't buy that third vacation home in the Hamptons.
When/if Clinton decides to take a hard stance on redressing this issue, rather than just paying it lip service, I'll start to get fired up over her candidacy.
Like I said in another thread:
At least it is marginally believable coming from her. Hell, even Mike Huckabee, who I do not like has been talking about it, and I could believe he was actually being ernest.
But coming from Cruz, or Ryan, or Romney? That is laughable.
Like with a lot of issues, wealth inequality is a balance problem. Which means those who are advantaged by the current system must be comparatively disadvantaged by any attempt to correct the injustices of that system. 
What we need to realize, as a society, is that unless your household income is over a half-million $US or so, you are not one of those who is being advantaged by the current system. If you're under that mark, you'll be better off if we redress the wealth inequality, and it's in your best interests to get on board. If you're over, well, I really don't see why I should give your complaints that much credence; you're the ones benefiting from the current unjust distribution, and you've got more than enough wealth (and will continue to) to assuage any negative impacts that result just fine. It's not like addressing wealth inequality means rich people go to the poorhouse. It just means that maybe they don't buy that third vacation home in the Hamptons.
When/if Clinton decides to take a hard stance on redressing this issue, rather than just paying it lip service, I'll start to get fired up over her candidacy.
Yeah, I am pretty much on the same page. She is trying, but it is hardly believable.
Like I said in another thread:
Retention of the status quo, as it is today, is still far more vastly appealing than an onslaught of reactionarianism.
Bernie "Mothafuckin'" Sanders for Prez 2016
I'd rather have Cruz.
Oh look, a bank pet and establishment crony whistling in tune of addressing real issues? Gee, I wonder where I've seen this one before..
Warren is the only real option.
Yeah, I am pretty much on the same page. She is trying, but it is hardly believable.
She's been too pro-corporate. I just can't believe she'll take a stance that's significantly aimed at negatively impacting corporate America and the 1%, which is fundamentally necessary to redress wealth inequality; there's only so much wealth, and to get more of it in the hands of the working poor and middle classes, it has to come from somewhere.
And before anyone says "class warfare! Redistribution!", it's already class warfare. The wealthy won, and redistributed the wealth upwards. That's why we're in this mess.
This is the same person that was giving speeches to groups of bankers for outrageous amounts of money? Yes...because when I think of someone who can relate to the struggling working class, I think of a Washington insider who has been neck-deep in DC politics for over 20 years.
LoL someone used the words Clinton and Income Inequality in the same sentence.
This is the same person that was giving speeches to groups of bankers for outrageous amounts of money? Yes...because when I think of someone who can relate to the struggling working class, I think of a Washington insider who has been neck-deep in DC politics for over 20 years.
Another issue, for me at least, is that she didnt leave her husband after he humiliated her in front of three hundred million people. It does not make her look like a strong leader to me. I believe a strong woman would have left a habitual cheater.
But coming from Cruz, or Ryan, or Romney? That is laughable.
Naxy won't stick around because he knows this is coming every time he makes a snarky comments about Hillary.
Remind me again, what does the conservative field look like?
This election is going to be hilarious.
Naxy won't stick around because he knows this is coming every time he makes a snarky comments about Hillary.
Remind me again, what does the conservative field look like?
This election is going to be hilarious.
I wonder if it will be as hilarious as the mid terms?
Another issue, for me at least, is that she didnt leave her husband after he humiliated her in front of three hundred million people. It does not make her look like a strong leader to me. I believe a strong woman would have left a habitual cheater.
What if she knew before and gave her blessing? Or do you actually believe that Bill Clinton was the first president in history to get head in the Oval Office or have sex outside of marriage? Or maybe, just maybe, that is a private issue between two married adults and it has nothing to do with anyone else?
Seriously, I guess I should have expected this from conservatives. Who cares about her policies when you can talk about how weak she looks "because reasons." That definitely explains how our country has been saddled with conservatives who are transparently crazy, obstructionist traitors.
I wonder if it will be as hilarious as the mid terms?
I guess I should clarify here, I mean a conservative from the US. Hillary would be the conservative candidate in most other countries. That is how disconnected from reality conservatives in the US are.
I wonder if it will be as hilarious as the mid terms?
With the number of people that turned out, yes. Unless we get an out Atheist, socialist running, anyone not a conservative would stand a good chance of winning. Because the general electorate is afraid of a tea party president, or the Ayn Rand acolytes running the country.
Normally, I'd take issue with this kind of statement, but honestly, I think the Republican Party is fracturing. A moderate candidate, like Romney was in 2012, doesn't fire up the Republican base, which is why Romney ended up losing, due to tepid support. An extremist right-wing candidate will lose the moderates. It isn't really possible for a single candidate to bring both branches of the party together, and it's going to hurt them.
I was actually hoping to see Huntsman run in 2012, and his early elimination from the primaries, to me, spoke volumes. Sensationalism was more productive than strength of policy.
I guess I should clarify here, I mean a conservative from the US. Hillary would be the conservative candidate in most other countries. That is how disconnected from reality conservatives in the US are.
Out of curiosity how shocked were you when the GOP took both houses?
That a conservative will be the next president is already determined. The only question is how far right they will be.
Out of curiosity how shocked were you when the GOP took both houses?
That's a pretty standard pattern. Mid-terms always have significantly lower turn-outs, and this generally affects the Democrats more seriously than the Republicans. Plus, you need to compare what seats were up for grabs, which also favored the Republicans in the last election.
