Iran Nuke Deal: Just how bad is it?
Is Obama now considered Chamberlainesque? Or, point forward, is Chamberlain now Obamaesque? 
To be fair to Toonces, an actual World War followed Chamberlain's lack of foresight and resolve. That hasn't happened yet in the Middle East. But paving Iran's way to nukes can only make the area more stable, yes? 
I don't think the price of oil will be down for too many years. Hold on to your minerals, gentlemen. 
What parts of the "agreement" do you find most objectionable?
There is no comparison. Obama is head of a supposed super-power. Chamberlain was dealing with a weak hand. His only choice to appeasement was war with the Reich then (he didn't know that a stance might have triggered Hitler's deposing, and didn't realize even Mussolini was still uncommitted.) And Deladier when returning to Paris in 1938 said "Fools!" under his breath when cheered. He knew they had at best, bought time. 
Obama's thing is different. It seems to be driven by something as weak as desire for a legacy. Hopefully that is not true, but when you think a bad deal is better than none, it looks more true. 
On the other hand, it seems there are things both sides don't like about the deal. A decent compromise tends to produce exactly such ambivalence. 
Its hard to tell. The fawning state of our media doesn't help. Otherwise could hope for the facts to be vetted out properly.
What are the best parts of the deal for us? Assuming the Mullahs keep with the the already disputed agreement. 
For all of this negotiating, what did we even get?
What parts of the "agreement" do you find most objectionable?
Does it matter what's in the deal? Seriously. Did it matter the details of the Munich Accord? 
In response to Iran publicly calling Obama a liar, liberals told us that Iran is not to be believed. They lie. 
So using the liberals' standards, Iran can be trusted to abide by this agreement?! 
Bizarro world.
That's part of the problem. So much has been kept secret, and when you couple that with this admin's penchant for deception, it leaves it uncertain. It also depends how much of the groundwork for this deal is pre-Obama, as it supposedly has been in the making a while. The greater the length of time, the more likely the deal is in fact, reasonable. Iran is a major state actor after all. 
Best can tell, it buys a few years where you know Iran is NOT building a nuke. But have no idea if that depends on verifications that are possible or not. 
However, this admin is so clumsy at foreign policy and big picture, it might still be worthwhile in this one case to kick the can down the road. Probably wouldn't want it in charge of such a confrontation, even if it means a risky wait. 
The one irony is that Munich deal had a `legacy' alright---but is it one that is to be envied?
And Titan is spot on about Chamberlain. Comparing Obama to Chamberlain is an insult to Chamberlain.
sq7: Just curious, what solution do you recommend? Declare war and invade? That is likely the only way to prevent Iran from joining the nuclear club, but it would open up a different set of problems. Iran is under extremely tough sanctions, thanks to the efforts of this administration. I am very skeptical of trusting Iran's leadership to abide by any agreement.
"We'll stop the centrifuges if you release your Harvard transcripts." 
"No deal, hummus breath."
http://scotthorton.org/interviews/2015/03/30/33015-tyler-cullis/ 
Quote:
Tyler Cullis, a Policy Associate at the National Iranian American Council, discusses the near-completion of an Iranian nuclear deal, and how eased economic sanctions will greatly improve the lives of ordinary Iranians.
sq7: Just curious, what solution do you recommend? Declare war and invade? That is likely the only way to prevent Iran from joining the nuclear club, but it would open up a different set of problems. Iran is under extremely tough sanctions, thanks to the efforts of this administration. I am very skeptical of trusting Iran's leadership to abide by any agreement.
Just as a different set of problems are opened up by them having nukes, yes? Like controlling the entirety of the Straits of Hormuz, foe example. Look, not every situation is the same, I know. Obviously, we are concerned about them acquiring nukes, otherwise why the dance? How much of Parliament put forth your first and second questions in 1938. And how many later admitted that it would have been better to deal with Hitler earlier rather than later? 
Am I smart enough to know? No. My concern is that the guy running the show is an intellectual phony, work and grade skating layabout with zero experience in this area. A guy who gave Queen Elizabeth, a woman who knew Churchill and listened to his war time speeches....live....an iPod with his vacuous campaign speeches written by staffers. He is unserious and incapable. 
I can only wonder if Israel will be less willing to play the part of Sudetenland in this updated version. 
A guy who gave Queen Elizabeth, a woman who knew Churchill and listened to his war time speeches....live....an iPod with his vacuous campaign speeches written by staffers. He is unserious and incapable. 
I had forgotten about that.
A guy who gave Queen Elizabeth, a woman who knew Churchill and listened to his war time speeches....live....an iPod with his vacuous campaign speeches written by staffers. He is unserious and incapable. 
I had forgotten about that.
I never forget it. It is like a punch to the gut thinking about it. Hell, why not a signed campaign poster for good measure? And a photo of himself to hang at Windsor Castle? 
What a clumsy, clueless tool. 
The Hell of it is...The Great Orator Barack has been in the public eye for 7 years now and I don't think he has a single memorable sentence or utterance. No "we choose to go to the moon"....no "tear down this wall"....no "the only thing we have to fear is fear itself". Nothing. Nada. 
Sorry, fanboys, but "we are the ones we have been waiting for" will not qualify. "You didn't build that", is his most memorable line and it was a gaffe. President Spock my ass.
Hopefully the next President will restore Churchill's bronze bust to its rightful place in the White House.
But those are exactly the reasons think, yes, maybe its for the best that this can be kicked past Jan 2017. Its hard to think can do worse, and for once it looks like the GOP may have a strong hand. Even the establishment candidates seem stronger. 
And for what it is worth, Iran really isn't ISIS. I know that is the picture painted, but it is highly doubtful they are just waiting to launch a nuke against Israel and thus detonate their own country. Remember, Israel is a nuclear power also. It is very scary, but still, Iran is probaby more likely to sit on a nuke like Pakistan did and does, and not deploy it. 
Instead, the real worry is how it might add to their ability to intimidate the Mideast and possibly trigger a proliferation race.
It is hard to tell how bad the deal is. Apparently the Devil is in the Details. Iranian and Obama stooges are telling conflicting stories of what is agreed too. Supposedly English and Farsi versions of the agreement differ on many issues. But, from what I understand: Iran gets to keep a bunch of Centrifuges and gets to keep spinning them doing what I am not sure, not a single Iranian Nuke Facility is shuttered, the inspectors can not make surprise inspections, Iranians won't come clean on what they have or what they have accomplished, Iranian created enriched nuclear material supposedly stays in Iran and may or may not be diluted back to lower levels. None of these sound like parts of a good deal. 
I think that the Israeli's will be the final judges of if it is a good deal or not and the Israeli's will err on the side of caution. 
The deal gives Iran a legitimate pathway to make nuclear bombs while we lift sanctions and free their economy to thrive. But it won't matter much because Iran won't recognize Israel's right to exist so Netanyahu very recently said yet again Israel won't let Iran have the bomb! Israel's existence depends on it and Istael will succeed.
The deal gives Iran a legitimate pathway to make nuclear bombs while we lift sanctions and free their economy to thrive. But it won't matter much because Iran won't recognize Israel's right to exist so Netanyahu very recently said yet again Israel won't let Iran have the bomb! Israel's existence depends on it and Istael will succeed.
So you honestly think Iran would nuke Israel?
Obama badly needs a foreign policy "win" and they were going to get some kind of deal by the deadline no matter what (though Iran and the US and France can't agree on what they agreed to in the framework agreement). There was NO way he was going to not get this done and leave it up to Congress. 
3 big problems with the deal: 
1. We know Iran cheats. They did in 2003 in the Nonproliferation agreement and they did in 2013 (despite Obama's claims they have 100% complied - he lies, also - the UN and IAEA say Iran did not comply in 2013). 
2. Inspections need to be anytime, anywhere and that almost certainly will not be the case in the final agreement. 
3. Snap-back Sanctions. This is a BS marketing term they came up with and is not realistic. Once sanctions are lifted or partially lifted there will be Asian and European countries that will rush in to grab some of the high potential Iranian market. These countries, along with China and Russia, could not care less whether Iran gets a nuke and they would rather enjoy the financial benefits of doing business with Iran. And since this will likely fall to the UN and China and Russia have a veto, the chances of sanctions getting reimposed is unlikely, especially under this Admin with how weak Obama has been. 
This whole thing is about getting a deal, a win, for this Admin and kicking the can down the road. If that means signing an agreement that we know Iran won't comply with down the road, so be it. That will be someone else's problem and Obama did his part. Perhaps the Nobel committee will deem him or Kerry worthy of another prize. 
We would be better off not doing a deal and leaving sanctions in place than removing sanctions when we know they will cheat anyway. Why let them take in billions of dollars, much of which will be funneled to their terror program, when we know their quest for a nuclear bomb will continue?
FIFY
The deal gives Iran a legitimate pathway to make nuclear bombs while we lift sanctions and free their economy to thrive. But it won't matter much because Iran won't recognize Israel's right to exist so Netanyahu very recently said yet again Israel won't let Iran have the bomb! Israel's existence depends on it and Istael will succeed.
So you honestly think Iran would nuke Israel?
Yes.
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
So they are suicidial?
So they are suicidial?
I'm not saying that Iran would nuke Israel. Israel has their own...and more...and probably a hell of a lot better delivery systems....but, suicide and martyrdom are two separate things.
The deal gives Iran a legitimate pathway to make nuclear bombs while we lift sanctions and free their economy to thrive. But it won't matter much because Iran won't recognize Israel's right to exist so Netanyahu very recently said yet again Israel won't let Iran have the bomb! Israel's existence depends on it and Istael will succeed.
So you honestly think Iran would nuke Israel?
What does it matter what he thinks? How is that relevant? If he doesn't believe it, does that change the mind of Israel?! 
Israel believes it and they are the ones who will respond accordingly.
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
Again for the 10000000th time, it's not about nuking someone. It's about them using the nuke as leverage to become the world's nightmare. 
They are already a menace. Just think what they'll be able to do with a bomb in their pocket.
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
Come on now Aggie4life, you know logic has no place in POTUS bashing.
So they are suicidial?
Absolutly! Iranian radical Muslims have been actively blowing themselves and others up. Their religion preaches death to infidels and rewards them with virgins after death. 
Why do you want Iran to have nuclear bombs? This nuclear deal gives them a clear pathway to the bomb and you are for it. Why? 
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
Come on now Aggie4life, you know logic has no place in POTUS bashing.
That's not logic. That's his opinion based on who knows what.
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
Again for the 10000000th time, it's not about nuking someone. It's about them using the nuke as leverage to become the world's nightmare. 
They are already a menace. Just think what they'll be able to do with a bomb in their pocket.
Probably the same thing Russia has done when they were the ultimate evil.
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
Come on now Aggie4life, you know logic has no place in POTUS bashing.
That's not logic. That's his opinion based on who knows what.
Having nukes has yet to equate to using them and never will because everyone know the moment they use it they cease to exist. Are the Iraninas who wish the ultimate death unto Israel, sure, and probably in the same amount that there are Israelis who wish the same to Iran. That they would use them and then become anihalated from the planet though, no.
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
Again for the 10000000th time, it's not about nuking someone. It's about them using the nuke as leverage to become the world's nightmare. 
They are already a menace. Just think what they'll be able to do with a bomb in their pocket.
Probably the same thing Russia has done when they were the ultimate evil.
Russia never harbored, trained, funded, backed and sponsored world terrorism. And Russia was not run by religious nuts. 
Apples and oranges.
Iran won't be nuking anybody, even if they had nukes.
Again for the 10000000th time, it's not about nuking someone. It's about them using the nuke as leverage to become the world's nightmare. 
They are already a menace. Just think what they'll be able to do with a bomb in their pocket.
Probably the same thing Russia has done when they were the ultimate evil.
Russia never harbored, trained, funded, backed and sponsored world terrorism. And Russia was not run by religious nuts. 
Apples and oranges.
So if Iran evolved into a completely secular country, with only political nuts (like we saw Russia for so many decade) and didn't do any of the other things you mentioan, then would you be okay with them having nukes?
The heads of the iranian regime want a nuke as a shield,long term. Not to use, but to threaten with and to bargain with and threaten retaliation with.
So Iran gets a nuke...and that just somehow occurs in a vacuum and fails to impact the rest of the region? 
Which other nations will want a nuke if the Iranians get one? Saudis perhaps? Jordan? 
So if you're the Jewish state of Israel, and you know that about a quarter billion Muslims want your entire nation wiped off the map, exactly how many majority Muslim nations would you want having access to nuclear weapons? 
Also at what point do you have to be concerned with proxies of these various governments acquiring nuclear weapons? Hezzbollah? What if Hamas got one? Al Qaeda? Isis? It's not fear mongering....it's just a consideration Israel has to make. Hundreds of millions of Muslims want them dead and the more nations that become nuclear, the greater chance a weapon gets in the hands of one of those people.
