Hillary Clinton and email archiving
Not sure if any of you guys have been following the news recently but it seems former Secretary of State, Hillary Clinton, is in hot water over how she’s been using email.
﻿It seems that she chose not to use her government email account, used a private server in her family home to house her emails and decided (with her staff) which emails to delete and which to turn over to the State Department for review.
Her email usage has also exposed major flaws in the State Department's archiving practices as not all email traffic from senior officials was automatically archived.
http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/03/13/clinton-emails-state-not-_n_6868054.html
http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3007646/Clinton-aides-used-personal-emails-communicate-NYT.h....﻿
﻿What do you all think? 
Was this reckless behavior on behalf of Clinton? Has she risked US national security with her email practices? Is it worrying that the US government didn't appear to take email archiving seriously? 
Has this whole issue been vastly blown out of proportions?﻿ 
And all because, it would seem, she couldn't figure out how to get 2 email accounts on a single device, so chose to use her personal one for everything.
At best, it's ridiculously incompetent.
Prime example of why the user should do what the IT guy says / sets up!
Here's how I figure it. Working for a public school system, I fall under the same rules that she does when it comes to email. And I know she has lots of excuses and loopholes and whatever, but here's the thing that gets me; When she "handed over" all those emails, she said that she with-held the emails pertaining to personal matters like yoga, her mom's funeral plans etc. She then ended that statement saying that she expects privacy just as anyone else would. Well here's the thing, if she was using her government email address the way she was supposed to be, she wouldn't have the right or ability to filter out those messages from the public's eyes. So right there is a prime example of how she feels she is above the law.
Strike one was having her own email server. Strike two was filtering through her emails and then claiming to delete the personal ones. As a public servant, I don't get that option, nor does she. If someone uses he freedom of information act to ask for my emails, every single one of them becomes available.
And lastly, I believe punishment for this should be hard and swift. Anyone who violated this rule, helped her violate it, or saw that she was breaking the rule and didn't say anything, should be punished. And she deserves to kicked out. If I pulled this, I would be fired. I don't believe her punishment should be any less.
From my point of view, it certainly opens her up to the allegation of not handing over damaging emails. This just simply should not have been allowed to happen. She should be setting an example of good practice, not using the systems to her advantage.
I just don't believe that she is unable to get her systems set up properly, so I have to believe she is unwilling to have her systems set up properly, and you have to wonder why.
She was a government official and had regulations to follow. She clearly didn't follow those regulations. Then she risked national security by using a personal server. I don't care if it was in Fort Knox, it is still a security risk. Lastly, she compromised herself by admitting that she deleted "personal" emails. Yeah, okay, and Obama is a "good" President.
I foresee a square office with bars instead of an Oval one overlooking a garden in her future. At least she will have a view.
Yes, but is your last name Clinton? 
No? Didn't think so. Rules don't apply to these people, everyone knows that. She'll probably get a slap on the wrist, everyone will forget it in a couple of months.
Yes, but is your last name Clinton? 
No? Didn't think so. Rules don't apply to these people, everyone knows that. She'll probably get a slap on the wrist, everyone will forget it in a couple of months.
I would be amazed at a slap on the wrist. This person was named for the guy who climbed Everest (was 11 or so then), made amazing money in cattle futures, dodged non-existent sniper fire, and said stuff about taking things away for the common good among many other things.
Any normal people would have been marched off to Leavenworth pending trial and every last piece of property seized. 
it is just Clintons being Clintons.
there will be no repercussions for her actions. 
supporters will say it is a republican witch hunt, and the mainstream press will soon say it is old news and let it go.
but lets face it, she is undeniably smart.  she knew what she was doing all this time, it was not an oversight, it was planned to allow her to hide correspondence, like Nixon erasing the tapes.
on a side note: boy - I would hate to be her IT person, bet she never opens a helpdesk ticket :)
Regardless of any politics involved or political fallout, it does provide a valuable talking point when I jump in my user's cornflakes about using personal e-mail for work-related information.  In the construction world, we need to make sure any project related information is preserved and discoverable.  Change orders, etc., handled outside of official channels are a potential disaster should legal battles break out if a project comes in over budget or defects are found.  People have no sense of humor when there are tens of millions on the line. :-/
So much for the "transparent" administration, more like cloak and dagger administration. 
Personally I think what she did is borderline treason, depending on the real content of those emails. But nothing will happen to her, Dems will say it's a Republican witch hunt, and the Republicans will fold, because, well they do that so well.
BTW what's with this administrations issue with email? First Lois Lerner now Clinton.
I can't blame her for not wanting to release private emails, but why isn't a third-party review an option? I haven't seen that mentioned yet. It would seem to be a good medium between privacy and accountability.
http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/03/18/media-clinton-bush-jeb-emails-ignore_n_6893366.html
http://www.cnn.com/2015/03/16/politics/hillary-clinton-jeb-bush-email-2016/
This is obviously a user education issue as politicians seem to do what they want and deal with the aftermath later.
When I was a private in the US Army I wasn't allowed to use anything but my government email address when I was conducting official business, this was the policy in place and there was no bending that. When it was deemed that I needed to be contacted 24/7 I was issued a BlackBerry that was only linked to my official email address. Why this is different for any other aspects of government communication I have no idea.
This is why policies exist, to protect data. Instead of being outraged that a democrat did something and then a republican did something; why aren't we outraged that there isn't a clear cut policy to prevent them from doing these things to begin with?
It's a head scratcher. Why would she do that unless she had something to hide? How much did it cost her to put that together? There's no way in hell she was supporting it herself so she obviously either got free IT work or paid to have it done. Also, how did people let her get the point where she was doing this? Doesn't she collaborate with other politicians? Don't they say, "Hm...that's coming from a different domain name...what's that all about?"
I mean, I didn't read the articles so I don't really have all the details (nor would I if I had read it) but this is fishy. It's another Clinton scandal except this time it has nothing to do with conjugal visits from secretaries.
All I know is that there's something very weird about that and the Clintons weren't the only ones involved.
It's a head scratcher. Why would she do that unless she had something to hide? How much did it cost her to put that together? There's no way in hell she was supporting it herself so she obviously either got free IT work or paid to have it done. Also, how did people let her get the point where she was doing this? Doesn't she collaborate with other politicians? Don't they say, "Hm...that's coming from a different domain name...what's that all about?"
I mean, I didn't read the articles so I don't really have all the details (nor would I if I had read it) but this is fishy. It's another Clinton scandal except this time it has nothing to do with conjugal visits from secretaries.
All I know is that there's something very weird about that and the Clintons weren't the only ones involved.
From the CNN Article that I linked:
"Wait — the rest of the 2016 field has an email problem?
Right!
This isn't unique to Bush and Clinton. Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker, former Texas Gov. Rick Perry, Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal and New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie all used private emails themselves, or their staff used private emails, to conduct public business. Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley has said that he used his private Gmail account for official business as well.
At least one potential contender has skirted the controversy altogether by avoiding email. Sen. Lindsey Graham recently admitted that he has never used email."
This is a political issue across the country and it happens at all levels, there is a local level case right now in my county dealing with an elected official that only used his personal email address to avoid putting anything on public record. 
hey Neal sounds like your making excuses for the inexcusable.. considering the amount of lying the government douches have tossed in the faces of the SHEEPLE particularly the Clintons', DOES IT REALLY MATTER ? 
Was this reckless behavior on behalf of Clinton? reckless no ? calculated, intentional, malicious, arrogant, unethical, unscrupulous, despicable.. yes all ov the above and more.
Has she risked US national security with her email practices? yes and has undermined this countries constitution and the SHEEPLE, they dont give a rats ass about national security.. and they are in bed with the enemy.
worrying that the US government didn't appear to take email archiving seriously?  ahaha no apparently they dont does it really matter ? as clinton would say... 
imho: your either naive or ignorant to think otherwise.. sheeple.
From the CNN Article that I linked:
"Wait — the rest of the 2016 field has an email problem?
Right!
This isn't unique to Bush and Clinton. Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker, former Texas Gov. Rick Perry, Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal and New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie all used private emails themselves, or their staff used private emails, to conduct public business. Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley has said that he used his private Gmail account for official business as well.
At least one potential contender has skirted the controversy altogether by avoiding email. Sen. Lindsey Graham recently admitted that he has never used email."
This is a political issue across the country and it happens at all levels, there is a local level case right now in my county dealing with an elected official that only used his personal email address to avoid putting anything on public record. 
Thanks for sharing the quote. It's one thing to avoid using it. It's another thing to have it and selectively give e-mails back for archiving. That just doesn't make sense.
I understand some things are private for public safety but not everything is private for public safety. In fact, many more things need to be public for public safety. This might be a trend but it doesn't mean it's the right thing to do.
My personal opinion is that this type of setup should be banned and no private accounts can be used for work-related communication by a public official.
hey Neal sounds like your making excuses for the inexcusable.. considering the amount of lying the government douches have tossed in the faces of the SHEEPLE particularly the Clintons', DOES IT REALLY MATTER ? 
Was this reckless behavior on behalf of Clinton? reckless no ? calculated, intentional, malicious, arrogant, unethical, unscrupulous, despicable.. yes all ov the above and more.
Has she risked US national security with her email practices? yes and has undermined this countries constitution and the SHEEPLE, they dont give a rats ass about national security.. and they are in bed with the enemy.
worrying that the US government didn't appear to take email archiving seriously?  ahaha no apparently they dont does it really matter ? as clinton would say... 
imho: your either naive or ignorant to think otherwise.. sheeple.
I'm not exactly sure what you're ultimate message was supposed to be here. Are we sheep for not wanting them to have a method to destroy evidence should we need to review it?
I mean, I guess you're right in a way. If we find out about a scandle we'll just end up voting another piece of garbage into office...so what's the point?
And all because, it would seem, she couldn't figure out how to get 2 email accounts on a single device, so chose to use her personal one for everything.
At best, it's ridiculously incompetent.
yet she traveled with 5 or so devices
yet she traveled with 5 or so devices
Yep, and she has the power to make decisions on America's behalf. Bravo, America. How can we Americans be so full of ourselves when we have idiots like this in office. I guess smart people wouldn't touch politics with 29 1/2 foot pole.
Some wise person remarked that politics is Hollywood for the ugly. 
Let's keep this focused on the email issue, or the politics rhetoric will get this moved to the Soapbox :)
From the CNN Article that I linked:
"Wait — the rest of the 2016 field has an email problem?
Right!
This isn't unique to Bush and Clinton. Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker, former Texas Gov. Rick Perry, Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal and New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie all used private emails themselves, or their staff used private emails, to conduct public business. Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley has said that he used his private Gmail account for official business as well.
At least one potential contender has skirted the controversy altogether by avoiding email. Sen. Lindsey Graham recently admitted that he has never used email."
This is a political issue across the country and it happens at all levels, there is a local level case right now in my county dealing with an elected official that only used his personal email address to avoid putting anything on public record. 
but those examples are state governors, who are not under the same rules and regs as the Secretary of State, which is federal.  it may or may not be against the rules for governors to use private email accounts, but it was for the Secretary of State.
also, remember the hubub when it was discovered Sarah Palin was using Yahoo email while she was governor, and they crowd sourced going through her email in an attempt to find anything illegal or embarrassing?
funny how that is not happening here.
birdlaw, im saying they think of the american people as sheep to be herded as needed into believing the lies.. 
through media and television and the lies out of their mouths, what they have perpetrated;  slowly but surely the undermining of America.. the people and all it stood for..  all the data is out there for everyone to see except mostly are blind to the truths or consider the data as conspiracy.. except history has proven many of those once believed conspiracies are really not conspiracies at all.. 
Am I the only one who wants to lay at least some of the blame at the feet of the people who allowed her to get away with this? That's like saying the employee who is 15-20 minutes late every day is the only at fault when their boss knows they're doing it &amp; does nothing about it. IT's as much the fault of the higher-ups that let her get away with it. What good are procedures &amp; rules &amp; regulations if everyone is not forced to follow the damn things?!?
