Negotiations with Iran .......
Originally Posted by Crash Course
If you're proud that America gave away EVERYTHING and got nothing in return you'd be an idiot......
We had absolutely nothing to gain by negotiating with Iran, and lifting the sanctions. 
The world in general, and the MidEast in particular, has lost considerably with this deal. 
Jim, since you seem to believe this was "America at her best," please explain the benefits of lifting sanctions on Iran--a country that openly sponsors terrorism, openly calls for the complete destruction of one of its neighbors, and is right now wreaking havoc in Syria, Lebanon and Yemen, while infiltrating Iraq under the guise of fighting ISIS. A country that other powers in the mideast (including our allies) have taken the amazing step of uniting against and actively fighting in Yemen. 
Be specific in your answer. 
-Brad
That's no fair Brad!!
"Be specific in your answer."
You can't do that here!!!!
He, He!!
pdq67
That's no fair Brad!!
"Be specific in your answer."
You can't do that here!!!!
He, He!!
pdq67
Actually, it's the Liberals that can't do that here. 
If pushed, most others seem to be able to back up their beliefs based with something other than "I think" and "I feel."
-Brad
The only two plausible reasons for the administration's position are; they believe in the inevitability of Iran getting nuclear weapons and the best course is to delay as long as possible, or the desperation that this is Obama's last opportunity for a "legacy" move (which likely will backfire). Either way, releasing Iran from the sanctions at a time of massive unrest in the Mideast is very dangerous. It will only give them more resources to further destabilize the region. The best course seems to me to be talk tough, continue to tighten the financial screws and turn our head the other way when the Israelis bomb their facilities.
"al-Taqiyya: 
deception; the islamic word for concealing or disguising one’s beliefs, convictions, ideas, feelings, opinions, and/or strategies."
And permitted by Allah, Mohammed and anyone else in the Islamic world with any influence. Straight out of the Quran, boys. 
Is there ANYONE who can say with a straight face Iran intends to mothball any and all production of weapons-grade uranium for the next 10 years, as the deal spells out? Does anyone believe that taking 600 centrifuges offline (they have nearly 7000) is going to stop development in its tracks? 
You can't believe those people if they tell you that water is wet. Lying is in their DNA. We didn't do anything in Switzerland except spend a bunch of time and money - and give Iran's mullahs the tools to do whatever in hell they have on their mind.
When kerry and obama are involved how could it not be a cluster fuck. valerie jarret must be happy though.
I only hope that the inevitable happens there, before the Statute of Limitations runs out here........
I only hope that the inevitable happens there, before the Statute of Limitations runs out here........
What? your hoping air force one has a pilot on ssi drugs?
How can we negotiate when the Commander in Chief tells everybody in a speech that 'war is not an option', explain that technique when you tell your adversary what you aren't going to do. the old 'I am not going to punish you' method of child rearing will not get teenagers home on time. 
So now they have concluded 'negotiations' and the sanctions are about to be lifted and they have 6000 centrifuges cranking out enriched uranium? What? They had the centrifuges cranking away before the 'negotiations' for chrissake, the centrifuges were what we need to get rid of and Kerry managed to get rid of just the fuking sanctions!? You shitting me? Thats not a negotiation that is called a 'concession!' 
Kerry negotiated to leave the centrifuges in place and to lift the sanctions? Do I have that right? man, he drove a hard bargain and Iran capatulated. Folded like a cheap tent and 'agreed' to Obamas harsh terms.
They are whooping it up in Tehran tonight, Jesus Joseph &amp; Mary, how did we ever get here?
How can we negotiate when the Commander in Chief tells everybody in a speech that 'war is not an option', explain that technique when you tell your adversary what you aren't going to do. the old 'I am not going to punish you' method of child rearing will not get teenagers home on time. 
So now they have concluded 'negotiations' and the sanctions are about to be lifted and they have 6000 centrifuges cranking out enriched uranium? What? They had the centrifuges cranking away before the 'negotiations' for chrissake, the centrifuges were what we need to get rid of and Kerry managed to get rid of just the fuking sanctions!? You shitting me? Thats not a negotiation that is called a 'concession!' 
Kerry negotiated to leave the centrifuges in place and to lift the sanctions? Do I have that right? man, he drove a hard bargain and Iran capatulated. Folded like a cheap tent and 'agreed' to Obamas harsh terms.
They are whooping it up in Tehran tonight, Jesus Joseph &amp; Mary, how did we ever get here?
Political correctness and mind control television.
Political correctness and mind control television.
FOX news = Mind control and war mongering.
Iran's theocracy is dying out. Why do you righties worship Saudi Arabia?
Political correctness and mind control television.
and vote fraud.
FOX news = Mind control and war mongering.
Iran's theocracy is dying out. Why do you righties worship Saudi Arabia?
The rest of the Middle East would disagree with you. 
-Brad
I see a series of "accidents" at some of Irans centrifuges in the not so distant future.....there a lot of ME countries that AREN'T Interested in Iran getting closer to having nukes.
