Isis
Lots of talk about ISIS after an excellent (but not perfect) Atlantic piece that is one of the better installments in the MSM on the group, here is that piece and a few others that continued the discussion it started - also very interesting look at why some women are joining up with ISIS.
The Atlantic piece:
What ISIS Really Wants - The Atlantic
Two pieces continuing the discussion and making followup points:
ISIS Islamic Credentials Spark Public Debate | The New Republic
What The Atlantic Gets Dangerously Wrong About ISIS And Islam | ThinkProgress
The piece on women joining ISIS:
Women and Islamic Militancy | Dissent Magazine
the Atlantic piece is very good. 
the think progress article is apologetic ball washing.
Always so charitable to people with other opinions! 
THough you keep a better handle on the "disgust" lever than say, Jeffsus or Magyar, i'll give you that.
Hollywood Studio Caught Producing ISIS Videos - DrudgeReport
green screen antics ?
Hollywood Studio Caught Producing ISIS Videos - DrudgeReport
green screen antics ?
it's a "fake" news story put out by the National Report.
Always so charitable to people with other opinions! 
THough you keep a better handle on the "disgust" lever than say, Jeffsus or Magyar, i'll give you that.
Oh, my dear Praktik, merely because we have different opinions, you are choosing to throw around the "disgust" adjective?
I haven't had much to say in the last two weeks but I think the events in the news have pretty much been saying it for me.
I'll summarize the pillars of my opinion for the last time and then wash myself of any further concern.
1. All belief without evidence is crazy, and people who hold absurd opinions, say that Elvis lives or that a cracker is actually divine flesh, deserve ridicule as a consequence of holding ridiculous beliefs. 
2. Not all belief without evidence is equal: some is benign (ie. there are unicorns flying on a rainbow somewhere) some is dangerous (ie. God told us to murder your entire civilization, and I will)
3. Islam fits squarely into the "dangerous" category, because:
4. Unlike Christianity, Judaism, or other religions' holy books, the Koran claims to be the direct authored unerring word of God. Whereas the Bible is just a collection of other books, which it self admits was written by men, and even includes four different accounts of the same events (ie. the Gospels), the Koran claims nothing less than being written by God himself and without error.
5. The Koran claims it cannot be interpreted in any other way than literally
6. The Koran claims it cannot be scrutinized or criticized, modified, annotated, amended, or any such thing. It is, as is, the exact word of God, written by God, 100% correct, completely finished, forever.
7. There are passages in the Koran that talk about extending kindness to others, but these are overwhelmed by the calls to violence, and in any case the calls to kindness apply only to other Muslims, and at that only "true" Muslims, as opposed to "hypocrites". Hyopcrites being anyone who adopts or follows a kind of watered-down, gentler version of Islam that most of our friends follow.
So as far as the Osama Bin Laden types or ISIS types go, they've got "true" Islam correct. They are meticulously following the example of Mohammed and the teachings of the Koran. This is factually indisputable. It also happens to be abhorrently violent.
Now, you're having trouble reconciling the fact that most people who call themselves Muslims and are peaceable, friendly chaps, do not resonate or support ISIS or Al Qaeda or the recent attacks in west Africa, France, Belgium, Canada, Denmark, Syria, Iraq, Lybia (did I forget anywhere?). 
You and others have attempted to characterize me as someone who does not recognize that there are various factions or interpretations of Islam and that I am presupposing that somehow my interpretation is the only correct one. Nothing could be further from the truth. There are, after all, Shiites, Shia, Wahabi, and more, including "extremists". The only thing claiming to be absolutely correct is the Koran itself and the "extremists" who follow it.
So why do I bother to talk about this at all? Why does it seem like I care? Well in short, it's a troubling development in the world, which we've seen at least once (in the last century, in western civilization), with the Nazis in WWII, that fanaticism can develop very quickly and among what would otherwise seem to be very normal people. I, likely along with you, would be absolutely horrified if the strategies of ISIS, say, bring us into a military clash of cultures.
And that's what it is. It's not a "war on terror", as GWB tried to market it. It's not a fight against "violent extremism" as Obama is forced to call it. It really is a fight against the literal interpretation of Islam. 
Unless we come to terms with that truth, which may make a multicultural populace like Canada's squirm with the feeling of "racist worms" in their shorts, we will never be able to stop this kind of cancer. 
"Moderate Muslims" (for lack of a better term) deserve a better outcome in their own homes and countries, and themselves have to grapple with an ideological battle between what their holy book and prophet says and what behaviour fits into a modern world. So, they are doubly stressed. The solution is not to flee as refugees to parts of the world that have already dealt with religious, ideological, and political conflicts of massive proportions. Part of the solution is for those "moderate Muslims" to revolt against those who seek to oppress them. Not flee. The west, by accepting such refugees, is in effect an enabler of ISIS. The French revolution, the American revolution, WWII, Franco Mark, you know I can go on - the west is sitting in a lofty and healthy position only because it's own citizens spent blood, sometimes usefully, sometimes ridiculously, to achieve the western status quo. 
By no means am I saying ours (ie. the west's) the only solution, after all, China is doing a fair job of lifting 100's of millions into a comfortable middle class; but the political and cultural mindset of north Africa and the middle east can really only change, by definition, by the people who live there.
For the rest of us, I'd say, just leave us alone please! 
-jM
A&amp;D
THE ATLANTIC IGNORES MUSLIM INTELLECTUALS, DEFINES “TRUE ISLAM” AS ISIS
https://firstlook.org/theintercept/2015/02/20/atlantic-defines-real-islam-says-isis/
So as far as the Osama Bin Laden types or ISIS types go, they've got "true" Islam correct. They are meticulously following the example of Mohammed and the teachings of the Koran. This is factually indisputable. It also happens to be abhorrently violent.
You talk like this....
You and others have attempted to characterize me as someone who does not recognize that there are various factions or interpretations of Islam and that I am presupposing that somehow my interpretation is the only correct one.
And then find this characterization of you strange... It's like you have accepted the OBL propaganda as them being the "true stewards" of Islam. Though I recognize that YOU recognized "other" interpretations exist . Just strange that you can recognize that and talk of the OBL view in such monolothic tones all the time, and write passages where you gnash your teeth at the lack of "moderat muslims" (if such a thing existed) and talk for all intents and purposes as OBL does: that they are the only true muslims and all others are apostates, not "really" being muslim..
Maybe your emotions has you up at such a level you dont even remember what you wrote in this very thread? Though here, in this post, I see a lot more nuance than that which has been historically available in your posts to date.
Bill Maher seems to be on a more nuanced path too lately - acknowledging in his latest shows, that a "variety of factors" drives muslim violence, not just religion... So maybe there's something going around these days!
So why do I bother to talk about this at all? Why does it seem like I care? Well in short, it's a troubling development in the world, which we've seen at least once (in the last century, in western civilization), with the Nazis in WWII, that fanaticism can develop very quickly and among what would otherwise seem to be very normal people.
No argument here.
And that's what it is. It's not a "war on terror", as GWB tried to market it. It's not a fight against "violent extremism" as Obama is forced to call it. It really is a fight against the literal interpretation of Islam.
Its more than that - its also a geopolitical Great Game being played by ME countries many of whom have completely ordinary and boring motivations like prestige/"penumbras of influence" and control over resources. Over top of that we have the Great Game of the greater powers - and you can add to that mix a certain set of religious motivations for some actors involved, certainly. There's the weight of history bearing down on this all the time: the horribly designed colonial borders and colonial history, the long-standing tribal rivalries, the shadow of tyranny enforced by brutal dictators - the recent blood shed in conflict calling for more blood. But this is a much more deeply set regional problem in the ME being fueled by a lot of people with a lot of money and a lot of mixed up tribal/religious/political motivations....
Some people in this fight are very much religiously motivated - many more are not.
"Moderate Muslims" (for lack of a better term) deserve a better outcome in their own homes and countries, and themselves have to grapple with an ideological battle between what their holy book and prophet says and what behaviour fits into a modern world. So, they are doubly stressed.
On this we can agree, and its nice to know you acknowedge they exist
"For the rest of us, I'd say, just leave us alone please! 
-jM
A&amp;D
Im just here to put up a counterpoint, fear no actual engagement from me - for I dont feel we'll align on much, save only a few islands of common ground. The gulf is too wide!
As I said to Magyar, there's always the "ignore" function!
I'll also say the Maher nuance this week brought me back to an old feeling I had about these debates - that we're all falling victim to the:
It was THIS *or* THAT
Human nature is to believe in single-causes, and multi-factored causes aren't as easy for us to understand and certainly dont push emotional buttons as much.
But at core, this whole debate has everyone being right - since the factors behind ISIS and islamic violence in general ARE very much multifactored. Its religion, its politics, its recent conflict creating space for their rise, its a whole number of things.
And we're basically all arguing over matters of degree, and "which factor is the most important".... this causes us to fall down to more cruder levels of discourse, ending up almost arguing that our most heavily weighted factor is the ONLY one, if we're not careful....
And when I think about these debates in this way I wonder if the gaps are really so wide between the poles of debate, or if we're actually just taking up tribal sides on this and making the gaps wider: letting our tribalism turn this debate into an abstract exercise in pedantry we essentially use as a litmus test to decide who is on our team and who is not on our team. Who "gets it", and in a way that affirms how much we as individuals also "get it" - because clearly the other side on this are a bunch of wooly headed fools...
More nuanced view from the main expert consulted in The Atlantic piece - extended interview with the academic reveals some gaps in way the Atlantic piece portrayed ISIS:
What The Atlantic Left Out About ISIS According To Their Own Expert | ThinkProgress
http://thinkprogress.org/world/2015/02/20/3625446/atlantic-left-isis-conversation-bernard-haykel/
More nuanced view from the main expert consulted in The Atlantic piece - extended interview with the academic reveals some gaps in way the Atlantic piece portrayed ISIS:
What The Atlantic Left Out About ISIS According To Their Own Expert | ThinkProgress
http://thinkprogress.org/world/2015/02/20/3625446/atlantic-left-isis-conversation-bernard-haykel/
I think this pretty much covers whay I have been trying to say about ISIS and islamic extremism:
More nuanced view from the main expert consulted in The Atlantic piece - extended interview with the academic reveals some gaps in way the Atlantic piece portrayed ISIS:
What The Atlantic Left Out About ISIS According To Their Own Expert | ThinkProgress
http://thinkprogress.org/world/2015/02/20/3625446/atlantic-left-isis-conversation-bernard-haykel/
I think this pretty much covers whay I have been trying to say about ISIS and islamic extremism:
Great piece! ISIS members are clearly victims, which explains why they beheaded Copts last week and set fire to the captured Jordanian pilot in a cage.
Nonsense about terrorism's 'root causes' - CNN.com
http://www.cnn.com/2015/02/19/opinion/bergen-terrorism-root-causes/index.html
The type of question not asked in 2002 and 2003 (and with libya):
CENTCOM Mosul Offensive: Can Iraqi Forces Hold the City After the Battle? - Atlantic Mobile
http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2015/02/the-murky-strategy-behind-recapturing-mosul/385732/
Great piece! ISIS members are clearly victims, which explains why they beheaded Copts last week and set fire to the captured Jordanian pilot in a cage.
^^wilful misreading, distortion and sarcasm noted
^^wilful misreading, distortion and sarcasm noted
The fact that you treat religion and all of its nonsense with seriousness and respect makes it hard to do likewise with your idiotic defenses -- most of which are based on liberal bullshit that college kids eat up in the name of politcal correctness -- of Islam.
Nonsense about terrorism's 'root causes' - CNN.com
http://www.cnn.com/2015/02/19/opinion/bergen-terrorism-root-causes/index.html
I believe this attempt to eliminate "poverty" from the discussion is successful only when the most crass and simplistic forms of this argument are used as a foil - and when this is done people like Bergen aren't really engaging with the argument, they're just setting up strawmen and knocking them down. Don't get me wrong, there's some good points and useful data in the piece - its just he seems to be thinking that the discussion about poverty is that poverty alone causes terrorism, or that poor people are terrorists, or that poverty somehow is THE most important factor driving terrorism.... So while I think he's clearly right that ideology is more important - I think it's wrong to go so far that you end up thinking poverty has *nothing* to do with it.
The argument was never that poverty = terrorism in some simplistic, deterministic formula that only poor people would commit terrorism (so therefore here are some rich saudis who *obviously* make that ridiculous to say!) or that it is some linear relationship between poverty and terrorism. 
Actually in the materials I've read discussing the links between poverty and terrorism they discuss the wider effect of what an impoverished country has on the social fabric: civil society will be nonexistent or extremely ineffective, typically you will have a strict heirarchy or tyrannical form of government, unemployment rates will be high. In short, an impoverished society is often a *stressed* society - and this will create a reservoir of resentment that rich, middle class and well educated ideologues can more easily tap.
I think its absolutely true that many terrorists are men of means - but I wonder, given the time you'd need to teach yourself the ideology and the means required to actually coordinate and execute terrorist attacks if its plausible to even imagine poor people being the driving force inside terrorist groups.
So in the overall weighting of things, Bergen is absolutely correct - ideology is probably a lot more important. However he fails to note that *political* and *tribal* motivations may be right up there in importance with ideology - and I think the argument about poverty he chooses to engage with is the most simplistic version of the argument possible, and isnt an honest engagement with what people who discuss poverty and terrorism are actually saying.
The fact that you treat religion and all of its nonsense with seriousness and respect makes it hard to do likewise with your idiotic defenses -- most of which are based on liberal bullshit that college kids eat up in the name of politcal correctness -- of Islam.
Whatever Magyar, you just totally handwaved away the Sunni angle to the story of ISIS - which shows to me someone completely unconcerned with facts and more concerned with scoring points.
Wilful ignorance would be another apt term.
Anyway, back to the poverty thing, I agree its probably an *overemphasized* causal factor but would say its likely going too far to say isnt a factor at all. Take note of the way the Taliban, Hezbollah, Hamas and even ISIS have been able to play a role winning hearts and minds by providing basic services: health care, sanitation, security - roads, wells, etc.
An impoverished society with poor governance (or a region where powers retreat from, leaving a vacuum) will basically open a political/economic door for these people to walk in and build a loyal power base.
Kristof discussed this a while back and hits this note:
http://kristof.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/03/13/linking-extreme-poverty-and-global-terrorism/?_r=1
And you can see ISIS doing the same in territory ceded to them by the Assad regime (from the NYRB article):
"ISIS’s leaders, who include a number of former Iraqi Baathist military men as well as veteran jihadists, are known to use several buildings in Raqqa such as the governor’s palace, the municipality, and the Armenian church of the martyrs, and they wield tight control over areas outside the city such as Division 17, a former army base, and oil installations, where many of the group’s Western and other hostages subsequently executed or released for ransom were held. A division has been made between ISIS’s military and civilian arms, and alongside its military and security forces, there are ministries run by ministers, although they appear not to have physical central locations. The group has set up new courts, local police forces, and an extensive economic administration, while taking over the existing education, health, telecom, and electricity systems (with some utilities still supported by the Syrian government).
...
Raqqa has also been a model for ISIS’s system of taxation: shopkeepers from Raqqa told me the group takes 2.5 percent of their revenue, deemed zakat, the alms payment in Islam, and 1,500 SYP monthly fee (it is never described as a tax). ISIS now collects around 400 SYP per month for telephone lines, even though the costs are borne by the regime. Locals also report that salaries are regularly paid by a new state office to both civilian workers and fighters, who may get $400 or more per month, and that prices of goods are tightly regulated by the government.
All this would have been difficult to imagine as recently as two years ago. Although there had been some protests when the Syrian uprising began, Raqqa had remained fairly loyal to the Assad regime, partly because of Damascus’s patronage of local tribes, partly because the large number of displaced Syrians who came to the city during the opening years of the conflict were not intent on rebellion."
So wouldn't a context of poverty make these kinds of opportunities more available to forces like ISIS looking to take control of territory and build a power base? Of course it isn't poverty on its own here - but in combination with political contexts and conflict contexts that it becomes a contextual element that can contribute to the rise and spread of terrorist groups...
Sam Harris interviewed Graeme Wood (the author of the Atlantic piece) :
The True Believers : Sam Harris and Graeme Wood discuss the Islamic State : Sam Harris
http://www.samharris.org/blog/item/the-true-believers
great piece, but quite long.
Sam Harris on the Charlie Hebdo and general religion-based problem of Islam, a religion of violence.
http://youtu.be/zxkq5bHe_fA
-jM
A&amp;D
An excellent and deep entry in recent pieces analyzing the lure of ISIS to young westerners in Europe and NA - notable for its deep grounding in history and cultural practise of Islam:
Lure of the Caliphate by Malise Ruthven | NYRblog | The New York Review of Books
http://www.nybooks.com/blogs/nyrblog/2015/feb/28/lure-caliphate-isis/?insrc=hpbl
And very cool look at the "Canadian clusters" of young jihadis on their way to Syria:
The Clear Banner: Canadian Foreign Fighters in Syria: An Overview | JIHADOLOGY
http://jihadology.net/2015/03/04/the-clear-banner-canadian-foreign-fighters-in-syria-an-overview/
