TIL, for over 20 years, Cuba has been aiding and treating more than 18,000 children affected by the 1986 Chernobyl disaster, for free.
Cuba. Free healthcare.
Is that a bad thing? I don't think so.
From what I remember from school, firefighters who got radiation poisoning from battling the fires were treated at a local hospital, and their clothes were thrown down into the basement after it was realized that they were contaminated as well. That hospital's basement is still one of the most radioactive places on the planet.
Hotspot of 380 microsievert per hour. Which is quite high. Might be amongst the highest publically accesible spots.
Hugging that spot for a year would increase your cancer risk by 16.5%.
http://chernobylgallery.com/chernobyl-disaster/radiation-levels/
that doesnt seem like much
It's really not. It's about the same as eating 3,720 bananas an hour. And no one has gotten cancer from that.
Wait...how are bananas giving me cancer?
They aren't. They're just high in potassium, which is one of the most radioactive elements present in living things.
Oh! Okay! Good to know that I can continue to masturbate worry-free.
You got that right. Pandora's Promise (on Netflix) is a great watch that tries to dispel some of the misconceptions/hysteria around nuclear power.
Wait, how are y..
.
Oh, oh god
Bananas are famous for their naturally occurring potassium, and a very tiny portion of that potassium is a radioactive isotope. It's so extremely miniscule that nobody in the history or future of humanity has or ever will get cancer from eating bananas.
It's used an example of the miniscule radioactivity that you're exposed to every day. From space, stuff in the air, your food, and so on.
A banana will give you a dose of .098 μSv. Which is twice the dose you would get from sleeping next to someone.
So stay single and eat more bananas.
Note that the Banana Equivalent Dose doesn't work well as a comparison here. Aside from the logistical challenges of eating so many bananas, your body will, in order to avoid potassium poisoning, rapidly excrete potassium, which isn't accounted for by the BED.
"Ukrainian authorities have expressed their gratitude to Cuba on several occasions. But though it forms part of Cuba's international revolutionary PR, the difference between this programme and others – such as the exchange of Cuban medical expertise for Venezuelan oil – is that there is no economic gain. The programme even survived Cuba's economic crisis of the early 90s, the so-called "special period" after the fall of the Soviet bloc."
Good for Cuba.
"Austerity is still apparent across the island, but the Chernobyl project has survived thanks to an agreement between the two countries: Ukraine covers transportation, while room, board, schooling and medical services are covered by Cuba. Some unofficial estimates put Cuba's expenditure at more than $300m (£180m) in medical costs alone."
An amazing contribution to humankind. Thank you Cuba.
Cuba is cool and all, but i mean the U.K's aid budget is 12bn 8bn£ per year.
Most nations do foriegn aid, partly for P.R partly to foster local allies.
Cuba does this because it wins cuba political capital. That's why everyone does foreign aid.
Edit: Put deptment budget not actual good example figure.
Edit 2: Ok well, guess I'll be clearer. Why praise Cuba for something literally every western nation and many others do. Don't get. Only time Aid comes up in most western countries is when people are being upset about how much is being spent.
Frankly, I think we massively under-appreciate 'our' (inset nation here really) efforts. Often a lot of actual human effort by individuals. Even if it is for geopolitical reasons.
But you see this 'wow cuba medical services, so charity'.
Yeah, not ragging on it, but you never see 'wow French medics/NHS Staff/USAID, such help'.
uh huh. Randomly quoting another nation's aid budget to prove what? That your country is richer than Cuba? lol
It's to prove that the cubans are paying a disproportionately larger amount on aid than the UK is.
$300m of $68.23bn is 0.4% of GDP
$8bn of $3.002tn is 0.2% of GDP
I bet that isn't by choice of the average Cuban. They would be better off looking after their own people.
Cubans enjoy pretty decent health care.
Sound the buzzard he is WRONG.
The buzzard?
The Bay of Pigs was over 50 years ago. Get over it.
The Cubans had a pretty good reason to overthrow their former government.
Big deal so does most of the civilized world
Are you referring to Universal Health care?
Not at all.
you are counting one program that happened over twenty years, not the entire countries aid budget like in the UK.
Possibly true. But then we don't know what other international aid Cuba provides.
I believe the UK total foreign aid budget is supposed to be 0.7% of GDP.
Cuba GDP = $68.23 billion USD
UK GDP = $3.002 trillion USD
Wow I would have gussed the UK's HDP was around 1 trillion.
Where did you get the $3 trillion estimate? The closest I can find is $2.4349 trillion USD last year.
Cubas GDP is less than that of most US states, counties and several hundred companies.
When a rich nation sets aside a few billion it means less than when a poor nation sets aside hundreds of millions.
Sure the larger nations can do more good, but the poorer nations seem to set aside a higher portion than the rich nations.
The US aid budget is definitely not a charity though. It is used as a political weapon.
There have been lots of articles praising the US, UK, France, etc for sending doctors to Liberia to fight Ebola. Cuba was not singled out for praise for fighting Ebola despite the fact that they sent far more doctors than anyone else compared to Cuba's small population and economy.
The complaint of why is this article (which is 6 years old) about Cuba and not some other country is just stupid and pointless. Not every article is going to be about the exact subject you want to talk about.
don't drink the kool-aid 
http://townhall.com/columnists/humbertofontova/2010/02/23/cuba%E2%80%99s_free_and_fabulous_healthcare?page=full
Stuck with it until the Fox News plug.
You would think accusations of bias wouldn't happen so close to heavy handed use of bias, but the proof is in the link.
It's so good that MSLSD, CNN, ABC, NBC, and CBS never exhibit any bias, preserving ahr Freedums. Besides, there are thousands of other websites that affirm how shitty Cuban 'free health care' is, take your pick.
The World Health Organization and every other medical organization with any knowledge of Cuban Healthcare acknowledge that Cuban Healthcare is excellent. The opinions of conservative bloggers in the US that have know nothing about Cuba or health care is irrelevant.
There are hospitals for tourists/party officials, and other ones for 'the people'. Read and learn. 
http://www.discoverthenetworks.org/viewSubCategory.asp?id=627
My entire post was that the opinions of random conservative bloggers with no knowledge of the subject matter is irrelevant. You respond with a link to another blog by another idiot with no knowledge of public health or Cuba. Why can't you find a single article written by a legitimate media source or a legitimate medical organization?
Stossel is but one example of someone who knows more about the subject than you ever will. Here's something from the extreme neo-con right-wing website Al Jazeera:
By the time I moved to Cuba in 1997, there were serious shortages of medicine - from simple aspirin to more badly needed drugs.
Ironically, many medicines that cannot be found at a pharmacy are easily bought on the black market. Some doctors, nurses and cleaning staff smuggle the medicine out of the hospitals in a bid to make extra cash.
Although medical attention remains free, many patients did and still do bring their doctors food, money or other gifts to get to the front of the queue or to guarantee an appointment for an X-ray, blood test or operation.
If you do not have a contact or money to pay under the table, the waiting time for all but emergency procedures can be ridiculously long.
Many Cubans complain that top-level government and Communist Party officials have access to VIP health treatment, while ordinary people must queue from dawn for a routine test, with no guarantee that the allotted numbers will not run out before it is their turn.
And while the preventative healthcare system works well for children, women over the age of 40 are being shortchanged because yearly mammograms are not offered to the population at large.
I saw many hospitals where there was often no running water, the toilets did not flush, and the risk of infections - by the hospital's own admission - was extremely high.
Healthcare for hard currency
In all fairness, in the past five years, the government has made great efforts to improve hospitals and health centres, but again, lack of resources is making the process painfully slow.
The system is free, but it is neither fast nor efficient for two important reasons. One is obviously the lack of financial resources, and the other - which is related to the first - is the "export" of doctors, nurses and dentists in exchange for hard currency.
Thousands of Cuban doctors go to Venezuela to provide primary healthcare there. Their tour of duty lasts a minimum of two years and they are paid approximately $50 a month, plus expenses. In exchange, Hugo Chavez, Venezuela's president, sends Cuba petrol, part of which can be sold for hard currency.
When a friend of mine was unable to be operated on as scheduled, because there was no anesthesiologist available, "they are all in Venezuela" was a complaint I regularly heard.
Another way the country is attempting to obtain hard currency is to offer health services to foreigners - something that has been dubbed "health tourism". But some question whether visitors really get what they pay for.
The Al Jazeara article is good. Did you seriously think anyone would just read your out of context section of the article? http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/features/2012/06/201265115527622647.html
Have some more http://www.therealcuba.com/Page10.htm
On another hand Cuba owned USSR 30 something billion dollars which was mostly written off. USSR spent a ton of money in Cuba and helped with specialists, building hospitals and all kind of infrastructure. Military expenses were probably big part of it as well.
Cuba is an amazing country. Of course it needs to head for more freedom and more real democracy, but destroying the Cuban socialism would be a real loss to the world. Amongst the few places we have to look how we can work towards a functioning society outside capitalism, Cuba is an important one.
Despite its tough global political situation it has some great successes including an amazing medical system and to be the only country in the world that is "highly developed" by UN standards while having a sustainable ecological footprint.
http://imgur.com/a/x6F9X
This seems misleading. Its like saying I'm better than X because of my ecological footprint is less, but I can't afford a car.
Would the reason why they are rated this way be more relevant than the fact that they are?
