What ISIS Really Wants
 
I read this article a couple weeks ago and found it interesting. As I'm neither a regular reader of The Atlantic nor am I familiar with the author Graeme Wood, I was curious as to others thoughts on any or all of the three.
 
If indeed the core philosophy is antithetical to establishing a nation-state existing among other nations, but is instead aimed at bringing on an end-times apocolypse, that has some rather thorny implications.
 
Apologies if this has been discussed already, I didn't see any references but also didn't perform an exhaustive search of threads.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
Good article... A bit narrow.  Boko harum sprouted independently just like ISIS sprouted independently... The problem is bigger and broader.
Here's an interesting article if you had t seen it:
You Can't Understand ISIS If You Don't Know the History of Wahhabism in Saudi Arabia
http://m.huffpost.com/us/entry/5717157
Too many words in that article. Can someone just tell me who to vote for so the world doesn't end?
Too many words in that article. Can someone just tell me who to vote for so the world doesn't end?
It does not matter, resistance is futile, assimilate or die
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, 
If people can be talked into stupid things it's probably fair to say at least some can be talked out if it.
 
There's also the lead-by-example angle.
Taking a step back, what kind of organization can recruit so many people from all over the world to join their cause and die for it?  Yes there are precedence in the past, but to the worldly scale ISIS has accomplished on such a short and shocking period of time?
 
no ISIS fighter I have heard of has surrendured and claimed rights under the Geneva Conventions.  They will fight to the end.... gladly.
 
To understand your enemy is key to defeating them.  I think this is the starting point.  Because dropping hundred thousand dollar guided bombs on their heads do not seem to be working right now.  Just my opinion.
Taking a step back, what kind of organization can recruit so many people from all over the world to join their cause and die for it?  Yes there are precedence in the past, but to the worldly scale ISIS has accomplished on such a short and shocking period of time?
They don't call it the "world-wide" web for nothing.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
Before we attempt to use "psychology and coercion" against the ideology that brings people into this kind of thing, we have to be ready to discuss what it is. We have an administration who refuses to do that. And they refuse to allow the DOD to fight them the way they need to be fought. The idea we can win from the air, or allow Iran to win this for us and expect Iraq to be in any way stable afterwards is fantasy.
Taking a step back, what kind of organization can recruit so many people from all over the world to join their cause and die for it?  Yes there are precedence in the past, but to the worldly scale ISIS has accomplished on such a short and shocking period of time?
 
no ISIS fighter I have heard of has surrendured and claimed rights under the Geneva Conventions.  They will fight to the end.... gladly.
 
To understand your enemy is key to defeating them.  I think this is the starting point.  Because dropping hundred thousand dollar guided bombs on their heads do not seem to be working right now.  Just my opinion.
They would not be given consideration under the Geneva Conventions. They are not a signatory of the Conventions, nor are they an organized force or militia who are operating under command or leadership of a signatory. Additionally, they do not follow the intent or spirit of the Conventions.
ISIS has been growing to this capacity for years. It hasn't been as rapid as many people think.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
Before we attempt to use "psychology and coercion" against the ideology that brings people into this kind of thing, we have to be ready to discuss what it is. We have an administration who refuses to do that. And they refuse to allow the DOD to fight them the way they need to be fought. The idea we can win from the air, or allow Iran to win this for us and expect Iraq to be in any way stable afterwards is fantasy.
Is it worth the lives of your kids, grand kids, nieces, nephews, etc... to fight the fight you believe needs to be fought?
I've read similar articles about how ISIS is like an apocalyptic religious cult. Understanding that does tell us one thing... There's no negotiating with this group. That would be pointless. I think the draw they have for some will fade as people see them for what they are. They will continue to draw the most extreme types in the region and the nutty sociopathic western converts they seem to pull in. So, they do need to be fought to be held in check. That should mainly be by those that live in or near that area. However, I think we (the US) has an obligation to assist, because we brought about the current situation in Iraq. First with Bush's regime change, then with Obama's abandonment of Iraq.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
Before we attempt to use "psychology and coercion" against the ideology that brings people into this kind of thing, we have to be ready to discuss what it is. We have an administration who refuses to do that. And they refuse to allow the DOD to fight them the way they need to be fought. The idea we can win from the air, or allow Iran to win this for us and expect Iraq to be in any way stable afterwards is fantasy.
Recent Obama statement on what ISIS is:
 
“From a school in Pakistan to the streets of Paris, we have seen violence and terror perpetrated by those who profess to stand up for faith — their faith — professed to stand up for Islam, but, in fact are betraying it,” he said, describing the Islamic State as “a brutal, vicious death cult that, in the name of religion, carries out unspeakable acts of barbarism.”
 
Seems pretty clear to me.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
Before we attempt to use "psychology and coercion" against the ideology that brings people into this kind of thing, we have to be ready to discuss what it is. We have an administration who refuses to do that. And they refuse to allow the DOD to fight them the way they need to be fought. The idea we can win from the air, or allow Iran to win this for us and expect Iraq to be in any way stable afterwards is fantasy.
Recent Obama statement on what ISIS is:
 
“From a school in Pakistan to the streets of Paris, we have seen violence and terror perpetrated by those who profess to stand up for faith — their faith — professed to stand up for Islam, but, in fact are betraying it,” he said, describing the Islamic State as “a brutal, vicious death cult that, in the name of religion, carries out unspeakable acts of barbarism.”
 
Seems pretty clear to me.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
Before we attempt to use "psychology and coercion" against the ideology that brings people into this kind of thing, we have to be ready to discuss what it is. We have an administration who refuses to do that. And they refuse to allow the DOD to fight them the way they need to be fought. The idea we can win from the air, or allow Iran to win this for us and expect Iraq to be in any way stable afterwards is fantasy.
Recent Obama statement on what ISIS is:
 
 
Seems pretty clear to me.
Let's see how that works this week.... [heating up some popcorn]
BBC Reports ISIS are using Chorine gas in roadside bombs near Tikrit
 
Thats a serious escalation by them
^ Or their latest marketing campaign.
Taking a step back, what kind of organization can recruit so many people from all over the world to join their cause and die for it?  Yes there are precedence in the past, but to the worldly scale ISIS has accomplished on such a short and shocking period of time?
They don't call it the "world-wide" web for nothing.
Interesting point.  If they can use the Internet for their benefit, yet we can't use it to ours...
BBC Reports ISIS are using Chorine gas in roadside bombs near Tikrit
 
Thats a serious escalation by them
I once dated a chorine and she was a gas.  Or maybe she had gas.
I've read similar articles about how ISIS is like an apocalyptic religious cult. Understanding that does tell us one thing... There's no negotiating with this group. That would be pointless. I think the draw they have for some will fade as people see them for what they are. They will continue to draw the most extreme types in the region and the nutty sociopathic western converts they seem to pull in. So, they do need to be fought to be held in check. That should mainly be by those that live in or near that area. However, I think we (the US) has an obligation to assist, because we brought about the current situation in Iraq. First with Bush's regime change, then with Obama's abandonment of Iraq.
Here's what people don't understand: The people who SHOULD be fighting them off aren't fighting them off. They are not just moving into these areas, they are moving in, emplacing themselves within the structure of their governments, and taking over every aspect of them. When they move in to a city, they occupy and marry their fighters to the families. They use the same kinds of strong arm tactics the Taliban  used when they took over and instituted Sharia law. you can't just turn around the mindset of these people who believe what is happening is according to the will of Allah. They are extremely passive.  So the vacuum will be filled with us (and our friends) or the Iranians. And that is what is happening now...the Iranians are moving in to "help". So how much involvement do we want the Iranians to have in the government of Iraq?
So how much involvement do we want the Iranians to have in the government of Iraq?
At least they're on the same continent... heck, even neighbors...
I read Executive orders.
 
It didn't end well.
So how much involvement do we want the Iranians to have in the government of Iraq?
At least they're on the same continent... heck, even neighbors...
You'd better watch out for the eggplant that ate Chicago,
For he may eat your city soon.
You'd better watch out for the eggplant that ate Chicago,
If he's still hungry, the whole country's doomed.
- Norman Greenbaum, Dr. West's Medicine Show &amp; Junk Band
So the vacuum will be filled with us (and our friends) or the Iranians. And that is what is happening now...the Iranians are moving in to "help". So how much involvement do we want the Iranians to have in the government of Iraq?
This is what makes it so complicated. There's no good solution. However, since ISIS is taking over territory in a country we helped create in its current form, I do think we have an obligation to ensure it doesn't all go to the crazies.
 
Looking back, George H.W. Bush's decision not to take out Saddam in 1991 was smart. Part of that decision was because Iran and Iraq created a balance of power between Sunnis and Shiites.  I wish there was an easy way to fix the current situation, but there just isn't one.
So the vacuum will be filled with us (and our friends) or the Iranians. And that is what is happening now...the Iranians are moving in to "help". So how much involvement do we want the Iranians to have in the government of Iraq?
This is what makes it so complicated. There's no good solution. However, since ISIS is taking over territory in a country we helped create in its current form, I do think we have an obligation to ensure it doesn't all go to the crazies.
 
Looking back, George H.W. Bush's decision not to take out Saddam in 1991 was smart. Part of that decision was because Iran and Iraq created a balance of power between Sunnis and Shiites.  I wish there was an easy way to fix the current situation, but there just isn't one.
I do like the idea of doing what we can to maintain a balance of power between Sunnis and Shi'ites.  ISIS has made enemies of both sects, who are fighting them on the ground while our air power helps.
I've read similar articles about how ISIS is like an apocalyptic religious cult. Understanding that does tell us one thing... There's no negotiating with this group. That would be pointless. I think the draw they have for some will fade as people see them for what they are. They will continue to draw the most extreme types in the region and the nutty sociopathic western converts they seem to pull in. So, they do need to be fought to be held in check. That should mainly be by those that live in or near that area. However, I think we (the US) has an obligation to assist, because we brought about the current situation in Iraq. First with Bush's regime change, then with Obama's abandonment of Iraq.
I too have read several articles that talk about ISIS as being your basic "end of days" group where the hardcore believe that The Final Battle between the followers of Islam on one side and the Christians and Jews on the other will be starting any day now. Of course you cannot negotiate with the hardcore as they will fight to the death. But the truly hardcore are always the minority in any group like this.They gain their strength by attracting converts who, when faced with the prospect of The Grim Reaper, tend to quickly change their belief. As long as it is Muslim v. Muslim over there, it does not fulfill the hardcore's belief that The End of Days is here. Only when the world of Islam is united (of course with ISIS at helm) and is at war with the Christians and Jews will The Final Battle take place.
ISIS has made enemies of both sects, who are fighting them on the ground while our air power helps.
Without a ground presence that, at a minimum, provides significant HUMINT, COMINT, SIGINT, training and arms (especially for the Kurds), our air power amounts to little more than throwing handfuls of poop at the wall and seeing if it sticks.
I too have read several articles that talk about ISIS as being your basic "end of days" group where the hardcore believe that The Final Battle between the followers of Islam on one side and the Christians and Jews on the other will be starting any day now.
Curiously, the article mentions that at least Christians are left alone as long as they accept and subjugate to the Islamic regime and pay a special tax. I'd say the person in the absolutely worst position is an ex-Muslim who no doubt would be automatically sentenced to death for apostasy.
I too have read several articles that talk about ISIS as being your basic "end of days" group where the hardcore believe that The Final Battle between the followers of Islam on one side and the Christians and Jews on the other will be starting any day now.
Curiously, the article mentions that at least Christians are left alone as long as they accept and subjugate to the Islamic regime and pay a special tax. I'd say the person in the absolutely worst position is an ex-Muslim who no doubt would be automatically sentenced to death for apostasy.
Today in the NY Times these was an article about an increasing number of ISIS fighters being killed by fellow ISIS members for trying to flee. The piece had a few sources from people that did leave ISIS because they were disgusted by the level of violence, beheadings, etc.
I too have read several articles that talk about ISIS as being your basic "end of days" group where the hardcore believe that The Final Battle between the followers of Islam on one side and the Christians and Jews on the other will be starting any day now.
Curiously, the article mentions that at least Christians are left alone as long as they accept and subjugate to the Islamic regime and pay a special tax. I'd say the person in the absolutely worst position is an ex-Muslim who no doubt would be automatically sentenced to death for apostasy.
Today in the NY Times these was an article about an increasing number of ISIS fighters being killed by fellow ISIS members for trying to flee. The piece had a few sources from people that did leave ISIS because they were disgusted by the level of violence, beheadings, etc.
Let's hope they have passed their high water mark and are on their way out.  Probably with a few big bangs.
Let's hope they have passed their high water mark and are on their way out.  Probably with a few big bangs.
Do I see a silhouette of somebody pointing an AK from a tree?
CLICK, BANG,
Oh, what a hang,
Bagdhadi just shot poor me
And I hear you say, as I fade away
We don't have to wait till tomorrow
 
(With apologies to the late Jimi Hendrix) 
Today in the NY Times these was an article about an increasing number of ISIS fighters being killed by fellow ISIS members for trying to flee. The piece had a few sources from people that did leave ISIS because they were disgusted by the level of violence, beheadings, etc.
Yeah, it's not completely without irony that these tools end up killing each other for not being extreme enough or in the right way, when the fundamental principles of their beliefs are equally idiotic.
 
Only wish they'd get into an internal power struggle leading to the demise of all of them asap.
Today in the NY Times these was an article about an increasing number of ISIS fighters being killed by fellow ISIS members for trying to flee. The piece had a few sources from people that did leave ISIS because they were disgusted by the level of violence, beheadings, etc.
Yeah, it's not completely without irony that these tools end up killing each other for not being extreme enough or in the right way, when the fundamental principles of their beliefs are equally idiotic.
 
Only wish they'd get into an internal power struggle leading to the demise of all of them asap.
That isn't going to happen. They are increasing their range and numbers of external groups who support them. If you think they are going to simply implode into nothingness, you're looking through the lens of fantasy.
Today in the NY Times these was an article about an increasing number of ISIS fighters being killed by fellow ISIS members for trying to flee. The piece had a few sources from people that did leave ISIS because they were disgusted by the level of violence, beheadings, etc.
Yeah, it's not completely without irony that these tools end up killing each other for not being extreme enough or in the right way, when the fundamental principles of their beliefs are equally idiotic.
 
Only wish they'd get into an internal power struggle leading to the demise of all of them asap.
That isn't going to happen. They are increasing their range and numbers of external groups who support them. If you think they are going to simply implode into nothingness, you're looking through the lens of fantasy.
IS may well implode, but some other similar group will sprout to take its place.
Today in the NY Times these was an article about an increasing number of ISIS fighters being killed by fellow ISIS members for trying to flee. The piece had a few sources from people that did leave ISIS because they were disgusted by the level of violence, beheadings, etc.
Yeah, it's not completely without irony that these tools end up killing each other for not being extreme enough or in the right way, when the fundamental principles of their beliefs are equally idiotic.
 
Only wish they'd get into an internal power struggle leading to the demise of all of them asap.
That isn't going to happen. They are increasing their range and numbers of external groups who support them. If you think they are going to simply implode into nothingness, you're looking through the lens of fantasy.
You know "wishing" that something wouldhappen isn't the same thing as saying it probably will, yes?
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
Before we attempt to use "psychology and coercion" against the ideology that brings people into this kind of thing, we have to be ready to discuss what it is. We have an administration who refuses to do that. And they refuse to allow the DOD to fight them the way they need to be fought. The idea we can win from the air, or allow Iran to win this for us and expect Iraq to be in any way stable afterwards is fantasy.
Is it worth the lives of your kids, grand kids, nieces, nephews, etc... to fight the fight you believe needs to be fought?
If they are not fought and stopped what makes you think your kids, grandkids or anyone else will be safe here at home? They have plans to attack us here, they desire to kill Americans. If they are allowed to grow their power further they will have more capability to do so. If they dont have that capability and plans already. If we stay out of the fight over there they will bring it here. That is inevitable. Defeat them now or bring the war home to our shores.
I think the world's response does not change:
for people thinking of joining ISIS, divert them into other paths;
for people who already have joined ISIS, fight them until they give up or die.
And how do you propose we divert those to other paths, and "fight them until they give up or die..."?
To divert people to other paths - psychology and coercion.
 
To fight them until they give up or die - I defer to the experts in the Department of Defense.
Before we attempt to use "psychology and coercion" against the ideology that brings people into this kind of thing, we have to be ready to discuss what it is. We have an administration who refuses to do that. And they refuse to allow the DOD to fight them the way they need to be fought. The idea we can win from the air, or allow Iran to win this for us and expect Iraq to be in any way stable afterwards is fantasy.
Is it worth the lives of your kids, grand kids, nieces, nephews, etc... to fight the fight you believe needs to be fought?
If they are not fought and stopped what makes you think your kids, grandkids or anyone else will be safe here at home? They have plans to attack us here, they desire to kill Americans. If they are allowed to grow their power further they will have more capability to do so. If they dont have that capability and plans already. If we stay out of the fight over there they will bring it here. That is inevitable. Defeat them now or bring the war home to our shores.
I would like to be there when you explain to your kids or grand kids why they have to go die.
 
I would also like to hear you explain to the thousands of parents why exactly their kids died in Iraq.
 
Why exactly was that?
If they are not fought and stopped what makes you think your kids, grandkids or anyone else will be safe here at home? They have plans to attack us here, they desire to kill Americans. If they are allowed to grow their power further they will have more capability to do so. If they dont have that capability and plans already. If we stay out of the fight over there they will bring it here. That is inevitable. Defeat them now or bring the war home to our shores.
I would like to be there when you explain to your kids or grand kids why they have to go die.
 
I would also like to hear you explain to the thousands of parents why exactly their kids died in Iraq.
 
Why exactly was that?
In his defense though ISIS and Saddam's Iraq were two completely different entities with completely different fundamental motivations and thus fundamentally different 'problems'.
 
There was nothing in Saddam's regime that promoted it spreading around the world, other than his personal greed. Parts of his own population as well as neighboring countries could have (and did) take care of that problem. There's nothing in it for an Iranian to support Saddam's greed, nothing in it for Saudis, Jordanians etc.
 
With ISIS the promo-material is religion and it is an inherently dangerous thing. It spreads like a virus in the right conditions, and across national borders. Very different.
 
Having said that it's obviously a good question if and how the "outside" should deal with it. I think the "head-in-the-sand" is really not limited to those who give ISIS a free pass for fear of Islamophobia but also includes those who justify the horrible basic tenets of religion that ISIS uses to further its goals. You can't on the one hand say that someone is doing something wrong based on a premise that you on the other say you yourself support. It doesn't work.
 
Preventing people from going there to join up? Tricky. Didn't we have a problem with the east not allowing its citizens to travel abroad? I recall the argument was that a basic freedom was to be able to travel freely and leave one's country. Surely this must apply again? And do we or don't we recognize nations/states that declare themselves independent? If we don't, then based on what? Lack of a domestic consensus? Outside pressure? At what point is it justified to militarily attack, invade and occupy (again) to create a better society? And better according to whom?
 
I don't think it's a simple answer to it. To get back to your point I'd feel a lot better about it if the US had mandatory military service for its youth. Things would change for sure. Battles would be picked based on more sound reasoning because "everyone" stood to lose something.
