al-Shabaab once again does what Islam does best
http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/...0MT0CK20150402
Reminiscent of their 2013 Nairobi mall attack that killed 67 people, but way worse.
Personally, I'm disgusted by this and believe that the world would be a far better place if the entire Islamic world were turned into glass.
You may have meant your last sentence metaphorically, but we consider such sentiments are beyond the pale. They are not welcome here.
Perknose
Forum Director
I find the world would be a better place if all religious people were turned to glass.
Are you religious?
The usual apologists will be along to flame you shortly.
I find the world would be a better place if all religious people were turned to glass.
Are you religious?
And hate-filled atheists like you.
http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/...0MT0CK20150402
Reminiscent of their 2013 Nairobi mall attack that killed 67 people, but way worse.
Personally, I'm disgusted by this and believe that the world would be a far better place if the entire Islamic world were turned into glass.
And hate-filled atheists like you.
You idiots do realize that the best way to combat Islamic terrorists is to work with Muslims to root out the cancerous parts of their religion's followers? Condemning the entire religion as evil and equating all 1.6 billion Muslims with these terrorists only provides to create a divide with more people joining the terrorist side.
And hate-filled atheists like you.
Lol! So the wishing of 1.4 billion people by the OP to be dead results in silence by you but I say include all religious people and suddenly I'm the bad guy?
Maybe if you actually had real principals and not fake religious ones you'd be outraged by the OP's comment AND this latest terrorist attack. Nah, your religion is the only one that has justification of murder.
Lol! More and more fucking morons every day.
You idiots do realize that the best way to combat Islamic terrorists is to work with Muslims to root out the cancerous parts of their religion's followers? Condemning the entire religion as evil and equating all 1.6 billion Muslims with these terrorists only provides to create a divide with more people joining the terrorist side.
They are too stupid to see anything but red, including their own hypocrisy.
They are too stupid to see anything but red, including their own hypocrisy.
dude your fail is so bad it reeks of fail.
dude your fail is so bad it reeks of fail.
Ah...good one brah!
dude your fail is so bad it reeks of fail.
In what way is he wrong? Or are you going to agree with Kadarin and Ferrel and advocate genocide?
I see they are demonstrating their peaceful tolerance again huh?
Disgusting. The really sad part is that this happens so often now that such a massacre isn't even the news headline of the day.
Hey, there's no denying that today Muslims are responsible for most of the religious based horror in the world but they have allies. Whenever some moron Christian leader burns a Quran you can bet that the terrorist ranks will expand and people will die because of it. 
Frankly, they are all the same and the big three religions have the blood of hundreds of millions on there hands. God must be happy with them...
Brian
The religion of peace sure makes a lot of human pieces. Maybe the mistranslated "pieces" as "peace".
Hey, there's no denying that today Muslims are responsible for most of the religious based horror in the world but they have allies. Whenever some moron Christian leader burns a Quran you can bet that the terrorist ranks will expand and people will die because of it. 
Frankly, they are all the same and the big three religions have the blood of hundreds of millions on there hands. God must be happy with them...
Brian
What an incredibly twisted world view you have...just saying.
You can always spot the brainwashed when they trott out lines like these.
http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religion_of_Peace
I see they are demonstrating their peaceful tolerance again huh?
Disgusting. The really sad part is that this happens so often now that such a massacre isn't even the news headline of the day.
The religion of peace sure makes a lot of human pieces. Maybe the mistranslated "pieces" as "peace".
You can always spot the brainwashed when they trott out lines like these.
http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religion_of_Peace
How does your link help your case? It's says it's a descriptor for Islam which is what we're talking about when we use that phrase. And I'm sure we're all using it in jest cause it's fun 
Hey, there's no denying that today Muslims are responsible for most of the religious based horror in the world but they have allies. Whenever some moron Christian leader burns a Quran you can bet that the terrorist ranks will expand and people will die because of it. 
Frankly, they are all the same and the big three religions have the blood of hundreds of millions on there hands. God must be happy with them...
Brian
and yet they are still playing second fiddle to the people who have killed in the name of jesus.
I'm sure a true hero here will have a final solution to the Muslim question.
How does your link help your case? It's says it's a descriptor for Islam which is what we're talking about when we use that phrase. And I'm sure we're all using it in jest cause it's fun 
Context is everything guy, perhaps you can reread the posts I quoted and see where you went wrong
http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/...0MT0CK20150402
Reminiscent of their 2013 Nairobi mall attack that killed 67 people, but way worse.
Personally, I'm disgusted by this and believe that the world would be a far better place if the entire Islamic world were turned into glass.
Its actually more comparable to the Pakistan School attack where terrorists killed 145 muslims. 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2014_Pe...chool_massacre
You idiots do realize that the best way to combat Islamic terrorists is to work with Muslims to root out the cancerous parts of their religion's followers? Condemning the entire religion as evil and equating all 1.6 billion Muslims with these terrorists only provides to create a divide with more people joining the terrorist side.
I think the best and only way is to root out their finance souces. They're mainly mercenaries, cut both money and weapons supply and they're dead.
Now, and after more than Twelve-years of the so-called war on terror, don't we have the right to know who exactly have had financed al-Qaeda all over the years?
I mean, with all the intelligence power available in US-Middle East alliance, is it really impossible to identify and cut their financing sources?
Today I had read about ISIS gaining entry and control of the devastated Yarmouk Palestinian-refugee camp in Syria. As far as we know, it was supposed to be completely surrounded and controlled by Syrian forces since few years, hundreds at least are starving because of this and we have seen pictures of those who starved to death (would never forget in my life). 
How possibly could ISIS-entry into the camp area be explained?
I'm too so tired of every criminal who buy, sell, and kill by the name of his religion, but I'm as well tired of Islamic-terrorists using magic carpet to fly between countries or areas.
You idiots do realize that the best way to combat Islamic terrorists is to work with Muslims to root out the cancerous parts of their religion's followers? Condemning the entire religion as evil and equating all 1.6 billion Muslims with these terrorists only provides to create a divide with more people joining the terrorist side.
Typical apologist statement. 
All of the ingredients are there in the Q-book. The example of their great, Imerious Leader, big-m, is what it is.
islam will never, ever be non-violent until we can have an HONEST discussion about big-m's violent example, and the constant anger expressed in the q-book.
But NoooOOOOOoooo... all we get is the constant denial, deflection, and "how dare you question!" attacks instead of tackling the issue head-on.
...this unrest will only worsen in every single country until we either convert, die, or eliminate them once and for all. Sounds awful, right? Every liberal in the room is now in a rage but it doesn't change the facts. The only peaceful muslims are the ones NOT following the q-book or big-m's example.
They're saying "convert or die".
It's time the rest of the world said back "civilize yourselves or face the fight you keep trying to start with us".
I wonder if nuking Mecca and eliminating the ability to enter paradise would end the religion, or would they ignore the q-book and just build a new borg cube to march around?
and yet they are still playing second fiddle to the people who have killed in the name of jesus.
Even if true (which is debatable), irrelevant.
You idiots do realize that the best way to combat Islamic terrorists is to work with Muslims to root out the cancerous parts of their religion's followers? Condemning the entire religion as evil and equating all 1.6 billion Muslims with these terrorists only provides to create a divide with more people joining the terrorist side.
To do that we'd need Islam to have a Christianity-style enlightenment. Any ideas on how to enlighten 1.6 billion largely impoverished people living in shitholes that doesn't take centuries?
Islam may not be inherently evil, but it encourages and caters to those who are.
What an incredibly twisted world view you have...just saying.
Muslims preach hatred and kill thousands. Christians burn the Quran and hundreds more Muslims become terrorist and kill still more people. Looks to me like a tag team from hell.
Brian
