How World Leaders Plotted Jonathan's Defeat
http://www.tribune.com.ng/news/top-stories/item/33450-how-world-powers-plotted-jonathan-s-defeat
America and their politics, they ar only interested in Nations with crude oil eg Libya, Iraq, Syria, Qatar, Sudan, Saudi Nigeria. By the tym they dry our oil our eyes will open.
I dedicate this to our fellow Igbo in Lagos. Lagos is no man's land as oil is no man's resourses. Nigeria belongs to all of us. Oba Akiolu be warned
Jonathan caused the whole issue himself. We Voted for him only for him to tell us that some " CABAL " are bigger than the masses.
Shebi dem don rest now wey dem don put person wey dem go d remote abi. Ok ooo
.
In other news
G
Any time America plots against you, it means you're doing something great for your people.
If America likes any govt, it usually means that govt is serving American interest rather than the citizens interest.
History revealed America fights for its interest and not the other way round.
I would hate Buhari if he becomes American stooge and I would like to know what Buhari promised America.
Buhari should not try and repeal the "homosexual" bill, we don't want American style culture here.
We don't want America "Change" here either, look what America "Change" did in Libya, Iraq and Syria.
If true then we should all be thankful to these countries from saving Nigeria from Jonathan and his corrupt government
At the end of it all, Nigerians themselves removed Jonathan from power. God bless Nigerians
Buhari please dont forget to bring down the import duty on cars... 
senseless policy..
spare me d trash talk ,dude plotted his own defeat,how u go carry thieves along with u??
Please can someone summarize that book?  
Really?
We'll keep seeing more of this
One thing is for sure there is no positive change in APC,
Maybe a Change for something else, because all I see is recycled greedy politicians that got us in this mess, trying to continue the same trend.
Y
Jonathan lost the election before 2015 but the chants from his supporters was so loud he couldn't hear...at least he has his "hero" status to bank on let's see how long it lasts....grin
Ok
Are the world leaders the one casting the ballot ?
Conspiracy theories here and there. Na real wa o!
His administration is corruption personified simple! Its not what he did but what others did because he let them. Embezzling public fund is one thing but giving presidential pardon to wanted criminals is a signal to the rest of the world that the Jonathan government condone stealing of public funds. 
From a religious point of view who are we to judge? Perhaps the Otueke fisherman is trying to act like the biblical Jesus. But again one needs to be submissive to higher authority and last I checked Nigeria operates the rule of law and at such the law is the highest authority which everyone must submit to. 
As much as I like the man I do not like his administration for one bit. 
Well, there is still time for redemption, sir. Just expose the thieves in your administration to the General and he would handle things from there. Just so you know sir, we are aware of some names that should top the list e.g madam petrol.
So na the world leaders make am no know him job?
politics of this world is about selfish interest, America and its step brother engineer wars all over the world for resouces and sales of amunition. but weda jonathan or buhari, the will of the west will be done u can ask mugabe or gadaffi, if u do not lick the white mans a$$ like Mandela nothing for u as an african country grin, so this ur story na crap
Goodness gracious!
The media and sensationalists should give this a rest already.
GEJ has moved on...u guys should try to do the same
story for the gods .
the last time i check Nigerians voted him out not world leaders
truth is gradually coming the so called change have not work anywhere in the world from usa, egypt, algeria etc
Rubbish...Rubbish...Rubbish....Absolute Rubbish.
jonathan is the architect of his own downfall cheesy grin
Jonathan lost because Nigerians wanted change. In 2011 he was voted in cos he promised fresh air. but rather than giving us the promised fresh air, he opened all the suck away pits in otueke and unleashed the bad odour on us. Now we needed change cos we cannot continue to inhale that bad and smelly odour for another 4 years. It had nothing 2 do with d international community.
WOW!! grin
i see
Were they the one that also voted on election day.
He lost because nigerians were tired of his cluelessness.
if there is anyone behind gej election loss,it is ffk,fayose,ifeanyi ubah and not forgetting pej.
So you people think u.s.a and co as the time for your politics?
We are just trying to claim relevance and familiarity.
ok
If this report is true, and a big 'IF', then I condemn America's meddlesomeness with the strongest possible terms.
I am yet to see the benefit of being allies with USA, we are subjected to all sorts of derision when we seek to visit USA, our environment has been greatly polluted by American oil companies and America abandoned us in our war against terror.GEJ asked you to sell weapons to him , you refused, he bought weapons from Russia you remove him.
My plead to General Buhari is to invest in the future of Nigeria-Let us build our own weapons, cars, planes etc. We have the manpower and the intellect to transform Nigeria. Neither America,UK nor Russia has our best interest at heart, we are just pawns in their game of 'power' chess
