"Let's drop the first I in ISIS"
In a recent interview with the HuffPost's Post Editor in Chief Arianna Huffington, Queen Rania of Jordan, extremely well known for her advocacy works in the middle-eastern sphere and a rather iconic figurehead, has stated that "ISIS has nothing to do with with faith and everything to do with fanaticism". 
Here's a link to the article: www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/03…
Now, what's your opinion on what she said?
----------SKIP TO NEXT SECTION IF YOU DON'T LIKE SARCASM----------
Personally, I think it's great news! Christians can be finally free of the burden of their ancestors, because The Crusades weren't promoted and executed by real Christians! Catholics can sigh in relief, since the reported episodes of pedophilia doesn't involve real Catholic priests! The far left can finally leave behind the prejudices associated with them, because Mao Tze Tung, Stalin and many other dictators were not real communists by any stretch! And that's not to speak of the joy and liberation the far right must be feeling right now...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
In all seriousness now, isn't this train of thought dangerous? Even if they don't fit her idea of what an exemplary muslim would do, that doesn't make them any less muslim, even if extremely misguided. Don't get me wrong, I get that it's the (completely understandable) reaction of a muslim who wants to distance herself from the heinous acts people sharing her religion did, but we have to remember the reasons why this group is doing what it's doing: interlocking religion and politics to exploit the world as they see fit.
P.S: I kinda dislike HuffPost because it's imho particularly biased, I'm linking to it only because this bit of news came to my country using that source.
People from that country don't even look at them as Muslim. People have interviewed and its usually the same thing, everyone agrees ISIS are not actually Muslim. 
I know some mostly islamic countries like Queen Rania's are also militarly involved in eradicating that organization, but progress so far has been so slow.
That's the name they picked for themselves :shrug: what would they rather we called them? NISIS? 
I think "Politically Correctly Changed Name So No-One's Feelings Are Hurt"  is much better.
and if you ask the guys in Isis or the Taliban, or Boko Haram, or from any other Islamic extremist group... They will tell you that "peaceful Muslims living and working in the west for the benefit of western governments and corporations are not real Muslims, but traitors  :|
XD woow
Progress seems to be slow on most actions usually 
I think you hit the nail on the head here. Their faith and fanaticism is what makes them the most dangerous... They truly believe they are doing God's work. 
I think it is ridiculous to try to separate Islam from Islamic extremist. These guys are violent terrorist because they follow the example of the prophet mohammed and a literal interpretation of the Quran. (Here is a complete video of what you need to know about Islam youtu.be/ywNYoAgLzm4 )
However there are 1.6 billion Muslims in the world. That is 23% of the worlds population. en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muslim_w…
Usually Muslims are the most ignorant and illiterate people of the world, according to this wikipedia link I quote: "Of the 1.4 billion Muslims 800 million are illiterate (6 out of 10 Muslims cannot read). In Christendom, adult literacy rate stands at 78 percent"
wikiislam.net/wiki/Muslim_Stat…
Most Muslim obviously never read the Quran, because they cannot read :slow: and they are nothing but puppets of theocratic dictatorships and their corrupt leaders, who keep them ignorant and stupid.
I think out of compassion the western media tries to separate Islam from terrorist, after all who wants to piss off 1.6 billion brainless violent zombies :shrug: So, the media sends them mixed messages and they fall for it...
I also believe that the west is interested in developing a peaceful form of Islam, in order to tame muslims and use them as slave labour. 
And they consider other muslims as infidels. So who gets to say who are the fake ones?
It is a question of perspective :shrug:
I always see that kind of reply pop up even from a couple of friends who I like to confront my ideas with. 
No doubt that most of these people are being manipulated by those they look up to as spiritual guides, but what about all those westerner muslims in Europe (and North America) going to join them? I doubt they are illiterate, as I doubt that all their families approve of their actions. What causes them to decide to go down that particular path?
Muslims living in the west face a horrible reality, they see wealthy happy people around here. For example at university here in Canada, non Muslim students go to the bar, party, drink, make love, study, work hard, have money and are happy :party:
While students of Muslim origin come from low income families, they cannot drink, have sex, party, and have no money.... So these muslims are sexually frustrated, and somehow to see happiness around here, happiness they cannot enjoy due to their dumb religion, radicalize some of them and makes them hate happy people. Out of their frustration and dull life, they turn to self segregation and terrorism :nod:
It is cruel to allow muslims to live among us, it is better to leave them in their Muslim nations.
I think we should call them mongrel retards and be done with it
They just kill anyone in their way and most of those are Muslims...
I don't like calling then 'ISIS' because it's an insult both to the Egyptian Goddess and the section of river Thames at Oxford. The terrorist group IS claim to be Muslims, and to be fighting for an Islamic state, so I will take them at their word. If most other Muslims don't like them and regard them as a betrayal of Islam, then it is for them to do something about them. I don't see how IS are deviating greatly from the example of the warlord/torturer/rapist/mass murderer/despot prophet Muhammad, personally.
Muslims, peaceful or violent, would not be our problem without the twin insanity of allowing mass third-world immigration into Western nations and constant meddling in the Middle East. We should leave the region alone, and let the Muslims fight it out among themselves to determine who is and isn't a true Muslim. They've spent the last 1400 years doing that anyway, and they will probably spend the next 1400 years similarly occupied. Let's just make sure they aren't doing so in our back yard. Islam has enough of the world to blight as it is. Around 50 nations.
Muslims having been warning against ISIS since the group existed over 250 year years ago. They change their name a few times over the years, but nonetheless, they have never been a part of the muslim community. They were started by a man called Muhammad ibn Abdulwahhab, which is why his followers have always been called wahhabies, they were responsible for the Ottomons leaving arabia, the establishment of the saudi family as the ruling family of arabia, and the eventual fall of the calipha. Oh, they were funded by the British, heh. You can thank the Queen.
Just give it up already, white people and western culture is dying, I'm glad I could help.
Are you serious? Muslims are mostly middle and upper class in western society. Muslims are a significant portion of world wide STEM graduates as well.
The news making up stories or the odd guy who actually does join them. Do you think propaganda ended with the cold war or something?
Of course not. I never said anything like that. In fact if you check my other posts in this thread you'll notice me talking about propaganda. However I don't see how the case of the attempted terrorist attack on the White House or the Charlie Hebdo case, or even the alledged identification of the beheader are made up stories.
It's not about trying to disprove them, they were never proven to be true in the first place. You didn't get the police reports from any of those incidents, heck, chances are you were not there so the only way you know they even happened allegedly is because media told you so. When it comes to places a bit further from the western world, yes, you can simply make stuff up and people will believe it. That is what we have editors for. 
All media from the get go is false by default unless proven true. That should be rule number one for everyone when it comes to news and journalism.
Muslims need to come together and speak out against extremism in their faith. 
They have to stop targeting those against Islam, and instead, strike the source. 
Muslims need to denounce groups like ISIS, and call out extremism. 
Mother Russia will conquer europe soon to protect us whites.
Listening to defeatists and cultural traitors is not a survival strategy, so you'll forgive me if I disregard everything you say, matey. 
In which planet do you live? Recently lots of Muslim war refuges from Syria and Iraq have been granted asylum in western nations, also from Somalia. We are talking hundreds of thousands across the western world. All are dirt poor and live of welfare. There are Muslim gethos in the uk, France and pretty much all across Europe.
That train of thought is dangerous imho, but they do the same thing in the US with pretty much all Christian terrorism and acts of violence. They always go "no no no, they aren't REAL Christians because...yadda yadda".  To say they aren't allowed to do that with Islam is a bit of a double standard.
They do do that. All the time. No one ever listens though.
They aren't doing it loud enough. 
It doesn't matter how loud they are if no one is listening. Very rarely is it covered by major news sources because it doesn't fit the narrative.
Most major news sources are not against Islam. 
No. Killing infidels is commanded in the Quran. ISIS is very Islamic. Just because they happen to make us doubt that one religion isn't that great, doesn't mean they're not Muslims.
ISIS are not a bunch of crazies. They follow a different philosophy than ours. Theirs is simply too far out there to ever exist side-by-side with us.
Maybe not in Edenia, but in the US they're still one of the most publically hated groups out there. They can't even build a friendly neighborhood mosque without a protest against it making the 6 o'clock news.
That depends where it's at, in the case of Ground Zero, the protest was totally justified.
First of all, that was four blocks away and wasn't justified at all. It was a freaking community center. Second of all, not the point.
Muslim mosques are rarely protested in the United States. 
Though I can very much understand why they would (and should) be protested in the UK, France, or Germany. 
You say "they" as if they all did that. IS received an alarming level of positive feedback in France after the Charlie hebdo attack.
They're protested every time a new one is built. And there's no good reason to protest them any more then one should protest a church or temple.
Except that the fact that Islam really isn't compatible with European culture.
