For liberal Israelis, Netanyahu's win is a reality check
Doesn't look to me like the two-state solution is growing in popularity the way some had tried to make everyone believe.
http://news.yahoo.com/liberal-israelis-netanyahus-win-reality-check-115401998.html
Why would it be a reality check? This is the closest liberal Israeli's have come to winning. As Netanyahu continues to turn the rest of the world against Israel, it can only strengthen Israel's liberal parties.
"Drink cyanide, bloody Neanderthals. You won," award-winning Israeli author and actress Alona Kimhi wrote on her Facebook page, before erasing it as her comments became the talk of the town. "Only death will save you from yourselves."
"Drink cyanide, bloody Neanderthals. You won," award-winning Israeli author and actress Alona Kimhi wrote on her Facebook page, before erasing it as her comments became the talk of the town. "Only death will save you from yourselves."
What is that supposed to prove?
If I were an Israeli liberal, I'd try to comfort myself with two potential mitigating factors:
First, as much as Bibi says Israel will go it alone if it has to, I doubt that it would/could.
Second, Bibi may just be trying the Reagan approach, peace through strength, all that, some amount of bluster &amp; bluffing.
And I could be wrong on both counts. I do know that I sure as hell wouldn't want to be living there.
Israeli liberals can just count on more cash and leadership from the Obama administration.
Why would it be a reality check? This is the closest liberal Israeli's have come to winning. As Netanyahu continues to turn the rest of the world against Israel, it can only strengthen Israel's liberal parties.
Name me one Arab nation where Arabs are more free than Israel and I'll play your game.
https://youtu.be/YM5kTgXdvzY
Why would it be a reality check? This is the closest liberal Israeli's have come to winning. As Netanyahu continues to turn the rest of the world against Israel, it can only strengthen Israel's liberal parties.
Name me one Arab nation where Arabs are more free than Israel and I'll play your game.
Better name an Arab country that holds millions in gulags.
Why would it be a reality check? This is the closest liberal Israeli's have come to winning. As Netanyahu continues to turn the rest of the world against Israel, it can only strengthen Israel's liberal parties.
Name me one Arab nation where Arabs are more free than Israel and I'll play your game.
Better name an Arab country that holds millions in gulags.
Pakistan, Bangladesh, Afgahnistan for starters
