We Made Sacrifices To Win 2015 Election – Oyegun
http://leadership.ng/news/438335/we-made-sacrifices-to-win-2015-election-oyegun?fb_ref=Default&amp;fb_source=message
Cc lalasticlala
Yes indeed sir and those sacrifices has culminated into probably the best chance Nigeria now have at rebirth.
Issah Allah, our sacrifices will yield the desired result for this country.
God bless APC supporters
God bless PMB,VP-PYO
God bless Nigeria.
angry
When they mean "sacrifice" ... they really mean paying every money they have to make sure the election favor them...
Not surprise that he knew the result before the announcement .....
the best rigger won last election undecided
Absolutely correct. In order to win the election, they had to put personal interests aside and adopt the most popular candidate, knowing that's the only chance they had at clinching at the presidency. They should also be prepared to make more sacrifices because Buhari is not someone you push around using selfish interest, he cares about his hard earned reputation and legacies and he wants to deliver without much interference...
angry
When they mean "sacrifice" ... they really mean paying every money they have to make sure the election favor them...
Not surprise that he knew the result before the announcement .....
the best rigger won last election undecided
angry
angry
undecided
undecided
uu are too blunt n unkind to the ruling party
uu are too blunt n unkind to the ruling party
they did the same thing when pdp was in power even in the last rivers election they keep saying the same thing
Ok
I understand totally what he is saying.
I was blocked by some friends on social media and even lost someone I thought was a potential date because of my love for Buhari.
All in all, I have not one single regret! smiley
Thank God Nigeria, and by extension APC, is now being seen by countries of the world as a case study in devicing ways on how Opposition can win elections. 
Kudos should also go to Jonathan, atleast he no be stubborn person...I think those people coming to understudy how APC won the elections should go and meet Tinubu, guess he has the password on how to unlock very stubborn sit-tight regimes....he did it to OBJ and also GEJ...
I understand totally what he is saying.
I was blocked by some friends on social media and even lost someone I thought was a potential date because of my love for Buhari.
All in all, I have not one single regret! smiley
why should i not laff at u? eh?
Thank God Nigeria, and by extension APC, is now being seen by countries of the world as a case study in devicing ways on how Opposition can win elections. 
Kudos should also go to Jonathan, atleast he no be stubborn person...I think those people coming to understudy how APC won the elections should go and meet Tinubu, guess he has the password on how to unlock very stubborn sit-tight regimes....he did it to OBJ and also GEJ...
Note that Apc got its tactics from almighty USA(obama) get your facts right abeg b4 u start blab
yea,u made sacrifice in alleging that someone who had won ur parties primary was dead so as to enable u nd ur cabal substitute his name with a candidate of ur choice abi....sacrifice indeed.
