AIPAC urges Obama to strengthen ties with Netanyahu
Source:ToI
The American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC) on Thursday night called on Washington to strengthen its ties with Israel following the reelection of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, and castigated the White House for its cool response to the Israeli leaders statements that  contrary to his preelection stance  he supports the two-state solution.
Today, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu strongly and clearly reaffirmed his commitment to a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, a statement by AIPAC said.
Unfortunately, administration spokespersons rebuffed the prime ministers efforts to improve the understandings between Israel and the US, it continued. In contrast to their comments, we urge the administration to further strengthen ties with Americas most reliable and only truly democratic ally in the Middle East.
A solid and unwavering relationship between the US and Israel is in the national security interests of both countries and reflects the values that we both cherish.
Read more:http://www.timesofisrael.com/aipac-urges-obama-to-strengthen-ties-with-netanyahu/#ixzz3Uvj2xXk3
1. Obama should tell AIPAC to fuck off. nt
18. Took the words right out of my mouth. n/t
32. Same here.  n/t
40. I could not have said it better than that.
43. I most heartily agree.
45. Hear hear!
2. Go away AIPAC and take Bill Kristol with you on the way
3. They should change their name
Or at least delete the first "A."
4. AIPAC should scold Netanyahu for his dancing away from truth.  He has shown be is not
Trustworthy. He want to talk about Iran's ability to abide by agreements and he goes and pulls his stunts. We should send Tom Cotton and Netanyahu on a field trip to wonder in the wilderness for forty years.
19. I live that 40 years in the wilderness idea for them - neither will be missed nt
27. Hey, no manna either.
33. Except...
they'd destroy the wilderness simply by being there.
Both are a waste of good air that could be put to better use by endangered species.
34. Sorry, didnt mean to harm the wilderness or cause the poor animals to have to
Exist with these two.
35. with any luck
the bears would take care of that.
36. Ok.  but bad meat, let's call in the buzzards.
38. Yeah, buzzards for sure...
but bears are omnivores and eat some pretty nasty stuff. Wouldn't be surprised if they wouldn't touch them after the kill though.
5. AIPAC can go pound sand.
We are not the Palestinians, we aren't forced to kiss Israel's ass. AIPAC always forgets America's interests and puts Israel's first.
And as far as being an ally, that's bullshit. Israel is a liability to us. The only thing reliable about Israel is that it takes the US for granted.
6. Israeli Fascists PAC would be a nice name for them.
7. Shameless rightwing liars and agents of a foreign power.
Let's not pretend that anyone in that organization has the best interests of the United States at heart.
Today, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu strongly and clearly reaffirmed his commitment to a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict
Oh please.
13. so which one are we suppose to believe ....the one before he won the election or the
one after???? we now know he lies...either to his people or ours???
14. the one before the election reflects his actual behavior in office
it's also the one Israeli voters wanted, as shown by their election results
8. Obama to AIPAC and Bibi: Go 'way from my window. Leave at your own chosen speed
I'm not the one you want, babe
I'm not the one you need
You say you're lookin' for someone
Who's never weak but always strong
To protect you an' defend you
Whether you are right or wrong
Someone to open each and every door
But it ain't me, babe
No, no, no, it ain't me babe It ain't me you're lookin' for, babe.
Go lightly from the ledge, babe
Go lightly on the ground
I'm not the one you want, babe
I will only let your down
You say you're lookin' for someone
Who will promise never to part
Someone to close his eyes for you
Someone to close his heart
Someone who will die for you an' more
But it ain't me, babe
No, no, no, it ain't me babe
It ain't me you're lookin' for, babe.
Go melt back into the night
Everything inside is made of stone
There's nothing in here moving
An' anyway I'm not alone
You say you're looking for someone
Who'll pick you up each time you fall
To gather flowers constantly
An' to come each time you call
A lover for you life an' nothing more
But it ain't me, babe
No, no, no, it ain't me, babe
It ain't me you're lookin' for, babe.
They help orchestrate an affront to a sitting president, including a letter, now they have the
fucking gall to point the blame at Obama while they back peddle for Bibi.
AIPAC, idiots on steroids.
21. That deserves this
24. Thanks! n/t
22. Parts of that sound as if they could have been written for our relationship with Israel
Who's never weak but always strong
To protect you an' defend you
Whether you are right or wrong
All he needs to add is " to veto each and every resolution, whether our policy or not."
23. lol I like that, very clever:
...to veto each and every resolution, whether our policy or not."
9. There really is a Welfare Queen
And it isn't the poor in America.
10. I have never seen any indication that bibi wants
a two-state solution. Never. Not once. Ever.
41. He is just saying that so the next $3,000,000,000 welfare check won't be delayed.
11. This line...
A solid and unwavering relationship between the US and Israel is in the national security interests of both countries
Made me laugh so,sohard. This "unwavering relationship" has brought nothing good to the United States, in terms of security. Quite the opposite.
12. so was Netanyahu lying when he said:
he supported the two state solution?
or when he said (pre-election) he did not support a two-state solution
or when he recently said (post-election) that he supports a two state solution?
20. Yes. n/t
25. Bibi was emboldened by HRC's earlier statement on West Bank: "If I were the Israeli PM,
youre damn right I would expect to have control over security, This was viewed by many as casting Clinton's support for a two-state solution into doubt.http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2014/08/hillary-clinton-failure-to-help-syrian-rebels-led-to-the-rise-of-isis/375832/
Apparently, Bibi assumes that the next US President will see things much more his way than does Barack Obama. If Hillary is the nominee, he may be right.
28. and given how little difference there is
between the GOP and Democrats on the subject of Israel you are probably correct. Even progressive heroes like Elizabeth Warren and Bernie Sanders are remarkably mainstream when it comes to Israel
29. Even if the differences are small, they are significant.  Netanyahu believes he will get away with
this body-slam to Obama because it is so widely presumed that Hillary is the inevitable candidate, and because as she has said, "there is no daylight" between herself and Netanyahu on issues impacting Israel, such as Palestine and Iran. With this context, expect Bibi to get even more maximalist in his positions, and the Mideast to edge ever closer to total war.
31. Clinton also said this:
This is my biggest complaint with the Israeli government. Im a strong supporter of Israel, a strong supporter of their right to defend themselves. But the continuing settlements, which have been denounced by successive American administrations on both sides of the aisle, are clearly a terrible signal to send if,at the same time, you claim youre looking for a two-state solution.
She knows Netanyahu doesn't support the two-state solution. She holds much the same beliefs as Obama, but has always been more willing to pander to the "Israel uber alles" due to her general lack of political courage.
37. The real Hillary here?: "I was often the 'designated yeller'."
During the same interview with CNN, Hillary also alluded to her complicated (theatrical) relationship with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu while she was Secretary of State. I was often the designated yeller, she said. Her criticism has been far more muted since leaving the Obama Administration.http://jpupdates.com/2014/07/27/hillary-clinton-bashed-israels-settlement-activity-highlights-yelling-sessions-w-netanyahu/
Bibi can take likely solace in Hillary's deeply-held ambiguity.
15. AIPAC Should Just STFU...
...they have overplayed their hand and worn out their welcome.
..."Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu strongly and clearly".....LIED. He already said what he is committed to doing.
No one left to listen but the legion of hand puppets they own in DC and the puppets are getting lots of pressure from their constituents to quit shilling for these bunch of liars and users.
We do not consent to waging and funding their wars.
It is the time for peace and those who are not with the program can fend for themselves.
16. I urge Obama to tell AIPAC to STFU.[n/t]
17. AIPAC should tell Netanyahu that Obama is our President and is owed respect
if he expects respect in return.
The fact is that Netanyahu lied at least once this week -- and he wants us to accept that there is no difference between the two completely opposite statements.
It is Netanyahu's dishonesty that AIPAC should be asking about -- ie how can Jews in the diaspora defend Israel, when the PM makes thugish unhelpful comments.
26. The best thing we can do right now is to
ignore AIPAC and go balls/walls to improve our relationship with Iran. IMHO
30. Israel is not a democracy.
39. If you believe Bibi really means that, then I want to talk to you
I've got some beachfront property by the Sea of Tranquility that might interest you. Great prices if you buy now.
?fit=580%2C580
46. Hey .. THAT beach has a shower ...
I'm in !
42. That will be easier said than done with boner interferring in everything.
44. President Obama to AIPAC
Go to hell assholes!
Hey maybe AIPAC can funnel more millions in from overseas and bribe more Senators and congressman!!
Thanks SCOTUS! (you fucking traitorous bastards!)
47. If Israel wants to be the friend of the US, its up to Israel to make it work.
The US has no obligation to accept bad behaviour from a supposedly friendly country. Its significant that AIPAC isnt telling Netanyahu to stop destroying the good relationship with the US, instead its the US President who should take the abuse and apologize for having a backbone.
This is exactly why I dont like AIPAC.
48. ''Urges'' = ''Warns''
- Fuck AIPAC.
49. Did they tell how high Obama must jump.
