OBAMA - LEADER OF THE ISLAMIC TERRORIST WORLD
Last week, Islamic terrorists…ISLAMIC TERRORISTS…stormed a university in Kenya and barbarically MURDERED 147 Christians…CHRISTIANS. According to Collins Wetangula, the Student Union Vice Chairman…“If you were a Christian you were shot on the spot.”
Other reports stated clearly that the gunmen were asking everybody to quote from the Quran. Those that could were allowed to live…those who couldn’t…were murdered.
The group responsible for the murders was al-Shabaab.
Translated…al-Shabaab means the Youth…in Arabic and the terrorist group is a radical ISLAMIST wing of the Union of ISLAMIC Courts from Somalia that also enlists ISLAMIC JIHADISTS from neighboring countries…the UK and the U.S. to make up it’s nearly 9000 members.
This is the exact same ISLAMIC TERRORIST group that, only 2 years ago, staged an attack in the Westgate shopping center in Nairobi that left 68 dead and in that attack, just like the one last week on the campus of Kenya’s Garissa University…reciting verses from the Quran was the key. Those who could…lived while those who couldn’t…died.
CLEARLY…al- Shabaab is an ISLAMIC terrorist group and just as clearly…their aim is to kill CHRISTIANS which takes us to last week’s statement from the Islamist in the White House regarding the massacre at Garissa University…
“Michelle and I join the American people in expressing our horror and sadness at the reports coming out of Garissa, Kenya. Words cannot adequately condemn the terrorist atrocities that took place at Garissa University College, where innocent men and women were brazenly and brutally massacred. We join the world in mourning them, many of whom were students pursuing an education in the pursuit of a better life for themselves and their loved ones. They represented a brighter future for a region that has seen too much violence for far too long. We also commend the heroism of the responders who lost their lives in the selfless protection of the students and faculty.”
Hmmmmm….
Terrorists and students huh?
Yep…terrorists and students…no mention whatsoever of what terrorists or which students…just random terrorists and random students.
Let’s go back to the opening sentence from this article for the sort of clarification Obama is loathe to provide.
Last week, Islamic terrorists… ISLAMIC TERRORISTS…stormed a college in Kenya MURDERING 147 Christians…CHRISTIANS.
Obama, an Islamist himself, doesn’t want you thinking of HIS ilk as ISLAMIC TERRORISTS…he wants you to think of them as generic terrorists and certainly, he doesn’t want you to think of the victims of his ilk as CHRISTIAN students…he wants you to believe they were just generic students.
The fact that all the terrorists who took part in that massacre were ISLAMIC and all the students who were killed in that attack were CHRISTIAN is just…a minor coincidence and nothing worthy of note.
This wasn’t Obama’s only cloaking of the truth last week when it came to his ISLAMIC ilk either. Maybe this got beneath your radar as well…
“Al-Qaeda is having a resurgence.”
Oh, that’s not just ME saying that and it’s not some Conservative running for office saying it either. Those were the words of California liberal Congressman Adam Schiff on a Sunday show. He’s talking about the situation in Yemen which is deteriorating rapidly as ISLAMIC SHIITE rebels…the Houthis…are in the process of overthrowing the Yemeni government allowing al-Qaeda to move in making Yemen a safe-haven for them as they work and train with ISIS…yet another ISLAMIC TERRORIST bunch of 7th century barbarians.
So let’s just get this straight shall we?
One ISLAMIC TERRORIST group…the Houthis…is overthrowing the Yemeni government while other ISLAMIC terrorist groups…al-Qaeda and al-Shabaab…are filling the vacuum and THOSE groups have been forming an alliance with yet ANOTHER…ISLAMIC TERRORIST group…ISIS and what does the Obama ISLAMIC regime have to say about it?
You can’t make this stuff up.
Saying “We have had success in counter-terrorism efforts in Yemen” sort of reminds one of some OTHER recent bit of bullcrap spewed by the Obama regime…now what was that exactly???
Oh yes…John Kerry uttering, ”We have made genuine progress,” regarding the Obama surrender to Iran in the nuclear ‘negotiations.’
Again, don’t take MY word for it on the surrender…take the word of the world’s foremost experts on surrender…the French whose Foreign Minister, Laurent Fabius said that Iran’s threat to walk out of the talks, “persuaded the American delegation to capitulate to the demands of the Ayatollah’s regime,” leaving the ISLAMIC Republic with everything THEY wanted including ALL of their nuclear facilities OPEN and doing the business of obtaining nuclear weapons.
Given all of this…is it any wonder that when Netanyahu offered that any ‘deal’ with Iran should include strong and clear language regarding Israel’s right to exist that Department of State spokesweasel Marie Harf, who not so long ago offered that ISIS would back down if only they had jobs stated… “This is an agreement that is only about the nuclear issue.”
Well, that IS the issue…the NUCLEAR issue…because once Iran HAS nuclear weapons, if they already don’t…they will USE them against ISRAEL thus threatening Israel’s existence. The nuclear ‘deal’ talks with the ISLAMIC Republic of Iran and their quest to obtain nuclear weapons cannot be separate issues.
Now, let’s look at one more little thing…
Iran just gave Hamas tens of MILLIONS of dollars to help RECONSTRUCT tunnels that Hamas…AN ISLAMIC TERRORIST group used to use to launch attacks against Israel but the tunnels aren’t the only thing benefiting from Iranian aid…Hamas will ALSO be adding to its dwindled stockpile of MISSILES and ROCKETS with part of that funding.
And here you thought the only reason Obama removed both Iran and Hamas from the terrorist list was to clear the way for the nuke ‘deal.’
Iran which, by terms left intentionally OUT of the ‘deal’ doesn’t have to observe Israel’s right to exist is funding tunnels and rockets for HAMAS in Gaza and NEITHER is currently on the terror watch list. Now isn’t THAT convenient?
Liberals will, of course, attack me for this but that is simply because they can’t argue with the facts presented here…Obama isn’t working for any sort of peace in the Middle East…
Obama is working FOR our enemies and AGAINST our allies.
He’s working for ISLAM and ISLAMIC TERRORIST groups to speed the building of the caliphate and the destruction of Israel.
Perhaps before we put Iran and Hamas back on the terrorist list…we should put BARACK HUSSEIN OBAMA on it first.
After all…Obama IS the leader of the ISLAMIC TERRORIST world!
tl; dr
Quality first post.
Also tl;dr
Got about 1/3rd of the way through
Obama has killed/ordered the killing of more Muslims than this group, IMO.
How do you reconcile that with your point, (disclaimer, didn't read it all).
Also tl;dr
Got about 1/3rd of the way through
Impressive.
Is this copied from somewhere or legit?
I actually took the time to read through the whole post.
Ok, Obama is an idiot. I think most people know that by now. But there was nothing to show he's the leader of the Islamic terrorist world.
Obama is a Christian masquerading as a Muslim masquerading as a Christian. It's all part of his plan. Kill a few Muslims to create street cred while simultaneously arming the Iranians and ISIS with nukes. Invoke global Armageddon. End result, the Rapture.
Ok, Obama is an idiot.
Really? Graduating magnum cum laude from Harvard Law School can be accomplished by an idiot? I'm not dumb enough to think Ted Cruz is an idiot even though I find his policy ideas horrific because I can find somebody's politics bad without automatically labeling them stupid.
