The US 'will pay'
Mother of Boston bomber says the US 'will pay'
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
https://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/world/a/27041688/mother-of-boston-bomber-says-the-us-will-pay/
Mother of Boston bomber says the US 'will pay'
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
https://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/world/a/27041688/mother-of-boston-bomber-says-the-us-will-pay/
First OJ and now these boys. Will the conspiracy never end?
An opinion of mine, which I have expressed on this forum before, is that at least half the people in USA jails are there because of their parents.
Mother of Boston bomber says the US 'will pay'
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
https://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/world/a/27041688/mother-of-boston-bomber-says-the-us-will-pay/
Terroristic Threat, she should be arrested! (nt)
Mother of Boston bomber says the US 'will pay'
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
https://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/world/a/27041688/mother-of-boston-bomber-says-the-us-will-pay/
Throw her in prison with him - Enough of this anti-America crap already! /t
Hows that Nikkor 80-400 working out?
I did not buy the S version, I bought the screwdriver focus type, which is cheaper of course but not as fast as the S version.  I have mixed feelings about it, it is quite sharp, I like it, but it adds too much weight to my carry-on when travelling, so I have bought the Nikon 70-200 f4 to take with me when travelling and I intend to get the Nikon Teleconverter 1.4 version III to add to it when required. The 80-400 will accompany with me when I shoot around where I live or I am going by car, but to take that in a carry-on will not be possible as I am already over my 7kg carry-on limit.
Mother of Boston bomber says the US 'will pay'
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
https://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/world/a/27041688/mother-of-boston-bomber-says-the-us-will-pay/
https://twitter.com/iowahawkblog/status/585869230131650560
(I'm sure her mindset has nothing to do with Islam.)
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
There was an absolute mountain of evidence against both brothers, even before the younger one's lawyers admitted that he did just about every crime that the prosecution said that he did.  Instead of going with a plea-bargain, the prosecutors insisted on introducing their evidence - and I'm glad they did, because now if the defense retracts their admission, that won't be enough to get him out of the results of the trial.
I would have said that we should feel sorry for the mother for having two sons who turned out to be such ungrateful, rotten terrorists.  But after her promise that the U.S. will "pay" for convicting her darling boy, with the strong implication that we will "pay" in the blood of more innocents, she's not only lost any sympathy, she's gone beyond the boundaries of protected free speech and given law enforcement reason to wonder if she is a risk.
http://nypost.com/2015/04/09/boston-bombers-mom-us-will-pay-for-my-sons/
Hey lady, "good luck" ever getting a visa to visit the U.S. again!
BTW, although the younger brother (found guilty on all 30 counts) is eligible for the death penalty (as per the wording of the news report), the jury has not reached a verdict in the penalty phase of the trial that will decide whether he gets it.
After 911 the Saudi Ambassador went on a US TV tour and said US must end occupation
Wimp Bush never complied with the ambassador. After Barry took over he stepped up the US genocide campaigns in Gaza, Palestine, and elsewhere.
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
There was an absolute mountain of evidence against both brothers, even before the younger one's lawyers admitted that he did just about every crime that the prosecution said that he did.  Instead of going with a plea-bargain, the prosecutors insisted on introducing their evidence - and I'm glad they did, because now if the defense retracts their admission, that won't be enough to get him out of the results of the trial.
I would have said that we should feel sorry for the mother for having two sons who turned out to be such ungrateful, rotten terrorists.  But after her promise that the U.S. will "pay" for convicting her darling boy, with the strong implication that we will "pay" in the blood of more innocents, she's not only lost any sympathy, she's gone beyond the boundaries of protected free speech and given law enforcement reason to wonder if she is a risk.
I guess when you have a mother fundamentalist so inflated with hate, as a child you don't need bad friends.
Is she not back to Chechenya now? This is the same kind of people who came on a tourist visa and applied for refugee status and would beg the US to let them stay because if they go back they would be tortured and killed.
Mother of Boston bomber says the US 'will pay'
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
https://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/world/a/27041688/mother-of-boston-bomber-says-the-us-will-pay/
You could show her all the evidence, and the video's of her son's placing the bombs.  You could show her the video of her son hiding in that boat, for no reason what so ever I guess.  You could show her all the posts where her son's planed on going to New York next.    You could show her the receipts of her son's buying the pressure cookers with their credit cards.  And she would still claim "set up".
Just another case of Mother supporting her criminal sons.  Not that we all haven't seen that enough, right?
If she feels that badly about it...
I'm sure we could give her a ride back to her home country of Chechnya.
You've seen what Putin did to the Ukranians for just getting a bit independent. One can only imagine what he'd do to a Chechen with ties to terrorism.
My guess is the ride from the airport would be a short one.
Mother of Boston bomber says the US 'will pay'
The mother of Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev condemned the guilty verdict delivered by the jury in his federal death penalty trial on Wednesday, calling Americans terrorists and proclaiming her son's innocence.
https://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/world/a/27041688/mother-of-boston-bomber-says-the-us-will-pay/
You could show her all the evidence, and the video's of her son's placing the bombs.  You could show her the video of her son hiding in that boat, for no reason what so ever I guess.  You could show her all the posts where her son's planed on going to New York next.    You could show her the receipts of her son's buying the pressure cookers with their credit cards.  And she would still claim "set up".
Just another case of Mother supporting her criminal sons.  Not that we all haven't seen that enough, right?
It is common for criminals to have the unconditional support of their parents.  No matter how many other parents have had their kids killed by the criminal.
In the local area, a young man fled when the police showed up at the family's home.  The police were after his brother and not him.  He just thought they wanted him because of the truck he had stolen.  He took off in the truck and the police followed.  He wound up running over two couples on motorcycles when he ran a red light.  Three people died with one seriously injured.  The young man's parents blamed "that darn truck" the young man had stolen.
You can breed horses, cats, and dogs for certain behavior traits.  Can you breed humans for certain behavior traits?
If she feels that badly about it...
I'm sure we could give her a ride back to her home country of Chechnya.
You've seen what Putin did to the Ukranians for just getting a bit independent. One can only imagine what he'd do to a Chechen with ties to terrorism.
My guess is the ride from the airport would be a short one.
I thought the mom and dad were in Russia somewhere when everything happened.
If she feels that badly about it...
I'm sure we could give her a ride back to her home country of Chechnya.
You've seen what Putin did to the Ukranians for just getting a bit independent. One can only imagine what he'd do to a Chechen with ties to terrorism.
My guess is the ride from the airport would be a short one.
I thought the mom and dad were in Russia somewhere when everything happened.
It seems to me they are not in the US anymore where they were granted refugee status.
Re: Boston Marathon Bombings’ Guilty Verdict Exposed as a Gross Travesty of Justice
http://www.globalresearch.ca/boston-marathon-bombings-guilty-verdict-exposed-as-a-gross-travesty-of-justice/5442240
Re: Boston Marathon Bombings’ Guilty Verdict Exposed as a Gross Travesty of Justice
http://www.globalresearch.ca/boston-marathon-bombings-guilty-verdict-exposed-as-a-gross-travesty-of-justice/5442240
If I could delete your post, I would.
It's not that I'm America's biggest fan.
Sure, everyone, even the guilty as hell, should have someone to defend them, which is why I don't so much mind his mother's little rant, but that article isn't about defending him. It's simply anti-American; it's propaganda. It's garbage.
What's more, the article relies on far too many crutches to try and get its argument to stand up.
Firstly, look at the title of the book it attempts to promote,
The Globalisation of War - America's "Long War" against Humanity;
The amount of crutches used tells me that when preaching to the congregation, its fans will just see, "Globalisation, America's war against humanity", and many will just see; America = bad.
But those crutches are glaring. The author has had to use them to try and whip up some credibility.
If the argument can't be made without leaning on feelings /suspicions about 9/11, then it starts to look like a white-wash.
When it has to also lean on similar doubts about the truth surrounding the death of (President) JFK, then it's starting to scrap the barrel.
And when it has clawed away the bottom of the barrel and is spewing out all over the place, as demonstrated by trying to appeal to those who don't much like Obama (yeah, why not drag him in to, eh?), along with quoted 87% of those who feel they "simply do not trust their own government", the notion that the article is aimed at an audience of Americans who hate the USA starts to play out along with the irony that having removed the bottom of the barrel, its barrel of arguments are presented as if assumed to be safely on a sound footing. er, duh! No! They're not.
Re: Boston Marathon Bombings’ Guilty Verdict Exposed as a Gross Travesty of Justice
http://www.globalresearch.ca/boston-marathon-bombings-guilty-verdict-exposed-as-a-gross-travesty-of-justice/5442240
I had to skim-read that article as I have no time to read lengthy essays on DPR. So are you backing the mother's claim: my darlings are innocent, it was a setup?
Re: Boston Marathon Bombings’ Guilty Verdict Exposed as a Gross Travesty of Justice
http://www.globalresearch.ca/boston-marathon-bombings-guilty-verdict-exposed-as-a-gross-travesty-of-justice/5442240
If I could delete your post, I would.
It's not that I'm America's biggest fan.
Sure, everyone, even the guilty as hell, should have someone to defend them, which is why I don't so much mind his mother's little rant, but that article isn't about defending him. It's simply anti-American; it's propaganda. It's garbage.
What's more, the article relies on far too many crutches to try and get its argument to stand up.
Firstly, look at the title of the book it attempts to promote,
The Globalisation of War - America's "Long War" against Humanity;
The amount of crutches used tells me that when preaching to the congregation, its fans will just see, "Globalisation, America's war against humanity", and many will just see; America = bad.
But those crutches are glaring. The author has had to use them to try and whip up some credibility.
If the argument can't be made without leaning on feelings /suspicions about 9/11, then it starts to look like a white-wash.
When it has to also lean on similar doubts about the truth surrounding the death of (President) JFK, then it's starting to scrap the barrel.
And when it has clawed away the bottom of the barrel and is spewing out all over the place, as demonstrated by trying to appeal to those who don't much like Obama (yeah, why not drag him in to, eh?), along with quoted 87% of those who feel they "simply do not trust their own government", the notion that the article is aimed at an audience of Americans who hate the USA starts to play out along with the irony that having removed the bottom of the barrel, its barrel of arguments are presented as if assumed to be safely on a sound footing. er, duh! No! They're not.
Maybe so. I wanted to present an alternative opinion.
Aren't you happy that you live in a country which celebrates 'freedom of speech?' Where censorship laws are not as raampant as in some other places?
