260	Netanyahu’s ‘Flip-Flop’ and the Willful Blindness of the Mainstream Media
357	When Benjamin Netanyahu declared this week that he would work to prevent a
432	Palestinian state from being established if reelected as Israeli Prime
503	Minister, the mainstream media described it as a “reversal” from a policy
577	speech he gave in 2009, in which he ostensibly expressed support for a
648	two-state solution. Then he insisted two days later that his policy view
721	hasn’t changed, prompting mainstream commentators to accuse him of blatant
796	inconsistency. A closer examination, however, reveals that this inconsistency
874	is an invention of the media. The real lesson from this episode is in how well
953	it illustrates the institutional myopia among mainstream commentators, and how
1032	the mainstream discussion serves only to perpetuate the illusions required to
1110	maintain US policy towards the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.
1180	The ‘Flip-Flop’ Narrative
1215	Certainly, when Netanyahu promised to prevent Palestinian statehood, he was
1291	saying something he thought that at least a plurality of Israeli voters wanted
1370	to hear, in order to win the election. And his tactic appears to have worked.
1457	Pre-election polls showed the Zionist Union ahead of Netanyahu’s Likud
1528	party. Then, in what the New York Times described as a “seemingly desperate
1604	bid to rally support halfway through the balloting,” Netanyahu “went on a
1678	tirade against Israel’s Arab citizens.” He said that the Israeli
1743	right-wing was “in danger” because “Arab voters are streaming in huge
1813	quantities to the polling stations.”He also promised that a Palestinian
1885	state would not be established if he was reelected.
1946	When Likud emerged victorious, the Times described it as a “stunning
2015	turnabout” attributable to Netanyahu “promising that no Palestinian state
2089	would be established as long as he remained in office and insulting Arab
2162	citizens.”
2182	That wasn’t the only turnaround mainstream media has perceived, however. In
2258	the New York Times, Jodi Rudoren described Netanyahu’s rejection of
2326	Palestinian statehood as having “reversed” his 2009 “endorsement of a
2396	two-state solution”. Her colleague Isabel Kershner concurred that it was
2469	“a reversal of a stance he had taken six years earlier.” William Booth in
2543	the Washington Post likewise asserted that Netanyahu’s remarks “appeared
2616	to reverse” his “previous declarations of support for a sovereign
2682	Palestinian state.” John Hudson and Column Lynch at Foreign Policy wrote
2755	that Netanyahu’s “pre-election declaration that he would never allow the
2828	creation of a Palestinian state” had “completely reversed the Israeli
2898	leader’s previous support for an independent Palestine as part of a
2966	permanent peace deal between the two sides.” David Francis likewise claimed
3042	at Foreign Policy that Netanyahu had announced “that he was willing to
3113	accept the creation of an independent Palestinian state” in his 2009
3182	Bar-Ilan speech, but that he “reversed course” during the election.
3259	Unsurprisingly, this narrative is being propagated not only by the media, but
3337	also by the US government. State Department spokesman Jen Psaki chimed in that
3416	Netanyahu’s remarks indicated that he had “changed his position”, and
3486	had at least “brought into question” his commitment to a two-state
3553	solution.
3572	But then, just two days later, according to the continuing media narrative,
3648	the Israeli Prime Minister reversed himself once again. “I don’t want a
3720	one-state solution”, Netanyahu said in an interview with NBC News. “I want
3795	a sustainable, peaceful two-state solution.”
3849	NBC sensationalized it as another “STUNNING REVERSAL”. It was “another
3920	reversal”, agreed Foreign Policy. CNN concurred that “Netanyahu walked
3991	back his disavowal of a two-state solution”. The Associated Press declared
4066	that Netanyahu has now “backtracked from hard-line statements against the
4140	establishment of a Palestinian state in the face of a diplomatic backlash.”
4216	In particular, Netanyahu’s rejection of Palestinian statehood had “angered
4291	the Obama administration, which views a two-state solution as a top foreign
4367	policy priority.”
4394	White House spokesman Josh Earnest noted that the US’s longstanding policy
4469	of habitually opposing any UN resolutions critical of Israel—including
4540	vetoing an uncontroversial Security Council resolution condemning Israel for
4617	illegal settlement activity in 2011—was “predicated on this idea that the
4691	two-state solution is the best outcome.” But Netanyahu during the election
4766	had said Israel he was “no longer committed to that solution”, which
4835	meant, Earnest said, that “we need to reevaluate our position in this
4905	matter”.
4923	The question put to Obama for a Huffington Post interview was revealing:
4996	“Given Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu’s recent comments on a two-state
5070	solution in the close of his campaign, can the US continue to oppose
5139	Palestinian efforts to gain statehood at the United Nations?” The US, of
5212	course, opposes Palestinian statehood at the UN in the name of supporting
5286	Palestinian statehood. The question itself laid bare the US’s true
5353	rejectionist policy, scarcely concealed behind a thin veil of rhetoric.
5434	Obama’s answer was also revealing. He said his administration was
5500	“evaluating what’s taking place” because “we continue to believe that
5570	a two-state solution is the only way for the long-term security of Israel, if
5648	it wants to stay both a Jewish state and democratic. And I indicated to him
5724	that given his statements prior to the election, it is going to be hard to
5799	find a path where people are seriously believing that negotiations are
5870	possible.”
5890	So Obama, too, laid bare the real issues, as far as Washington is concerned.
5967	The first problem is that Palestinians exist and have a tendency to procreate,
6046	which poses a threat to Israel’s identity. If the Palestinians can’t be
6118	made to accept some form of limited autonomy over an area of land they could
6195	apply the term “state” to, the alternatives are permanent occupation or
6267	annexation. With massive and growing global public opposition to Israel’s
6341	occupation and illegal colonization, it will become increasingly difficult for
6420	the US to provide the backing required for its continuance. This is what Obama
6499	meant a few moments later in the interview, when he said that “the status
6573	quo” could not be maintained “in perpetuity”. But annexation would come
6645	with its own set of problems. The world would not tolerate another apartheid
6722	state, but to respect the equal rights of the Palestinians as citizens of
6796	Israel would threaten its identify as a “Jewish state”.
6861	Hence the best solution, insofar as US policy is concerned, remains to force
6938	the Palestinians to acquiesce to Israel’s demands in direct, US-mediated,
7012	negotiations. This brings us to the second problem, which is convincing the
7088	public to believe that the so-called “peace process” is actually intended
7162	to bring about peace, as opposed to beating the Palestinians into submission.
7240	So long as enough of the world believes that the Palestinians should have to
7317	negotiate with the Occupying Power over their own independence, Washington
7392	will be able to maintain the status quo. If, however, the “peace process”
7466	loses its credibility, the US will no longer be able to maintain the same high
7545	level of support for Israel’s criminal conduct.
7602	The problem for Netanyahu’s comments, from the view of the Obama
7667	administration, is that such honesty makes it hard to maintain illusions.
7750	It is true that Netanyahu did speak words expressing support for a two-state
7827	solution in 2009. What neither the Obama administration nor the mainstream
7902	media is telling the public, however, is that the two-state “solution”
7973	favored by the US and Israel differs entirely from the two-state solution
8047	favored by the rest of the planet. Though the mainstream media isn’t
8116	enlightening the public about it, what Netanyahu actually said in 2009 is
8190	quite relevant.
8215	Netanyahu’s Bar-Ilan Speech
8252	On June 14, 2009, at Bar-Ilan University in Tel Aviv, Netanyahu gave a speech
8330	in which he invited Arab leaders to meet with him to “make peace”. Then he
8405	outlined what would be required for the “peace” he desired to occur. He
8477	reiterated his demand that the Palestinian leadership must “begin peace
8549	negotiations without prior conditions”. This was in accordance with US
8620	policy that the Palestinians must enter talks with Israel “without
8687	preconditions”, a euphemism meaning while Israel’s expansion of
8751	settlements in the occupied West Bank continues, despite this activity being a
8830	violation of international law.
8871	Israel, Netanyahu declared, was “committed to international agreements, and
8947	expects all sides to fulfill their obligations”. This was in accordance with
9024	US policy that the Palestinians must abide by the Oslo Accords and stick to
9100	the US-led “peace process” by engaging in negotiations with Israel, rather
9175	than appealing to institutions like United Nations, the International Criminal
9254	Court (ICC), and the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to resolve the
9327	conflict through the application of international law.
9391	The “root of the conflict” was not Israel’s occupation, colonization,
9461	and rejection of Palestinian self-determination, Netanyahu declared. Rather,
9538	it was the refusal of the Palestinians “to recognize the right of the Jewish
9615	People to its own state”. This was in accordance with US policy that the
9688	Palestinians must recognize Israel’s “right to exist”, as well as the
9758	Obama administration’s subsequent acceptance of Netanyahu’s demand in the
9832	framework for negotiations that the Palestinians recognize Israel as the
9905	“Jewish state”.
9930	Then Netanyahu declared that the illegal colonization of Palestinian land
10004	would continue; reiterated Israel’s rejection of the internationally
10073	recognized right of Palestinian refugees to return to their homeland; and
10147	announced that any “area in Palestinian hands”, whether or not it was
10217	called a “state”, would need to be defenseless (Palestinians could not
10288	have an army, could not control their own air space, and could not enter
10361	“military treaties”). All these preconditions, too, were in accordance
10432	with US policy and its role as mediator in the “peace process”.
10505	If the Palestinians would agree to these demands to surrender their rights and
10584	sovereignty, Netanyahu said, only then would he be “ready to agree to a real
10661	peace agreement, a demilitarized Palestinian state side by side with the
10734	Jewish state.”
10758	In other words, Netanyahu’s “acceptance” of “a two-state solution”
10825	to the conflict consisted of an explicit rejection of Palestinian
10891	self-determination, as well as an explicit rejection of the two-state solution
10970	founded on the principles of international law that is favored by most of the
11048	planet (the exceptions being Israel and its superpower benefactor, the US
11122	government).
11144	The international consensus on the two-state solution is grounded in
11213	principles of international law that there is a universal right to
11280	self-determination and that the acquisition of territory by war is
11347	inadmissible. This latter principle was emphasized by the UN Security Council
11425	when, in the wake of the June 1967 Israeli-Arab war, it passed Resolution 242,
11504	which called on Israel to withdraw from the territories it had occupied: The
11581	Syrian Golan Heights; the Egyptian Sinai Peninsula; and the Palestinian
11653	territories comprised of the West Bank, including East Jerusalem, and the Gaza
11732	Strip. This principle is also reflected in the 2004 advisory opinion of the
11808	ICJ that Israel’s separation wall and settlement regime in the occupied
11880	Palestinian territories violate international law.
11940	The governments of Israel and the US may speak of supporting a two-state
12013	solution; but what they favor is emphatically not the same as the two-state
12089	solution. The entire framework for negotiations under the US-led Oslo “peace
12166	process” is premised on rejecting the applicability of international law to
12242	the conflict. Its whole purpose is to prevent the implementation of the
12314	two-state solution and instead to force a different “solution” on the
12384	Palestinians; namely, the Palestinians must surrender their internationally
12460	recognized rights, including the right of refugees from the ethnic cleansing
12537	of Palestine to return to their homeland. And until the Palestinians agree to
12615	these terms of surrender, Israel will continue its oppression and violence
12690	against them, as well as prejudice the outcome of “peace process”
12756	negotiations on borders by continuing to illegally expand settlements in the
12833	occupied West Bank.
12862	Notwithstanding the actual meaning of Netanyahu’s words, the Washington Post
12939	reported his Bar-Ilan speech under the headline, “Netanyahu Backs 2-State
13013	Goal: Endorsement Comes With Prerequisites for Palestinians”. The New York
13088	Times headline likewise announced: “Netanyahu Backs Palestinian State, With
13164	Caveats”. Neither the Post nor the Times bothered to elaborate for readers
13239	that the “Prerequisites” or “Caveats” accompanying his words of
13303	support in fact consisted of an unambiguous rejection of the two-state
13374	solution and included demands that the Palestinians surrender their
13442	internationally recognized rights and sovereignty.
13502	President Obama similarly responded to Netanyahu’s speech with praise,
13573	calling it an “important step forward” that showed how “committed”
13640	Netanyahu was to a two-state solution. It was a “positive” step, Obama
13711	told the press, while taking the occasion to reemphasize the longstanding US
13788	policy of treating Israel’s “security” as “non-negotiable”—unlike
13854	Israel’s obligation not to violate international law or Palestinians’
13924	rights, including the right to self-determination and the right of return,
13999	which are very much matters to be negotiated away in the framework of the
14073	“peace process”.
14099	Given what Netanyahu actually said, and the true meaning behind his words, it
14177	is evident that his 2009 Bar-Ilan speech was perfectly consistent with his
14252	election promise to prevent a Palestinian state from being established. So why
14331	the pretense to the contrary?
14370	The Significance of Netanyahu’s ‘Flip-Flop’
14423	The Obama administration’s policy with regard to the conflict has been and
14498	continues to be synonymous with the Netanyahu government’s. The narrative
14572	being propagated by the media serves one simple purpose: to obfuscate the fact
14651	that this US policy has always been to block implementation of the two-state
14728	solution, meaningless rhetoric about support for “a two-state solution”
14800	notwithstanding.
14826	That is not to say that there isn’t a difference of opinion between the
14898	Obama and Netanyahu regimes. The Obama administration’s frustration with
14971	Netanyahu over his recent comments is certainly understandable. The problem
15047	with Netanyahu, from the Obama administration’s point of view, is that he
15121	makes it very difficult for the US government to sustain the illusion that it
15199	supports Palestinian self-determination. Statements like Netanyahu’s make it
15276	hard for the US to maintain the perception that it is an “honest broker”
15349	in the Israel-Palestinian conflict and that it supports Palestinians’
15419	rights.
15436	It is the same problem that arose in March of 2010 when Israel announced plans
15515	for further illegal settlement construction after US Vice President Joe Biden
15593	had arrived in the country as part of the administration’s efforts to revive
15670	the stalled “peace process”. That sparked what Israeli Ambassador to the
15743	US Michael B. Oren theatrically described as “a crisis of historic
15810	proportions” in US-Israeli relations.
15857	There had been countless other Israeli announcements of plans to expand
15929	settlements. The distinguishing characteristic of this particular announcement
16008	is that it was done while a high-level US official was in the country on a
16083	much-publicized mission to restart “peace” talks. The problem was strictly
16158	that the timing of this particular announcement drew unwanted attention to the
16237	true nature of the US-led “peace process” and risked undermining US
16305	efforts at managing perceptions, including among its Arab allies, which in
16380	turn undermined the US’s overarching policy in the Middle East, aimed at
16453	maintaining its hegemony over the region, including through the use of
16524	military force.
16549	“What you’re doing here undermines the security of our troops who are
16619	fighting in Iraq, Afghanistan and Pakistan”, Biden reportedly lectured
16690	Netanyahu. “That endangers us and it endangers regional peace.”
16763	As US Central Command (CENTCOM) commander General David Petraeus explained in
16841	testimony to the Senate Armed Services Committee, “The enduring hostilities
16917	between Israel and some of its neighbors present distinct challenges to our
16993	ability to advance our interests in the AOR [CENTCOM Area of Responsibility].
17071	Israeli-Palestinian tensions often flare into violence and large-scale armed
17148	confrontations. The conflict foments anti-American sentiment, due to a
17219	perception of US favoritism for Israel. Arab anger over the Palestinian
17291	question limits the strength and depth of US partnerships with governments and
17370	peoples in the AOR and weakens the legitimacy of moderate regimes in the Arab
17448	world. Meanwhile, al-Qaeda and other militant groups exploit that anger to
17523	mobilize support.”
17551	The significance of Netanyahu’s recent remarks is not that they represent
17625	typical election flip-flopping or demonstrate some change in Israeli policy.
17702	The significance is that his comments summarized the Israeli government’s
17776	longstanding policies concerning the Palestinians, and in doing so also
17848	revealed the true nature of US policy—and how Netanyahu has been making it
17923	exceedingly difficult for the Obama administration to maintain illusions.
18006	As the editor-in-chief of the Israeli daily Haaretz, Aluf Benn, observed,
18080	“Benjamin Netanyahu won the election because he delivered a crystal-clear
18154	sharp message to his voters: I am the true right and I am committed to the
18229	values of the ‘national camp,’ topped by hatred of Arabs and opposition to
18304	withdrawal from territories conquered by Israel in 1967. This is what his
18378	voters wanted to hear and they rewarded him generously at the polling
18448	stations.”
18468	Haaretz columnist Gideo Levy similarly commented on how Israelis “voted for
18544	the man who admitted to having duped half the world during his Bar-Ilan
18616	speech” and has now “torn off his mask”.
18666	The episode lays bare the prevailing racism among Israeli Jews. Indeed, the
18742	Zionist project itself is predicated on racist ideology. It was this racist
18818	ideology that led to the ethnic cleansing of three-quarters of a million Arabs
18897	from Palestine in order to establish the “Jewish state”, and it continues
18971	to underlie Israeli policies today—policies that, meaningless rhetoric to
19045	the contrary notwithstanding, are fully backed by the US government,
19114	financially, diplomatically, and militarily.
19168	Like Netanyahu, other prominent Israelis in government do little to conceal
19244	their racism. The New York Times relayed one insightful incident that occurred
19323	during the election:
19353	Avigdor Lieberman, Israel’s nationalist foreign minister, stared coolly at
19428	the Arab politician sitting at the opposite end of a glass table during a
19502	televised election debate.
19538	“Why did you come to this studio, why not to Gaza, or Ramallah? Why are you
19614	even here?” asked Mr. Lieberman, who frequently calls Israel’s Arab
19682	citizens traitors and suggests that their towns be transferred to Palestinian
19760	control. “You are not wanted here; you are a Palestinian citizen.”
19836	The politician, Ayman Odeh, the leader of an alliance of Arab parties formed
19913	to contest Israeli elections on Tuesday, appeared unruffled.
19983	“I am very welcome in my homeland,” he said, a subtle dig at Mr.
20048	Lieberman, an immigrant from the former Soviet republic of Moldova. “I am
20122	part of the nature, the surroundings, the landscape,” he said in
20187	Arabic-accented Hebrew.
20220	The true significance of the “flip-flop” incident lays scarcely concealed
20294	beneath the surface of the US media’s fictional narrative. Jodi Rudoren
20366	acknowledged in the New York Times that Netanyahu “fulfilled many world
20438	leaders’ suspicions that he was never really serious about peace
20503	negotiations.” Times columnist Roger Cohen noted that Netanyahu’s
20569	rejection of Palestinian self-determination reflects “a wide section of
20641	Israeli society” that “prefers its Palestinians invisible behind
20706	barriers.” These candid remarks are hardly profound; but they are
20772	nevertheless remarkable for having actually appeared in the mainstream
20843	discussion—and for illustrating the cognitive dissonance inherent in the
20916	media narrative. Indeed, Netanyahu himself stated explicitly that the premise
20994	that he had reversed himself was false.
21043	“I haven’t changed my policy”, he told NBC. “I never changed [my
21108	position from] my speech in Bar-Ilan University six years ago calling for a
21184	demilitarized Palestinian state that recognizes the Jewish state.”
21260	“And I don’t want a one-state solution”, he added later in the
21323	interview. “I want a sustainable, peaceful two-state solution, but for that
21399	circumstances have to change.”
21439	That, of course, simply means that the Palestinians will have to accept the US
21518	and Israel’s demands to return to the “peace process” and negotiate away
21591	their rights rather than appealing to the international community and seeking
21669	legal remedy through the application of international law.
21737	The editorial board of the New York Times, too, noticed that Netanyahu’s
21810	actual deeds over the past six years (including “aggressively” building
21882	illegal settlements “and never engaging seriously in negotiations”) had
21954	“long convinced many people that he has no interest in a peace agreement.”
22029	Indeed, it must take have taken an extraordinary amount of self-discipline on
22107	the part of mainstream American commentators—including the Times
22172	editors—to maintain the pretense to the contrary.
22231	The editors indicated that they have finally become convinced: Netanyahu’s
22306	rejection of Palestinian statehood, they added, “laid bare his duplicity”
22380	and “confirmed Palestinian suspicions”. But one can reasonably expect that
22455	it won’t be long before the Times editors are back to declaring their
22525	opposition to any “unilateral” moves at the UN by the Palestinians and
22596	affirming their support for the US-led “peace process”.
22661	Conclusion
22681	Netanyahu spoke honestly about his government’s longstanding policy of
22752	rejecting Palestinian self-determination, and it won him an election. He will
22830	face criticism at home for seemingly walking back from his promise to oppose a
22909	two-state solution if reelected, but it isn’t likely he’ll lose any sleep
22983	over this because his actions will prove that he is indeed committed to that
23060	election promise.
23087	He will face criticism from the US for having put in jeopardy the Obama
23159	administration’s ability to maintain its policy of supporting Israel’s
23230	crimes against the Palestinians and rejection of their rights. But the Obama
23307	administration let Netanyahu know he had stepped out of line, and Netanyahu
23383	obediently reaffirmed his commitment to the US-led “peace process”. That
23456	alone was not enough, of course, to provide the requisite cover for the US to
23534	maintain its own policy. More will be required of Netanyahu and the new
23606	Israeli government. It might take another so-called “freeze” of new
23674	approvals for settlement construction, or some other such symbolic commitment
23752	to the Oslo process. But it is unlikely that a political gaffe from the
23824	Israeli Prime Minister will spell the end of the “peace process”.
23899	At most, it will mean a significant shift in tactics for the US. There is
23973	already talk about the US itself now turning to the very institution is has
24049	long insisted should have no role in the “peace process” (apart from the
24122	Secretariat giving his endorsement to Quartet statements). This is indicated
24199	by the Obama’ administration’s statements about reassessing its policy.
24271	“We’re currently evaluating our approach”, said State Department
24336	spokeswoman Jen Psaki. “We’re not going to prejudge what we would do if
24408	there was a UN action”. The purpose of the shift in tactics would be to
24480	maintain the overarching policy. A former member of the Obama
24542	administration’s Middle East peace team, Ilan Goldenberg, told Foreign
24613	Policy “that Washington might be inclined to support a Security Council
24685	resolution backing a two-state solution as an alternative to the Palestinian
24762	effort to hold Israel accountable at the ICC.” Such a resolution, Goldenberg
24839	added, “could protect Israel from a worse outcome”.
24900	And the American intelligentsia, of course, will play along with the whole
24975	charade, of course, and enlighten the public about the importance of
25044	preventing the Palestinians from making “unilateral” moves at the UN and
25117	ensuring that any “peace” efforts are undertaken within the framework of
25190	the Oslo process. Israel’s occupation and illegal settlement regime will
25263	meanwhile continue, as ever, with US support.
