232	June Steenkamp: Pistorius terrorised my daughter
304	The mother of Reeva Steenkamp - who was shot dead by her paralympian boyfriend
383	Oscar Pistorius - said that he terrorised her daughter during the controlling
461	relationship.
484	June Steenkamp, speaking to the BBC World Service, said that Pistorius treated
563	Reeva like "his arm candy" and tried to dictate what she wore, how she behaved
642	and how she spoke prior to killing her on Valentine's Day in 2013.
718	Steenkamp described the time when Reeva, 29, called her during their
787	three-month relationship to say that Pistorius was driving dangerously at
861	161mph (259 km/hr) with her in the car.
910	She said: "One day she phoned me and said, 'Mummy, Oscar's driving like a
984	lunatic.' And I said, 'Well, you just put him on the phone.'
1054	"And I said to him, 'if you hurt my baby, I will have you wiped out' - just
1130	trying to scare him.
1160	And apparently he slowed down straightaway."
1214	Pistorius, a double-amputee Olympic sprinter, was convicted of culpable
1286	homicide on September 12 for which he received a maximum prison sentence of
1362	five years, with the possibility of serving the rest under correctional
1434	supervision after 10 months.
1472	Steenkamp said about sitting near him in the trial: "That was scary. Because
1549	he was the one who killed her, and he hurt her and he terrorised her.
1628	"We all love our children and we adored Reeva. And to sit next to the person
1705	who killed her - and she didn't do anything and she had no protection -
1777	horrible."
1797	Pistorius, 28, pleaded not guilty to murder and said that he mistook Reeva for
1876	an intruder in his bathroom before he shot four times through the door, with
1953	three bullets hitting his girlfriend.
2000	Steenkamp, whose book Reeva: A Mother's Story is out in the UK, also said that
2079	her only child Reeva kept quiet about their relationship at the beginning as
2156	"she wasn't sure if they were compatible" and she told her mother that she
2231	could not understand why they were fighting so early on.
2297	She said: "She didn't tell me about Oscar - the first time I saw them together
2376	was on the red carpet at a sports award. And I thought: "Now, who is this
2450	man?" Because I'd never heard of him."
2498	Reeva moved from her parents' home in Port Elizabeth aged 22 to the bigger and
2577	more dangerous South African city of Johannesburg to continue a successful
2652	career in modelling - which she had done since the age of 14 - after
2721	graduating with a law degree and working as a paralegal.
2787	Also a reality television star, Reeva was due to be shown in Tropika Island of
2866	Treasure two days after she was shot by Pistorius. Her parents gave SABC 1
2941	permission to air the show.
2978	Steenkamp said: "I said I would just love to see her alive, happy and
3048	laughing. Lots of people couldn't understand that but to me it was like
3120	bringing her back, seeing her laughing and enjoying herself."
