230	Abdusalami hails Jonathan for conceding defeat
300	A former Head of State, Gen. Abdusalami Abubakar, has commended President
374	Goodluck Jonathan for conceding defeat and congratulating Maj. Gen. Muhammadu
452	Buhari on his victory in the Saturday’s presidential election.
524	Abubakar spoke with State House correspondents shortly after leading members
601	of the National Peace Committee for the 2015 general elections to a
669	closed-door meeting with Jonathan at the Presidential Villa, Abuja.
746	He said Buhari had earlier told him that Jonathan called him at about 5.15pm
823	to congratulate him.
853	While saying that they were in the Presidential Villa to thank Jonathan for
929	his statesmanship, the former military leader urged all stakeholders to
1001	emulate Jonathan’s sportsmanship.
1044	He said, “We are here to ensure peace is maintained at this moment. We thank
1121	Nigerians and all international community who came to support us during the
1197	elections.
1217	“The elections have been very peaceful despite the hitches here and there.
1292	At the end of the elections, at the counting, there are a lot of upheavals
1367	that have happened but thankfully they have been contained.
1436	“We were at the middle of a meeting with the international observers to try
1512	to see how we can still water the tension down when gladly I called Gen.
1585	Buhari that we are going to see him. He told me that Mr. President has called
1663	him at about 5.15 pm and congratulated him and conceded defeat.
1736	“We were spellbound and the reason we have come here is to thank President
1811	Jonathan for this statesmanship.
1853	“In the history of Nigeria, I think this is the first time where a
1920	contestant has called his rival to congratulate him and through this point,
1996	President Jonathan maintains a point that the blood of Nigerians is not worth
2074	his Presidency and by his action, he has proven that.
2137	“He has proven that he is a man of his word,‎ because during our
2202	interaction on this peace committee, he has always maintained that he is going
2281	to accept the result of the elections whichever way it is done. And he has
2356	proven this.”
2379	Abubakar urged all Nigerians to join hands and assist the President in
2450	peaceful handing over.
2482	He said all politicians, those who are celebrating and those who are ruing
2557	their loss, to give peace a chance.
2602	The former Head of State said, “In any contest, there is always going to be
2678	a winner and President Jonathan has accepted that he lost and we want to thank
2757	him on behalf of Nigerians.
2794	“I want to thank President Jonathan for being the statesman that he is, he
2869	has proved that he is a statesman and he has the love of this country in his
2946	heart. So, Nigerians should please help him to ensure this is real.
3023	“For any Nigerian, who is aggrieved, the electoral law has procedures for
3097	seeking redress, so if anybody has ‎any grievance, he should apply through
3172	the law.
3190	“I appeal again to our youth, to everybody to please give peace a chance and
3267	accept that the chief contestant himself has accepted.”
