253	Sons of Turkish academic join extremist group ISIL
327	Three sons of an assistant professor at a Turkish university left Turkey to
403	join the extremist Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), a Turkish
477	daily has reported.
506	According to the Hürriyet newspaper, 19-year-old Süleyman Bengi İ., who was
582	studying at the dentistry faculty of one of Turkey's prominent universities,
659	Hacettepe University, left the guesthouse in Ankara where he had been staying
737	on March 10, leaving a note behind that said: “Selamün aleyküm (May God's
811	peace be with you), dear mother. You may give my belongings to poor and needy
889	people. God bless you.”
922	His 16-year-old twin brothers Dilar and Dilşat also left their homes in
994	Turkey's southeastern city of Diyarbakır on the same day. The parents of the
1071	boys went to the police to report their missing sons and security forces found
1150	video showing the brothers heading to Turkey's border with Syria. The
1220	information was also sent to the National Intelligence Organization (MİT) and
1298	the agency confirmed that the boys had crossed into Syria and joined the
1371	extremist group.
1397	After crossing the border, the brothers reportedly sent a text message to
1471	their parents, reading: “We have found peace here. Do not be concerned about
1548	us.” MİT learned that the boys crossed into Iraq from Syria and got in
1619	touch with them there. Efforts are ongoing to rescue the brothers, according
1696	to Hürriyet. The boys' contacts in Turkey that helped them to join ISIL are
1772	also under investigation.
1807	The father of the teenagers, Assistant Professor M. Şefik İ., asked for help
1884	from the Presidency, the Prime Ministry, MİT and security units to bring his
1961	sons back to Turkey.
1991	In remarks to Hürriyet, the family said they are having difficulty
2058	understanding why their children joined the group.
2118	“The associations, the books they have read made our children reach this
2191	point. We ask the government to bring back our sons,” the parents pleaded.
2275	Süleyman was known to be a successful and quiet boy; however, his opinions
2350	started to change after joining an association and attending meetings at a
2425	publishing house in Ankara, Hürriyet said.
2477	According to the report, citing official records, 2,307 Turkish citizens have
2555	joined the extremist group. Out of this number, more than 500 are still
2627	fighting alongside ISIL. A total of 11 Turks were killed in clashes with ISIL.
2706	Since 2014, 680 families have filed missing persons reports regarding their
2782	children who are assumed to have joined ISIL.
2837	Seven associations in Turkey suspected to be linked with ISIL and al-Qaeda and
2916	recruiting fighters for these groups have been under investigation.
