212	Is Sara Netanyahu's conduct affecting PM's performance?
291	Op-ed: When our prime minister doesn’t sleep at 3 am, it should be because
366	of red phone, not because he has to take care of a bag of milk.
439	The affair revealed last week by Meni Naftali, the former caretaker at the
514	prime minister's official residence, did not knock a single person who is
588	somehow involved in the political system off his or her feet – including the
665	media and every editor and reporter.
711	We hear the type of stories told by Naftali, and much worse stories, on an
786	almost daily basis. And not just from a nanny or a housekeeper, but from the
863	closest people to the Netanyahu couple – ministers, advisors, spokespeople,
939	former friends.
964	So when a person who worked at the prime minister's residence for 20 months
1040	comes out and talks about the conduct of the prime minister's wife and the
1115	backing she receives from the prime minister, we are not surprised, and we
1190	don't doubt him either, especially because this time we are talking about the
1268	man who is the salt of the earth, an elite unit fighter, a security guard who
1346	received a high security classification and excellence awards. This time these
1425	things cannot be swept under the rug – and not just because Mrs. Netanyahu
1500	is obsessed with dirt.
1542	The descriptions provided by Naftali point to a regular pattern, that same
1617	element judges always look for among serial criminals. That degrading pattern,
1696	arrogant attitude, unrestrained tongue-lashing by Sara Netanyahu, the
1766	outbursts, insults and humiliation her workers are subject to. Those
1835	unreasonable demands, a bottomless pit which can never be satisfied, and this
1913	time troubling racist statements were also revealed.
1985	The prime minister has turned to the media more than once, asking that his
2060	wife and children be left alone. When he does that, there is an expression on
2138	his face which creates empathy among quite a few people. A sort of personal,
2215	touching appeal from a person defending his loved ones with his own body
2288	against the bad guys' harm. And the Israeli public loves it – the person who
2365	jumps on the grenade to save his comrades. The fact is that despite these
2439	troubling stories, which in a different country would have already brought the
2518	leader down, here people go on voting for the Netanyahu couple again and
2591	again.
2617	Time to speak up
2643	But it's time to shatter this lie. Those complaining about Sara Netanyahu's
2719	behavior are not the bad guys in this story. The media outlets covering these
2797	cases are not the bad guys either. And what happens in the prime minister's
2873	residence is not gossip. When a prime minister talks to his caretaker at 3 am
2951	and asks him to satisfy his wife's whims – this time to replace milk in a
3025	plastic bag with a carton of milk – it's not a couple's problem. And by the
3101	way, Mr. Netanyahu, as opposed to the impression you are trying to create,
3176	this is not normative, regular behavior either, one that can be found in every
3255	house. Absolutely not.
3297	Yes, yes, let's call a spade a spade here too: What is happening in our prime
3375	minister's residence is not normal, and it's impossible that this does affect
3453	his performance. If the caretaker talks about "physical and mental damage,"
3529	it's impossible that these things just pass by Netanyahu's head. The staff
3604	turnover at the prime minister's residence, the atmosphere, the pressure, the
3682	irrational behavior we are being exposed to for the umpteenth time – it's a
3758	matter which should be of great interest to the public.
3833	We want to know that when the prime minister doesn’t sleep at 3 am it's
3905	because of the red phone, not because he has to take care of a bag of milk.
3981	And no one can convince us that the prime minister's performance is intact the
4060	next morning. Even the strongest person is affected when his closest
4129	surroundings is unstable. Imagine how each and every one of us would function
4207	after a nightmarish night with our partner.
4270	But these comments are not directed at Benjamin Netanyahu. Neither are they
4346	directed at the media, which are finding it difficult to publish what they
4421	know because of legal issues, even if they wanted to. They are directed at
4496	those ministers, advisors, assistants, former friends, and all kinds of
4568	associates who have closely witnessed what is happening at the Netanyahu
4641	residence and are failing to reveal what they know.
4712	We journalists are tired of listening to you tell us, always off the record of
4791	course, the stories you know, while making sure – pardon my French – to
4863	cover your ass. Get up and talk. Don't wait for the junior workers to do it
4939	for you. If our prime minister is not a fully functioning person because of
5015	what is happening in his home, and you know about it – you are part of it.
5099	If the Israeli public is being directly or indirectly harmed by a prime
5171	minister who is under an influence – you are partners in crime.
5254	It's time for you to speak up. Now, not when the prime minister leaves office
5332	and then you'll publish your stories.
5389	Then it will be a cowardly, miserable act, and most importantly – it will be
5466	too late.
