218	Tsarnaev trial: New surveillance footage revealed
291	When the first bomb went off, everybody turned their heads in startled
362	surprise -- except for one person. The young man with the white, turned-around
441	ball cap had been standing by a tree and he quickly strolled away, leaving his
520	backpack behind.
546	He was looking back over his shoulder when the second explosion came.
625	Federal prosecutors on Monday showed a video compilation of images, some never
704	before seen by the public. They were taken from surveillance cameras along the
783	route leading to the finish line of the Boston Marathon on April 15, 2013, the
862	day three people were killed and more than 240 people were injured by hot
936	shrapnel, nails and BBs from two pressure cooker bombs that had been hidden in
1015	backpacks and dropped amid the crowd.
1062	The man prosecutors say is defendant Dzhokhar Tsarnaev strolls along the
1135	sidewalk lining Boylston Street, unnoticed by the cheering people around him.
1213	He stops by the tree and looks to his right, and then to his left. He drops a
1291	heavy backpack to his feet, a few feet behind a line of children. He makes a
1368	phone call.
1389	Prosecutors say that 19-second call was to his brother, Tamerlan Tsarnaev, who
1468	also is shown on the video. They arrive together, turning the corner from
1542	Gloucester Street onto Boylston. Then they split up.
1604	"We called them Black Hat and White Hat," testified Anthony Imel, a digital
1680	forensics analyst for the FBI. Prosecutors say Black Hat is Tamerlan Tsarnaev,
1759	at 26 the older of the pair. He died in a gunbattle with police a few days
1834	after the bombings.
1863	"White Hat," they say, is the defendant. At the time, "Jahar" Tsarnaev was 19.
1942	Now he is on trial for his life; 17 of the 30 counts against him carry a
2015	possible death sentence.
2049	Tsarnaev has acknowledged that he and Tamerlan were responsible for setting
2125	off the bombs near the marathon's finish line. By taking responsibility for
2201	the carnage, he is hoping the jury will spare his life after hearing the full
2279	story.
2295	Federal prosecutors say it was the worst act of terror on U.S. soil since
2369	9/11. Jurors were told 118 people were carted off in ambulances and police
2444	vehicles within 20 minutes of the blasts.
2495	On the third day of testimony, prosecutors began to build their case in
2567	earnest, moving from the devastation caused by the bombs to the alleged motive
2646	behind them: terrorism.
2679	This is where prosecutors and defense attorneys disagree.
2746	The defense maintains that Tsarnaev was a stooge for his older brother.
2818	Questioning an FBI analyst in what had been limited cross-examination, defense
2897	attorney Miriam Conrad underscored a point: The video shows Tamerlan leading,
2975	and Jahar following several paces back.
3024	Jurors also heard more heart-wrenching testimony from the victims of the
3097	bombs. They watched videos of the brothers planting their backpacks and viewed
3176	an animation showing the path they took.
3226	They watched more videos showing Tsarnaev paying $3.49 for a half-gallon of
3302	milk at a Whole Foods store in Cambridge less than a half-hour after the
3375	bombings. And they saw him enter the gym on the campus of UMass Dartmouth
3449	shortly after 9 p.m. on April 16, the day after the bombings.
3520	Surveillance video revealed
3557	The surveillance video was collected from businesses and through social media
3635	by FBI agents in the aftermath of the bombing.
3691	It shows Tamerlan Tsarnaev walking past the Forum restaurant on his way to the
3770	finish line, where he dropped his homemade bomb, fashioned from a pressure
3845	cooker packed with gunpowder, nails and BBs.
3899	He is followed by Dzhokar, who lingers in front of Forum for about four
3971	minutes.
3989	There is an explosion and everybody's head turns toward the finish line --
4064	except Dzhokar Tsarnaev's. He casually walks away from his spot by the tree,
4141	without his backpack. He is glancing back when the second bomb goes off 12
4216	seconds after the first. It is not yet 3 p.m.
4271	Then he can be seen running with the crowd fleeing the bombs he and his
4343	brother set off.
4369	Prosecutors: Tweets show plot was on Tsarnaev's mind for months
4442	On Monday, prosecutors also presented evidence they said showed targeting the
4520	marathon had been on Tsarnaev's mind for at least a year.
4587	Jurors viewed posts from two Twitter accounts that FBI forensics analysts
4661	linked to Tsarnaev.
4690	The first, @J_tsar, is fairly well known.
4741	"I shall die young," @J_tsar tweeted on April 12, 2012.
4806	"They will spend their money &amp; they will regret it &amp; they will be defeated,"
4891	he tweeted on April 16, the day of the 2012 Boston Marathon.
4961	Prosecutors also revealed a second account, they say is evidence Tsarnaev led
5039	a double life. By day he was a slacker college sophomore who played video
5113	games and worked out at the gym with his friends. But late at night, he was a
5191	wannabe jihadist, posting on the second account, @Al_firdausiA.
5264	The name evokes the highest level of paradise a martyr can achieve. He called
5342	himself Ghuraba, the stranger. In one tweet, he urged people to listen to
5416	radical cleric Anwar al-Awlaki's lectures.
5468	"You will gain an unbelievable amount of knowledge," he said in March 2013,
5544	just weeks before the bombings. Prosecutors also allege in the indictment that
5623	Tsarnaev downloaded al-Awlaki's writings, calling him a "well-known al Qaeda
5700	propagandist." He was killed in a U.S. drone strike in 2011.
5770	Tsarnaev's other account, which was more mainstream, featured 1,100 tweets.
5846	Among them, the infamous note at 8 p.m. on the day of the bombing: "Ain't no
5923	love in the heart of the city, stay safe people." His final tweet, on April
5999	16, the day after the bombing, was, "I'm a stress free kind of guy."
6077	'There was smoke, there was blood'
6121	Jurors also heard more wrenching stories of bombing victims st what suddenly
6198	has become and unusually fast paced trial. Twenty-six people have testified in
6277	three days, including bombing victims, first responders and FBI agents and
6352	analysts.
6371	Monday began with dramatic testimony from a nurse and newlywed who lost both
6448	her legs; her husband also lost a leg.
6496	Jessica Kensky told the jury she didn't see or hear the explosion but felt as
6574	if she'd been launched on a rocket ship.
6624	"I remember being happy, I remember feeling sunlight on my face. I remember
6700	feeling free," she said. And then came the explosion.
6763	"I just felt like I was on a rocket," she said. "There was smoke, there was
6839	blood. I went into nurse mode. I was focused on my husband. His foot and part
6917	of his leg was completely detached, hanging on by a thread."
6987	She used her purse strap to make a tourniquet to stop the bleeding from her
7063	husband's leg.
7087	Then a man came to her and said, "Ma'am, you're on fire, you're on fire," she
7165	recounted.
7185	She lost one leg almost immediately. She made a difficult decision to have the
7264	second amputated in January.
7302	"I wanted to paint my toenails and put my feet in the sand. I wanted all of
7378	those things, and to lose my second leg was a gut-wrenching decision," she
7453	said.
7468	Danling Zhou, a friend of bombing victim Lingzi Lu, testified that the bomb
7544	tore a gaping wound in her abdomen. She said she pushed on her midsection
7618	"with all the strength I had" to keep her internal organs from spilling out.
7704	She looked at Lu and thought she would be fine. The bomb blew out her eardrums
7783	and she couldn't hear her friend screaming but she could see her. Then Lu
7857	lapsed into unconsciousness with her hands over her face.
7924	At the hospital, she asked about Lu every time she woke up. Finally, a friend
8002	told her that Lingzi was dead.
8042	"I guess everyone found out earlier," she said. "They were trying to protect
8119	me, so they didn't tell me."
8157	A physician who happened to be watching the marathon tried to help Lu, whose
8234	leg had been slashed from her hip to her ankle. When he heard what he called
8311	"agonal breathing," literally her last gasps, he said he knew he couldn't save
8390	her.
8404	In her purse, he said, he found a piece of metal from the bomb. It was still
8481	warm.
