363	Pope praises Iran nuclear deal in Easter message
435	VATICAN CITY: In an Easter peace wish, Pope Francis Sunday praised the
506	framework nuclear agreement with Iran as an opportunity to make the world
580	safer, while expressing deep worry about bloodshed in Libya, Yemen, Syria,
655	Iraq, Nigeria and elsewhere in Africa.
703	Cautious hope ran through Francis' "Urbi et Orbi" Easter message, a kind of
779	papal commentary on the state of the world's affairs, which he delivered from
857	the central balcony of St. Peter's Square.
909	He had just celebrated Mass in rain-whipped St. Peter's Square for tens of
984	thousands of people.
1014	Francis made his first public comments about the recent framework for an
1087	accord, reached in Lausanne, Switzerland, and aimed at ensuring Iran doesn't
1164	develop a nuclear weapon.
1199	"In hope we entrust to the merciful Lord the framework recently agreed to in
1276	Lausanne, that it may be a definitive step toward a more secure and fraternal
1354	world."
1371	Decrying the plentitude of weapons in the world in general, Francis said: "And
1450	we ask for peace for this world subjected to arms dealers, who earn their
1524	living with the blood of men and women."
1574	He denounced "absurd bloodshed and all barbarous acts of violence" in Libya,
1651	convulsed by fighting fueled by tribal and militia rivalries. He hoped "a
1725	common desire for peace" would prevail in Yemen, wracked by civil warfare.
1809	Francis prayed that the "roar of arms may cease" in Syria and Iraq, and that
1886	peace would come in Africa for Nigeria, South Sudan, Sudan and Congo.
1965	He recalled the young people, many of them targeted because they were
2035	Christians, killed last week in a Kenyan university, and lamented kidnappings,
2114	by Islamic extremists, that have plagued parts of Africa, including Nigeria.
2200	On Good Friday, Francis chastised the international community for what he
2274	called the complicit silence about the killing of Christians. On Easter he
2349	prayed that God would alleviate "the suffering of so many of our brothers
2423	persecuted because of his name."
2465	During Mass, Francis was shielded from pelting rain by a canopy erected
2537	outside St. Peter's Basilica, while prelates carried umbrellas in the yellow
2614	and white colors of the Vatican.
2656	The downpour petered out to a drizzle, and by the ceremony, the rain had
2729	stopped. Francis, wearing a white overcoat, was driven through the square in
2806	the open-sided popemobile so he could wave to the faithful.
