304	David Cameron says 'callous murder' of Boris Nemtsov must be rapidly investigated
409	Prime Minister says "callous murder" of Russian opposition politician "must be
488	fully, rapidly and transparently investigated, and those responsible brought
565	to justice"
586	David Cameron has said he is "shocked and sickened" by the murder of Boris
661	Nemtsov.
679	The Prime Minister said the "callous" killing of the Russian opposition
751	politician "must be fully, rapidly and transparently investigated, and those
828	responsible brought to justice".
870	Mr Nemtsov, a leading critic of president Vladimir Putin and of the war in
945	Ukraine, was gunned down near the Kremlin on the eve of a major rally in
1018	Moscow.
1035	“I am shocked and sickened by the callous murder of Boris Nemtsov as he
1107	walked in the heart Moscow last night," Mr Cameron said in a statement on
1181	Saturday morning.
1208	"This despicable act must be fully, rapidly and transparently investigated,
1284	and those responsible brought to justice."
1336	Mr Putin is reported to have taken personal charge of the investigation which
1414	his spokesman said "has all the makings of a contract hit and is extremely
1489	provocative".
1512	Mr Cameron added: “Boris Nemtsov was a man of courage and conviction. His
1586	life was dedicated to speaking up tirelessly for the Russian people, to
1658	demanding their right to democracy and liberty under the rule of law, and to
1735	an end to corruption.
1766	"He did so without fear, and never gave in to intimidation. He was greatly
1841	admired in Britain, not least by his friend Lady Thatcher, who visited him in
1919	Russia and who would have been appalled by today's news. The courage of
1991	Nemtsov's life contrasts with the utter cowardice of his murder.
2065	“I extend my condolences to Boris Nemtsov's family and friends. The Russian
2141	people have been deprived of a champion of their rights. Boris Nemtsov is
2215	dead. But the values he stood for will never die.”
