340	Hillary Clinton begins weighing details of a 2016 bid, with a spring announcement likely
452	Hillary Rodham Clinton is considering the nitty-gritty details of how and when
531	to organize a presidential campaign amid signs that she will postpone making
608	her shadow campaign official until later in 2015 than expected, according to
685	advisers and Democratic strategists.
731	Clinton and her small circle of close advisers are weighing legal advice to
807	set up a strict firewall between her and the numerous outside groups backing
884	her presumed 2016 candidacy, according to a person familiar with the talks.
960	The quarantine would run for a set period of time before she would announce
1036	her candidacy, as a way to make sure that the campaign and outside groups do
1113	not run afoul of federal election rules.
1163	Clinton is also debating whether to establish an exploratory committee — a
1238	placeholder organization that would allow her to raise money to pay for
1310	consultants, office space and other operating expenses. But the move would
1385	trigger financial disclosures she can now avoid, and Clinton is getting a lot
1463	of advice against forming such a committee, two Democratic strategists said.
1549	An exploratory committee might also appear too coy for a previous candidate
1625	with obvious ambitions for a second try, according to several Democratic
1698	advisers, who, like others, spoke on the condition of anonymity because
1770	Clinton has not yet said she is running.
1820	“At this point, what would she be exploring?” one strategist with ties to
1894	Clinton said.
1917	The strategy discussions provide further evidence that the former secretary of
1996	state and first lady is edging closer to another run for the presidency, after
2075	two years writing and promoting a memoir, giving paid speeches and
2142	strengthening ties with key Democratic interest groups. But rather than
2214	announce in January — as she did in 2007 — Clinton allies are increasingly
2289	working under the assumption that an official announcement will not come until
2368	spring.
2385	Several potential Republican candidates, including Sen. Rand Paul (Ky.) and
2461	Texas Gov. Rick Perry, have also signaled that they plan to wait until spring
2539	or later for a final decision. The only official 2016 candidate so far is
2613	former U.S. senator Jim Webb (D) from Virginia, who formed an exploratory
2687	committee last month.
2718	The enforced separation now under discussion by Clinton and her aides would
2794	erect a clearer legal barrier between her and her unofficial
2855	campaign-in-waiting. It would put an end to the informal discussions now
2928	taking place between Clinton’s inner circle and operatives working for
2999	outside groups backing her.
3036	Because Clinton is not a declared candidate for federal office, she and her
3112	advisers are allowed to communicate informally with groups such as Priorities
3190	USA Action, Ready for Hillary and American Bridge, whose Correct the Record
3266	project functions as a rapid-response operation on her behalf. If and when she
3345	announces her bid, however, Clinton’s campaign would not be able to share
3419	strategic information with allies outside the campaign and Democratic Party.
3505	Another issue her aides are considering is a Federal Election Commission rule
3583	that requires a 120-day waiting period before an outside group can make an
3658	expenditure on a candidate’s behalf if they have hired a vendor or
3725	strategist who worked for the candidate’s campaign.
3786	The rule led Restore Our Future, the super PAC that backed Mitt Romney in the
3864	2012 campaign, to delay running its first ad until 120 days after it brought
3941	former Romney fundraising officials on board.
3996	Priorities and Correct the Record are expected to function as an outside
4069	flanking operation for an official Clinton campaign, organizing and paying for
4148	advertising, research efforts and other activities. Ready for Hillary —
4220	which has collected an extensive database of declared supporters and potential
4299	donors for a Clinton 2016 candidacy — plans to close down if she announces a
4376	bid.
4390	Clinton’s status as an almost universally known political figure and
4459	presumptive front-runner means that the usual benefits of an exploratory
4532	committee — including a home address for campaign hiring and fundraising —
4607	are less relevant, some strategists said. She can afford to wait later than
4683	she did during the 2008 cycle and skip the exploratory committee step she took
4762	then, these strategists said.
4801	After announcing an exploratory committee in January 2007, Clinton waited
4875	until September of that year to form the official Hillary Clinton for
4945	President campaign. But there was no real doubt during that time that she
5019	would run, and some Democrats saw the exploratory committee as unnecessary and
5098	excessively cautious.
5129	Barack Obama generated buzz in political circles by largely dispensing with
5205	the exploratory phase. He made what was seen as a bold challenge to Clinton by
5284	replacing his three-week-old exploratory committee in February 2007 with the
5361	official Obama for America campaign.
5407	Clinton has already said she is thinking about another presidential campaign
5484	and that she is likely to make her decision after Jan. 1. She has given no
5559	hints in recent public remarks that she has reached a final decision or when
5636	she might do so.
5662	Clinton has accepted commercial speaking engagements into March that would be
5740	awkward for an official candidate, increasing speculation that she is
5810	postponing an announcement until after that date.
5869	Ready for Hillary has scheduled top-dollar fundraisers through March, on the
5946	assumption that she will not announce before then, according to a person
6019	familiar with the group’s plans.
6061	Clinton is scheduled to give a paid keynote address March 19 to the New York
6138	and New Jersey chapter of the American Camp Association, MSNBC reported this
6215	week. That’s the furthest ahead on the calendar that Clinton’s plans are
6288	known.
6304	Although she could continue to give paid speeches after announcing a
6373	presidential bid, strategists who support her candidacy but are not advising
6450	her directly said she is highly unlikely to do so. It would be unseemly and
6526	open her to criticism for perceived conflicts of interest, the strategists
6601	said.
6616	But other strategists said she could easily cancel speeches booked far in the
6694	future, or forgo her usual speaking fee of $250,000 or more. Although Clinton
6772	also makes appearances that do not earn her money, paid speeches — brokered
6848	by an agent — are a significant source of revenue for a public figure who
6922	has no regular salary at the moment.
6968	“There is quite a consensus that she would not be giving these paid speeches
7045	once she becomes a candidate, and that is appropriate,” said one close
7116	Clinton friend who is not directly advising her.
