328	Carl Pistorius, brother of jailed Paralympian Oscar, to be charged over motorway crash
438	Mr Pistorius was left in intensive car after the head-on accident, which
511	happened on one of the country’s main motorways towards the end of his
582	brother’s trial for killing Reeva Steenkamp
635	Carl Pistorius, the brother of the athlete Oscar Pistorius who was jailed last
714	year for killing girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp, is to be charged with reckless
790	and negligent driving.
822	South Africa’s National Prosecuting Authority confirmed it had served a
894	summons on Mr Pistorius to appear before a court to face the charge in the
969	coming weeks.
992	He is to be charged after a motorway car crash in August which left him in
1067	intensive care.
1092	Mr Pistorius was trapped in his car and suffered several ruptured organs as
1168	well as severe leg injuries after the head-on collision at around 8pm on
1241	Friday August 1 last year. He attended his brother’s high-profile trial in
1316	Pretoria in a wheelchair and leg braces.
1366	The crash was the second in which Mr Pistorius has been involved and for which
1445	he has faced charges. In May last year, he was acquitted of a culpable
1516	homicide charge over the death of a motorcyclist.
1575	The latest crash involved two cars, Mr Pistorius’s Toyota Corolla and the
1649	other driver’s Hyundai, and happened on the N1 motorway around two hours
1722	north of Pretoria as he drove home from a business meeting.
1791	Mr Pistorius’s family said it was caused by the other motorist, who was
1863	stuck in traffic in the opposite lane, pulling out in front of him.
1940	The South African Police Service and the National Prosecuting Authority this
2017	week announced that Mr Pistorius, but not the other motorist, would be charged
2096	with reckless and negligent driving.
2142	Colonel Ronel Otto, of the SAPS Limpopo, said Mr Pistorius had ignored several
2221	attempts by the investigating officer to take his statement about what
2292	happened.
2311	“One of the biggest reasons he is being charged is because he failed to
2383	co-operate with the police investigation,” she said.
2445	Nathi Mncube, spokesman for South Africa’s National Prosecuting Authority
2519	denied this was the case.
2554	“He has the right to remain silent, there must be evidence to bring such a
2629	charge,” he said.
2656	He rejected suggestions on social media that South Africa’s prosecuting
2728	authority – which has appealed against a judge’s decision not to convict
2801	Oscar Pistorius for murdering Miss Steenkamp – was pursuing a “vendetta”
2874	against the family.
