237	Slain Russian’s Complicated Romantic Life May Be Key to the Case
325	Boris Nemtsov's tangled love life is revealed as model Anna Duritskaya helps
402	police piece the puzzle together
444	Ukrainian model Anna Duritskaya became a witness to the murder of the
514	prominent Russian opposition leader 55-year-old Boris Nemtsov, the charismatic
593	opposition figure and critic of President Vladimir Putin who was shot earlier
671	today.
687	Ms. Duritskaya, a 23-year-old Ukrainian citizen, was being interrogated by the
766	police all night tonight. According to a source in the Russian police, the
841	young woman had “a very close personal romantic relationship” with the
912	murdered politician, says TV program Vesti. That relationship is already four
990	years old—since she was 19 years-old, in other words.
1053	Thanks to Ms. Duritskaya, the police have been able to establish the
1122	chronology of the events of this tragic night. According to her account, she
1199	was waiting for Mr. Nemtsov since 10 p.m. at the Bosco-café of the GUM
1270	shopping mall at the Red Square right across the Kremlin.
1337	The couple had dinner at around 11 p.m. Moscow time and then left the mall and
1416	went for a walk toward Vasilievsky embankment right by the Kremlin walls.
1490	Their intended destination was the posh building half a mile away from the
1565	Kremlin where the murdered politician had an apartment.
1630	As they were crossing the Big New-Moskva Bridge, an unidentified man ran out
1707	of the underpass of the bridge and shot Mr. Nemtsov multiple times. Then he
1783	jumped into the passing white car without a license plate.
1851	Mr. Nemtsov died on the scene.
1891	According to the Speaker for Prosecutor General Office, the “Ukrainian
1962	trace” of the brazen murder is one possible motive of the crime because of
2037	Ms. Duritskaya’s origin and recent arrival from Kiev.
2100	Other motives include a hit by his political enemies, including Russian
2172	nationalists and Islamic terrorists; business deals of the victim; and even
2248	the variant of Mr. Nemtsov’s murder being the “sacred sacrifice” by the
2320	Russia enemies that want to destabilize the political situation in the
2391	country.
2409	Boris Nemtsov is survived by his four children from three of his different
2484	“wives.”
2502	Mr. Nemtsov had a very unusual—some would say scandalous—relationship with
2577	a row of women. Although never divorced from his wife Raisa, during the last
2654	20 years of his life he lived openly with a number of different female civil
2731	partners. He has one daughter with his wife Raisa, a son and a daughter with
2808	the socialite and TV host Ekaterina Odintsova and a daughter with his former
2885	secretary Irina Koroleva, who used to work for the Administration of the
2958	Russian President.
2986	According to Mr. Nemtsov’s friend, while celebrating his 50th anniversary,
3061	Mr. Nemtsov had all his “wives” and children at the same table. He also
3133	never hid the fact that for a number of years he had a “relationship” with
3208	one Anastasia Ogneva, Dni.ru reports.
3255	The spotlight on the complicated personal life of the opposition leader burned
3334	brightly after the organized leak of his private telephone conversation about
3412	opposition journalist and socialite Bozhena Rynska exactly two years ago.
3486	During this conversation, Mr. Nemtsov had this to say about his colleague from
3565	the opposition: “Fuck her! She is The Bitch! Just because I did not fuck her
3642	she was washing my dirty laundry and putting me down in her paper for a year.
3720	And she was writing not on the theme of me fucking her. Let’s organize the
3795	Club of Those Who Never Fucked Bozhena Rynsky!”
3852	Back then, the opposition believes, the leak was organized by the FSB security
3931	service and was directed at Mr. Nemtsov to discredit the politician.
4009	The 23-year-old Ms. Duritskaya, who just arrived from Kiev, is not a suspect,
4087	but possibly was used by the criminals without her knowledge. She calls
4159	herself a model and an actress, although is not known for having any parts in
4237	movies or on the scene. She studied bookkeeping at Kiev University and worked
4315	for obscure model agencies that she left after having found the friendship of
4393	Mr. Nemtsov.
4415	Mr. Nemtsov did not feel safe in Russia and two years ago seriously considered
4494	the possibility of applying for political asylum in Lithuania, according to
4570	the ex-Prime Minister of that country.
