296	‘ISIS’ vs. ‘ISIL’ vs. ‘Islamic State’: The political importance of a much-debated acronym
409	Tonight, President Obama in his State of the Union address refered to "ISIL,"
487	or the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant.
541	Here's the portion of his speech in which he refers to the terror group:
623	In Iraq and Syria, American leadership – including our military power – is
698	stopping ISIL’s advance. Instead of getting dragged into another ground war
774	in the Middle East, we are leading a broad coalition, including Arab nations,
852	to degrade and ultimately destroy this terrorist group. We’re also
919	supporting a moderate opposition in Syria that can help us in this effort, and
998	assisting people everywhere who stand up to the bankrupt ideology of violent
1075	extremism. This effort will take time. It will require focus. But we will
1149	succeed. And tonight, I call on this Congress to show the world that we are
1225	united in this mission by passing a resolution to authorize the use of force
1302	against ISIL.
1325	In September, President Obama went on "Meet the Press" to talk with new host
1402	Chuck Todd. They talked at length about terrorism and the administration's
1477	plans to counter it, but they didn't couldn't quite agree on what to call the
1555	enemy.
1571	"I'm preparing the country to make sure that we deal with a threat from ISIL,"
1650	Obama said. ISIL stands for the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant. Todd
1725	followed up with, "Obviously, if you're going to defeat ISIS, you have used
1801	very much stronger language." ISIS stands for the Islamic State of Iraq and
1877	Syria.
1893	Later, after the interview ended, Todd told his panel, "Obviously we refer to
1971	it at NBC News as ISIS. The Obama administration, president, says the word
2046	ISIL. The last S stands for Syria, the last L they don’t want to have stand
2122	for Syria." The insinuation is that the country Obama decided to stay out of
2199	last year is also his Voldemort, better left unnamed.
2262	Many conservative news organizations agreed that the acronym was worth 1,000
2339	words.
2355	Many politicians and media organizations that have chosen ISIL rather than
2430	ISIS have said they went with the former as a paean to grammar. When you
2503	translate the Arabic name for the group of insurgents (Al-Dawla Al-Islamiya fi
2582	al-Iraq wa al-Sham) into English, many argue that using "the Levant" (a.k.a.
2659	ISIL) to describe the region is most accurate -- as this WorldViews post from
2737	June explains.
2761	Others have interpreted this acronym choice differently. Maureen Dowd wrote in
2840	an Aug. 9 column:
2867	It’s a bit odd that the administration is using “the Levant,” given that
2940	it conjures up a colonial association from the early 20th century, when
3012	Britain and France drew their maps, carving up Mesopotamia guided by economic
3090	gain rather than tribal allegiances. Unless it’s a nostalgic nod to a time
3165	when puppets were more malleable and grateful to their imperial overlords.
3249	The White House has often faced an army of deconstructionists whenever words
3326	come out of Obama's mouth -- and even when they don't -- and it seems a bit
3402	excessive to infer an entire foreign policy from an acronym. But politicians
3479	and media organizations all over have struggled with what to call this group
3556	of Sunni insurgents, and how their choice would be interpreted.
3629	House Democrats last year decided after a long debate that they too would call
3708	the extremist group ISIL -- partly because ISIS was a name that first belonged
3787	to a goddess, and then to thousands of women who took said goddess's name,
3862	before a terrorist group claimed it.
3908	ISIL might sound odd, which is why it has the virtue of not already being
3982	taken by other people. The Obama administration has been clear that the Sunni
4060	insurgents represent a serious threat, and if the group sounds like nothing
4136	you've ever heard before, both in deed and name, it's probably easier to make
4214	that sink in.
4237	The Levant also denotes a far larger region than just Iraq and Syria. By
4310	calling the group ISIL instead of ISIS, it implies that the group is not only
4388	a serious threat, it is a large one too.
4438	Going back to Congress: Even before House Democrats decided to go with ISIL,
4515	there was an evident partisan split on Congress on how legislators decided to
4593	refer to the group, as shown by data collected by the Sunlight Foundation.
4677	Out of all the mentions of ISIS that have occurred during floor speeches, 86
4754	percent have come from Republicans. Fifty-four percent of ISIL mentions have
4831	come from Democrats. However, this split could be explained by many other
4905	things -- Republicans out-talking Democrats on the Islamic State overall or
4981	the fact that Congress has had the same difficulties settling on a name as the
5060	media has.
5080	While the government has been choosing between ISIS and ISIL, many news
5152	organizations have been making similar decisions in their style guides. The
5228	Washington Post has decided to refer to the group as the Islamic State, after
5306	the group itself declared that its ambitions outstripped Iraq and Greater
5380	Syria. Several other news organizations have also made the switch, including
5457	the Associated Press, as Poynter reported.
5509	About a month ago ISIL changed its name, so our approach is to refer to them
5586	on first reference simply as “Islamic militants,” “jihadi fighters,”
5655	“the leading Islamic militant group fighting in Iraq (Syria), etc.” On
5726	second reference, something like “the group, which calls itself the Islamic
5802	State,” with “group” helping to make clear that it is not an
5863	internationally recognized state.
5906	The ISIL-ISIS debate continues in large part because that the Islamic State is
5985	not internationally recognized, and officials wouldn't want to recognize the
6062	existence of a state that remains an ambition of a group they hope to
6132	extinguish.
6153	Regardless of the reasoning, the fact that the Islamic State suffers so many
6230	synonyms has probably done little more than confuse the public, which has only
6309	figured out who these Sunni insurgents are very recently. A NBC/Wall Street
6385	Journal poll from July asking for opinions on the United States' actions
6458	against the group had 40 percent of respondents saying they didn't know enough
6537	to have an opinion. A recent ABC News/Washington Post poll shows that people
6614	now seem much more informed, but no polling exists testing public opinion on
6691	ISIL or the Islamic State.
6727	The lesson: This situation is moving so fast -- the many explainers written
6803	about ISIS v. ISIL in June are already a few steps behind -- and the Islamic
6880	State's identity is changing so rapidly that it seems futile to treat acronyms
6959	as a magnifying glass.
6991	However, it also isn't surprising. Given the White House's caution in
7061	explaining its thinking on how to deal with the Sunni insurgents, the media
7137	hasn't had much to parse beside the one letter that differentiates the
7208	administration from many of the news outlets that cover it.
