269	Phone transcript reveals Sara Netanyahu rant at political rival's wife
363	Binyamin Netanyahu’s wife accuses Monique Ben Melekh and husband Eli Moyal
438	of jealousy of Israeli prime minister who is ‘admired by the entire world’
522	Sara Netanyahu, the wife of the Israeli prime minister, has been thrust to the
601	centre of his election campaignafter the release of an alleged transcript of
678	her ranting down the phone to the wife of a political rival during the war in
756	Gaza last summer.
783	The transcript – written up by an an Israeli journalist who has heard the
857	tape – was published as Sara Netanyahu gave a lengthy interview in which she
934	alleged her enemies were trying to humiliate her in their determination to get
1013	at her husband.
1038	Binyamin Netanyahu’s Likud party is nervous that the audio tape itself will
1114	be released to embarrass him on the eve of the 17 March elections in which,
1190	polls suggest, he is trailing his main rival, Yitzhak Herzog.
1261	While she is not up for election, Sara Netanyahu, has been propelled into the
1339	campaign amid allegations regarding her behaviour towards staff in the prime
1416	minister’s official residence and allegations of the couple’s excessive
1488	spending funded by the state.
1527	In the interview in the Jerusalem Post, the educational psychologist describes
1606	her husband as a “hero of the free world” and compares disgruntled staff
1679	to “scheming” servants in Downton Abbey.
1729	Amid speculation that the 30-minute tape would be released by Monique Ben
1803	Melekh, the wife of the former mayor of Sderot, Eli Moyal – who had
1871	criticised Netanyahu’s handling of the Gaza war – journalist Ben Caspit
1943	released his own transcript of the bizarre conversation.
2009	The prime minister’s wife accuses Ben Melekh and her husband of being
2079	jealous of Netanyahu as she brags about his talents and how he is admired and
2157	loved.
2173	“Does anyone in the country want anyone else other than Bibi? Huh?! Someone
2249	in this entire country?! They admire Binyamin Netanyahu the entire world over!
2337	“[He is] a man [who] took all of the State of Israel upon his shoulders; he
2413	sends soldiers to war, he behaves with rare political wisdom, speaks with
2487	leaders all the time! Binyamin Netanyahu’s experience, his wisdom, his
2558	education!
2578	“[He has] extensive education, university degrees. He also reads books,
2650	understands the economy, security, policy, he knows how to speak with leaders
2728	of the world! Where is your man? He doesn’t even reach the ankles of my
2800	husband, what, did Eli Moyal ever speak once with leaders of the world?! Did
2877	he ever do something in his life?
2920	“… He [Binyamin Netanyahu] is one of the most veteran leaders in the
2989	world. In the United States they say that if he had been born in the US,
3062	he’d have been elected president there.”
3112	At one stage, Ben Melekh asks Sara Netanyahu: “Why do you think that Eli is
3188	jealous of the prime minister?”.
3230	The prime minister’s wife replies: “He is jealous of him because he is so
3304	successful, because he is a great leader!! And your man just babbles and
3377	babbles. He is jealous of him because he’s a million times smarter than him,
3454	because he’s a million times more successful, because he’s a giant of a
3526	leader! Where would be today without him? Where? Running from studio to studio
3605	and bragging!! [referring to Moyal] That’s all he knows how to do. He brags
3681	everywhere possible …
3712	“I’m just waiting to see if he gives an interview against me … if he
3781	does that, he will be subhuman …”
3824	In an interview with the Jerusalem Post and the Hebrew newspaper Maariv,
3897	apparently designed to rebuff recent criticism, Sara Netanyahu blamed the
3971	recent media focus on her on a campaign by political enemies – foremost
4043	among them Noni Mozes, publisher of the mass circulation tabloid Yedioth
4116	Ahronoth – and the left wing.
4155	“It’s an elitist and chauvinist approach that blames the woman, that says
4229	everything must be the woman’s fault,” she said. “It’s a very sexist
4298	approach – a concerted effort to humiliate the prime minister’s wife in
4370	her natural role as partner and helpmeet.”
4422	She said the couple had been media targets since 1996 when Netanyahu was first
4501	elected as prime minister.
4537	“We were a young couple from the wrong side of the political map, not bad
4611	looking, educated, with cute little children. As a journalist once told me:
4687	‘If you had been from the left, you, just as you are, would have been our
4761	queen.’”
4779	It seems unlikely, however, that her comments will do much to help dispel the
4857	image some have of her as grandiose, somewhat paranoid and lacking in
4927	judgment.
4946	Elsewhere in the interview, Sara Netanyahu appeared to echo the sentiments
5021	from the taped tirade.
5053	“He’s a hero not only of the Jewish people, but of people everywhere who
5126	feel themselves part of the free world, people who oppose the horrors that
5201	Islamic State is inflicting and Iran’s nuclear plans. I see my relationship
5277	with him as a great responsibility.”
5323	Commenting on allegations made by their former housekeeper regarding her
5396	behaviour, she compared her and her husband’s situation to the British TV
5470	drama Downton Abbey.
5500	“It’s the idea that some people earn their livelihood by throwing dirt on
5574	other people, their reputations – and not just anyone, but someone who you
5649	worked for, who was by your side.
5692	“If you’re unhappy at work, why not just leave? Why do you have to spit
5764	into the well you drank from? What kind of person does something like that? I
5842	can’t help thinking of the BBC drama Downton Abbey, with its
5903	upstairs/downstairs intrigue, scheming staff and the bubbling cauldron of
5977	endless gossip.”
