247	My life of hell with Oscar Pistorius: Watch ex-lover reveal how she feared Blade Runner would kill her
373	Samantha Taylor was left with bruises and scars after the Blade Runner bit and
452	pinched her - she was also tortured mentally during the 18-month relationship
539	Oscar Pistorius’s former girlfriend has spoken of her ­terrifying
605	­relationship with the “angry and possessive” Paralympian.
673	Samantha Taylor said she feared he would kill her and revealed she once hid
749	his gun after he flew into a rage at her.
800	Pistorius, 27, was cleared of murder yesterday, but he could still be jailed
877	today for shooting dead his model ­girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp.
949	And ahead of the verdict, Samantha, 20, said: “It could have been me.”
1029	Follow live updates from the court as the judge delivers her final verdict
1104	here
1118	Samantha said she was left with bruises and scars after the Blade Runner bit
1195	and pinched her, but she was also tortured mentally by him during the 18-month
1274	relationship.
1297	She said: “Oscar used to lock me in his house and then go out. I had no
1369	food, I couldn’t get out. It was dangerous.
1422	“He often went out saying he will just be an hour or so and ended up out all
1499	day or night. I wouldn’t hear from him all night and his phone would be off.
1585	“He would say he’s going out for an hour and the next day, three in the
1657	morning, he would drive home.”
1697	She also described how he once left her paralysed with fear when he used his
1774	beloved Porsche as a weapon, driving her at up to 200mph to “punish” her.
1857	Pistorius shot Reeva, 29, on Valentine’s Day 2013. And since that moment,
1931	Samantha has had nightmares.
1969	Shuddering, she said: “What happened to Reeva Steenkamp could so easily have
2046	happened to me. I definitely think that could have been me – without a doubt
2123	– many, many, many times.”
2159	Samantha first met Pistorius in 2010 when she was 16 and he was 23 at a rugby
2237	match, but they did not start dating for another year.
2301	Speaking of one ordeal, she said: “He gets so mad, so angry he can’t even
2375	speak.
2391	“He was trying to string his words together, spitting, shouting, grabbing.
2466	It was horrible. He used to bite me a lot, pinch me in anger and in fun. I had
2545	bruises and scars. It was painful.”
2590	Another time the couple rowed when he accused her of sticking up for one of
2666	her ex-boyfriends.
2694	She said: “I was really scared. He made me stand on the stairs and shouted
2769	at me. It was like I was on the naughty step.”
2825	But one night, things got so bad she thought he was going to shoot her at his
2903	home in Pretoria, South Africa, with the gun he would later turn on Reeva.
2987	Samantha said: “I had to hide his gun, I was so scared of him.
3059	“We had friends over for dinner, at his house and we’d all had a little to
3134	drink but I think he was going for one that night.
3194	“He was on the hard liquor. He moved all the couches and set the floor on
3268	fire and danced around it.
3304	"It was a marble floor and he used alcohol to light it on fire. He slipped and
3383	he chipped his tooth.
3414	“But because he was so drunk he thought I’d beaten him up. He started
3484	screaming at me.
3510	"He was looking for his gun. He was saying I was a bitch because I beat him
3586	up. ‘What kind of person are you? You bitch.’
3641	"I felt threatened. Both of us went upstairs to bed and I was walking a bit in
3720	front of him."
3744	She continued: “When I got to the room I hid his gun, because I really did
3819	think he’d use it.
3847	“I hid it under the bed knowing he wouldn’t look there. He kept that gun,
3921	the one used on Reeva, on his table or by his prosthetic legs on the floor.
4006	"He slept on the right near the windows and he never kept that gun under the
4083	bed, like he claimed in his statement.
4131	“He kept telling me I was a bitch because his lip was cut, but I think he
4205	realised things had gone too far.” The next day the couple went to a
4274	wedding.
4292	She said: “We rushed and he didn’t realise he had left his gun at home and
4367	he said to me ‘Oh my word, where’s my gun?’ I told him why I had hidden
4439	it.
4452	“He didn’t apologise but didn’t want to acknowledge what had
4513	happened.”
4533	Pistorius would vanish for nights of boozing, partying and chatting up
4604	impressionable women.
4635	But when the couple were apart for longer periods, like when Oscar had
4706	athletics events abroad, his jealousy erupted.
4762	Samantha said: “His jealousy was very tough. He’d phone my mum and dad 10
4836	times a day to find out where I was. In one month I received around 700 calls.
4924	“It was excessive. If I hadn’t replied to messages within 30 seconds I was
4999	doing something wrong.”
5032	Miming taking a selfie, she explained: “I had to show him photos ‘look at
5106	me in my pyjamas – I’m not out! Look I’m watching TV, sitting with my
5176	brother.’
5195	“He’s a very insecure man. He’d call at all hours. I was scared of him
5266	at times because he had very bad anger issues. He was so possessive, he would
5344	look through my phone and find a photo from long ago or look on my Facebook,
5421	and often get quite angry.
5457	“It was horrible, when you are in a relationship you want someone to trust
5532	you. He never allowed me to wear make-up and would make me take my belly ring
5610	out.
5624	"If we were going out he would just give me a few minutes so I would not have
5702	time to get ready.
5730	“He didn’t like me dressing up and other men looking at me.”
5800	Samantha said everywhere Pistorius went his gun went with him – tucked in
5874	his “pants”.
5896	She also struggled to keep up with his rapidly changing personality –
5966	switching from sweet and charming to sobbing and suicidal.
6034	She said: “He would arrive at my house at 5am drunk and wake everyone up. He
6111	had a temper. Everyone has a switch inside of them, but when his went off he
6188	couldn’t control it. You just have to be calm with him. Not react to it.
6270	“He shouted at me for random stuff, like if his coffee wasn’t made. He
6341	would get angry about weird things that shouldn’t really get to someone.
6423	“He screamed and shouted at me a lot. He’s got quite a foul mouth.”
6500	At Pretoria High Court yesterday, Pistorius was cleared of murder, but he
6574	could still be found guilty of culpable homicide – the equivalent to
6643	manslaughter here.
6671	Samantha had to testify and has since revealed her frustration at watching him
6750	“lie, lie and lie again” in the witness box.
6804	She was so outraged she even tweeted mid-trial: “Last lies you get to tell.
6880	You better make it worth your while.”
6927	She said: “When I gave evidence we stared at each other all the time.
7006	“I was just so frustrated because he was lying. He was so good at lying.
7088	“Among my family we always had a joke he’s got a different personality
7159	every day. One day he was a gangster, the next day he is a romantic, then a
7235	race driver and the next day Rambo with a gun. We used to say ‘who are you
7310	today?’.”
7329	Speaking of today’s looming verdict she added: “I have a lot of faith in
7402	the judge, I am sure the decision she makes is a good one.
7470	"I did not know what to expect – so many people have preconceived ideas. It
7546	looks like the judge is going towards culpable homicide.”
