221	It was him' Boston bomber's lawyers admit guilt
292	A lawyer for the accused Boston Marathon bomber said at the start of his trial
371	that their client bore responsibility for the attacks that killed three people
450	and injured 264 with a blunt admission: "It was him."
513	But Dzhokhar Tsarnaev was a secondary player in the April 15, 2013 bombings at
592	the famous race and the fatal shooting days later of a police officer, defense
671	attorney Judith Clarke said in her opening argument in US District Court in
747	Boston. She indicated that the 21-year-old's older brother, Tamerlan, was the
825	prime mover.
847	The defense strategy, which did not include a move to change Tsarnaev's
919	not-guilty plea, appeared aimed at sparing Tsarnaev from the death penalty. If
998	he is convicted, the jury will decide whether he is executed or gets life in
1075	prison without possibility of parole.
1122	A prosecutor, William Weinreb, told jurors how Tsarnaev and his brother, both
1200	ethnic Chechens, carefully selected the places where they left the bombs in an
1279	effort to punish the United States for military actions in Muslim-dominated
1355	countries.
1375	Assistant US Attorney Weinreb anticipated the defense's strategy of casting
1451	blame on 26-year-old Tamerlan Tsarnaev, who was killed when his younger
1523	brother inadvertently ran him over after a gunbattle with police a few days
1599	after the bombing.
1627	"The focus is going to be on the defendant," the prosecutor said. "That's
1701	because it's his day in court. He's the one the government has to prove
1773	guilty, not his brother."
1808	But Clarke said although Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, then 19, set off a homemade
1880	pressure-cooker bomb at the marathon's crowded finish line and three days
1954	later participated in the fatal shooting of the police officer did not tell
2030	the whole story.
2056	"If the only question was whether that was Dzhokhar Tsarnaev ... it would be
2133	very easy for you,"
2162	Clarke said her client played a secondary role in a scheme hatched and driven
2240	by his older brother.
2271	"It was Tamerlan Tsarnaev who self-radicalized. It was Dzhokhar who followed
2348	him," Clarke said. "The evidence will show that Tamerlan planned and
2417	orchestrated and enlisted his brother into this series of horrific acts."
2500	The approach set up an immediate conflict with US District Judge George
2572	O'Toole. He ruled shortly before opening statements that the question of the
2649	relative culpability of the two brothers was best left to the trial's second
2726	phase, which would follow providing Dzhokhar is found guilty.
2797	"Some evidence of the brother's interactions will be inevitable," O'Toole
2871	allowed in brief remarks before the trial opened. But he interrupted Clarke
2947	several times to warn her against going too deep into family history so early
3025	in the trial.
3048	'Soldier in a holy war'
3081	In his argument, Weinreb said that Dzhokhar had read radical online magazines,
3160	where he learned how to build the shrapnel-filled bombs that tore the legs off
3239	of about 16 people at the race's crowded finish line.
3302	"He believed that he was a soldier in a holy war against Americans," Weinreb
3379	said of Tsarnaev.
3406	The prosecutor also stressed the brutal nature of the injuries caused by the
3483	pressure-cooker bombs.
3515	"The purpose of that kind of bomb is to shred flesh, shatter bone, set people
3593	on fire and cause people to suffer painful deaths," said Weinreb. He described
3672	the painful final moments of the three who died: restaurant manager Krystle
3748	Campbell, 29; graduate student Lingzi Lu, 23, and Martin Richard, 8.
3826	He noted that Tsarnaev left the backpack he carried the bomb in behind a group
3905	of child spectators, including Martin.
3953	"He pretended to be a spectator but he had murder in his heart," Weinreb said.
4041	The prosecutor also described in detail how Dzhokhar Tsarnaev killed his
4114	brother following a gunbattle with police in the Boston suburb of Watertown,
4191	while the two were trying to flee.
4235	"The defendant rolled right over his brother and dragged his body about 50
4310	feet (15 meters) down the street," Weinreb said. The defendant had been trying
4389	to run down the police officers who were attempting to arrest the pair.
4470	A dozen or so people injured in the attack and family members, including
4543	dancer Heather Abbott and Marc Fucarile, both of whom lost legs in the blasts,
4622	and Richard's parents, sat quietly in court during the proceedings.
4699	The jury saw several videos of the bombs going off and of badly injured people
4778	screaming on the ground, surrounded by bits of metal shrapnel and thick smoke.
4866	"I was blown through the air. There was a deafening explosion," said Colton
4942	Kilgore, who had traveled from Asheville, North Carolina, to see his
5011	mother-in-law race. "As I was sitting up my brain was in this haze and I
5084	couldn't hear out of my left ear and there was screaming and I realized ... it
5163	must have been a bomb."
