275	Oscar Pistorius should get house arrest, community service: social worker
372	South African track star Oscar Pistorius should serve three years of partial
449	house arrest and community service for the negligent killing of his
517	girlfriend, a witness said on Monday at the first day of the athlete's
588	sentencing.
609	The 27-year-old Paralympic and Olympic star, whose lower legs were amputated
686	as a baby, was convicted of culpable homicide last month for the shooting of
763	29-year-old law graduate and model Reeva Steenkamp on Valentine's Day 2013.
848	The case has riveted South Africans and gripped millions around the world,
923	shocked by the fall of a man widely admired as an inspiration for disabled
998	people and a symbol of triumph over adversity.
1054	Arguing against a prison term, correctional services social worker Joel
1126	Maringa said Pistorius was a "co-operative" person who should be sentenced to
1204	three years of "correctional supervision", which would mean the athlete would
1282	have to spend a portion of the day at home.
1335	Maringa also said Pistorius should carry out community service, such as
1407	sweeping the streets outside museums in Pretoria.
1466	State prosecutor Gerrie Nel, who is pushing for a lengthy prison sentence,
1541	described the social worker's recommendations as "shockingly inappropriate".
1627	Judge Thokozile Masipa adjourned the hearing early as Nel requested time to
1703	review documents before he calls at least two of the state's witnesses on
1777	Tuesday. Sentencing is expected to conclude by the end of the week.
1854	Earlier the court heard from Pistorius' psychologist, Dr Lore Hartzenberg, who
1933	said the athlete was a caring, remorseful person who was suffering from
2005	post-traumatic stress disorder and sometimes spent sessions weeping as she
2080	held him.
2099	"What we are left with, My Lady, we are left with a broken man who has lost
2175	everything," Hartzenberg said, as Pistorius stared at the floor in the packed
2253	Pretoria courtroom. "It is foreseen that Mr Pistorius will require intensive
2330	and ongoing psychotherapy."
2367	Cleared of murder
2394	Masipa cleared Pistorius of the more serious charge of murder, saying
2464	prosecutors had failed to prove his intent to kill when he fired four 9mm
2538	rounds through the door of a toilet in what he said was the mistaken belief an
2617	intruder was hiding behind it.
2657	A murder conviction would have almost certainly carried a jail sentence.
2730	Culpable homicide, South Africa's equivalent of manslaughter, can be punished
2808	by anything from 15 years in jail to a suspended sentence or community
2879	service.
2897	A stony-faced Pistorius earlier stared straight ahead as police officers
2970	escorted him into the court building. He declined to answer questions from the
3049	scrum of reporters but greeted his family inside the court with smiles and
3124	hugs.
3139	After a dramatic six-month, on-off trial, opinion is starkly divided on the
3215	eventual outcome.
3242	A non-custodial sentence would be likely to spark public anger, fuelling a
3317	perception among black South Africans that, 20 years after the end of
3387	apartheid, wealthy whites can still secure preferential justice.
3461	"At the end of the day, a young lady was killed and someone should pay for
3536	it," 57-year-old Mildred Lekalakala, a member of the Women's League of the
3611	ruling African National Congress, said outside the court.
3678	The decision by 66-year-old Masipa, only the second black woman to rise to
3753	South Africa's bench, to absolve Pistorius of murder drew criticism from many
3831	legal experts and the public in a country infamous for violence, particularly
3909	against women.
3933	Pistorius said the shooting in his upmarket Pretoria home was a tragic
4004	mistake, but at the trial prosecutors presented a written firearms license
4079	test in which he acknowledged that using lethal force against an intruder was
4157	only allowed if there was a direct threat to a person's life.
4228	With this in mind, as well as the questions over Masipa's ruling on intent,
4304	the state could yet decide to appeal the culpable homicide verdict in pursuit
4382	of a murder conviction. Under South African law, an appeal cannot be launched
4460	until sentencing has been concluded.
