212	The controversy surrounding American Sniper
279	The promotion and defense of Clint Eastwood’s American Sniper is the latest
355	means by which the political and media establishment in the US is pursuing its
434	militaristic agenda. Such is the ferocity of this campaign that the relatively
513	toothless critical comments of filmmaker Michael Moore and actor-director Seth
592	Rogen have provoked controversy and brought down upon them a torrent of abuse.
671	The two have been denounced as “traitors,” and Moore has received death
743	threats.
761	American Sniper is part of the effort to create a mythology around the illegal
840	invasion and occupation of Iraq by the US military, an undertaking that has
916	destroyed that Middle Eastern country’s infrastructure, provoked a murderous
993	sectarian civil war and led to the deaths of one million or more Iraqis. The
1070	motive is not simply to legitimize past crimes, but to intimidate and poison
1147	public opinion and undermine opposition to future and even greater crimes.
1231	The hero of American Sniper is Chris Kyle (Bradley Cooper), a Navy SEAL who
1307	reportedly killed 160 or more Iraq insurgents. The film paints him as an
1380	upright, patriotic, God-fearing individual who was prompted to join the
1452	military, above all, by the September 11, 2001 suicide attacks.
1525	The sequences set in Iraq present the American forces as engaged in a
1595	righteous campaign against an almost inconceivably savage and evil foe.
1667	American Sniper’s attitude toward Iraqis, and Arabs generally, is hostile
1741	and contemptuous. The US forces represent order, modernity, civilization and
1818	sanity; the Iraqis—superstition, backwardness, treachery and violence. The
1893	American soldiers are obliged, according to the logic of the film, to
1963	exterminate great numbers of Iraqis both in self-defense and as some sort of
2040	act of public hygiene.
2072	The work never raises a single question about the legitimacy of the Iraq war,
2150	its origins, its historical context or its larger geopolitical implications.
2227	American Sniper is intended to block questioning and criticism.
2300	A determined attempt is underway in the US to revive the jingoistic spirit of
2378	“My country, right or wrong,” so discredited in the eyes of millions
2447	through the experience of the Vietnam War.
2499	The primitivism of the film’s outlook is matched by the primitivism of the
2574	psychology and motivations depicted. The stolid Kyle is single-minded about
2650	protecting American lives; his rather whiny wife is single-minded about having
2729	him return home; the filthy Iraqis are single-minded about killing Americans,
2807	etc. Whitewashing a bloody, criminal operation in a comprehensive fashion is a
2886	time-consuming and, in its own way, demanding task; the filmmakers had little
2964	energy left over to create believable, complex human characters or dialogue.
3050	It should be noted that Eastwood’s film considerably downplays and dilutes
3125	Kyle’s semi-fascistic views and behavior. Cooper is a far more subdued and
3200	sorrowful individual than Kyle as the latter describes himself in his
3270	autobiography.
3294	The son of a Southwestern Bell and AT&amp;T manager, who was also a deacon and
3373	owned a small business, Kyle (whose plan was to become a ranch manager) grew
3450	up in semi-rural, north-central Texas in an atmosphere steeped in militarism,
3528	anti-communism and “family and traditional values.” It is hard to conceive
3603	of a more reactionary background.
3646	As for Kyle’s insights into the Iraq war, his ghost-written memoir states:
3721	“Savage, despicable evil. That’s what we were fighting in Iraq. That’s
3792	why a lot of people, myself included, called the enemy ‘savages.’”
3868	He adds: “My country sent me out there so that bullshit wouldn’t make its
3942	way back to our shores. I never once fought for the Iraqis. I could give a
4017	flying fuck about them… I loved what I did. I still do… it was fun. I had
4091	the time of my life being a SEAL.”
4135	When he was investigated for allegedly killing an unarmed civilian, Kyle, an
4212	anti-Muslim bigot, told an army colonel: “I don’t shoot people with
4280	Korans. I’d like to, but I don’t.”
4324	Kyle also served briefly as a bodyguard for former Alaska Governor Sarah
4397	Palin. Extreme right-wing Christian fanaticism and related fascistic notions
4474	are reportedly prevalent in elite US death squads such as the SEALs and Army
4551	Special Forces.
4576	The liberal critics, who have either shifted far to the right themselves or
4652	are thoroughly cowed, generally responded favorably to American Sniper. David
4730	Denby in the New Yorker, for example, argued that the film “is both a
4800	devastating war movie and a devastating antiwar movie, a subdued celebration
4877	of a warrior’s skill and a sorrowful lament over his alienation and
4945	misery.”
4963	The New York Times’ A.O. Scott, while not quite placing the present work
5036	among Eastwood’s “great movies,” found that “its considerable power
5104	derives from the clarity and sincerity of its bedrock convictions. Less a war
5182	movie than a western… it is blunt and effective, though also troubling.”
5264	Official Hollywood joined in the foul campaign to promote American Sniper
5338	January 15 by bestowing six Academy Award nominations on the film, including
5415	in the Best Picture, Best Actor and Best Adapted Screenplay categories.
5496	The critics, the media and the entertainment establishment were clearly going
5574	to present no problem to the pro-war counter-offensive aimed at deadening
5648	public consciousness.
5679	The “controversy” that emerged in late January was more of a provocation
5752	than anything else. The ultra-right, pleased as punch with the film and its
5828	commercial success, was simply waiting for someone well known to say the wrong
5907	thing.
5923	When Michael Moore and Seth Rogen (fresh from participating in his own
5994	sinister provocation, the anti-North Korean film The Interview ) uttered a
6069	couple of “wrong things,” they were pounced on and undeservedly branded as
6144	opponents of the valiant American military.
6197	On January 18, without mentioning the film, Moore tweeted, “We were taught
6272	that snipers were cowards… Snipers aren’t heroes. And invaders [are]
6341	worse.” He tweeted a second time to the effect that defending “your
6409	home… from invaders” who have come 7,000 miles was “brave.”
6478	Rogen tweeted January 19 that American Sniper “kinda reminded me” of the
6551	Nazi propaganda film shown in Quentin Tarantino’s Inglourious Basterds.
6632	The two came under ferocious attack. Rogen threw in the towel immediately,
6707	asserting he had been misunderstood: “I actually liked American Sniper. It
6782	just reminded me of the Tarantino scene… I wasn’t comparing the two.”
6861	Moore, who hasn’t a political leg left to stand on (especially after
6930	vociferously defending Kathryn Bigelow’s pro-torture Zero Dark Thirty ),
7003	wrote a miserable, defensive comment on Facebook in which he disputed the
7077	right-wing’s claim that “Michael Moore hates the troops.” He asserted
7147	that he had opposed the “senseless” Iraq war, but insisted, “I’m the
7216	one who has supported these troops,” and referred to the “brave young men
7290	and women” of the military.
7327	This is truly fighting on your knees. It is one thing to explain that
7397	individual members of the armed forces are not responsible for the crimes of
7474	the US government and military, and that they are also victims of the
7544	imperialist war drive. It is quite another to praise the troops as heroes, as
7622	though the fact that they are involved in crimes is of no consequence, and
7697	accommodate oneself to the permanent militarism that has afflicted the US for
7775	the past 15 years, as Moore does.
7818	The occupation of Iraq produced the decimation of Fallujah (where white
7890	phosphorus was used) and other cities where resistance was put up, the
7961	barbarity in Abu Ghraib, the massacre in Haditha, the gang-rape of a
8030	14-year-old Iraqi girl and the murder of her family in Al-Mahmudiyah, the war
8108	crimes committed by the group of US military personnel in Baghdad known as the
8187	“Leavenworth 10,” the murders carried out by Marines in Hamdania, the
8257	Baghdad airstrike known as “Collateral Murder,” and countless other
8325	atrocities.
8346	Violence and mayhem directed against the Iraqi population were committed by
8422	American forces in Iraq on a daily basis, only a tiny portion of which ever
8498	became public knowledge. That is the nature of colonial
8554	“counter-insurgency.” The US military-intelligence apparatus is the
8622	principal force for violence and terror on the planet, as masses of people
8697	around the globe understand all too well.
8748	The American Sniper affair needs to be seen in the context of the unremitting
8826	drive to glorify the US military, intimidate and overcome opposition, and make
8905	those who are hostile to war and militarism feel isolated and alone. The
8978	desperate character of the pro-militarist effort speaks to the crisis of
9051	American capitalism, whose efforts in the Middle East and Central Asia have so
9130	far resulted largely in reversals and failure.
9186	Whatever the intentions of the aging Eastwood, who continues to insist that
9262	his film is “antiwar,” American Sniper serves to fuel xenophobia and, in
9335	the wake of the Charlie Hebdo shootings, fan anti-Muslim hatred and violence.
9413	In its own way, this crude propaganda effort demonstrates that American
9485	imperialism has no intention of withdrawing from the Middle East, or any other
9564	part of the globe. The entire business comes as a serious warning.
