371	Hillary Clinton: The Power of Women, TV review: Women's rights isn't about the battle of the sexes - it's the inequality, stupid
523	Before BBC2 turned to the possible next US President in Hillary Clinton: the
600	Power of Women, it launched a new documentary series The Ladykillers: Pest
675	Detectives. The latter's premise was based on the fact that a mere six per
750	cent of pest-control professionals in the UK are women. It's a classic bit of
828	man-bites-dog TV commissioning. Look at the women! Killing the rats! Fancy
903	that!
918	But while six per cent is obviously a flimsy number in any profession, look at
997	the United States Senate, which in its existence has only ever had 31 female
1074	Senators. A grand 1.4 per cent of the total. Even today only 20 of the 100
1149	sitting Senators are women. It's the same in the US Congress and the UK is
1224	hardly any better, with 22 per cent. But it's still dismal.
1293	One of those 31 Senators was – of course Hillary Rodham Clinton – who left
1368	the Senate in 2009 to concentrate on her bid to be President. Which, if it
1443	finally happens in 2016, will mean that 2.2 per cent of all US Presidents will
1522	have been women. And she'll be all 2.2 per cent of them. Well done, the
1594	patriarchy.
1615	The title of this documentary might lead you to think that this was a profile
1693	of the former Secretary of State as she almost certainly begins the
1761	18-month-long slog towards the 2016 US Presidential elections. It wasn't quite
1840	that, alas. It was more the story of what's happened to women in the world
1915	since Clinton gave a landmark speech at the UN's Fourth World Congress on
1989	Women in 1995. There, the then First Lady asked for that particular gathering
2067	to be a call to action to improve women's rights around the world.
2143	Taking that as a lead-off, director Francis Whately took us through a brief
2219	– mainly depressing – ride through some of the worst things to happen to
2292	the planet's women over the past 20 years, starting in war-torn Yugoslavia,
2368	where rape was being used as a weapon of war, with Bosnian women's bodies
2442	being used as frontlines by soldiers in an attempt to destroy ethnic
2511	identities, ie by forcing them to have Serbian children.
2577	There was quite a telling moment in this part of the film. The backbone to the
2656	thread here was three interviews by executive producer and media grandee Tina
2734	Brown with America's three female Secretaries of State (4.4 per cent),
2805	Clinton, Condoleezza Rice and Madeleine Albright. At the height of the
2876	Yugoslav conflict, Albright was the US Ambassador to the UN and here she
2949	recounted talking to other UN officials about the ghastly situation for
3021	Bosnian women and was told: "Don't be so emotional."
3083	Among tales of horror and mass rape in DR Congo, people-trafficking in India;
3161	the gory medieval dominion of the Taliban and sexual assault in the midst of
3238	the Arab Spring, there were some hopeful – albeit – well-known tales.
3308	Leymah Gbowee and Liberia's Women in White who rose up against the tyranny of
3386	Charles Taylor; Afghanistan's first elected female MPs, including Fawzia
3459	Koofi, and brave Arab activists such as Mona Eltahawy.
3523	This was their story more than it was Clinton's. And though it made sense to
3600	append her name to title, it was misleading.
3654	Still, Clinton's role cannot be understated. The fact is that despite some
3729	slightly pragmatic dealings with unenlightened allies as Secretary of State,
3806	she gets the importance of women's rights. If she becomes POTUS #45, expect
3882	conversations like the ones in this film to finally take centre stage.
