227	Hillary for Liberals: A Conversation With Walter Shapiro
307	"As a campaigner, Hillary can do a shot and a beer better than Barack Obama
383	can," Shapiro says. So there's that.
429	As a reporter and columnist for Time, Newsweek, the Washington Post, USA
502	Today, Esquire, Salon, and other publications, Walter Shapiro has covered nine
581	presidential elections and the nation’s politics for four decades. He is
654	currently a fellow at the Brennan Center for Justice at New York University
730	and a lecturer in political science at Yale while he finishes a book about his
809	great-uncle, a vaudevillian and con man who once swindled Hitler.
884	Shapiro is also an accomplished Hillary-ologist, having first interviewed
958	Hillary Clinton in the Arkansas governor’s mansion for Time in September
1031	1992. In early May, Shapiro sat down with Prospect editor-at-large Harold
1105	Meyerson to talk about a question he’s internally debated for years: On
1177	balance, would a Hillary Clinton candidacy and presidency be a good or bad
1252	thing for the liberal cause?
1290	The following discussion has been edited for concision and clarity.
1367	Harold Meyerson: Walter, when liberals look at Hillary Clinton, what should
1443	they see? The Democratic Party and the country have certainly changed since
1519	she was first lady, and even since she was a senator and secretary of state.
1605	Walter Shapiro: I’ve always thought that Bill Clinton was never really a
1678	person of the ’60s. Bill Clinton started in 1960 as a 14-year-old who wanted
1755	to be governor of Arkansas. He came out of the ’60s as a 24-year-old who
1828	wanted to be governor of Arkansas without going to Vietnam. But Hillary did
1904	the full, life-changing conversion from the obedient Goldwater Girl to
1975	delivering an ethereal but genuinely anti-war address at Wellesley in ’69.
2050	So in a sense, as far as the culture of the time washing over someone, it
2124	washed over her more than it ever washed over Bill.
2185	HM: Still, she spent so many years in Arkansas, and Arkansas’s political
2258	culture is not one with which most liberals are comfortable. Both Clintons
2333	were clearly supportive of the civil-rights revolution. But the other part of
2411	that culture is the Stephens investment firm and Wal-Mart, and to get
2481	somewhere in Arkansas politics, you eventually have relations with them.
2554	Hillary famously was on the Wal-Mart board for a while.
2619	WS: What stayed with me, and I still think it’s really important for
2688	understanding Hillary, happened in March of 1992, at a debate before the
2761	Illinois primary. Jerry Brown (Bill Clinton’s primary opponent) went after
2836	Bill Clinton in part for the legal work that Hillary did at Rose Law Firm on
2913	behalf of banks. And Hillary at some point said, in effect, “Of course I
2986	work for banks; who do you expect me to work for if I’m a lawyer?” Well,
3059	there were, believe it or not, other clients in the state of Arkansas in the
3136	1980s while her husband was governor.
3183	HM: That’s no small part of what gives liberals pause about Hillary—who
3255	is, of course, still going around giving talks to the Goldman Sachses of the
3332	world. Is she too inextricably linked to that world? One of the major issues
3409	liberals had with Obama is that his economic team has been, like Bill
3479	Clinton’s, primarily Robert Rubin protégés. That’s two straight
3543	Democratic presidencies with a Wall Street pedigree.
3605	WS: As a campaigner, Hillary can do a shot and a beer better than Barack Obama
3684	can. She was an exceedingly good candidate when it was too late in the ’08
3759	primaries with white working-class voters in Pennsylvania, in Indiana, in
3833	states like that. That said, everything in the ledger says she’s not a
3904	policy populist.
3930	Remember that the Bill Clinton administration at its most successful was the
4007	Democratic answer to Reaganism. It was what the French call “the spirit of
4082	the staircase”—coming up with everything you should have said at the party
4157	just after you’ve left it. The administration said, let’s get off the
4227	table everything Reagan criticized about the Democrats. It was welfare, so
4302	they ended it; it was crime, so they came up with funding for 100,000 more
4377	cops; it was economic deficits, so they came up with a balanced budget.
4458	To some extent, electing Hillary Clinton in 2016 could continue a debate with
4536	Ronald Reagan that no one else in American life is still having. The Democrats
4615	have mostly forgotten Reagan, and the Republicans have turned him into this
4691	sainted soul of political constancy. But a Hillary presidency would be still
4768	framed by the Democratic memory of those horrible years in the wilderness in
4845	the 1980s, when the Democrats got wiped out in three successive elections.
4929	HM: But the political landscape, the demographic profile of voters has changed
5008	so much since then. More political space has opened up on the left; the nation
5087	has plainly moved in a liberal direction on social issues; there are very few
5165	Blue Dogs remaining. Is this defensive crouch against the Republicans a
5237	politically viable stance?
5273	WS: I’m talking about what makes her tick. Of course, she won two elections
5349	in a very diverse state since Bill’s presidency, and she won an awful lot of
5426	presidential primaries in ’08. She understands the diversity of America in
5501	2017—except in the economic sense.
5545	That said, I don’t think she’s the candidate of Archie Bunker’s America.
5618	But the worst thing that could have happened to her in terms of framing any
5694	economic populist message was to run for the Senate from New York rather than,
5773	say, Arkansas. Not only do the Clintons have a certain psychological need for
5851	money—that would probably be a separate course in the Department of Hillary
5927	Studies—but her constituents were Wall Street, and they were also the people
6004	who were funding all the Clinton initiatives and giving speaking fees to Bill.
6092	Ultimately she has an orthodox, mainstream, centrist, Eisenhower Republican
6168	view of the economy. It is much to the left of today’s Republican Party
6240	since there are no Eisenhower Republicans left, but it is also much less in
6316	keeping with large segments of the Democratic Party. I can see her being very
6394	involved in raising the minimum wage, because it’s not as if hedge-fund
6466	billionaires are on the barricades against it. But trying to do a better,
6540	tougher version of Dodd-Frank? Let’s merely say that the polls would have to
6617	get very dismal for Hillary leading up to the 2020 election for that to even
6694	be on her agenda.
6721	HM: Let’s go to foreign policy.
6762	WS: If you wanted me to state my own personal reservations about Hillary, I
6838	would have started with foreign policy.
6887	HM: What would those reservations be?
6934	WS: First of all, other than the anti-war feeling, which is more generational
7012	than an elaborate, nuanced foreign-policy view, I don’t think she had
7082	terribly developed foreign-policy views during Bill’s presidency. OK, there
7158	was the general, and to my mind, admirable tilt toward humanitarian
7226	intervention in both Haiti and, much more important, in Bosnia. I do not think
7305	she would have dithered the way Obama has on Syria.
7366	That said, I’ve seen no evidence that she had too much anguish over her vote
7443	to authorize Bush to go to war in Iraq. John Kerry turned himself into
7514	elaborate pretzel positions to try to justify that vote. Hillary may have
7588	anguished about many things, but that does not seem to be in the Top 10
7660	Hillary Anguish moments.
7694	HM: What do you think her hawkishness on Iraq would portend for foreign policy
7773	if Hillary were president?
7809	WS: While she is not a Dick Cheney groupie, in a situation where there is a
7885	range of military actions on the table and there’s a responsible, mainstream
7962	opinion within the administration toward using the military—and the
8030	foreign-policy community says military action is called for—she would
8100	probably go with it and cheerlead it on. I don’t think she’s going to
8170	invent a war with Mongolia out of some crazed geopolitical effort to encircle
8248	China. But hers would probably be a more hawkish administration than we have
8325	now with Obama and John Kerry.
8365	I’m much less worried about her starting a war with Denmark, though, than I
8441	am by the fact that she is probably the Democratic presidential candidate who
8519	would do the least to rein in the National Security Agency and all the
8590	leftover aspects of the “war on terror.” Sadly, both Hillary and Bill know
8665	that civil liberties is that which closes on Saturday night.
8735	HM: Bill Clinton was not famed for his managerial prowess and neither is
8808	Barack Obama. That’s certainly part of the president’s job. Is Hillary a
8881	better manager than Bill?
8916	WS: I think she is much more than just that. If you have been through a
8988	disaster like the first two years of the Clinton administration, you know what
9067	to do now. Flash forward to a White House in 2017. First, Bill and Hillary
9142	will have worked out their marriage, with her 69 and him 70, as well as any
9218	couple is likely to. If ever there’s a marriage that by 2017 has few
9287	surprises, it’s probably that one. Second, Hillary has been through two
9359	disastrous, disorganized White Houses under Bill Clinton and Obama. The way
9435	Obamacare was handled, in that the entire story of health care got lost, also
9513	the failure to put enough emphasis on the economy after the stimulus
9582	passed—all these things Hillary saw. She would come into the White House
9655	with a greater understanding of White House dysfunction than anyone in
9726	Democratic Party history. To have been in the Obama cabinet would also steel
9803	you against creating a White House where people believe they’ve invented the
9880	wheel, that they’re geniuses—the problems that have afflicted this White
9953	House.
9969	HM: Bill is clearly going to be her chief adviser. How does this factor into
10046	everything?
10067	WS: It will cause certain lines-of-authority confusion in the White House. But
10146	ultimately, I think it’s more good than bad. Every president, from what
10218	I’ve read and seen, communes with the ghosts of presidents past. It’s sort
10293	of nice to have a ghost of presidents past available on call. There will come
10371	a point if Hillary is president in, say, 2019, that something happens that
10446	already happened somewhere, sometime during Bill Clinton’s eight years in
10520	the White House. It would be really good to have the lessons from that
10591	analogue on tap.
10617	HM: Right now, there’s no one else in the Democratic Party who’s within 40
10692	or 50 points of Hillary in presidential polling. How do you assess her
10763	strengths and weaknesses as a candidate? A lot of what you’re describing is
10839	not necessarily the stuff that resonates with younger voters, except possibly
10917	that her election would be historic.
10963	WS: There is an iron law of campaign journalism: Never assume anything with
11039	absolute certainty in presidential politics, because there are always
11109	surprises. President Muskie would be the first to remind us. That said, I had
11187	drinks last night with two prominent Republican consultants. What they told me
11266	is that they believe that Hillary—running as a centrist, not a populist, and
11343	moderately hawkish—would just sweep the field. There is no Republican who
11417	could possibly beat her except in exceptional circumstances. Part of it is the
11496	history-making nature of the race. But it is also this: All the things that
11572	make liberals a little uneasy about a Hillary presidency are the things that
11649	are perfect for a general election against a fill-in-the-blank Republican. Of
11727	course, in the remote chance that Rand Paul got the nomination, it would be
11803	interesting to see a Republican running against a Democrat with the Republican
11882	running to the left on national security.
11933	But the larger point—and it’s one of the reasons, after going back and
12004	forth within myself, I am more in favor of her running than not—is that
12076	American politics since the 2000 election has been balanced on a knife’s
12149	edge. While there are moments when one party surges ahead, pretty much the
12224	country has been in equal balance. Beyond 2000, had just 130,000 votes been
12300	different in Ohio in 2004, John Kerry would have been president even though he
12379	would have lost the popular vote. Mitt Romney, not exactly someone who is
12453	going down in the Candidate Hall of Fame, still got, what, 47 percent of the
12530	vote?
12545	HM: That was the appropriate percentage for him.
12603	WS: The point is that Hillary could win a resounding victory that could bring
12681	in a Democratic majority to govern. And I would much rather have a president
12758	with a majority to govern, even if the decisions she made were not always
12832	decisions I agreed with, than another eight years, or four years, of a
12903	Democrat hamstrung by a divided Congress.
12954	HM: Why don’t we hear more of an outcry from the left of the party for an
13028	alternative to Hillary?
13061	WS: Three reasons come to mind. For some, it’s that electing a woman
13130	president would be historic. For others, there is the depressed sense of
13203	dashed expectations after five years of Obama. But the biggest reason, I
13276	suspect, is the political truism: “You can’t beat somebody with nobody.”
13349	And despite Elizabeth Warren fantasies, the Democratic left doesn’t have
13422	anyone who looks like a plausible president now willing to run.
13495	That doesn’t mean that Hillary will run unopposed. Maybe it will be former
13570	Governor Brian Schweitzer of Montana. Maybe it’ll be Howard Dean—or
13638	Senator Bernie Sanders, to keep coming up with Vermonters. I went back and
13713	checked since World War II. Aside from incumbent presidents, no one has ever
13790	been handed a presidential nomination unopposed other than Richard Nixon in
13866	1960. And even Nixon had to kiss the hem of Nelson Rockefeller’s garment
13939	with something called the Compact of Fifth Avenue.
13999	HM: Can Hillary turn out young people like Obama did—a key to both his
14070	victories? Can she engender a remotely comparable excitement factor?
14148	WS: No. But probably neither can any other Democrat. Obama leached the sense
14225	of political excitement out of an entire generation with the gap between his
14302	campaign style and his governing style.
14351	Also, remember that young voters in 2016 will have different life experiences
14429	than young voters in 2008. A 21-year-old in 2016 will have been in first grade
14508	on 9/11 and was too young at the time to understand the lies that sent us to
14585	war with Iraq. That means that these 2016 voters—no matter the
14648	candidates—will react to different stimuli than young voters in 2008.
14727	So how can Hillary win in 2016? Maybe by sparking greater enthusiasm from
14801	women—especially single women. Maybe a 54-year-old waitress in Waterloo,
14874	Iowa, will vote for the first time. Hillary might also change the political
14950	map by running competitively in states like Kentucky, West Virginia, Indiana,
15028	and Arkansas.
15051	HM: How would a primary challenge from someone like Warren affect Hillary’s
15127	campaign? In terms of constituencies, I can see the party
15185	establishment—unions, electeds, blacks, traditional donors—sticking with
15258	her. But could that “Mondale-ize” her? And could Warren muster the kind of
15333	support that Gary Hart did in his 1984 challenge to Mondale?
15403	WS: My heart goes pitter-patter whenever I get a Walter Mondale question.
15477	Which, oddly enough, happens less and less these days. But Mondale-Hart in
15552	’84 is one of those races that explains the Democratic Party, along with
15625	Carter-Kennedy in 1980 and Bobby Kennedy versus Gene McCarthy in 1968.
15705	I’d be stunned beyond belief if Elizabeth Warren ran against Hillary. Of
15778	course, I never expected Spiro Agnew, Dan Quayle, and Julia Louis-Dreyfus to
15855	be vice presidents of the United States. The Hart challenge to Mondale, which
15933	was based on amorphous “new ideas,” was in hindsight a generational
16001	battle. Elizabeth Warren is only two years younger than Hillary.
16075	There has to be an issue with a passionate following to sustain a major
16147	primary challenge to Hillary. Right now, the Democrats don’t have one. For a
16224	project at Brookings, I’ve been watching what’s being stressed in
16290	Democratic House primaries around the country. At this point, NSA spying and
16367	drone attacks are just not voting issues for liberals. Getting tough with Wall
16446	Street—like single-payer health insurance—was something much more likely
16519	to trigger an adrenaline rush for the left in 2009 than in 2016.
16593	HM: But Walter, a lot of recent polling done for Democrats shows that there is
16672	a sizable constituency that believes the economy is rigged; that the rich get
16750	away with low taxes while the middle class can’t; that free trade with other
16827	nations has damaged our economy; that when a candidate says he or she sides
16903	against Wall Street and with workers, they have more of a claim on this
16975	constituency’s support. Don’t you think there’s real political space for
17048	a candidate who positions herself or himself to Hillary’s left on these
17120	issues?
17137	WS: Polls, schmolls. Which should be a Yiddish word meaning “enough with the
17214	cross-tabs.”
17236	I agree that there’s space on the left. But that’s a lot different than
17308	having a charismatic candidate capable of exploiting it. What’s needed to
17382	run against Hillary is more than just the ability to play to the choir by
17456	mouthing off on MSNBC. That’s the campaign of Dennis Kucinich redux.
17534	The more that we talk about this, the more I wish that Paul Wellstone were
17609	still alive. I don’t see anyone of his liberal stature—anyone with his
17680	sense of fun—willing to take on Hillary. It would take an exceptional
17750	candidate to harvest that underlying unease with a Clinton restoration. But
17826	it’s 18 months until Iowa and, boy, have I been wrong before.
17897	For Hillary, a challenge from the left—as long as it didn’t catch
17963	fire—would actually help set her up for the general election since it would
18039	send the message that she was more of a centrist than a Karl Rove caricature.
18117	I also suspect it would be easier for Hillary to co-opt a primary challenge by
18196	making the right dovish noises on foreign policy or NSA eavesdropping than by
18274	attacking Wall Street, which would be for her an Olympic-level gymnastic
18347	trick. But, then, we’ve already seen Bill Clinton’s Dick Morris–inspired
18420	triangulation for the 1996 campaign. So maybe I shouldn’t dismiss
18486	Hillary’s malleability on economic issues if that was what was needed to win
18563	the nomination. But I wouldn’t count on follow-through if she got to the
18636	White House.
