246	Bradley Cooper on 'American Sniper': Chris Kyle 'didn't really leave me'
342	"You've got your back to the window, so you're kind of screwed," Bradley
415	Cooper said.
437	Cooper was scanning the room from a high-backed chair, his eyes tracking the
514	waiter carrying his breakfast, the guy in the hoodie tapping away on a laptop
592	near the door, the "at risk" reporter staring back at him.
660	Assessing the potential threats in a space — even in a Tribeca luxury hotel
736	on a sleepy December morning with horizontal rain — was a habit Cooper had
811	picked up while making "American Sniper."
862	"After that, you're more aware of everything," he said of the experience of
938	crawling inside the mind of the military's deadliest sniper, Chris Kyle. "He
1015	didn't really leave me."
1049	The role became imprinted on Cooper in other ways: He gained 30 pounds of
1123	muscle, perfected a West Texas twang and learned how to shoot a .300
1192	Winchester Magnum rifle. He also delivered a rugged type of screen stoicism
1268	that his "American Sniper" director, Clint Eastwood, made a career of.
1348	For the effort, Cooper, 40, has earned his third Oscar nomination in as many
1425	years, after the David O. Russell films "Silver Linings Playbook" and
1495	"American Hustle," a feat only nine other actors have achieved.
1568	And the movie, a best picture nominee that Cooper produced and championed
1642	despite others' doubts about its marketability, has become a box office
1714	phenomenon, earning more than $250 million domestically. Along the way, it has
1793	also ignited political debate about the Iraq war and the toll on the people
1869	who fought it.
1893	The success for "Sniper" comes at a time when Cooper is performing on Broadway
1972	in "The Elephant Man" as a very different sort of man, John Merrick, the
2045	deformed Englishman who became a celebrity in 19th century London society.
2129	Cooper plays the role without the use of prosthetics, contorting his arm and
2206	face and speaking in a labored, high-pitched voice.
2267	"As an actor, [Chris Kyle and John Merrick] were both very similar in terms of
2346	what I had to do physically," Cooper said, "the fact that I had to change my
2423	body chemistry, the physicality as an entranceway into the roles. Both of
2497	them, oddly enough, were also very clear as to who they were. Both men felt
2573	very planted in the ground."
2611	Late last year, as "The Elephant Man" had opened to rapturous reviews and
2685	"American Sniper" was yet to arrive in theaters, Cooper talked about how the
2762	two roles were a culmination of an interest that was sparked when he was 12,
2839	growing up in a Philadelphia suburb.
2885	It was then that Cooper saw David Lynch's 1980 version of "The Elephant Man,"
2963	starring John Hurt as Merrick.
3003	"It crushed me," Cooper said of the Lynch film. "I just felt this real
3074	emotional reaction to Merrick's plight, to how he was able to be so positive
3151	and joyful, and saw the goodness in stuff when he was afflicted with this
3225	disorder."
3245	At the time, Cooper's family said, "'Oh, Brad wants to be an actor. How cute.
3323	Go eat some ravioli,'" he said.
3364	But after getting a bachelor's in English at Georgetown University, Cooper
3439	studied at the Actors Studio Drama School in New York, home of the James
3512	Lipton-hosted "Inside the Actors Studio." In a 1999 episode of the Bravo show,
3591	an earnest, shaggy-haired Cooper asks guest Sean Penn a question from the
3665	audience.
3684	Cooper found early work in television, on series "Alias" and "Jack &amp; Bobby,"
3765	and in film comedies "Wet Hot American Summer" and "The Wedding Crashers"
3839	before his breakout role as a playboy ringleader in the "Hangover" films
3912	helped transform him into a box office commodity and a People magazine
3983	"sexiest man alive."
4013	After he played a man with bipolar disorder in "Silver Linings Playbook,"
4087	Cooper learned about Kyle's story from a friend, screenwriter Jason Hall, and
4165	came aboard the project as a producer before ultimately agreeing to star to
4241	get a studio interested. Cooper never met Kyle. He was killed at a shooting
4317	range while helping a veteran on Feb. 2, 2013, just one day after Hall turned
4395	in his first draft of "American Sniper."
4445	The project cycled through multiple possible directors, including Steven
4518	Spielberg, before Eastwood came aboard in the summer of 2013.
4589	As a producer, Cooper was heavily involved, both in the planning and the
4662	editing room, according to Eastwood.
4708	"Bradley was engaged in all aspects of the film and has an unparalleled work
4785	ethic and concentration level," Eastwood said. "He was very invested in the
4861	overall project, as I was when I was young. Being interested in every detail
4938	is what drove me to want to direct, and I would not be surprised to see
5010	Bradley wanting to direct in the future." (In fact, Cooper has expressed an
5086	interest in directing a dramatic comedy by "Crazy, Stupid, Love" writer Dan
5162	Fogelman.)
5182	Critics have praised Cooper's performance for its naturalism and for
5251	humanizing a closely guarded character.
5300	"Bradley's basically playing a guy who does not reveal his emotions,"
5370	"American Sniper" producer Rob Laurenz said. "Emotion is how you connect with
5448	an audience, so to not be able to express it in a big way is hard. You rely on
5527	subtleties in the eyes and in the face. It's a wildly challenging role."
5609	Cooper said he knew he was taking a risk by playing Kyle, a man so different
5686	from him in background, physicality and bearing, and a political lightning rod
5765	to boot.
5783	"I knew I could get crushed for doing this role, but at least I know why I'm
5860	doing it," Cooper said. "It's so clear to me. I love Chris. That's all I had
5937	to work with. Forget everything else. That's a huge anchor, you hold on to
6012	that."
6028	Living in New York for the play, he said he still takes the subway and often
6105	walks past his old apartment on Barrow Street in the West Village.
6181	Next he plans to bring "The Elephant Man" to London and reteam with Russell on
6260	a project with his "Silver Linings Playbook" costar Jennifer Lawrence.
6340	"I get to go to work every day and do something I love to death ... and have
6417	people react in a way that I would want them to, that they're affected by it,"
6496	Cooper said. "That's it, dude. That's why I'm an actor."
