233	Officials: 147 Dead in Al-Shabab Attack in Kenya
305	Kenyan officials said Thursday that a daylong siege at a university in the
380	country's northeast was over, leaving 147 people and four Islamist al-Shabab
457	terrorists dead.
483	Police and survivors said the gunmen stormed the campus of Garissa University
561	College, about 370 kilometers (230 miles) east of Nairobi, and opened fire
636	"indiscriminately."
665	But some students said the attackers were separating the Christians from the
742	Muslims and holding them hostage.
785	Security forces surrounded the campus and battled the militants for 15 hours,
863	rescuing more than 500 students trapped by the violence.
929	At least 79 people were injured, and many were airlifted to Nairobi, Kenya's
1006	national disaster body said.
1044	Interior Minister Joseph Nkaissery said the four gunmen had explosives
1115	strapped to their bodies and they blew up "like bombs" when police shot them.
1202	Al-Shabab said the attack was revenge for Kenyan military action inside
1274	neighboring Somalia, where the Islamist militant group is based.
1348	It was their most violent attack in Kenya since the 2013 terrorist strike on
1425	Nairobi's Westgate Mall, which killed more than 60 people.
1493	The attack at the university “is one of those incidents that would surprise
1569	any country,” Nkaissery said. He ordered a dusk-to-dawn curfew in Garissa
1643	and in the nearby counties of Wajir, Tana River and Mandera — all near the
1718	Somali border.
1742	Early morning attack
1772	Witnesses said the assailants began the attack about 5 a.m. near the
1841	classrooms and then worked toward the residence halls.
1905	The number of attackers initially was not clear, although witnesses reported
1982	seeing four or five armed men on campus. The Kenyan Interior Ministry said
2057	earlier that one suspect was arrested trying to flee the scene.
2130	In a televised statement to the nation earlier in the day, President Uhuru
2205	Kenyatta said police and the Interior Ministry were coordinating the
2274	government response to the attack. He urged Kenyans to remain calm and give
2350	authorities any information they had in connection with all security threats.
2437	Kenyatta also offered his condolences to the victims' families: “We continue
2514	to pray for the quick recovery of the injured and the safe rescue of those
2589	still being held hostage.”
2625	A spokesman for the militants told  the French news agency AFP that the
2697	group's mission was to "kill those who are against the Shabab."
2770	The U.S. ambassador to Kenya, Robert Godec, said the United States "strongly
2847	condemns al-Shabab's heinous terrorist attack" and stood "shoulder to shoulder
2926	with the government and people of Kenya in the effort to end the scourge of
3002	terrorism."
3023	Kenyan authorities named alleged al-Shabab commander Mohamed Kuno as the
3096	mastermind of the attack. A security brief seen by VOA said Kuno was a former
3174	madrassa teacher in Garissa in the late 1990s and was now said to be
3243	al-Shabab's chief for external operations against Kenya.
3309	Student details attack
3341	Students in campus housing were awakened Thursday by the sound of gunfire.
3416	Student Beatrice Mathai told VOA she and fellow students fled when they heard
3494	what she called a heavy exchange.
3537	"We run from where we were, kneeled down and looked out towards the football
3614	club," Mathai said. "Finally, we jumped over the building’s wall.  Before
3688	the attack we were 29 students, now we are seven. We are very frightened and
3765	even do not know where we are now."
3810	Student Mercy Chebet told VOA she and other students evacuated the dormitories
3889	as the gunmen approached.
3924	“It started in the classes and we were in the hostels sleeping, so when we
3999	heard the bullets, we just moved out of the hostels and ran to the field,”
4074	Chebet said. “When we were in the field, they came to the hostels and they
4149	were shooting where we were."
4188	She said the gunmen then moved into the dormitories and began firing. She said
4267	she spoke by phone to some friends who were being held hostage inside.
4347	Collins Wetangula, the vice chairman of the student union, told The Associated
4426	Press he was preparing to take a shower when he heard gunshots coming from
4501	Tana dorm, which hosts both men and women, 150 meters away.
4570	He said that when he heard the gunshots, he locked himself and three roommates
4649	in their room. When the gunmen arrived at his dormitory, he could hear them
4725	opening doors and asking the people who had hidden inside whether they were
4801	Muslims or Christians.
4833	“If you were a Christian, you were shot on the spot,” he said. “With
4902	each blast of the gun, I thought I was going to die.”
4965	The gunmen then started to shoot rapidly and it was as if there was an
5036	exchange of fire, he said.
5072	“The next thing, we saw people in military uniform through the window of the
5149	back of our rooms who identified themselves as the Kenyan military,”
5218	Wetangula said. The soldiers took him and around 20 others to safety.
5297	Threat letter
5320	The University of Nairobi warned its students last week that al-Shabab was
5395	planning attacks on Kenyan institutions, including a "major university."
5477	In an email obtained by VOA with the subject "TERROR THREAT" dated March 26,
5554	the University of Nairobi's security office said information about a possible
5632	attack was "being processed by the relevant government agencies."
5707	It is not clear yet that Garissa University received or posted the same
5779	warning.
5797	The town of Garissa, in northeastern Kenya, is about 200 kilometers (125
5870	miles) from the border with Somalia and has, in recent years, been the site of
5949	sporadic gun and grenade attacks blamed on al-Shabab.
6012	Al-Shabab is known for assaults on large buildings, such as the Westgate Mall
6090	in Nairobi in 2013, and Somalia's presidential palace, which it attacked twice
6169	last year.
6189	Last week, al-Shabab claimed responsibility for a deadly siege on a Mogadishu
6267	hotel that lasted more than 12 hours and in which at least 24 people,
6337	including six attackers, were killed.
6384	Kenyatta announced that he would fast-track the training of 10,000 additional
6462	police, saying the country has “suffered unnecessarily due to shortage of
6536	security personnel.”
6566	Also, Kenyan authorities are offering a $200,000 reward for Mohamed Mohamud,
6643	also  known as Gamadhere or Dulyadayna. He is suspected to be al-Shabab's
6717	chief for external operations against Kenya and allegedly is connected to the
6795	Garissa attack.
