225	All Progressives Congress may change name
290	There are indications that mega oppposition party, All Progressives Congress,
368	is considering a name change should the African People’s Congress beat it to
445	the APC acronym.
471	Both political associations are laying claim to the acronym in their bid to be
550	recognised as political parties by the Independent National Electoral
620	Commission.
641	SUNDAY PUNCH gathered that APC may add the alphabet “N” (which will stand
715	for Nigeria) to its version of APC, to distinguish it from any other.
794	A prominent member of the association said adding ‘N’ to the acronym will
868	solve the controversy.
900	“We may just add ‘N’ to our acronym if this matter drags on for too
968	long. We find it diversionary.”
1009	However, National Publicity Secretary of the Congress for Progressive Change,
1087	Rotimi Fashakin, said the name change was speculative.
1151	He said, “Whatever anyone tells you about our merger now is speculative and
1227	untrue. We have said it over and again that the acronym APC is our
1294	intellectual property, whatever the PDP and its agents in the system are doing
1373	to frustrate our registration will not succeed.”
1431	Also speaking on the issue, National Publicity Secretary of the Action
1502	Congress of Nigeria, Mr. Lai Mohammed, said the All Progressive Congress would
1581	not change its name.
1611	He said, “It is a big lie. We are not changing our name. We are sticking to
1687	our name.”
1707	Calls made to the mobile telephone number of the National Publicity Secretary
1785	of the All Nigeria People’s Party, Mr. Emma Enekwu, did not go through. He
1860	also did not respond to a text message sent to him.
1921	When one of our correspondents contacted the Chief Press Secretary to the
1995	National Chairman of INEC, Mr. Kayode Idowu, he said, “No comment.”
2072	Meanwhile, the Chairman of the Independent National Electoral Commission,
2146	Prof. Attahiru Jega,  said on Saturday that the commission was neither aware
2223	nor frustrating the registration of the All Progressives Congress.
2299	Jega who spoke on the Hausa programme, Hanu Dayawa, in Kaduna which was
2371	monitored by our correspondent  on Saturday , noted that the APC officially
2447	notified the commission of their intention to merge into a political party
2522	about six days ago.
2551	The INEC boss also ruled out the possibility of adopting the electronic voting
2630	in the 2015 general elections, saying the constitution was against the use of
2708	the system.
2729	Insisting that no political party had notified the commission of any merger
2805	plan ahead of the 2015 general elections, Jega said, “The issue has
2873	generated controversy in the past few weeks. Firstly, the truth is that no
2948	political party wrote to notify us that it is planning to merge with some
3022	other political parties until the past five days or so.
3087	“It is not true that we were notified. The issue became serious when one
3160	group came out to seek for registration and I guess that was what made them to
3239	write and notify us. But that is not the issue. The main issue is that there
3316	are guidelines for registered political parties who want to merge to become a
3394	new party. There are also guidelines for individuals or groups who want to
3469	form a political party for registration.
3519	“The guidelines for registering new political pray are different from that
3594	of registered political parties who want to merge. For registered political
3670	parties who want to merge, they must have agreed to merge and each of the
3744	political party in the merger must hold a convention and agreed to withdraw
3820	their registration as a political party to become part of the new party to be
3898	form through the merger.
3932	“After their conventions, they are expected to write and request INEC to
4005	withdraw their former registration and say they want to join a new party. In
4082	spite of all the controversies, none of these political parties who want to
4158	merge has held their convention.
4200	“We only read in the newspapers that they have the intension of merging and
4276	nobody wrote us until about five or six days ago. If anybody wants to register
4355	a political party, you are expected to tell INEC of your intention by saying
4432	that you want to register a party with so and so name and you want to know the
4511	procedure for doing so.”
4545	“People are just making noise over the name which is in the market while we
4621	have not even gotten to that stage. While all these noise were going on,
4694	another group came up seeking for registration with the same name.”
4771	On the use of the electronic voting system in the 2015 general election, 
4845	Prof. Jega  noted that it was clear that the Nigerian constitution has
4916	prohibited the use of the system, adding that  the commission would  only use
4994	technology to improve on the  registration of voters and improve on the
5066	electoral process.
