276	ISIL video purports to show Jordanian pilot's killing
353	The Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant group (ISIL) group has published a
429	video that purportedly shows the burning death of the captive Jordanian pilot
507	Moaz al-Kassasbeh.
535	The video released on Tuesday said that the killing of the 26-year-old air
610	force first-lieutenant was in response to Jordan's role in the US-led
680	coalition against ISIL.
713	Jordan's King Abdullah, who was in Washington DC to meet top US officials, cut
792	short his visit following the news of the murder.
851	"Today we stand together with the family of Moaz al-Kassasbeh," he said in a
928	video statement.
954	"This will only make us more united and powerful."
1014	A Jordanian army spokesperson pledged to avenge Kassasbeh's death, saying the
1092	response "will be proportional to this catastrophe that has struck all
1163	Jordanians.
1184	"His blood will not be shed in vain."
1231	The country's military has officially informed Kassasbeh's family of his
1304	death, Al Jazeera's Nisreen el-Shamayleh reported from Amman.
1375	'Very clear message'
1405	According to state television, Jordan has declared a period of mourning. It
1481	also reported that Kassasbeh, who had been in ISIL's captivity since December,
1560	was killed on January 3.
1594	Speaking to Al Jazeera, Abdel Bari Atwan, a Middle East analyst, said that if
1672	proven true, the killing of Kassasbeh was "unprecedented".
1740	"It's a very clear message and they are trying to show maximum brutality," he
1818	said, adding that ISIL was not interested in negotiations.
1886	"They are looking to terrorise."
1928	Reacting on the report, US President Barack Obama said that his government and
2007	coalition partners will redouble efforts "to make that that they [ISIL] are
2083	degraded and defeated".
2116	He said the killing of Moaz "is just one more indication of the viciousness
2192	and barbarity of this organisation".
2238	In Kassasbeh hometown, al-Karak, friends, family and supporters gathered to
2314	show their support and express anger at the news of his death.
2386	The ISIL video, which is 22 minutes and 34 seconds, also called for the
2458	killing of other Jordanian pilots.
2502	Planned prisoner swap
2533	Kassasbeh was taken hostage in ISIL's stronghold of Raqqa in Syria after his
2610	F-16 jet crashed.
2637	ISIL members have claimed to have shot down Kassasbeh's plane with a
2706	heat-seeking missile.
2737	ISIL, which controls large chunks of Syria and Iraq, had been demanding the
2813	release of Sajida al-Rishawi - a woman held by Jordanian authorities since
2888	2005 - in exchange for Kassasbeh's life.
2938	Rishawi was sentenced to death "for conspiracy to carry out terror acts" after
3017	a triple bomb attack on the Radisson SAS hotel in Amman.
3083	Security sources told our correspondent that Rishawi would be executed early
3160	on Wednesday in response to the killing of Kassasbeh.
3223	Five other individuals on death row could also be executed.
3292	The convicts have already been reportedly moved to al-Suwaqa Jail, where
3365	executions in Jordan are typically carried out, a family member of one of the
3443	convicts told Al Jazeera's el-Shamayleh.
