201	Kenyan President Vows Harsh Action, Declares Mourning Period
285	President Uhuru Kenyatta has announced three days of national mourning,
357	following the deaths of almost 150 people in one of the worst massacres in the
436	country's history. Kenyatta promised to "fight terrorism to the end."
515	In his first televised address since the attack ended on Thursday, Kenyatta
591	condemned the "barbaric slaughter" and asked help from the Muslim community in
670	rooting out radical elements.
709	"My administration shall respond in the severest way possible to the attack
785	and any other attack to us," Kenyan president said, speaking from the capital
863	Nairobi on Saturday. "Thursday wounded Kenya, Thursday wounded families,
936	friends and communities of the victims of the attack."
1000	Al Qaeda-linked al-Shabab gunmen killed around 150 people at Garissa
1069	University College campus, as retaliation for Kenyan participation in a
1141	mission against Shabab in Somalia. Most of the victims in the Thursday
1212	massacre were students attending the college situated some 200 km (120 miles)
1290	from the Somali border.
1323	Four of the attackers were killed after a 15-hour siege, while one was
1394	reportedly arrested.
1424	'We will bring them all to justice'
1469	In his Saturday address to the nation, Kenyatta said the task of countering
1545	terrorism had been made all the more difficult by the fact "the planners and
1622	financiers of this brutality are deeply embedded in our communities," and.
1706	"We will fight terrorism to the end," Kenyatta said.
1768	Five men have been arrested in wake of the attacks, for alleged connection
1843	with Shabab militants. Kenyan authorities also put a $220,000 (200,000 euro)
1920	bounty on the head of the alleged mastermind of the attack, Mohamed Mohamud, -
1999	also known as Dulyadin Gamadhere - who is believed to be in Somalia.
2077	Mohamud is a former teacher at a Kenyan Islamic Madrassa school.
2151	"I want you to know that our security forces are pursuing the remaining
2223	accomplices. We will bring all of them to justice," Kenyatta said, adding that
2302	the authorities were in "active pursuit" of the mastermind.
2371	Kenyatta also declared a three-day mourning period, with flags in the country
2449	flying at half mast.
2479	Dead gunmen on display
2511	Also on Saturday, Kenyan police drove the four bloated and naked corpses of
2587	the purported attackers through the streets, saying the display was made to
2663	help in determining the attackers identity.
2716	Hundreds of people, including children, came out to see the dead bodies, which
2795	were driven almost half a kilometer in the back of a pick up truck before
2869	being returned to hospital. While some jeered and took photos, other threw
2944	stones at the dead.
2973	"The intention was not a parade, but rather for public identification so that
3051	if anyone can recognise them whether they are a relative or someone who knows
3129	them," local police chief Benjamin Ong'ombe said.
3188	"Too many people turned out, so we had to return them," he added.
3263	Many of the citizens said they were disgusted by the showing of the bodies,
3339	which were starting to decay.
3378	"Instead of driving bodies around the streets now, the security forces should
3456	had pro-actively gone out to stop them from killing students," a student Ahmed
3535	Yusuf said.
3556	dj/rc (AFP, AP, Reuters)
