268	Evidence Surfaces That Chris Kyle's Killer Was Not Suffering From PTSD But May Have Been A Terrorist Sympathizer
404	"No combat experience. Let me say that again, he NEVER SAW COMBAT or any
477	aspect of traumatic events associated with a combat deployment."
551	With his trial to start very soon, new facts have surfaced surrounding the man
630	who shot and killed Chris Kyle.
671	The narrative until now has stated that Eddie Ray Routh was suffering from
746	PTSD when Kyle took him under his wing, attempting to help a fellow veteran in
825	need.  The new facts coming to light could show that Routh was not suffering
902	from PTSD but a converted Muslim who sought out Kyle as retribution for the
978	sniper's success in Iraq.
1013	Through the Freedom of Information Act, The Warfighter Foundation received
1088	Routh’s wartime record and made a startling discovery – Routh was never in
1163	combat or in any sort of traumatic experience.
1219	Posted to their Facebook page, they write:
1271	Eddie Routh served one tour in Iraq in 2007, at Balad Air Base (the 2nd
1343	largest U.S. installation in Iraq), with no significant events. No combat
1417	experience. Let me say that again, he NEVER SAW COMBAT or any aspect of
1489	traumatic events associated with a combat deployment (i.e. incoming mortar or
1567	rocket fire). He never left the base, EVER.
1620	He held a non-combat arms occupation of 2111 (Small Arms Repairer/ Technician
1698	or more commonly referred to as an Armorer). Balad Air Base had a Pizza Hut,
1775	24 hour Buger King, Subway, Popeye's, Baskin Robbins, movie theater, and even
1853	a miniature golf course. It even had a strictly enforced 10-mile per hour
1927	speed limit! What a dangerous place...
1975	His tour was comparable to being on a base in southern California, only with
2052	MANY more luxuries that were catered to the morale and welfare of the troops
2129	who occupied it. He was known to be a drug user and a below average performer
2207	while in the Marine Corps.
2243	This has NOTHING to do with PTSD. He was an individual with psychological
2317	problems that were not associated with his service. So don't give me that
2391	bleeding heart bullshit that he was a veteran suffering from PTSD.
2467	What is known. however, is that Routh, while never serving in combat, did work
2546	at the Bilad Airbase prison, guarding Muslim terrorists.
2612	Walid Shoebat, a former radicalized Muslim terrorist and member of the PLO who
2691	has since converted to Christianity, believes that because of his past and
2766	credentials, he is confident in his deduction that Eddie Routh was in fact
2841	becoming a radical Muslim, although there is no proof yet of the conversion.
2927	Shoebat brings as one proof a phone call Routh had with his father where he
3003	expressed sympathy for the detainees he was guarding.
3066	“During a phone call with his father, Routh expressed sympathy for the
3137	detainees and discontent over how the US was conducting the war as well as his
3216	reluctance to engage in combat” and “While working as a guard at Balad Air
3291	Base, Routh laments his [Muslim] prisoners’ poor living conditions.”
3369	He continues, “It is a known fact that Routh’s family contacted Kyle about
3444	their son’s diminishing mental health. Routh was admitted to inpatient
3515	psychiatric treatment prior to the events at Rough Creek Ranch, according to a
3594	report from the Daily Mail.  Routh had been taken to a mental hospital twice
3671	in the past five months and told authorities that he was suffering from
3743	post-traumatic stress disorder, police records show.”
3806	The second proof Shoebat brings is Routh's beard with a trimmed mustache. 
3881	Shoebat profiles Routh and writes, “In the story on Eddie Routh, who
3950	murdered Chris Kyle, there are signs of concern, especially the facial hair,
4027	it does match the profile of a convert.”
4077	Notice the trimmed mustache in one picture but not the other.
4148	“One main key in profiling a Muslim fundamentalist is that they usually trim
4225	the mustache,” Shoebat writes.  “Always remember, a Muslim fundamentalist
4299	is mandated by Islam to trim the mustache,” he adds.
4361	Is it a stretch?  Was Eddie Routh sent on a covert mission for extremist
4434	Muslims hell-bent on killing “The Devil of Ramadi?”  It will be
4498	interesting to watch as the trial unfolds and more information comes out if
4574	Kyle’s killer was suffering from PTSD or if he had ties to Muslim
4640	extremists.
