342	It was Reeva's bad luck she met him, sooner or later he would have killed someone': Reeva Steenkamp's parents attack 'gun-toting and trigger-happy ' Oscar Pistorius for killing their daughter
557	Barry and June Steenkamp said justice has not been served for Reeva
634	They said Oscar Pistorius would have killed someone 'sooner or later'
713	He has been jailed for five years, but could be out in 10 months
787	Mrs Steenkamp described him as 'pathetic' in book Reeva: A Mother's Story
870	Both parents have a recurring image of the model screaming in agony
947	The parents of the model shot dead by Oscar Pistorius have attacked the
1019	'volatile' and 'trigger-happy' athlete saying 'sooner or later he would have
1096	killed someone'.
1122	They have sat through an agonising seven-month trial, but June and Barry
1195	Steenkamp said justice for their daughter Reeva, 29, has not been served as
1271	the 'Blade Runner' could be out in 10 months.
1326	Mrs Steenkamp, 68, said she did not believe the athlete's story, describing
1402	him as 'vague, evasive and shifty' after he claimed he shot Reeva thinking she
1481	was an intruder.
1507	'It was Reeva's bad luck that she met him, because sooner or later he would
1583	have killed someone. I do believe that,' she said in an interview with The
1658	Times Magazine.
1683	'I wasn't happy with the sentence at all. I don't think that was justice for
1760	Reeva at all.'
1784	They have a recurring image of Reeva, terrified and alone in the small toilet
1862	cubicle, pleading for her life or screaming in agony once she had been shot.
1948	'Both of us are haunted by the same nightmare. The vision of Reeva suffering
2025	this terrible trauma. Her terror and helplessness. Her yells for help piercing
2104	the silent night air,' said Mrs Steenkamp.
2156	Her husband imagines her begging for her life. 'He agonises over what was
2230	going through her mind: 'Where is anyone? Who is going to save me?' '
2309	Pistorius told the court they were planning a life together, but Mrs Steenkamp
2388	thinks Reeva had 'nagging doubts about their compatibility'.
2458	'She had confided to me that she hadn't slept with him. They'd shared a bed,
2535	but she was scared to take the relationship to that level … She wouldn't
2608	want to sleep with Oscar if she wasn't sure,' she said.
2673	'I believe their relationship was coming to an end. In her heart of hearts,
2749	she didn't think it was making either of them happy.'
2812	In her book, titled Reeva: A Mother's Story, Mrs Steenkamp describes
2881	Pistorius, 27, as a 'pathetic figure'.
2929	The extract focuses on the athlete's public apology during the televised
3002	trial.
3018	'It was an extraordinary moment. You could cut the atmosphere in the courtroom
3097	with a knife: silence, but for the sound of journalists tapping on their
3170	screens. It put me in an awkward position.
3222	'Why decide to say sorry to me in a televised trial in front of the whole
3296	world? I was unmoved by his apology. I felt if I appeared to be sorry for him
3374	at this stage of his trial on the charge of premeditated murder, it would in
3451	the eyes of others lessen the awfulness of what he had done.
3521	'He was in the box trying to save his own skin after he had killed my daughter
3600	and I was sitting in that courtroom wanting to hear the factual truth.'
3681	The five-year sentence given to the double amputee athlete has been criticised
3760	by some as too lenient.
3793	But Miss Steenkamp's parents told ITV's Good Morning Britain they accepted the
3872	sentence and 'don't want revenge'.
3916	They said their daughter's death in the early hours of Valentine's Day last
3992	year remained shrouded in mystery, and 'only Oscar knows' the truth.
4070	Judge Thokozile Masipa ruled the state had failed to prove Pistorius knew it
4147	was Reeva when he opened fire through the locked toilet door of his apartment
4225	in Pretoria.
4247	Throughout the trial, he said he mistook his girlfriend of three months for an
4326	intruder.
4345	'He said pulling the trigger was 'an accident'. What? Four times an accident?'
4424	Mrs Steenkamp said in her book.
4465	'He said Reeva did not scream, but she would definitely have screamed. I know
4543	my daughter and she was very vocal.'
4589	Pistorius, who the court heard has no income and no property after selling it
4667	during the trial, was driven away in a police van with barred windows after
4743	his sentencing on Tuesday.
4779	He is expected to be held in the hospital section of a prison in Pretoria.
4863	Mrs Steenkamp's book is to be published on November 6.
