231	What Netanyahu’s Victory Means for America
297	The American political class has spent decades convincing itself that the
371	Israeli political class really does want a two-state solution to the
440	Israeli-Palestinian conflict. The last six years have been the
503	hardest—Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu proclaimed a tepid desire
579	for peace, but consistently acted contrary it—and yet the image of an Israel
656	that would strike the deal if only this or that condition was met by the
729	Palestinians persisted. Perhaps the image even grew stronger: who can forget
806	all the standing ovations Netanyahu received during his 2009 address to
878	Congress and, despite all the controversy, again this winter?
949	The illusion, however, of an Israeli body politic, perhaps even an Israeli
1024	electorate, happy to make peace was shattered as Netanyahu sailed to another
1101	victory—especially in light of the way he did it. Netanyahu’s last minute
1175	bid to strengthen his hand came not from fear-mongering about Iran, as he’d
1251	done for years, but about the Palestinians. His fired salvos at both
1320	Palestinian citizens of Israel (some 20 percent of the population) and against
1399	those Palestinians in the Occupied Territories. In the former case, Netanyahu
1477	warned his base Arabs were “coming out in droves to the polls”; in the
1548	latter, he boldly declared that no Palestinian state would be birthed were he
1626	elected (something Netanyahu had been hinting at throughout the campaign).
1710	The mantra of American Israel supporters, from grassroots lobby groups right
1787	up to 1600 Pennsylvania Ave., has always been that the United States and
1860	Israel hold “shared values”—chief among them the countries’ common
1927	democratic characters. But Netanyahu’s campaign put the lie to the notion.
2002	“Remember that Netanyahu’s version of democracy includes as few Arab
2071	voices as possible, simply because they are not Jewish,” wrote +972
2139	Magazine’s Michael Schaeffer Omer-Man. “Remember that the peace processes
2213	he has overseen for decades were not genuine, that he never had any intention
2291	of ushering in, let alone seeking, a two-state solution.”
