265	Is the ‘Islamic State’ Islamic?
320	On Feb. 25, 1994, an ultra-Orthodox Jew named Baruch Goldstein entered the
395	Ibrahimi Mosque in Hebron, occupied Palestine, with a machine gun. Seconds
470	later, he opened fire on the Muslim worshippers, killing 29 people and
541	wounding more than 125. He himself was lynched to death by the survivors in
617	the mosque, but only to turn into a martyr in the eyes of his comrades. That
694	is why he is to date buried at a tomb in a Jewish settlement in the West Bank,
773	whose inscription reads: “He gave his life for the people of Israel, its
846	Torah and land.”
872	Goldstein was a member of the “Jewish Defense League,” an organization
943	defined as “terrorist” and banned by the governments of both Israel and
1015	the United States. The ideology of the group was not just political but also
1092	religious. Some of its ideologues have depicted the Palestinians as the
1164	Biblical tribe of Amalek, for which the authors of the Bible did not have much
1243	sympathy. In the Book of Samuel, for example, a passage chillingly ordered:
1319	“Now go and smite Amalek, and exterminate everything that is his. Don’t
1391	pity him, but kill man, woman, infant and nursling.”
1453	Now, did Baruch Goldstein and his like-minded Jewish extremists have something
1532	to do with Judaism? Well, yes, of course. They were not just pious Jews, but
1609	also justified their violence by referring to Jewish sacred texts.
1685	But did they “represent” Judaism? No, not at all. Because the overwhelming
1760	majority of the world’s some 13.7 million Jews thought they were crazy
1831	fanatics. Moreover, the overwhelming majority of Jewish religious leaders
1905	found their deeply zealous and literalist reading of the Torah unacceptable.
1982	As you probably guessed, I am recalling the Baruch Goldstein example to shed
2059	some light on a more timely matter: The so-called “Islamic State” in Iraq
2133	and the Levant, also known as ISIL. What ISIL really stands for, how it is
2208	motivated, and what it means for Islam as a religion, is being hotly debated
2285	these days, with conflicting narratives that range from “ISIL has nothing to
2362	do with Islam,” to “ISIL is simply Islam itself.”
2421	Recently, American magazine The Atlantic published a notable story on this
2496	matter, titled, “What ISIS [ISIL] Really Wants.” The author, Graeme Wood,
2570	did an impressive job by evaluating the religious ideology of ISIL, especially
2649	by showing how it sees itself as a key player in the Islamic scenarios of the
2727	apocalypse. It is a must-read, I must say, for anyone who wants to get a good
2805	grasp of the group
2833	However, a conclusion that Mr. Wood made from all the data he collected about
2911	ISIL was a bit problematic. He wrote: “The reality is that the Islamic State
2988	is Islamic. Very Islamic.”
3024	This was like saying, “Baruch Goldstein is Judaic. Very Judaic.” That
3094	would be factual statement in the sense that Goldstein referred to the Jewish
3172	texts to justify his violence (Notably, apocalyptic scenarios are quite
3244	definitive in ultra-Orthodox Judaism as well). But it would an unfair
3314	statement for Judaism itself, whose representation cannot be narrowed down to
3392	a bunch of wild fanatics.
3427	In my view, ISIL of course has something to do with Islam, in the sense its
3503	keeps referring to the Quran, the hadiths, and the classical texts of Salafi
3580	jurisprudence. But the overwhelming majority of the world’s 1.6 billion
3652	Muslims and all mainstream Islamic scholars see them as crazy fanatics. Even
3729	other jihadist groups see ISIL as too violent and ruthless (Alas, even
3800	al-Qaeda finds them too extreme.) It would be utterly unwise to fail to see
3876	this very wide spectrum.
