221	You're on fire' - witness recalls Boston blast aftermath
301	Moments after being blasted into the air "like a rocket" in the Boston
372	Marathon bombing, nurse Jessica Kensky saw that her husband's leg had been
447	blown off and leaped into action, struggling to put a tourniquet on him, she
524	testified on Monday.
554	Running on adrenaline, she did not realize the blast from one of the two
627	homemade pressure-cooker bombs had set her back on fire, Kensky told jurors in
706	the third day of accused bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev's federal trial in Boston.
792	"There was smoke, there was blood. I was most focused on my husband, he was
868	right next to me still, and his foot and his leg were kind of detached," said
946	Kensky. "A man came over as I was trying to fumble to put a tourniquet on
1020	Patrick and said, 'Ma'am you're on fire, you're on fire.'"
1088	Tsarnaev, 21, is accused of killing three people and injuring 264, including
1165	Kensky, at the famed race's crowded finish line on April 15, 2013.
1241	Kensky lost her left leg on the day of the bombing. Her right leg was
1311	amputated in January of this year because it had failed to heal from injuries
1389	sustained in the blast.
1422	She and her husband, Patrick Downes, were taken to separate hospitals and did
1500	not see each other for two weeks until a volunteer medical crew brought her to
1579	visit him.
1599	Tsarnaev's attorneys opened their case last week by bluntly declaring that the
1678	defendant and his older brother were responsible for the attack as well as the
1757	fatal shooting of a police officer three days later, in an effort to focus
1832	attention on the brother's role in the plot.
1886	The jury on Monday viewed video taken by security cameras near the finish line
1965	on Boylston Street showing Tsarnaev walking with a backpack that prosecutors
2042	contend held a bomb, leaving it in a crowd in front of a restaurant, making a
2120	brief phone call and walking away shortly before the blast.
2189	Defense lawyers contend that Tamerlan Tsarnaev, 26, who died following a
2262	gunbattle with police three days after the bombing, was the driving force
2336	behind the attack, with Dzhokhar following along out of a sense of submission.
2415	By pinning the bulk of the blame on the older brother, defense lawyers hope to
2494	persuade the jury in US District Court in Boston not to sentence their client
2572	to death.
2591	Prosecutors maintain that the defendant also read jihadist magazines online
2667	and "believed that he was a soldier in a holy war against Americans."
2746	On Monday, they showed messages from a pair of Twitter accounts that Tsarnaev
2824	maintained, according to FBI agent Stephen Kimball.
2885	Hours after the bombing and using the handle "J_Tsar," Tsarnaev sent the
2958	message, "ain't no love in the heart of the city, stay safe people," Kimball
3035	said. Tsarnaev also responded to a message sent by another user about a man
3111	who had lost his fiancee with the words "fake story," Kimball testified.
3193	Tsarnaev, an ethnic Chechen, also briefly maintained a second Twitter account
3271	focused on Islam using the handle "@AL_FirdausiA" and the screen name
3341	"Ghuraba," Kimball said.
3375	"Ghuraba means strangers. Out here in the west we should stand out among the
3452	nonbelievers as one body," Tsarnaev tweeted, according to Kimball.
3528	Despite his lawyers' admission of responsibility, Tsarnaev has not changed his
3607	plea from not guilty.
3638	The bombing killed Martin Richard, 8; restaurant manager Krystle Campbell, 29,
3717	and graduate student Lingzi Lu, 23. Massachusetts Institute of Technology
3791	police officer Sean Collier, 27, was shot to death three days later.
