293	Is this Oscar Pistorius playing football in prison yard with notorious Czech gangster?
403	A video has emerged that claims to show Oscar Pistorius playing football in a
481	prison yard with a notorious underworld criminal.
540	The extraordinary footage appears to show a dramatically slimmer Pistorius
615	enjoying a penalty shoot-out competition with Radovan Krejcir, who was last
691	month charged with murder.
727	The disgraced sprinter, who was jailed for five years for killing his
797	girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp, has struck up an unlikely friendship with the
871	Czech fugitive since they became neighbours on the hospital wing at Kgosi
945	Mampuru prison in Pretoria.
982	In the 90 second clip, South Africa's two most notorious prisoners are seen
1058	taking turns to play striker and goalkeeper in the facility's concrete yard
1134	which they seemingly have to themselves.
1184	The footage, shot from above on a mobile phone reportedly by a convicted
1257	robber, was published today by South Africa's Daily Sun newspaper.
1333	The pictures appear to support recent reports that the double-amputee has
1407	slimmed down dramatically since his incarceration four months ago amid fears
1484	of poisoning by other prisoners.
1526	According to jail sources, the shamed athlete is surviving on tins of baked
1602	beans, pilchards and an African vegetable dish called 'chakalaka' bought at
1678	the prison tuck shop after spurning his rations.
1736	Wearing trainers, grey shorts and a white, unbranded T-shirt that appears to
1813	swamp his lean frame, the 28-year-old's thin arms protrude from its sleeves.
1899	The images are in stark contrast to the muscle-bound track star who made
1972	history at the London Olympic games by competing against able-bodied athletes.
2060	During the day, Pistorius is required to dress in the regulation orange jump
2137	suit which is issued to all inmates at the jail.
2195	But according to a spokesman for the jail, he is entitled to dress in sports
2272	gear for his hour of daily exercise.
2318	As a prisoner on remand, heavily-built Krejcir is entitled to wear his own
2393	clothes and is dressed in a striped top and deck shoes for his knockabout game
2472	with the famous athlete.
2506	Although in the video Pistorius appears to move easily on his prostheses
2579	despite his obvious drop in weight, during his long murder trial, his doctor
2656	told the court of the pain the fallen sprinter suffers a result of wearing
2731	artificial limbs that fit poorly as a result of weight loss.
2801	The bleak yard where the men are having a kickabout shows two narrow doors,
2877	one yellow and one red, apparently used to control the exit and entry of the
2954	prison's notoriously violent large population.
3010	For the purposes of their football game, the doors provide make-shift goal
3085	posts and Pistorius shows himself to be useful in goal, deflecting the older
3162	man's attempt to score by blocking one shot with a prosthetic leg.
3238	At one point, the one-time sporting idol has to delve behind some wheelie bins
3317	to retrieve the white ball after knocking away Krejcir's strike with his hand.
3405	In apparent deference to his opponent, the Paralympic gold medalist is seen
3481	moving a concrete-weighted pole and plastic bag out of the way in order for
3557	Krejcir to have more room to take aim at the goal.
3617	When it is his own turn to take penalties, Pistorius strikes hard, but hits
3693	one of the door 'goal posts', before sprinting off to reclaim the ball –
3766	clearly relishing the short burst of speed.
3819	Prison chiefs are mindful of the threat to Pistorius's safety at the massive
3896	jail, where gangs dominate prison life and sexual and physical violence is the
3975	only means to progress up the gangs' chain of command.
4039	He spends much of his day isolated from other prisoners, but Krejcir –
4110	despite his links with violent crime – is obviously perceived to pose no
4183	danger.
4200	Last month, MailOnline exclusively revealed how Pistorius had been
4267	re-classified to a low-risk A category prisoner, entitling him to greater
4341	freedoms and privileges behind bars, including 'contact' visits, a radio and
4418	the freedom to wear jewelry.
4456	The Daily Sun newspaper, which received the footage from a prisoner inside the
4535	jail, quoted an unnamed inmate who complained that Krejcir and Pistorius were
4613	getting preferential treatment because they are both white.
4682	The paper reports that Pistorius is given mineral water, fresh fruit and tea
4759	for breakfast - treats that are not afforded to other prisoners and prepared
4836	only for him.
4859	'We are all in prison and we must be treated the same. The colour of your skin
4938	should not be a passport to get on the sweet side of the law,' the prisoner
5014	told the paper.
5039	The noise of the prison, which houses 7,000 inmates, can be heard on the video
5118	soundtrack, drowning any exchanges between the two men.
5183	Krejcir, currently on trial for kidnapping, attempted murder and drug dealing,
5262	appears to enjoy the yard knockabout.
5309	The Czech fugitive is facing a long incarceration as a prisoner on remand,
5384	with a number of outstanding cases against him.
5441	Detectives said it would take years to wrap up investigations into the Czech's
5520	links with the criminal underworld including murder, drug trafficking, robbery
5599	and fraud.
5619	Krejcir currently has three court cases running against him, but as an
5690	unconvicted prisoner is entitled to greater privileges than his neighbour on
5767	the hospital wing.
5795	Krecjir's latest charge involves the murder of a Lebanese national who was
5870	shot more than 30 times when he stopped at a traffic light in Johannesburg 18
5948	months ago.
5969	News of the unlikely friendship between the two was revealed when Krejcir
6043	wrote a letter to prison authorities complaining that a treadmill and exercise
6122	bike – that he trained on alongside Pistorius –had been removed from the
6195	corridor outside his cell.
6231	Krejcir used a false passport to move to South Africa seven years ago and has
6309	been linked to the unsolved murders of, among others, a luxury car exporter,
6386	the owner of a string of strip joints and a known drug dealer.
6458	In 2013 he survived an attempt on his own life which involved
6520	remotely-operated guns which had been hidden - 007-style - behind the number
6597	plate of a parked car.
6629	In December, the double-amputee's brother told South Africa's YOU magazine how
6708	the athlete had hoped to begin a basketball training programme for inmates,
6784	many of whom suffer from ill health due to HIV, Aids and TB.
6854	According to Carl, Pistorius had requested a donation of basketballs from his
6932	family in order to set up the project after applying for permission from
7005	prison bosses.
7029	In October, Pistorius was convicted of culpable homicide over the death of 29
7107	year-old Mrs Steenkamp at his home on St Valentine's Day 2013.
7179	The double-amputee shot the model four times through a locked toilet door
7253	after mistaking her for an intruder.
7299	He could be released from jail in August and allowed to serve the remainder of
7378	his sentence under house arrest.
7420	However, the state has appealed Pistorius' acquittal on a charge of murder.
7496	The athlete's own lawyers have challenged the ruling to allow the appeal.
7579	The next hearing in the case is due to take place on Friday.
