279	Public goofus Hillary vs. private gallant Hillary
352	I’m calling bullsh** on the media’s portrayal of Hillary Clinton.
427	“The private Hillary is as warm and charming a woman as anyone could conjure
504	up. The public Hillary sometimes seems brittle, with the judgment of a raging
582	rhinoceros,” writes fellow syndicated columnist Ann McFeatters.
655	I don’t mean to pick on McFeatters. Everyone (in the media) says the same
729	thing: Hillary Clinton is so awesome one-on-one or maybe one-on-six, in
801	private. For example, Mark Leibovich says she is “quite human and funny”
874	in private.
895	She’s been a high-profile national politician for more than 20 years. Why
969	hasn’t she figured out how to charm the American public on TV?
1041	These repeated accounts of Hillarity are less than reliable, issued as they
1117	are by the kind of people in a position to have met Hillary Clinton, which
1192	pretty much guarantees that they’re boring and bland and not very smart —
1266	the kind of people who think Obama means well and that Jon Stewart is a laff
1343	riot.
1358	But let’s say it’s true. Who will we be voting for or against next year
1430	— Public Goofus Hillary or Private Gallant Hillary?
1491	If you evaluate presidential candidates based on how much fun they’d be to
1566	share a drink or six with, Hillary presents a trust dilemma. Who wants to
1640	throw back cold ones with greedy tone-deaf Public Hillary, worth $20 million
1717	if she’s worth a dime, as she whines that she’s not “truly well off”?
1796	But what if it’s true that Private Hillary rolls salt-of-the-earth style,
1870	wickedly funny and cool? Should you take a leap of faith, taking the word of
1947	the same press corps that gave us the Iraq War, and support the real —
2018	albeit secret and seen by few — Hillary?
2068	Perhaps you’re one of those voters who views the presidency as a role to
2141	fill, and presidential elections as a casting call. For you, the president of
2219	the United States is America’s representative on the world stage. He or she
2295	has to look — and feel — presidential. Your ideal prez would exude FDR’s
2368	charisma, wear Reagan’s suits, have Obama’s calm and JFK’s (or Mitt
2436	Romney’s) hair.
2461	For you image voters too, Private vs. Public Hillaries are a problem.
2540	Public Hillary is a nonstarter. She embodies the George W. Bush school of
2614	bull-in-a-China-shop diplomacy: the last thing we need is another war, one
2689	caused by her deployment of the same nasty exasperated expression she wore at
2767	the press conference where she tried to talk away her destruction of four
2841	years of electronic archives of the foreign policy history of the United
2914	States.
2931	On the other hand, Loveable Private Hillary could bond with Vladmir Putin and
3009	other troublesome world leaders, banging out peace treaties and favorable
3083	trade agreements at karaoke bars from Pyongyang to Moscow. But what if Private
3162	Hillary is as much of a chimera as Iraq leader Saddam Hussein’s WMDs? Public
3239	Hillary Who Is Also Private Hillary could piss off so many old enemies, and
3315	make so many new ones, that we’d be fending off ICBMs in no time.
3390	Or maybe you’re like me, an issues voter. As long as he or she supports the
3466	right policies and fight against the bad ones, you don’t care if a
3533	politician drinks, or womanizes, or drinks and drives a woman to the bottom of
3612	a pond. Show me the bills, dammit!
3656	If you’re in it for substance over style, the Tale of Two Hillaries is even
3732	more difficult to tease out.
3770	New York Times columnist Maureen Dowd calls Hillary a “feminist icon
3839	wallowing in regressive Middle Eastern states’ payola.” I’ll focus on
3909	the “feminist icon” part: what, aside from being a woman, has Hillary
3979	Clinton done for women? She has never proposed a significant piece of
4049	women’s rights legislation. Her 2008 presidential bid marketed her, not as a
4126	woman, but as a Margaret Thatcher-style “Iron Lady,” a man in woman’s
4196	clothing.
4215	Only now, echoing Obama’s double-win on the strength of historical
4282	symbolism, is she planning to emphasize the plight of girls and women in a
4357	patriarchal society.
4387	On policy, Public and Private Hillary blend together. Not because she’s
4459	integrated. Because she’s a mess of contradictions: a liberal who supports
4534	wars of choice, obsessed with her own privacy as she runs interference for the
4613	NSA.
4627	Even if Gallant is the real Hillary, and all that Goofus stuff is either her
4704	cynical attempt to work the system in a man’s world or reflects a
4770	personality unable to connect with people in large groups, I can’t vote for
4846	her.
4860	She supports war and drones and the NSA. Who cares if she’s a barrel of
4932	laughs behind closed doors? So was Josef Stalin.
4990	Anyway, my invitation to hang out with her appears to have gotten lost in the
5068	mail.
