242	Comedian Jay Leno Makes Comeback in Israel for Award Show
323	Jay Leno is making a comeback — in Israel.
375	The late-night legend says he will return to Israel in June to host the award
453	ceremony for the second annual "Genesis Prize." Leno also hosted the inaugural
532	ceremony last year for what is billed as "the Jewish Nobel Prize." The $1
606	million prize is being awarded to Oscar-winning actor Michael Douglas in
679	recognition of his "passion" for his Jewish heritage and Israel.
753	Leno said he was thrilled to be invited back, comparing the warm welcome he
829	received last year to a raucous Italian wedding.
887	"People seem to be genuinely happy to see you," he told The Associated Press.
965	"There you kind of get swarmed. People run over, and the grandmas pinch your
1042	cheeks. So that was kind of fun."
1085	He said he felt that people seemed especially appreciative of his decision to
1163	visit at a time when entertainers are under pressure to boycott Israel over
1239	its policies toward the Palestinians. "Israelis are thrilled when you actually
1318	show up," he said.
1346	Leno, who is not Jewish, described himself as a big supporter of Israel, and
1423	said he disagreed with critics who portray the country as an aggressor.
1504	"It seems like they [Israel] have the worst PR in the world," he said. "I
1578	don't understand how Israel is the bad guy here. It doesn't make any sense to
1656	me."
1670	The Genesis Prize Foundation said the June 18 ceremony will include a tribute
1748	to Douglas, a celebration of the contribution of Jews to Hollywood and
1819	Broadway and a segment on diversity and tolerance. Douglas, whose father,
1893	actor Kirk Douglas, is Jewish, has said he will donate his prize money to
1967	projects that promote inclusiveness in the Jewish community.
2037	"Michael Douglas has chosen to invest the prize award into initiatives which
2114	will resonate with Jews like himself — those who come from parents of mixed
2190	heritage who wish to be part of the Jewish community," said Stan Polovets,
2265	co-founder and chairman of the foundation.
2317	Leno said he is already gathering material to make fun of Douglas, a longtime
2395	acquaintance, as well as the country's politicians. Hundreds of VIPs,
2465	including the prime minister, are expected to attend.
2528	"After 22 years of hearing Jay poke fun of my movies on 'The Tonight Show,'
2604	it'll be a nice change to be there when he does it in person," Douglas said in
2683	a statement released by the foundation.
2732	One person who does not have to worry is Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's
2809	wife, Sara. Often portrayed as petty and demanding by Israeli comedians, Mrs.
2887	Netanyahu will be off limits, Leno said.
2937	"I tend to use the mafia model," he said. "You don't go after the wives and
3013	children."
3033	The Genesis Prize was founded by the prime minister's office, the Jewish
3106	Agency and the Genesis Philanthropy Group, a nonprofit organization that
3179	promotes Jewish education for Russian-speaking Jews worldwide. Last year's
3254	recipient was Michael Bloomberg, the billionaire philanthropist and former
3329	mayor of New York.
