222	Bibi wins big
259	As Netanyahu seems set to return to power, his relations with the Obama White
337	House appear to reach a new low.
379	Barack Obama might have hoped for a leadership change that would reboot his
455	poisoned relationship with Israel’s government. But he didn’t get it on
527	Tuesday, when Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu — thanks in part to
603	a hard lurch right — made a dramatic comeback after trailing in pre-election
680	polls.
696	“Against all odds: A great victory for the Likud. A major victory for the
770	Israeli people,” he posted on Facebook.
819	With more than 99 percent of the votes counted, Netanyahu’s Likud party had
895	earned 30 seats in Israel’s Knesset to 24 seats for the center-left Zionist
971	Union party led by his chief rival, Isaac Herzog. Netanyahu still needs to
1046	assemble a governing coalition to extend his rule, but that should be little
1123	challenge, given his surprisingly strong margin of victory.
1192	Indeed, Netanyahu will likely emerge strengthened, leading a more conservative
1271	coalition than he did before — and likely emboldened in his conflicts with
1346	the Obama administration over how to defend Israel.
1407	The results were demoralizing for Democrats who consider the Israeli leader
1483	tantamount to a partisan rival — particularly since Netanyahu’s March 3
1555	speech to Congress arranged by Speaker John Boehner behind the Obama White
1630	House’s back. In Herzog, Obama officials saw a possible fresh start with
1703	Israel on issues like the Israeli-Palestinian peace process and Iran’s
1774	nuclear program.
1800	“They hate him, they should, and they’re praying that he is out of
1867	power,” said a former senior Obama administration official as early returns
1943	came in Tuesday night.
1975	With those prayers unanswered, Netanyahu’s relations with Obama are likely
2050	to resume at their lowest point yet.
2096	In the closing days of the campaign, Netanyahu seemed to reject his previous
2173	support for a Palestinian state, potentially dashing hopes for a renewed peace
2252	process still nurtured by Secretary of State John Kerry and other U.S.
2323	officials.
2343	Netanyahu also cast himself as the target of foreigners — and while he was
2418	vague about the details, pro-Netanyahu media outlets often cited the role of
2495	former Obama campaign operative Jeremy Bird, who advised a grass-roots
2566	campaign organization that opposes Netanyahu. That group also partnered with
2643	the Washington-based OneVoice Movement, an international grass-roots group
2718	that supports the two-state solution and has taken State Department funding in
2797	the past.
2816	And Netanyahu startled some U.S. observers when he cast the election in a
2890	racial light by ominously warning supporters on Election Day that Israeli
2964	Arabs were turning out in large numbers against him.
3026	Netanyahu’s “scare tactics made the difference,” said Danny Ayalon, who
3098	served as Israel’s ambassador to Washington from 2002 to 2006 under a Likud
3174	government. “He now holds all the cards,” Ayalon said.
3238	In Washington, conservatives expressed delight at the results.
3310	“Sure loser: Obama,” tweeted Weekly Standard editor William Kristol.
3388	“His electoral success is all the more impressive given the powerful forces
3464	that tried to undermine him, including, sadly, the full weight of the Obama
3540	political team. American officials should not be undermining the elected
3613	leaders of our closest allies,” Republican Sen. Ted Cruz said in a
3680	statement.
3700	In particular, defending a nuclear deal with Iran would have been easier for
3777	Obama absent the protests of Netanyahu, who has warned Congress that Obama is
3855	striving for “a very bad deal” with Iran. Herzog also questioned the
3924	pending deal with Iran, but in more muted tones.
3982	Perhaps the biggest question looming over a Netanyahu victory is how the Obama
4061	administration will react to the Israeli leader’s rejection of a Palestinian
4138	state; a day before the election, with his victory uncertain, when an
4208	interviewer asked whether he would oppose the creation of such a state while
4285	prime minister, Netanyahu said yes.
4330	That would be a reversal of Netanyahu’s own stated position, as well a
4401	challenge to U.S. policy set in 2002 by President George W. Bush.
4476	State Department spokeswoman Jen Psaki seemed to downplay the remark, saying
4553	that “there are many things said leading up to elections.”
4621	Before the full margin of Netanyahu’s victory was clear on Tuesday, Ayalon
4696	predicted that “Bibi will retract” the statement.
4755	“He made the remarks as a candidate representing Likud,” he added. “As a
4828	prime minister, he represents the government. And that depends on the
4898	coalition he builds.”
4929	By Wednesday morning, some were far more pessimistic.
4992	“With Netanyahu withdrawing his already tenuous support for a Palestinian
5066	state, it’s safe to say that there isn’t a peace process,” said Matthew
5138	Duss, president of the Foundation for Middle East Peace.
