249	SF’s failure to back ISIS motion condemned
315	A decision by Sinn Fein MEPs to oppose a motion calling on EU states to
387	support action against ISIS has been condemned.
444	Two of the party’s European representatives voted against the motion backing
521	current measures against the extremist group, which also goes by the names
596	Islamic State and Da’esh.
631	The resolution also called for states to seek out non-military actions such as
710	cutting the group’s funding.
748	Ulster Unionist MEP Jim Nicholson said it was “hard to believe” that the
821	Sinn Fein members had taken the position they had.
881	The motion in question was titled, ‘European Parliament resolution on recent
958	attacks and abductions by Da’esh in the Middle East, notably of
1022	Assyrians’.
1043	It contained a number of clauses, including one calling on MEPs to support
1118	“international efforts against ISIS/Da’esh, including the military actions
1193	of the international coalition, coordinated by the United States, and
1263	encourages the EU Member States who have not already done so to consider ways
1341	of contributing to these efforts, including tracing and interdicting ISIS
1415	secret funds held overseas”.
1453	Sinn Fein declined to explain the decision on Monday night.
1522	When this clause came down to a vote on March 12, the website Votewatch.eu
1597	records that the overwhelming majority of politicians were in favour of it.
1682	However, 11 per cent voted against – including Matt Carthy and Lynn Boylan,
1758	two Sinn Fein MEPs from the Republic.
1805	Meanwhile, around one per cent of MEPs abstained.
1864	Sinn Fein’s Northern Irish MEP Martina Anderson is not listed as having cast
1941	a preference during the vote.
1980	In the European Parliament, Sinn Fein belongs to a bloc called the European
2056	United Left/Nordic Green Lef, which includes a number of communist parties.
2141	Most of the opposition to the clause in the motion had stemmed from this
2214	group.
2230	Sinn Fein was contacted on Monday to ask why the MEPs had taken such a stance,
2309	and what its position was on ISIS more generally.
2368	However, no answer was forthcoming.
2413	Long-serving UUP MEP Mr Nicholson said: “They voted against it. To have
2485	voted for it is what all right-thinking people would have done. I just do not
2563	understand it.
2587	“Sinn Fein have continued to support their communist friends in voting in
2661	favour of ISIS.”
2687	He suggested there was “a hair’s breadth” between supporting ISIS and
2757	opposing such a motion.
2790	He added: “I think when you look at the terrible atrocities that take place
2866	under the realm of ISIS in those countries at the moment, I think on that
2940	particular position I’d leave it for others to judge whether Sinn Fein are
3015	right or not.”
3039	ISIS has faced massive international condemnation for activities including
3114	harsh persecution of religious minorities, and beheading and burning alive
3189	captives.
