307	Chase Your Shadow by John Carlin: what the trial of Oscar Pistorius meant for South Africa
421	True Crime
441	Chase Your Shadow: The Trials of Oscar Pistorius
499	JOHN CARLIN
520	Atlantic Books, $29.99
552	The pervading sound of the trial of Oscar Pistorius was that of Pistorius'
627	whining, sobbing voice as he said he did not mean to kill his girlfriend: it
704	was an accident, an accident, he loved her.
757	Author and journalist John Carlin, who has written extensively on South
829	African issues, including biographies of Nelson Mandela and Playing the Enemy,
908	has produced a painstaking, detailed account of the life and times of the
982	Olympic athlete and at various points his prose sounds just as whining as did
1060	Pistorius  in his trial.
1094	In his conclusion Carlin purports that Pistorius reflects South Africa's
1167	development as a nation that today swings between characteristics of arrogance
1246	and progress. His book is, in fact, a spurious justification for a man who
1321	shot four bullets into a toilet door where his girlfriend hid, clutching her
1398	phone and screaming for help. Pistorius is now serving five years for
1468	manslaughter rather than murder. This outcome disguises the seriousness of a
1545	crime that was finally obfuscated by a lack of witnesses and hard evidence.
1630	Pistorius, commonly known as the Blade Runner, comes across in Carlin's book
1707	as a national hero whose physical prowess and athletic ability allowed him to
1785	play out his mercurial nature at will. He toys with a gun that goes off under
1863	a table in a crowded restaurant; he drives fast cars too fast, and he has a
1939	series of volatile relationships with various girlfriends. But you have to
2014	look for these facts, which are almost buried in the text. After initial
2087	release on bail Pistorius is "caged" inside his rich uncle's mansion. The
2161	family is on death-watch because poor Oscar is so depressed. He has been
2234	reduced to a desperately "needy child".
2283	So much sympathy for the man made me want to throw this book at the wall. What
2362	about his victim, Reeva Steenkamp, you want to ask? What about her beautiful
2439	life, which was blown into gory pieces? If Carlin was going to rationalise
2514	Pistorius' crimes in terms of a national characteristic, he would have done
2590	well to dwell on police statistics. According to The Guardian newspaper, seven
2669	women in South Africa were murdered each day in 2011 and one woman is raped
2745	every 17 seconds. But there was apparently no room for an examination of
2818	domestic/public violence against women in Carlin's book, which in effect
2891	diffuses a significant and historic miscarriage of justice.
