217	Putin executes opposition leader Nemtsov
281	Execution of enemy of KGB nation happened at the Bolshoy Zamoskvoretsky
353	Bridge.
370	The murder took place the day before the opposition march "Vesna/Spring",
444	which is scheduled for March 1.
495	"He was walking along the Bolshoy Zamoskvoretsky Bridge with a woman, unknown
573	people jumped out of the car and fired 4 times and disappeared", told the KGB.
661	The murder occurred at Vasilevsky Spusk/Descent. They fired in the back 4 to 7
740	times.
756	Opposition leader’s friends and his political allies rushed to the place of
832	murder.
849	"Unfortunately, I can see the corpse of Boris Nemtsov in front of me now. At
926	the Bolshoy Zamoskvoretsky Bridge. I see the body and lots of police around
1002	it", said Ilya Yashin, one of Nemtsov's colleagues in the RPR-Parnassus party.
1090	"I'm shocked, but I'm confident those bastards will pay a heavy price, said
1166	the former Russian Prime Minister Kasyanov. - Now every member of the
1236	opposition needs protection of society".
1286	Cops arrived at the scene of murder immediately frightened away everyone under
1365	the pretext that "experts will have to work".
1430	Kasyanov said he has no versions in connection with the execution of Nemtsov.
1508	"I have no versions, Nemtsov did not tell me of any threats or surveillance",
1586	said Kasyanov.
1610	According to preliminary information, at the time of the crime a native of
1685	Kiev, born in 1991, was with Nemtsov. On the radio station Echo of Moscow
1759	Yashin said that she did not suffer and is being interrogated. According to
1835	Yashin, this woman told him what had happened.
1891	Almost immediately after the murder, Putin press secretary Pesikov, and then
1968	the Kremlin ghoul himself declared that "the crime could have been a contract
2046	murder and has an exclusively provocative character is".
2112	Putin also hastened to declare that he "intended to personally monitor the
2187	investigation into the murder". Of course, who else doubted it. So it will be
2265	easier to hide traces of the crime, as in the case of the murder of Polish
2340	President Kaczynski and Polish elite.
2387	This is an old trick of the KGB-FSB. To kill a political opponent, and then
2463	resent in response to charges of murder - "are we such idiots to frame
2534	themselves. It's all provocateurs who so wish us harm".
2609	Putin has done this trick in the case of Yushenkov, Kaczynski, Politkovskaya,
2687	Berezovsky, Litvinenko. Now - Nemtsov.
2735	One of the first expressed condolences was president of Ukraine Petro
2805	Poroshenko. "Shock. They killed Boris. It's hard to believe. I have no doubt
2882	the killers will be found. Sooner or later. Eternal memory...", he wrote on
2958	Twitter.
2976	By the way, Nemtsov was killed a few meters from the Kremlin, in a heavy
3049	protected area.
3084	2 weeks before the murder Nemtsov in an interview said that Putin could kill
3161	him.
3175	In recent years, Nemtsov was one of the dissidents’ leaders of a Western
3248	democratist orientation. During his last visit to Vilnius, he asked the media
3326	not to call him either a politician or an opposition leader, but only a
3398	dissident same, as the KGB captured and illegally holding the powe, completely
3477	deprived him of every kind of political influence.
3537	KGB thugs in their blogs are rejoicing.
3586	- Boris Nemtsov, you run off my dear friend, writes "sotsializator.rf" and
3661	presents the following picture of a liquidator of Nemtsov.
