275	Oscar Pistorius trial books review – the case that mesmerised the world
370	Tim Lewis weighs up the evidence from three accounts of a gripping trial
452	There has never been a criminal trial like it. From the moment Oscar
521	Pistorius, the sci-fi athlete, shot and killed his model girlfriend, Reeva
596	Steenkamp, on the morning of Valentine’s Day in 2013, it became irresistible
673	rolling news. For the first time in South African history, a trial would be
749	shown, from opening statements to verdict, on live TV. A cable channel soon
825	offered 24-hour coverage and analysis. And, unlike the OJ Simpson case in
899	1995, social media stepped in with round-the-clock bloviating by everyone from
978	experts to Donald Trump. June Steenkamp, Reeva’s mother, remembers that as
1053	Pistorius took the witness stand there was rapt silence in the courtroom; the
1131	only sound was journalists tapping on their screens.
1193	Part of the appeal was superficial: Pistorius, handsome and charismatic, and
1270	Steenkamp, an FHM cover star and aspiring reality-TV star, were a glam couple
1348	(though only of three months’ standing) and her demise suggested perhaps a
1423	jealous crime of passion. But there was deeper intrigue, too: the case
1494	prompted discussion of the astonishing murder rate in South Africa, and
1566	particularly what appeared to be a culture of acceptance of violence by men
1642	against wives and girlfriends. What really fuelled debate, and charged our
1717	imaginations, however, was that, for all the phone records and Whatsapp
1789	messages the court trawled through, Pistorius alone knew whether he actually
1866	meant to kill Steenkamp.
1900	This unknown – and the complexity of separating the signal from a
1966	year-and-a-half’s noise – makes the Pistorius-Steenkamp story a compelling
2041	one for book treatment. Publishers seem to agree. First out of the blocks, in
2119	September, was Oscar: an Accident Waiting to Happen (Kindle only), co-written
2197	by Patricia Taylor, whose daughter Sam dated Pistorius for two (apparently)
2273	tumultuous years. Now, with the benefit of a few weeks’ further reflection,
2349	there are three more.Behind the Door by Mandy Weiner and Barry Bateman
2420	(Macmillan, 576pp, £16.99) could confidently claim to be the most
2486	comprehensive account of the trial. At 550-plus pages of dense print,
2556	including a grisly photo section and floorplan of Pistorius’s bedroom and
2630	bathroom, it is doggedly ordered and authoritative. Parts are satisfyingly
2705	encyclopaedic, but at times the detail is distracting: when Pistorius shoots
2782	Steenkamp, the narrative power dissipates in a fiddly discussion of the
2854	dark-wood magazine rack “packed with glossy titles” next to the toilet, or
2929	the aluminium and glass stand outside that showcased more than 40 pairs of
3004	Oakley sunglasses.
3032	Bateman, a broadcaster for South Africa’s Eyewitness News, acknowledges that
3109	he leans towards “dry, hard-fact accounts of events”, and credits Weiner,
3183	his colleague and the author of a book on Johannesburg’s underworld, with
3257	softening that impulse. Still, Behind the Door might have benefited from more
3335	style, less substance.
3367	The strongest of the accounts in this respect – and the best at supplying a
3443	context for what unfolded – is John Carlin’s Chase Your Shadow: the Trials
3518	of Oscar Pistorius (Atlantic, 384pp, £17.99). Carlin, a fine journalist, is
3594	clearly aware of the filmic potential of the tale; apparently, he was nudged
3671	to write the book by Paul Greengrass, director of the Bourne films. Carlin has
3750	previous here, too – his book Playing the Enemy: Nelson Mandela and the Game
3827	that Made a Nation was turned into Invictus by Clint Eastwood – and his
3899	recreation of that Valentine’s Day morning has the pace and energy of a
3971	movie script earmarked for, say, Channing Tatum and Jennifer Lawrence.
4051	Carlin makes a smart, convincing case that there are “two Oscars” and
4121	that, in this respect, Pistorius is a faithful reflection of South Africa in
4198	2014, a country that is the “undisputed global champion” of rape and
4267	violent crime against women and where 45 people are murdered every day.
4339	“There were two South Africas,” Carlin concludes. “One was uplifting;
4409	the other was frightening. One was made up of people who were unusually
4481	polite, who were generous, indomitable, forgiving and brave; the other of
4555	people who were reckless, volatile, violent, hot-headed.”
4622	What neither book offers is a view on Pistorius’s innocence or guilt. This
4697	is left to June Steenkamp in Reeva: A Mother’s Story (Sphere, 288pp,
4766	£14.99). The Steenkamps have not always been sympathetically portrayed in the
4844	media, maybe because they have demanded money for interviews. (The family
4918	still struggles financially: shortly before she died, Reeva transferred £60
4994	to her parents so they could watch her new reality show on cable TV.)
5073	But June Steenkamp’s book is no lightweight, hastily conceived cash-in but a
5150	forthright and endearingly honest account. Early on, she raises the
5218	possibility that the couple had a terrible row and he violently lost his
5291	temper, “because he shot her not just once, but bang, bang, bang, bang with
5367	9mm bullets until she was dead”. June Steenkamp claims not to hate
5434	Pistorius; she barely knows him. She spoke to him just once: one day, Reeva
5510	called from the car as Pistorius drove at 160mph and her mother, a tough
5583	Lancastrian, scolded him, “If you hurt my baby, I’ll have you wiped
5651	out.”
5666	When Pistorius testified, June Steenkamp sat forward in her seat, eager and,
5743	she says, open-minded to see if he could convince her. It didn’t happen.
5816	Pistorius will have another chance to display contrition when he publishes his
5895	own book, which, predictably, his agent has announced is already taking shape.
