257	Netanyahu apologizes to Arab Israelis for Election Day remarks
343	On Election Day PM urged Right-wing to go vote as Arab voters were going "en
420	masse to the polls."
450	In a meeting with representatives of minority communities in Israel on Monday,
529	Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu apologized for the remarks that he made on
606	Election Day about Arab Israeli voters.
655	"I know that the things I said a few days ago hurt some citizens in Israel,
731	the Arab Israeli citizens," Netanyahu said.
784	"This was not my intention and I am sorry," he said.
846	Netanyahu's Election Day remarks have garnered extensive criticism.
923	“The Right-wing government is in danger. Arab voters are going en masse to
998	the polls. Left-wing NGOs are bringing them on buses,” the prime minister
1072	said last week.
1097	Netanyahu said Monday that as prime minister he makes enormous investments in
1175	minority communities which proves the opposite of his comments last week.
1258	The prime minister said foreign elements outside of Israel should not be
1331	allowed to intervene in Israeli democracy.
1383	In the controversial statement on Election Day, Netanyahu said "funding from
1460	foreign governments to get more Israeli Arabs to vote worked, which means all
1538	Right-wing voters must make sure to go to the polls."
1601	Netanyahu told the gathered community leaders on Monday that he saw himself as
1680	the prime minister of every one of them, "without any difference in religion,
1758	race, or sex."
1782	"I see in every Israeli citizen a partner in the building of a flourishing and
1861	safe state of Israel for all," Netanyahu remarked.
1921	Joint (Arab) List head Ayman Odeh called Netanyahu's statement unacceptable
1997	and said a sincere apology should come in the form of passing laws intended to
2076	make state funding allocations in Israel more equal. He noted that after the
2153	meeting with the Arab leaders, Netanyahu met with Bayit Yehudi leader Naftali
2231	Bennett and spoke to him about advancing nationalist legislation.
2306	"This is just another zigzag by a man known for his zigzags," Odeh said. "He
2383	should turret the mandates he received for his incitement. We are waiting for
2461	a real apology, which means real equality."
