272	UAE official warns of potential for ISIS-Shabab link
348	The United Arab Emirates' top diplomat warned Wednesday that the Islamic State
427	of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) group could team up with Islamic militants in
498	Somalia, saying that more should be done to prepare for such a threat.
578	ISIS that now controls large parts of Iraq and Syria - also known by the
651	Arabic acronym Daesh - and the Somali militant Islamic group al-Shabab share a
730	common pedigree in that they both have had links to al-Qaeda. They frequently
808	use similar tactics such as explosives-laden cars, suicide bombers and attacks
887	on civilians.
910	They operate independently for now, but the Emirati foreign minister, Sheik
986	Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, suggested that could change.
1054	"What really scares us now is what we see from Daesh, and are we going to see
1132	in the future any sort of collaboration between different terrorist groups
1207	like Daesh and al-Shabab?" Sheik Abdullah said in an address at the opening of
1286	a conference focused on counter-piracy in Somalia.
1346	"I think we should start to ask ourselves: how ready we are as countries,
1420	companies and international organizations in facing these big threats," he
1495	added.
1511	Sheik Abdullah did not cite any specific intelligence pointing to active
1584	collaboration between the groups, but there has been speculation that the
1658	Somali rebels would shift their allegiance from al-Qaeda to ISIS.
1733	The Emirates is a Western-allied, seven-state federation that includes the
1808	Gulf shipping and commercial hub of Dubai and the oil-rich capital, Abu Dhabi.
1887	It is home to a sizable Somali expatriate population and is among the most
1962	prominent Arab allies taking part in U.S.-led airstrikes against ISIS.
2042	Al-Shabab last month named a new leader, Ahmad Umar, and reaffirmed its
2114	alignment with al-Qaeda after its longtime head, Ahmed Abdi Godane, was killed
2193	in a U.S. airstrike 105 miles (170 kilometers) south of the Somali capital of
2271	Mogadishu.
2291	The Islamic State group itself began as an Iraqi affiliate of al-Qaeda, but it
2370	was kicked out of the terror network earlier this year.
