233	Iran nuclear talks carry on into the wee hours
303	US Secretary of State John Kerry and his Iranian counterpart huddled in
375	Lausanne all night until early dawn Thursday negotiating face-to-face as they
453	sought to clinch a hard-fought deal to curtail Iran's nuclear programme.
535	They were joined by the EU's deputy foreign policy chief Helga Schmid for the
613	marathon session, aiming to end a stalemate which has dragged the negotiations
692	beyond a March 31st deadline.
741	"We are a few metres... from the finishing line, but we are well aware that
817	the final metres are the hardest," French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius told
896	reporters, as he arrived back in Switzerland to rejoin the negotiations.
988	The stakes were very high, he said, adding at issue was the question of
1060	non-proliferation, and "Iran's reintegration into the international
1128	community."
1159	Kerry and Zarif spent a sleepless night, talking from 9:20 pm Wednesday until
1237	5:50 am with just a small break in between, when the American diplomat met
1312	with his French and German counterparts, a US official said.
1392	Diplomats and experts from Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the
1467	United States also remained hard at work all night with their Iranian
1537	counterparts in a luxury Lausanne hotel in a flurry of separate meetings,
1611	before finally breaking from the negotiations just before dawn.
1694	"We're moving," Zarif said as he emerged for a breath of fresh air.
1771	High stakes
1792	After 18 months of intense negotiations, it remained unclear if the six world
1870	powers and Iran will pin down the main contours of a deal to put a nuclear
1945	bomb out of Iran's reach.
1990	The aim is to turn this into a comprehensive accord backed by specific
2061	technical commitments by June 30th when an interim deal struck in November —
2138	which saw Iran freeze certain nuclear activities in return for minor sanctions
2217	relief — expires.
2254	Success would end a 12-year-old standoff. Failure may set the United States
2330	and Israel on a road to military action to thwart Iran's nuclear drive.
2421	"Iran has shown its readiness to engage with dignity and it's time for our
2496	negotiating partners to seize the moment," Zarif told reporters late on
2568	Wednesday.
2598	Iran had shown it wants "an entente" with the world, but it "will not accept
2675	submitting to force and excessive demands," Zarif said.
2750	The White House said the talks were still "productive" and progress was being
2828	made.
2853	"But if we are in a situation where we sense that the talks have stalled then
2931	yes, the United States and the international community is prepared to walk
3006	away," said White House spokesman Josh Earnest.
3073	Iran's chief negotiator Abbas Araghchi had appeared hopeful Wednesday, saying
3151	he believed "that at the end of the day we will be able to come to a
3220	conclusion and a resolution for all issues."
3284	He said there were two main sticking points — a mechanism for lifting
3354	crippling sanctions against the Islamic republic, and the country's research
3431	and development of new nuclear machinery.
3482	Sanctions relief
3508	Global powers want Iran to scale down its nuclear programme to extend the
3582	"breakout" time needed to assemble enough nuclear material to make a bomb,
3657	which Iran has always denied seeking.
3714	But Iranian negotiators are under pressure from domestic hardliners not to
3789	give too much away — while also delivering on President Hassan Rouhani's
3862	promise to win the lifting of sanctions.
3922	Global powers have refused an immediate end to all sanctions, preferring
3995	instead a phased suspension to enable them to be put back in place if Iran
4070	violates the deal.
4108	US President Barack Obama also needs a deal which he can sell to hostile
4181	Republicans in Congress, who remain sceptical of Iran's pledges and are
4253	threatening to push for new sanctions from April 14th.
4327	Republicans and US allies like Israel and Saudi Arabia fear that if too much
4404	of Iran's nuclear programme is left intact, it will still have the ability to
4482	obtain a nuclear bomb.
