195	ISIS PUSHES WEST, EYEING A NEW CALIPHATE IN TUNISIA
270	It used to be known as the birthplace of the Arab Spring. Now, Tunisia could
347	become the latest addition to the so-called Islamic State.
415	There are increased signs that the self-proclaimed Islamic State has sets its
493	sights on expanding its caliphate to Tunisia next.
553	In the last two weeks, ISIS has published videos taunting the government,
627	shared pictures of some its fighters brandishing guns and made fun of a
699	Tunisian tourism campaign in the wake of a March bombing at a museum that was
777	reportedly carried out by ISIS. The group also has posted online photos of
852	supposed Tunisian martyrs to its cause—though the tweets don’t make clear
926	where those purported members died.
971	ISIS also announced that it is creating the Islamic State of Afrikah, an
1044	antiquated name for the region that is now Tunisia.
1105	For a time, Western counter-terrorism analysts hoped that ISIS’s recent
1177	territorial losses in Iraq weakened its ability to expand internationally.
1252	This lunge toward Tunisia undercuts those hopes.
1310	Not only would it be the furthest West ISIS in North Africa that has pushed to
1389	date, but Tunisia, the birthplace of the so-called Arab Spring of 2011, was
1465	largely seen as the most successful country to emerge from that period, when
1542	street protests led to the collapse of long-standing regimes there and in
1616	Egypt, Libya, and Yemen.
1650	That said, there had long been an undercurrent of Islamic extremism in
1721	Tunisia. The country is one of the biggest providers of fighters to the
1793	Islamic State. According to one estimate, roughly 4,000 Tunisians have joined
1871	ISIS in Libya and another 3,000 are part of ISIS in Syria.
1939	The messages indicating ISIS’s expansion into Tunisia are appearing on
2010	Twitter accounts and websites affiliated with ISIS. Some of the messages have
2088	since been deleted.
2117	“Afrikah for the world,” reads one message.
2170	Another mocks an online campaign that emerged after a deadly March attack on a
2249	Tunisian museum called “Yes, we will Visit Tunisia.” A man whose face is
2322	covered entirely in a black mask and carrying an AK-47 holds a sign in his
2397	other hand that reads: “I will come to Tunisia next summer.”
2467	Two U.S. officials told The Daily Beast that they are watching to see how the
2545	relationship evolves but could not say whether the recent messages from ISIS
2622	suggested the caliphate was moving into Tunisia.
2680	Tunisia “is definitely is an environment that ISIS can excel in,” one U.S.
2755	official explained. “At some point in the future I could see a [jihadist]
2829	contingent saying, ‘We are aligned’” with ISIS.
2886	But unlike its past campaigns to expand the caliphate into new states,
2957	ISIS’s push into Tunisia is more tepid. Rather than bold announcements or
3031	suggestions that ISIS has co-opted an existing local terror group, in Tunisia,
3110	ISIS appears to be making a series of suggestive announcements to inspire
3184	Tunisians to join them.
3217	“There are signs they are pushing toward making it official,” said Aaron
3290	Zelin, a fellow at the Washington Institute for Near East Affairs who studies
3368	jihadi movements. “They want to build up momentum and excitement.”
3444	Tunisia poses a couple of challenges that ISIS has not faced in other efforts
3522	to expand the caliphate outside its main bases of Iraq and Syria. It has
3595	neither a clear existing group or territory in Tunisia to latch onto, experts
3673	said.
3688	In Nigeria, for example, ISIS linked up with the biggest terror group there,
3765	Boko Haram, even though the groups share very different visions for Nigeria.
3842	The first signs of ISIS and Boko Haram working together emerged in February
3918	when Boko Haram transformed its media channel to a much more sophisticated
3993	effort that mirrored the Islamic State’s.
4044	While Boko Haram has been relatively calm since the March 27 presidential
4118	elections, there were signs of an expanding relationship between it and ISIS.
4196	Over the weekend, Boko Haram announced it changed its name to the Islamic
4270	State of West Africa, suggesting that Boko Haram, beleaguered by a regional
4346	military effort, appears to have grown more dependent on ISIS for funding and
4424	support.
4442	In Afghanistan, ISIS worked closely with disaffected Taliban, naming Hafez
4517	Sayed Khan Orakzai, a former commander of the Pakistani Taliban, as head of
4593	its caliphate there. And in Libya, ISIS has established itself through the
4668	vast ungoverned territory there, saying its state exists in part of the
4740	eastern city of Derna.
4772	But in Tunisia it has neither. So far, Tunisia’s best known terror group,
4846	Katibah Okba Ibn Nafaa, remains affiliated with al Qaeda in the Islamic
4918	Maghreb—and al Qaeda and ISIS are sworn enemies.
4976	In an audio recording, ISIS claimed responsibility for the March attack
5048	National Bardo Museum, when several men stormed the site and fatally shot 22
5125	people, most of them tourists, and injured 50 others. But the Tunisian
5196	government said it believed Katibah Okba Ibn Nafaa carried out the attack.
