231	Mixed reactions trail polls’ postponement
296	More reactions have continued to trail the postponement of the earlier
367	scheduled for February 14 and 28 general elections by the Independent National
446	Electoral Commission, INEC. Below are some of views expressed by lawyers,
520	including the Nigerian Bar association, NBA, on the issue. Excerpts:
598	By Dayo Benson and Bartholomew Madukwe
646	INEC should ensure PVC issue is resolved — NBA
702	THE Nigerian Bar Association notes the decision of INEC to postpone the 2015
779	General Elections by six [6] weeks in the light of the security advisory
852	received from the Security Agencies that the required security personnel are
929	engaged in a military operation against Boko Haram and will not be available
1006	to protect Electoral materials and staff if the elections were held on 14th
1082	and 28th February, 2015 as originally scheduled.
1140	The security advisory left INEC with no other option than to postpone the
1214	elections. INEC can certainly not be expected to proceed with the elections
1290	without the required security support.
1338	The new dates of 28th March and 11th April, 2015 fixed by INEC fall within the
1417	timeline provided in the Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria, 1999
1496	[as amended] CFRN. We advise INEC to utilize the said six [6] week period to
1573	resolve the challenges surrounding the issuance of Permanent Voter’s Cards
1648	(PVCs). There are still about 20 million PVCs yet to be collected by Voters
1724	while some PVCs are still being produced and/or awaiting delivery at this
1798	time.
1813	We restate our call on INEC, to request the Federal Government of Nigeria
1887	[FGN] to declare a minimum of two [2] work free days to enable voters collect
1965	their PVCs from their polling stations. INEC should also ensure that PVCs are
2043	produced for all voters whose names appear in the Voters’ Register.
2120	PVCs are central to the success of the 2015 General Elections and INEC must
2196	apply its best endeavours to ensure that all problems in respect of PVCs are
2273	resolved well before the 28th of March, 2015. Our entire democratic experience
2352	depends on the success of the 2015 General Elections and INEC must ensure that
2431	everything necessary is put in place for a successful 2015 General Elections.
2518	The NBA also notes that the Security Advisory relied upon by INEC in
2587	postponing the 2015 General Elections indicates that Nigerian security forces
2665	are aggressively combating the Boko Haram insurgency and expect to totally
2740	eliminate the insurgents and secure the North Eastern States of Nigeria, that
2818	have taken the brunt of the insurgents’ attacks, in the next six [6] weeks.
2894	The NBA hopes that this security advisory is not just to provide basis for
2969	postponing the elections as is being suggested in certain quarters, but
3041	represents the true and correct position of our security forces in their
3114	efforts to rid our Country of the Boko Haram insurgency.
3180	Are we stranded? Tani Molajo, SAN
3223	Our much awaited general elections have now assumed the unhappy appearance of
3301	a delayed airline flight. As the shifts in departure times are announced, the
3379	burning question also shifts from “when” to “if” the flight will
3444	depart at all.
3468	Given the limited time now available to comply with the requirements of the
3544	Electoral Act, that “if” has become a huge concern. By April 11 (the new
3617	date announced for the concluding Governorship and State Assembly elections)
3694	there will remain only 2 possible elections – day Saturdays (i.e. April 18
3769	and 25) before the commencement of the mandatory 30-day period (commencing on
3847	April 29) and ending on the May 29 handover date for political incumbents. In
3925	the circumstances, there is precious little room for any further
3990	postponements. Thus, we appear to be painfully enroute an answer in the
4062	negative to our question – “if”. It is pertinent to observe that the
4131	announced postponement has been tied to the Boko Haram insurgency. We are now
4209	into the 3rd year of that bloody crisis. Are we really to accept that it will
4287	be resolved in the course of this 6 – week postponement? Has our allegorical
4364	flight been delayed or cancelled? Are we stranded?
4424	President himself should be ashamed-Prof Fidelis Oditah QC, SAN
4497	I think it is really irresponsible of those who wrote the disgraceful letter
4574	to INEC alleging insecurity. The president himself should be ashamed; his
4648	primary responsibility is to ensure security.
4703	It is the blatant admission of incompetence for him to turn out and say
4775	election should be postponed because he has failed in his primary duty. The
4851	president himself should be ashamed; his primary responsibility is to ensure
4928	security.
4947	It is the blatant admission of incompetence for him to turn out and say
5019	election should be postponed because he has failed in his primary duty.
5091	Anywhere else, he would stand down on a shame. But here, people have no shame
5169	because we have lost all value.
5210	It is like an opportunity to keep on giving excuse—Prof Bankole Sodipo
5290	In a way, it is inexcusable because the national security officer who prompted
5369	INEC knew the situation before now. And giving the excuse of the state which
5446	has lost the PVC and so on, it is like an opportunity to keep on giving
5518	excuses.
5536	It is very unlikely that they would have sorted the problem out in 6 weeks. It
5615	is a problem that has been with us and has been escalating for almost 2 years.
5694	if it is a good excuse to postpone, now it has come to be a good excuse in 6
5771	weeks time.
5792	My position is that it is inexcusable and we should not postpone. Since the
5868	postpone is 6 weeks time, there is absolutely no excuse, we will take it that
5946	the governor wants to sit back.
5987	Postponement, in law, has no iota, semblance or modicum legal conformity-
6061	Chief Morah Ekwunoh
6090	Combination of hard, solemn and contemplative critique of INEC’s recent
6162	postponement, by six weeks, of the February, 2015, General Elections vis-a-vis
6241	the proffered  raison d’etre behind it leaves dispassionate and apolitical
6316	legal minds with no option than to conclude that the postponement, in the
6390	circumstances thereof, constitute faulty exercise of sacrosanct powers, and,
6467	by extension, clear, unmistakable and condemnable subversion of democratic
6542	process.
6560	The law gives INEC the power to postpone the election- Mr. Adekunle Oyesanya
6637	SAN.
6651	I heard Professor Jega part way talk about reasons for postponing the
6721	elections. From what he said was that the security persons gave a report that
6799	they were not ready to secure the election process. Honestly, even if some of
6877	the parties have been crying foul and saying that there is a hidden agenda of
6955	postponing the election, I do not think there is any prejudice to anybody.
7039	What the law says is that eventually the elections must be conducted at least
7117	thirty days before the handover date. The law gives INEC the power to postpone
7196	the election, so I don’t think anybody should be crying foul to it.
7264	Postponing it gives everybody and parties the time to prepare and INEC to have
7343	more time to prepare.
7374	Electioneering process
7406	More important is the voters, some people have not got their PVC yet. The most
7485	important person in this electioneering process is the voter.  One thing is
7561	very clear, the constitution does not recognize PVC, what it recognizes is the
7640	registered voters.
7668	As good as the PVC idea is to cub election malpractice. But if those people
7744	who have registered cannot get their PVC, that is unconstitutional and against
7823	their constitutional rights. If you go to the election ground and say you want
7902	to vote without your registered voter, it won’t count.
7966	Anybody can challenge that kind of process. In as much as we want the
8036	elections to hold as scheduled, but if postponing it is for the common good of
8115	Nigeria, why are we bothering ourselves?
8165	Didn’t INEC think about security before fixing Feb 14? —NBA Chairman,
8235	Lagos branch- Mr Alex Muoka
8272	The challenge has to do with reasons given for the postponement. If you recall
8351	on Thursday (Feb. 5), the Council of States meeting held and it was to confirm
8430	their readiness for the election. But on Saturday (Feb. 7), INEC came up with
8508	the issue of security which they said they cannot guarantee because of Boko
8584	Haram.
8600	The important thing is that didn’t they think about it before fixing the
8673	election for February 14? Why must it be on February 14? So it looks very
8747	funny. I am just tired of this system of saying one thing and later doing
8821	another thing. There have been calls from every well meaning quarter that the
8899	elections should go ahead as scheduled.
