263	Hillary Clinton Jokes About Fresh Start With the Press
341	The presumptive presidential frontrunner for the Democrats told a gathering of
420	journalists she was ready to give up her "zone of privacy."
489	Former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton acknowledged her rocky history with
567	the political press on Monday and said she hopes to turn over a new leaf as
643	she heads into a new campaign season as she implored journalists to focus on
720	telling substantive stories.
758	“My relationship with the press has been, at times, shall we say,
824	complicated,” she said as she addressed an awards ceremony celebrating the
899	late New York Times political reporter Robin Toner. Journalists filled the
974	two-dozen tables at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, a
1048	Washington think tank, as did a few press-facing current and former White
1122	House staffers.
1147	But as she prepares to launch her second presidential campaign and builds a
1223	press team that’s notably more cooperative than the one that worked for her
1299	in 2008, she conveyed that ready for a reset.
1354	"I am all about new beginnings,” she said. "A new grandchild, another new
1428	hairstyle, a new e-mail account. The relationship with the press. So here
1502	goes: no more secrecy. No more zone of privacy. After all, what good did that
1580	do me?”
1597	Then, she joked, with a hint that her transformation may not be a full one:
1673	"before I go any further, look under your chair, you’ll find a simple
1743	non-disclosure agreement my attorneys drew up. Old habits last."
1817	Clinton started on a light note but turned more serious. "We and our democracy
1896	depend on you,” she said before urging the reporters in the room to follow
1971	Toner’s lead and write substantive stories about policy.
2037	She conceded that “it has gotten even harder to do the kind of journalism
2111	that she did” as the country and the media have gotten more polarized, and
2186	technology has put new pressures on reporters.
2242	“I think the stakes are really high,” she said, with too much political
2314	discourse taking place in an “evidence-free zone.” The realities of the
2386	industry make it difficult, but it’s important to try to "get us out of the
2462	echo chambers we all inhabit.”
2502	“I believe we need more Robin Toners,” she added.
2561	Toner covered politics and also had an emphasis in her reporting on health
2636	care policy. Her final interview with Clinton, in the fall of 2007, was about
2714	the then-
2733	senator’s health care proposals during the Democratic presidential primary.
2818	Monday is the fifth anniversary of the passage of the Affordable Care Act and,
2897	while Republican Sen. Ted Cruz entered the presidential race vowing to repeal
2975	the law, Clinton said she hopes to improve the law, not dismantle it.
3054	The questions to ask are "how to improve the ACA...how to build on the
3125	successes,” she said. “I’m well aware none of this will be easy,” she
3195	continued, but it will be even more difficult without people like those in the
3274	audience explaining the policies and personalities at play.
3343	Clinton said the role of the press is to “hold us all accountable.” Still,
3418	she said, "those of us on the other side are not always going to be happy
3492	about what whatever it is you do but we understand in our more rational
3564	moments."
