217	Journalists surprised by top secrecy surrounding "Tsarnaev's case". Is there something to hide?
336	American journalists are frustrated by the behavior of US District Court in
412	Boston, writes The Washington Post, whose correspondent Gessen has been
484	covering the trial of Dzhokhar Tsarnaev.
544	In American courts, no video, or audio recording- or photos of the proceedings
623	is ever allowed, and transcripts are quite difficult to get, the newspaper
698	writes.
725	"But local court reporters say they have never faced the sort of restrictions
803	imposed by judge O’Toole in the case of Dzhokhar Tsarnaev. The bulk of files
880	in the case are under seal – including at least one defense motion that was
956	excerpted at length by The Boston Globe before the judge sealed it last week
1033	– and reporters are excluded from seeing or hearing much of the courtroom
1107	discussions that would customarily be public", the article says
1190	The trial is in the voir dire stage, the individual interview part of
1260	selecting a jury. On Wednesday, The Boston Globe filed a motion requesting
1335	public – meaning media – access to some of the challenges made to juror
1407	candidates by the lawyers on either side and the judge’s rulings on these
1481	challenges.
1512	"If a juror is so obviously dead-set on voting for the death penalty or,
1585	conversely, if a juror is unequivocally opposed to the death penalty, both
1660	sides may agree on the spot that the person cannot meaningfully participate in
1739	the penalty phase of the trial", the newspaper explains.
1815	The court has interviewed 98 people so far. "It would appear that most of them
1894	cannot serve on the jury, either because they hold strong beliefs about
1966	Tsarnaev’s guilt or about the death penalty", the newspaper writes.
2053	In open court proceedings, O’Toole said he didn’t want to tell jurors
2123	directly that they have been excused because he doesn’t want to “coach”
2195	other candidates on how to get out of jury duty in this case. "That may be a
2272	part of the reason he has closed the afternoon discussions to the press –
2346	though he has not explained this decision. Nor has he explained the decision
2423	to exclude journalists physically from the courtroom", the article says.
2515	Such restrictions in this court have not even been seen during the last year's
2594	trial of a notorious Boston gangster, Whitey Bulger.
2666	As a result, they agreed the access to the courtroom for three journalists.
2742	The time at which the court mutes the microphone, has been slowly shortening,
2820	too, and journalists can hear a little more. "Still, no one has been able to
2897	hear any of the chats that go on between Tsarnaev and public defender Miriam
2974	Conrad, who sits to his right", notes the newspaper.
