203	Boyfriend of U.S. woman killed by ISIS describes effort to free her
294	Had Kayla Mueller told her captors that she was married to her Syrian partner,
373	she might have been freed; but she denied being his wife.
440	Kayla Mueller was in a detention cell in Syria, face to face with her
510	boyfriend who was posing as her husband. Had she told her captors she was
584	married to Omar Alkhani, she might have been freed from the hands of Islamic
661	State militants, he said. Instead, she denied being his wife.
732	Her death was confirmed last week by the U.S. government and Mueller's family.
811	In the days since, hundreds of people have gathered to honor her in her home
888	state of Arizona.
915	Alkhani had persuaded a string of people to let him plead for her release, but
994	he left empty-handed. He said he saw Mueller's face for just a few seconds
1069	when guards uncovered it to show it.
1115	The guards told Mueller, 26, that Alkhani would not be harmed if she told the
1193	truth, so she apparently stuck to honesty to save him rather than take the
1268	slim chance to save herself, he said.
1315	"Since she's American, they would not let her go anyway. No sense to stay
1389	here, both of us," Alkhani said. "Maybe she wanted to save me. Maybe she
1462	didn't know I came back to save her."
1509	Thinking about others first was Mueller's nature. She had long been content
1585	without spending the wages she earned as an international aid worker on new
1661	clothes, a hair dryer or makeup so she could use her money to help others
1735	instead, Alkhani said.
1767	The Syrian spoke to The Associated Press on Sunday via webcam from Turkey in
1844	one of his first interviews, detailing how he met Mueller in 2010 and the last
1923	time he saw her in 2013 as a prisoner of the Islamic State group.
1998	Mueller and Alkhani were taken hostage in August 2013 after leaving a Doctors
2076	Without Borders hospital in Aleppo, Syria, where he was hired to fix the
2149	Internet connection. Mueller had begged him to let her tag along so she could
2227	see the suffering firsthand and help, despite the dangers of traveling into
2303	the war-torn region. He said he agreed reluctantly.
2364	"We argued about it," he said. "In the end, I was afraid if she didn't go with
2443	me, she would go with someone else."
2489	Mueller took advantage of an unexpected overnight stay at the hospital when
2565	the repairs took longer than expected and asked Syrian women about how they
2641	managed daily life. During what should have been a 10-minute trip to the bus
2718	station the next day, Mueller, Alkhani, the taxi driver and a fourth person
2794	were ambushed at gunpoint and threatened with death.
2856	Mueller remained a hostage, while Alkhani said he was released 20 days later
2933	after being beaten and interrogated about his work as a photographer, his
3007	religion and his relationship to Mueller.
3058	Against the advice of his friends, Alkhani said, he returned to Syria from
3133	Turkey later in 2013 to try to get back the woman he met three years earlier
3210	in Cairo after she responded to an advertisement he posted to house
3278	international visitors.
3311	Mueller had stayed less than a week in Cairo, but Alkhani said they quickly
3387	bonded and kept in touch through the Internet and traveled together,
3456	discussing ways they could change the world. They became a couple, and he said
3535	he promised her that he would always look out for her.
3599	While she was in France learning the country's language to go to north Africa,
3678	Mueller encouraged Alkhani to follow his dream of helping fellow Syrians. She
3756	eventually joined him in Turkey near the Syrian border.
3821	Alkhani said he spoke to her often about Syria, where bloodshed has gripped
3897	the country under the regime of embattled President Bashar Assad, and sent her
3976	recordings, photographs and other information that she used for her blog.
4050	Nearly half of Syria's population has been displaced, and some 200,000 people
4128	have died in the fighting.
4164	"She wanted everyone to use their freedom to help us get freedom," he said.
4249	When they were captured together and detained, Alkhani said he at least had
4325	some reassurance she was alive. He would cough or say something to make sure
4402	his voice was heard, and she sometimes would cough in return. Other times, he
4480	or his cellmates would peer under the door and see the sandals she was
4551	wearing, he said.
4578	When Alkhani was released, he was told to forget about Mueller and his camera
4656	equipment.
4676	Alkhani said he has been in touch with Mueller's family and held out hope like
4755	they did during her 18 months of captivity that she was alive. He convinced
4831	himself that the militants would release her, realizing she was only in Syria
4909	to help people.
4934	"I didn't realize one day I will receive this call from somebody telling me,
5011	'I am sorry,'" he said.
5044	A spokesperson for Mueller's family said they have no reason to not trust
5118	Alkhani's account, and the family believes he loved her and tried to help her.
5197	The spokesperson talked to the AP on condition of anonymity because the person
5276	works in media relations for other families in Middle East hostage situations
5354	and wants to remain anonymous for safety reasons.
