239	Kerry still confident of Iran deal
297	Barack Obama agrees legislation giving Congress the right to reject an
368	agreement
387	US secretary of state John Kerry has said he is still confident of a nuclear
464	deal with Iran after president Barack Obama agreed to sign legislation giving
542	Congress the right to reject an agreement.
594	Mr Kerry joined his counterparts from the G7 at a meeting in northern Germany
672	on the gathering’s second day, flying in overnight after discussing Iran in
748	Washington.
769	“Yesterday there was a compromise reached in Washington regarding
835	congressional input,” he told reporters in Lubeck. “We are confident about
910	our ability for the president to negotiate an agreement, and to do so with the
989	ability to make the world safer.”
1032	Mr Kerry said the challenge of finishing the negotiations with Iran over the
1109	next two-and-a-half months would loom large over the G7 meeting.
1183	Its host, German foreign minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier, said ministers
1257	would discuss the deal between the US administration and Congress, which he
1333	said would have “a certain influence” on whether a deal with Iran can be
1406	achieved by a June 30th deadline.
1449	Mr Steinmeier said other topics would include conflicts in the Middle East,
1525	prospects for peace talks between Israel and the Palestinians, efforts to
1599	combat the Islamic State group, the Ebola outbreak in West Africa, the impact
1677	of climate change on political stability in Africa and Asia, and the ongoing
1754	fighting in Ukraine.
1784	“The weather in international politics is quite stormy,” he said. “The
1855	conflict in eastern Ukraine is only two hours away from here.”
1927	Mr Steinmeier said the G7’s senior diplomats would also issue a statement on
2004	maritime security, noting that Lubeck was plagued by pirates until the
2075	Hanseatic League — an alliance of northern European trading cities —
2144	cracked down on the practice some 600 years ago.
2202	Although Russia was ejected from what was then the G8 last year over its
2275	support for armed separatists in eastern Ukraine, Mr Steinmeier praised Moscow
2354	for what he called its “constructive attitude” in not blocking a UN
2422	Security Council resolution imposing an arms embargo on Houthi rebel leaders
2499	in Yemen.
