232	Oscar Pistorius could still be convicted of murder
306	Judge grants prosecutors leave to appeal, opening the door for Pistorius'
380	conviction to be upgraded to murder
425	Oscar Pistorius could have his conviction upgraded from culpable homicide to
502	murder and face a possible 15-year prison sentence, after an appeal
570	application made by state prosecutors was granted.
630	It means the case, ongoing for almost 10 months, will reopen in South Africa's
709	court of appeal in Bloemfontein, and be heard by a panel of five new judges.
795	Granting the application, Judge Thokozile Masipa, who heard the original case,
874	said the appeal made by state prosecutor Gerrie Nel showed that the law
946	applied to the case could be open to a different interpretation.
1020	"I cannot say ... that the prospect of success at the supreme court of appeal
1098	is remote," Judge Masipa ruled at the High Court in Pretoria.
1169	"The application, therefore, in respect of count one is decided in favour of
1246	the applicant."
1271	Oscar Pistorius himself was not present to hear the application. He remains in
1350	prison in Pretoria, and will do so for at least another eight months, at which
1429	point he will become eligible for parole.
1480	South Africa's Supreme Court will not be asked to decide whether the athlete
1557	knew his girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp was behind the bathroom door when he fired
1636	four shots through it in the early hours of Valentine's Day morning last year.
1724	By his own admission, Pistorius believed an intruder was behind the door, and
1802	the case will hinge on whether the athlete foresaw that his actions would kill
1881	that person.
1903	In her sentencing, Judge Masipa decided that while he should have foreseen
1978	this, he didn't.
2004	If the Supreme Court decides otherwise, he could be convicted of second-degree
2083	murder, on the principle of dolus eventualis, the Latin term that has hovered
2161	over this incredibly protracted trial.
2209	Judge Masipa rejected the prosecution's application also to appeal the
2280	sentence she laid down, of five years, which Mr Nel called "shockingly
2351	inappropriate".
2376	But in practice, once the matter is in the hands of the Supreme Court, it can
2454	decide to overturn this in any case.
2500	Reeva Steenkamp's parents had previously said they were satisfied with the
2575	verdict and sentence handed down to Pistorius.
2631	The family's lawyer, Dup de Bruyn, said: "All they're saying is justice must
2708	run its course and they want to get on with their lives."
2775	Typically, cases take more than a year to appear before the Supreme Court, by
2853	which point Pistorius is likely to be out of prison and serving the rest of
2929	his sentence under house arrest.
2971	He would be unlikely to attend the trial, which would in the most part be a
3047	matter of arguing over whether the law had been correctly applied rather than
3125	hearing new evidence.
3156	It is a victory for the National Prosecuting Authority (NPA), which has been
3233	humiliated both by the Pistorius case and by the acquittal of Shrien Dewani,
3310	after seeking his extradition for the supposed contract killing of his wife.
3396	Nathi Mncube, the NPA's spokesman said: "Our argument was that [Pistorius]
3471	should have been convicted of murder, and then would have been sentenced to a
3549	minimum of 15 years."
