252	Chioma Ogwuegbu: Why I chose General Buhari over Goodluck Jonathan
342	Last October after the APC presidential primaries, I tweeted these words ‘I
418	will never vote Buhari.’ I had my reasons, the major one being my conviction
495	that voting a former military dictator does not bode well for a democracy.
570	That same reason was why I never voted General Olusegun Obasanjo the two times
649	he contested and won. The same reason I never voted Buhari in 2011 nor the
724	other times he had contested. I felt that all former military dictators had
800	had their time and it was time for us to move on.
859	I knew General Muhammad Buhari’s antecedents and track record, that of the
934	upright, somewhat rigid no-nonsense former military man who did not compromise
1013	his values or his integrity. He had always run on an anti-corruption campaign
1091	platform with the aura of someone who did not mind to go it alone if that was
1169	what was required of him. I admired that, but I was not convinced that was all
1248	that was required for me to give him my vote. Especially not after the
1319	massacre that took place during the 2011 elections and all the inciting
1391	statements that were attributed to him.
1440	Up until February 8th, I had not decided whom I would vote or rather, I had
1516	decided I would vote neither Buhari nor the incumbent, President Goodluck
1590	Jonathan but I did not have any other candidate. Sometimes, I toyed with the
1667	idea of voting Oluremi Sonaiya of KOWA Party but I did not know her track
1741	record. As for Jonathan, I did not vote him in 2011 and it felt like in the 4
1819	years since then he had proven why I thought it was a bad idea to not vote
1894	him. From mismanaging the economy to mishandling that nation’s security
1966	challenges, Jonathan has proven himself to be an incompetent leader.
2044	The abduction of the Chibok girls and the loss of Nigeria’s territories to
2119	insurgency due to mostly a lack of political will to tackle it convinced me
2195	that Jonathan does not have what it takes to remain president. I have a 5
2269	year-old somewhat precocious daughter, she has a mouth on her. Recently whilst
2348	we were driving somewhere, Kaline’s song ‘Bring Them Home’ (a tribute to
2421	the Chibok girls) came on the radio. My daughter said to me somberly,
2500	‘Mommy, if somebody took me away from you, I would miss you so much?’
2579	It saddened me that Nigeria had become a country where a 5 year-old could live
2658	under the apprehension that some unknown persons could come steal her away
2733	from her family. Who should get the blame for that if not the nation’s chief
2810	security officer, Dr Goodluck Ebele Jonathan? On top of all of this, to me the
2889	biggest testament to Jonathan’s failure as a president is the fact that
2961	Buhari has become a viable alternative.
3010	However, Buhari has not just become the viable alternative because of
3080	Jonathan’s incompetence but also because this time he has aligned himself
3154	with a competent, accomplished team. His campaign team has the right mix of
3230	technocrats and politicians. His choice of Professor Yemi Osinbajo, Professor
3308	of Law and a former attorney general of Lagos, as vice presidential candidate
3386	speaks volumes. The first time I encountered Osinbajo was in March 2013 when
3463	he held a meeting with some social media influencers. He spoke so eloquently
3540	about the APC’s plans and with a deep understanding of Nigeria’s
3605	challenges and how they could be tackled. I left that meeting hoping he would
3683	one day be able to work for Nigeria at the national level. I was impressed
3758	when Buhari chose him as running mate.
3806	I am not religious so my vote will not be based on religion. I am a
3874	nationalist so my vote will not be based on ethnic sentiments. Yet my vote
3949	will be based on sentiments, it will be based on emotions, on love for my
4023	country, love for my child and for myself. I do not want my beloved country to
4102	continue down this path of perdition, I still want my daughter to have a place
4181	she calls home 20 years from now. Buhari with his current team can put a stop
4259	this journey towards destruction. For this reason, I choose General Muhammad
4336	Buhari, to bring Nigeria back to the right path.
