258	Media ignores families of ISIS beheading victims
330	The mother of ISIS beheading victim James Foley told CNN’s Anderson Cooper,
406	on September 11, that she was “embarrassed and appalled” by the White
476	House’s handling of her son’s kidnapping. On September 8 a spokesman for
549	the family of ISIS victim Steven Sotloff claimed that both families were
622	“bullied and hectored” by the administration.
677	So how many Big Three (ABC, CBS, NBC) network stories have been devoted to
752	helping these families tell their shocking stories of a White House that let
829	them down and even intimidated them? Just three stories: (CBS 2, ABC 1, NBC
905	0).
918	However, in the summer of 2005 when anti-Iraq war mom Cindy Sheehan camped out
997	in front of George W. Bush’s Crawford, Texas ranch the networks flooded
1069	their evening and morning shows with 100 stories (ABC 37, NBC 33, CBS 30) in
1146	the first month (August 9 through September 9) of coverage alone.
1221	The eagerness of the networks to cover Sheehan stands in stark contrast in how
1300	they have covered the Foley and Sotloff families and other parents who have
1376	blamed the Obama administration for the loss of their loved ones. The
1446	complaints by the parents of Benghazi attack victims Sean Smith and Tyrone
1521	Woods also got short shrift on the networks (3 stories). The mother and father
1600	of Fast and Furious victim border agent Brian Terry haven’t found much of an
1677	network outlet for their criticism of Obama and Eric Holder either. (1 story).
1765	The following is a look at how each of these family tragedies have been
1837	covered on the ABC, CBS, NBC evening and morning programs:
1905	While the networks did run stories airing the parents’ pleas before Foley
1979	and Sotloff were executed by ISIS, they curiously decreased their coverage of
2057	those families when they began speaking out against the Obama administration.
2144	CBS ran just two stories. On the September 12 CBS This Morning Charlie Rose
2220	noted “The mother of James Foley, an American journalist is lashing out at
2295	the Obama administration. Diane Foley says U.S. officials threatened to
2367	prosecute her family if tried to raise ransom money. She told CNN’s Anderson
2444	Cooper last night that the government failed her son.” Rose then played a
2518	soundbite from the CNN interview.
2561	On the September 17 CBS This Morning Norah O’Donnell reported: “The
2629	families are making it clear this morning they wanted to do more to save their
2708	loved ones but U.S. officials wouldn’t help…His mother Shirley made a
2778	public appeal to his captors last month, begging for her son’s release. But
2854	behind closed doors, she and the family of James Foley were at odds with the
2931	U.S. government and its longstanding policy against paying ransom to
3000	terrorists…Last May, the families say a White House official threatened
3072	criminal prosecution if they paid a ransom.”
3126	After the O’Donnell piece Rose actually interviewed the Sotloff family
3197	spokesman Barak Barfi who told Rose: “We never really believed that the
3269	administration was doing anything to help us…We had meetings with the
3339	administration. The families sat with this National Security Council official
3417	and basically he bullied and hectored them and they were scared.”
3492	ABC [only carried] a single story about the Foley family charges against the
3569	administration. On the September 12 World News Tonight David Muir introduced a
3648	Brian Ross story: “This evening, anguish and now anger from the parents of
3723	one of those Americans executed by ISIS. They have direct words for President
3801	Obama. They say their son, journalist James Foley, dying an awful death. And
3878	this evening, a startling claim, that the family was actually threatened, they
3957	say, by the White House. Tonight, those parents going very public with this,
4034	talking to our own Brian Ross and Greta Van Susteren over at Fox.”
4110	So far NBC has yet to air any of the Sotloff or Foley family complaints.
