253	Opposing Pictures of Tsarnaev at Boston Marathon Bombing Trial
339	BOSTON — Almost two years after a pair of homemade bombs brought terror and
415	carnage to the Boston Marathon, the trial of Dzhokhar Tsarnaev opened on
488	Wednesday with the dramatic admission by his lead defense lawyer that her
562	client had in fact set off the blasts that killed three people and injured
637	scores of others.
664	“It was him,” the lawyer, Judy Clarke, said bluntly of her client, who sat
739	slouched in a chair at the defense table. She added that Mr. Tsarnaev, 21,
814	would not sidestep responsibility for his actions, which she described as
888	“inexcusable.”
912	But, she argued, he did not act alone. All the horror and grief of the bombing
991	was “caused by a series of senseless, horribly misguided acts carried out by
1068	two brothers,” she said, naming Dzhokhar Tsarnaev and his older brother,
1141	Tamerlan, 26, who is dead.
1177	Dzhokhar was led, she told jurors, on “a path borne of his brother, created
1253	by his brother and paved by his brother.”
1304	The stark admission of culpability was made in service of her ultimate goal
1380	— to persuade the jury to spare Mr. Tsarnaev the death penalty and sentence
1456	him instead to life in prison.
1496	But it was the persuasive powers of his older brother and the consequences of
1574	homegrown terrorism that dominated the opening of a gut-wrenching trial that
1651	is expected to last through June as it drags Boston and the country back to
1727	the marathon finish line and the scene of the worst terrorist attack on
1799	American soil since Sept. 11, 2001.
1844	In the opening statements, two portraits of Mr. Tsarnaev emerged. Prosecutors
1922	argued that he was an intellectually and emotionally committed “terrorist”
1997	bent on avenging American military campaigns in the Muslim world, partly to
2073	help him reach “paradise” after his death. Ms. Clarke argued that her
2143	client was a fairly normal teenager, interested in Facebook, girls and cars,
2220	who was under the heavy sway of the older brother he loved and respected.
2303	The judge, George A. O’Toole Jr. of Federal District Court, limited the
2375	degree to which the defense could bring up the defendant’s older brother in
2451	this phase of the trial, which decides guilt or innocence. But Tamerlan seemed
2530	to hover over the proceedings, present even in death, as the families of
2603	victims who died and survivors who were maimed by the blasts crowded into the
2681	packed courtroom here as the much-anticipated trial finally got underway.
2764	Perhaps anticipating the defense’s approach, the government’s lawyers, who
2839	spoke first, sought preemptively to smother any sympathy Ms. Clarke might stir
2918	up for her client.
2946	William Weinreb, an assistant United States attorney, offered searing
3016	descriptions of how the bombs had ripped the flesh off spectators at the
3089	marathon and sent body parts flying in the air.
3146	He described the precise way in which shrapnel had lacerated the three victims
3225	who died, as their families listened. Martin Richard, 8, “bled to death”
3298	on the sidewalk; Lingzi Lu, 23, had “the inside of her stomach pouring
3369	out”; and Krystle Campbell, 29, had “gaping holes” in her body. The
3437	government later called five eyewitnesses, three of whom suffered grievous
3512	injuries. All described the carnage after the bombing, their testimony
3583	accompanied by gruesome photos and video of victims lying in pools of blood.
3669	“I could feel my body going tingly, and I was getting increasingly cold, and
3746	I knew I was dying,” said Sydney Corcoran, 19, whose femoral artery was
3818	severed by the blasts, causing her to lose most of her blood.
3889	Another witness, Rebekah Gregory, 27, walked to the stand with a prosthesis on
3968	her left leg. “My bones were literally laying next to me on the sidewalk,”
4043	she said. She could hear her 5-year-old son calling for her but could not
4117	reach for him because her arm was shredded.
4170	The defense chose not to cross-examine any of the victims who testified.
4252	During his opening statement, which lasted about 50 minutes, Mr. Weinreb cast
4330	the brothers as “partners in crime,” saying they planned the bombings
4400	together and carried them out together.
4449	The killings, he said, led Dzhokhar Tsarnaev to believe that he “had taken a
4526	step toward reaching paradise.”
4567	The government also laced its narrative with references to Mr. Tsarnaev as
4642	coldhearted. Shortly after the bombings, Mr. Weinreb said, while paramedics
4718	were still trying to resuscitate Martin Richard, Mr. Tsarnaev went to Whole
4794	Foods and casually mulled what type of milk to buy. For the next few days,
4869	“he hung out with friends, partied and tweeted, ‘I’m a stress-free kind
4941	of guy,’ ” Mr. Weinreb said.
4979	Mr. Tsarnaev showed his true colors during the shootout in Watertown with
5053	police, Mr. Weinreb added, lobbing pressure-cooker bombs at the officers. He
5130	said that after the shootout, Mr. Tsarnaev drove at the police at top speed,
5207	“trying to mow them down.”
5243	Instead, Mr. Weinreb said: “The defendant ran right over his brother and
5316	dragged his body about 50 feet down the street.”
5374	Ms. Clarke, whose opening lasted just 20 minutes, argued against the
5443	government’s interpretation of Mr. Tsarnaev’s motive. She cast him as a
5515	typical teenager — so typical, she suggested, that he felt something as
5587	ordinary as sibling rivalry, saying that when he was hiding in a dry-docked
5663	boat before his capture, he had written revealing words about his brother:
5738	“He expressed he was jealous of his brother who achieved martyrdom,” she
5811	said, adding that he wished he could achieve it, too.
5874	“It was Tamerlan who self-radicalized,” she said. “It was Dzhokhar who
5945	followed.” Tamerlan had influence over his younger brother, she said,
6015	because of his age, their culture and the force of his personality.
6092	Ms. Clarke’s blunt, even surprising admission about her client’s actions
6165	seemed to be an effort to telegraph to the jurors that she would not waste
6240	their time with falsehoods, in part to earn their trust.
6306	Nancy Gertner, a former judge who teaches at Harvard Law School, called it
6381	brilliant. By conceding that her client had committed the crimes, Ms. Gertner
6459	said, Ms. Clarke was trying to limit the painful, graphic details the
6529	government could bring up to undermine any sympathy for Mr. Tsarnaev.
6608	Because Ms. Clarke is not disputing the crimes, Ms. Gertner said, those
6680	details are no longer relevant. “The question now is, how far will the
6751	government go to prove what she has essentially conceded?” Ms. Gertner said.
6837	For the defense, the relationship between the two brothers will be both vital
6915	and tricky.
6936	While noting that “some evidence of the brothers’ interactions will be
7007	inevitable,” Judge O’Toole said the issue of whether Mr. Tsarnaev was
7077	“more or less culpable” than others is generally not relevant in the first
7152	phase of the trial, before sentencing. And he curbed Ms. Clarke a couple of
7228	times during her opening statement as she sought to amplify the family
7299	relationships.
7323	As she closed, Ms. Clarke pleaded with jurors to keep an open mind, especially
7402	in the second phase of the trial, when they consider the sentence.
7478	“It’s going to be a lot to keep your hearts and minds open,” she said,
7549	“but that’s what we ask.”
