254	EXCLUSIVE: HILLARY CLINTON’S ‘CONFLICT OF INTEREST’
329	Citizens United has released a devastating new video, titled, “Conflict of
404	Interest,” which asks hard-hitting questions about Hillary Clinton’s lack
478	of transparency in providing information to the public about her Clinton
551	Family Foundation, which brings in over $200 million dollars in revenue each
628	year.
643	The video’s transcript reads:
682	Its 3am and your children are safe and asleep. But theres a phone in the White
761	House. And its ringing. Something’s happening in the world. A foreign leader
838	is calling. And Hillary Clinton is listening. Why? Because he’s also a
909	contributor to the Clinton Family Foundation. How much foreign money can buy
986	your president? Can we afford to find out?
1038	Citizens United President David Bossie told Breitbart News that the American
1115	people deserve “100% transparency from the Clinton Family Foundation,” and
1190	that means they should “disclose 100% of their donors–both foreign and
1261	domestic.”
1281	Bossie hoped by pushing Mrs. Clinton to release her donor information, “the
1357	American people would be able to see once and for all whether she is accepting
1436	money from rogue agents, governments, or businesses around the world that may
1514	be trying to gain influence to the Clinton Foundation.”
1579	“There will be a clear conflict of interest involving the countries that
1652	gave the Clinton Foundation money when Hillary Clinton becomes a candidate,
1728	and even more so if she¹s elected president,” predicted Bossie.
1801	“When it comes to the Clintons and foreign money, it’s like déjà vu all
1873	over again.  These shady foreign relationships need to be kept out of the
1947	White House this time,” he told Breitbart News.
2004	Clinton is widely presumed to be a shoo-in for the Democratic nomination in
2080	2016 and has polled very favorably against potential Republican nominees.
2163	On Wednesday, Republican leadership demanded that the White House address
2237	Hillary Clinton’s alleged violations of a “flawed agreement” that was
2307	intended to prevent potential conflicts of interest with her foundation while
2385	she served as secretary of state, McClatchy reported.
2448	In the letter, Republican National Committee Chairman Reince Priebus alleged
2525	that Clinton “blatantly ignored” the agreement she signed onto that was
2597	supposed to “alleviate conflicts of interest.”
