271	Should grandmothers be minding the kids or running the world?
356	Does being a good granny mean giving up the second half of your life, like
431	some of you did the first?
467	#GrandmothersKnowBest . Yes they do, Hillary Clinton, yes they do.
543	Clinton was using her sixth tweet of 2015 to get people to vaccinate their
618	kids. “The science is clear. The earth is round, the sky is blue and
687	#vaccineswork. Let’s protect all our kids. #GrandmothersKnowBest”.
763	Being a grandmother to Charlotte – the six-month-old child of Bill and
834	Hillary Clinton’s daughter Chelsea and her husband Marc Mezvinsky – may
906	yet knock those blue-stocking edges off Hillary in the eyes of the US
976	electorate. They love grandmothers.
1021	Kathleen Parker of the Washington Post wrote: “I would submit that
1088	Chelsea’s baby gives Hillary Clinton all the more reason to run for
1156	president. She not only will want to help shape a world in which women lead
1232	nations but also one in which babies and grandmotherhood are celebrated as
1307	integral to women’s lives.”
1344	Meanwhile, to misquote our own first woman president Mary Robinson, this week
1422	we found out that in Ireland the hands that rocked the cradle are still
1494	rocking it. The Irish Times/Ipsos MRBI Family Values poll found grandparents
1571	are the most popular source of childcare for working parents, providing nearly
1650	half of it. There was no gender breakdown of “grandparents” in the survey.
1725	Respondents were not asked if “granny” or “granddad” minded their
1791	grandchildren.
1815	For anyone getting dangerously close to that grandmothering juncture, things
1892	are not looking simple. Unlike Hillary Clinton, few of us are contemplating
1968	running a humongous country. Like Clinton, many of us have a lot done, more to
2047	do.
2060	We might be making some cash working at a supermarket checkout, teaching
2133	people Spanish verbs or writing articles about cross-generational care.
2205	Whatever we are up to, we are actually quite busy.
2265	Should women d’un certain age give everything up to mind their kids’ kids?
2340	Does being a good granny mean giving up the second half of your life, like
2415	some of you did the first?
2451	Former US president Bill Clinton has suggested his wife would rather be a
2525	grandma than a president. Talking to CBS News last year, he said: “If you
2599	ask her, I think she’d say grandmother, but I have found it best not to
2671	discuss that issue.” No, don’t discuss that issue, Bill.
2737	“There’s a disproportionate attention to her [Clinton] being a
2800	grandmother,” according to Debbie Walsh, of the Center for American Women
2874	and Politics at Rutgers University. “Certainly, many men have run for
2944	president as grandfathers and nobody worries if they can’t do their job.”
3027	Having benefited from grandmotherly goodwill to mind my own children, I know
3104	what a wonderful solution grandmothers can offer. And I am truly grateful. But
3183	as I get close to that juncture myself, things are not looking so simple. My
3260	own offspring can take this as advance notice.
3316	I’m really looking forward to being a granny, but before giving anything up
3392	to look after the next generation, I plan to make sure there is a woman
3464	leading this country, a woman leading the US, and the rights of all women are
3542	vindicated.
3563	I owe that much to my prospective granddaughter.
