259	AP sues State Department, seeking access to Clinton records
342	The Associated Press filed a lawsuit Wednesday against the State Department to
421	force the release of email correspondence and government documents from
493	Hillary Rodham Clinton's tenure as secretary of state.
557	The legal action comes after repeated requests filed under the U.S. Freedom of
636	Information Act have gone unfulfilled. They include one request AP made five
713	years ago and others pending since the summer of 2013.
777	The lawsuit, filed in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia,
853	comes a day after Clinton broke her silence about her use of a private email
930	account while secretary of state. The FOIA requests and lawsuit seek materials
1009	related to her public and private calendars, correspondence involving longtime
1088	aides likely to play key roles in her expected campaign for president, and
1163	Clinton-related emails about the Osama bin Laden raid and National Security
1239	Agency surveillance practices.
1279	"After careful deliberation and exhausting our other options, The Associated
1356	Press is taking the necessary legal steps to gain access to these important
1432	documents, which will shed light on actions by the State Department and former
1511	Secretary Clinton, a presumptive 2016 presidential candidate, during some of
1588	the most significant issues of our time," said Karen Kaiser, AP's general
1662	counsel.
1680	Said AP Executive Editor Kathleen Carroll, "The Freedom of Information Act
1755	exists to give citizens a clear view of what government officials are doing on
1834	their behalf. When that view is denied, the next resort is the courts."
1915	State Department spokesman Alec Gerlach declined to comment. He had previously
1994	cited the department's heavy annual load of FOIA requests — 19,000 last year
2071	— in saying that the department "does its best to meet its FOIA
2135	responsibilities." He said the department takes requests "first in, first
2209	out," but noted that timing depends on "the complexity of the request."
2290	Carroll said the AP intends to file additional requests using FOIA and other
2367	tools following the disclosure last week that Clinton used a private email
2442	account run on a server on her property outside New York while working at the
2520	State Department.
2547	Clinton on Tuesday said she sent and received about 60,000 emails from her
2622	personal email address in her four years as President Barack Obama's secretary
2701	of state. She said roughly half were work-related, which she turned over to
2777	the State Department, while deleting tens of thousands more that were personal
2856	in nature.
2876	The department says it will take several months to review the material Clinton
2955	turned over last year. Once the review is complete, the department said, the
3032	emails will be posted online.
3071	The AP had sought Clinton-related correspondence before her use of a personal
3149	email account was publicly known, although Wednesday's court filing alleges
3225	that the State Department is responsible for including emails from that
3297	account in any public records request.
3345	"State's failure to ensure that Secretary Clinton's governmental emails were
3422	retained and preserved by the agency, and its failure timely to seek out and
3499	search those emails in response to AP's requests, indicate at the very least
3576	that State has not engaged in the diligent, good-faith search that FOIA
3648	requires," says AP's legal filing.
3692	Specifically, AP is seeking copies of Clinton's full schedules and calendars
3769	from her four years as secretary of state; documents related to her
3837	department's decision to grant a special position to longtime aide Huma
3909	Abedin; related correspondence from longtime advisers Philippe Reines and
3983	Cheryl Mills, who, like Abedin, are likely to play central roles in a Clinton
4061	presidential campaign; documents related to Clinton's and the agency's roles
4138	in the Osama bin Laden raid and National Security Agency surveillance
4208	practices; and documents related to her role overseeing a major Defense
4280	Department contractor.
4312	The AP made most of its requests in the summer of 2013, although one was filed
4391	in March 2010. AP is also seeking attorney's fees related to the lawsuit.
4474	Other organizations have also sued the State Department recently after lengthy
4553	delays responding to public record requests.
4607	In December, the conservative political advocacy group Citizens United sued
4683	the State Department for failing to disclose flight records showing who
4755	accompanied Clinton on overseas trips. Last week, the National Security
4827	Archive, an organization that gathers declassified government records, filed a
4906	lawsuit after waiting more than seven years for the State Department to
4978	release of details of former secretary of state Henry Kissinger's telephone
5054	conversations.
5078	Thomas Blanton, director of the National Security Archive, predicted the State
5157	Department would speed up its review facing legal action, particularly given
5234	that Clinton has said that her email correspondence doesn't include classified
5313	material.
5332	"When the government is under a court deadline, or really wants to review,
5407	they can whip through thousands of pages in a matter of weeks, which they
5481	should do here," Blanton said.
5521	The State Department generally takes about 450 days to turn over records it
5597	considers to be part of complex requests under the Freedom of Information Act.
5676	That is seven times longer than the Justice Department and CIA, and 30 times
5753	longer than the Treasury Department.
5799	An inspector general's report in 2012 criticized the State Department's
5871	practices as "inefficient and ineffective," citing a heavy workload, small
5946	staff and interagency problems.
