265	Tsarnaev’s Lawyers in Boston Bombing Trial Ask for Change of Venue
355	BOSTON — A three-judge federal appeals panel on Thursday sharply questioned
431	lawyers in the marathon bombing case, challenging assumptions about the
503	ability of prospective jurors to be impartial as the judges weighed whether to
582	move the trial out of Boston.
621	Defense lawyers for Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, who is accused of planting deadly bombs
700	at the 2013 marathon finish line, say that the trial should be moved because
777	the case has affected almost everyone in Eastern Massachusetts and the vast
853	majority of people believe their client is guilty.
913	Sentiment against him is so pervasive, the defense argued, that even the
986	cement mixers at a construction site outside the federal courthouse where the
1064	arguments were heard are plastered with “Boston Strong” — the slogan of
1136	resilience and unity that arose after the bombings, which killed three people
1214	and injured more than 260 others.
1257	Lawyers for Mr. Tsarnaev have tried and failed several times to have the trial
1336	moved, but Thursday’s hearing gave them the opportunity to make oral
1405	arguments on the issue for the first time to three judges on the United States
1484	Court of Appeals for the First Circuit.
1533	Judith H. Mizner, a federal public defender arguing for the defense, said this
1612	was an extraordinary case, saturated with “inflammatory” pretrial
1678	publicity, in which most people in the jury pool had “six degrees of
1747	connections” to the case and might not even be aware of what may affect
1819	their ability to be impartial.
1859	Whether to move the trial, she said, is not a “routine trial management
1931	issue,” as the government has characterized it, but a central tenet “at
2003	the heart of the Sixth Amendment,” which guarantees a defendant a speedy
2076	trial by an impartial jury. (She did not note that the Sixth Amendment also
2152	says the trial must take place in the jurisdiction where the crime occurred.)
2239	Chief Judge Sandra L. Lynch said that Mr. Tsarnaev would suffer no irreparable
2318	harm if the trial stayed in Boston because if he were to be convicted and
2392	appeal that conviction, the question of the location of the trial could be
2467	raised then.
2489	But, Ms. Mizner countered, the main reason to move the trial is to inspire
2564	confidence in the justice system. “Justice has to have the appearance of
2637	justice,” she said.
2666	Mr. Tsarnaev, 21, has pleaded not guilty to the 30 counts against him, 17 of
2743	which carry the death penalty.
2783	The defense team said that questionnaires filled out by more than 1,300
2855	prospective jurors showed that 68 percent were already convinced that Mr.
2929	Tsarnaev was guilty, that 69 percent had a personal connection to the case and
3008	that finding a fair and impartial jury here was proving to be impossible.
3091	But the prosecution argued that the defense had provided a “selective and
3165	misleading” reading of those questionnaires and that, in fact, the trial
3238	judge, George A. O’Toole Jr. of Federal District Court, had identified
3309	several jurors so far who are qualified to sit.
3366	As of Wednesday, over the course of 17 days, Judge O’Toole and lawyers on
3440	both sides had interviewed 219 of the 1,373 prospective jurors. The process
3516	was slowed by detailed discussions with each of them about the defendant’s
3591	possible guilt and their views of the death penalty. In addition, winter
3664	storms have closed the courthouse for several days.
3725	Judge O’Toole has maintained that he can seat an impartial panel of 12
3796	jurors and six alternates. His plan is to create a pool of 70 qualified
3868	jurors, to be whittled down later by both sides through their peremptory
3941	challenges.
3962	So far, the court has found 61 people that it deems qualified, Ms. Mizner said
4041	on Thursday in court. But she said that the interview process was flawed, that
4120	it had not been able to determine whether people were genuinely able to put
4196	aside their prejudices, and that the judge had sometimes “cut off”
4263	questioning by lawyers meant to probe more deeply.
4323	William D. Weinreb, an assistant United States attorney arguing for the
4395	prosecution, said that moving a trial was justified only if a judge had
4467	overstepped his authority, which the defense has not alleged in this case.
4551	Judge Juan R. Torruella, who said in a previous ruling that he found the
4624	defense’s argument compelling, took up much of the prosecution’s allotted
4698	20 minutes with sharp questions to Mr. Weinreb about what qualified a juror as
4777	impartial.
4797	Mr. Weinreb said that the questionnaires cited by the defense were a “blunt
4873	instrument” that might be useful as a starting point in evaluating a
4942	potential juror. But, he said, the interview process had been productive, with
5021	lawyers able to ask follow-up questions and read body language.
5094	“Exposure to pretrial publicity alone does not disqualify a juror,” the
5166	prosecutor said, adding that jurors are legitimately able to form opinions
5241	“purely on evidence presented in the courtroom.”
5299	In addition, he noted, jurors take an oath about their exposure to pretrial
5375	publicity. The interview process has shown that people who have strong
5446	opinions about Mr. Tsarnaev have “unhesitatingly admitted them,” he said,
5520	leading him to conclude that the process is working.
5582	In a brief period for rebuttal, Ms. Mizner, the defense lawyer, said that
5656	personal connections to the case were as much a problem as pretrial publicity.
5744	A juror in Washington, D.C., for example, would not refer to “my best friend
5821	at the finish line,” she said, and would not have a spouse working at a
5893	hospital that treated bombing victims, as prospective jurors here have said
5969	under questioning.
5997	“This is not an appropriate place to try this case,” she concluded.
6074	The appeals court will issue its decision at a later time. After the
6143	arguments, Judge O’Toole resumed his questioning of prospective jurors.
