228	A Brief History Of Somalia's Al-Shabab Terror Group
303	On Thursday, militants of Somalia's al-Shabab terror group launched a deadly
380	assault on a college in eastern Kenya. Masked gunman stormed the grounds of
456	Garissa University College, targeting Christians and taking hostages in scenes
535	reminiscent of the horrific Westgate Mall attack which killed at least 67
609	people in 2013.
634	Thursday's attack comes at a time when al-Shabab is perceived to be losing
709	ground among jihadists. The group is recovering from the death of its leader,
787	Ahmed Abdi Gobani, in a U.S. airstrike last year and is potentially entering a
866	stage in which it seeks to maintain relevance through high-profile violence.
952	Al-Shabab
971	Al-Shabab, which means "the youth" in Arabic, started as a small faction of
1047	radicalized Islamists in Somalia's Islamic Courts Union, an alliance of Sharia
1126	courts. The ICU took over Somalia's government in 2006, but the coalition was
1204	removed from power with help from the United States mere months later.
1275	Al-Shabab splintered off from ICU in the wake of the alliance's demise, and
1351	grew into what the Council on Foreign Relations describes as a "full-blown
1426	insurgency."
1448	The group's well-established legacy of attacks in East Africa includes last
1524	year's assault on Kenya's Westgate Mall, brutal beheadings of suspected spies,
1603	as well as suicide bombings.
1641	Ahmed Abdi Godane
1668	In 2008, new leader Ahmed Abdi Godane rose to the helm of al-Shabab after the
1746	group's former head was killed in an American airstrike.
1812	While The Telegraph once described Godane as "Africa's most feared militant
1888	leader," the little that is known about his personal history may seem at odds
1966	with that description at first sight.
2013	Godane was thought to be around the age of 37 and may have grown up in
2084	northern Somaliland amid difficult circumstances. As The National Post notes,
2162	he had a background in accounting and also managed a grocery store with a
2236	friend, albeit one who he later ordered killed. He was also believed to be a
2313	lover of poetry.
2339	Godane served as al-Shabab's spiritual and political leader from 2008 until
2415	his death in 2014. As a Washington Post profile from last year describes, he
2492	was a prominent force in taking the militant group from a loose network of
2567	hardliners into a relatively cohesive, and notably al-Qaeda-aligned, militant
2645	group. His leadership has been described as both brutal and controversial. The
2724	Post explains:
2748	In areas that the militia controlled, Godane imposed strict Islamic sharia law
2827	enforced by public executions, amputations and stonings. The measures were so
2905	harsh, Hansen [an analyst specializing in al-Shabab] said, that even Osama bin
2984	Laden criticized him for going too far in implementing sharia and for killing
3062	other Muslims.
3086	Under Godane's rule, al-Shabab steadily internationalized its attacks, hitting
3165	targets in Kenya and Uganda. Paul Hidalgo explains in Foreign Affairs that the
3244	group did not only plot against foreign targets but also stepped up its
3316	recruitment drive abroad in an effort to export its ideology.
3387	The End Of Godane
3414	After surviving previous attempts on his life, Godane was ultimately killed in
3493	a U.S. airstrike on Sept. 1, 2014. His death was seen as a major blow to the
3570	organization, and was predicted to have far-reaching implications.
3646	Al-Shabab In 2015
3673	Days after the death of Godane was confirmed, al-Shabab announced it had named
3752	Ahmad Umar its new leader.
3788	Also known as Abu Ubaida, Ahmad Umar is a mysterious figure. He's believed to
3866	have joined the group in 2006 and issued vague threats to al-Shabab's enemies
3944	upon his appointment.
3975	Umar inherited a group whose influence, territory and revenue were in decline.
4063	Analysts described have described al-Shabab as in a state of disarray,
4134	desperate to keep apace with other rising terror groups. In a February 2015
4210	propaganda video, the group issued a lengthy propaganda video that called on
4287	attacks at western malls, shot in a style that mimicked Islamic State produced
4366	videos.
4383	While the decreased power of al-Shabab and death of its leadership were
4455	promising signs, experts also warned that the group could be anxious to
4527	maintain its power through continued violent attacks. As Paul Hidalgo warned
4604	in Foreign Affairs after the death of Godane: "Ahmed Umar will undoubtedly
4679	look to prove the skeptics wrong and unleash a series of attacks against the
4756	government in Mogadishu."
