279	Nigerian President Concedes Election To Opposition Candidate
363	Nigerian President Goodluck Jonathan has called his rival to congratulate him
441	on his victory.
466	The AP reports that opposition presidential candidate Muhammadu Buhari's
539	campaign said Jonathan made the call on Tuesday, after partial election
611	results showed Buhari leading by close to 3 million votes.
679	The AP reports:
704	"An aide in Jonathan's offices says the president is preparing to make a
777	speech. ...
798	"Celebrations have erupted all over Buhari's strongholds in northern Nigeria,
876	but the streets of Abuja, the capital, are deserted amid fears of violence
951	from Jonathan's supporters in the south."
1002	With the partial results, The New York Times also projected Buhari as the
1076	winner.
1093	The only outstanding votes come from the north of the country, the paper
1166	reported, "where Mr. Buhari enjoys broad support and the government has been
1243	widely condemned for allowing the Boko Haram militant group to sweep through
1320	villages and towns, killing thousands of civilians."
1382	As we reported, voting in the presidential contest took place amid continued
1459	violence. Over the weekend, Boko Haram militants opened fire on voters in two
1537	locations, leaving six dead.
1575	As the BBC reports, a sitting president has never lost an election in Nigeria,
1654	Africa's most populous country and one of the world's biggest democracies.
1738	The big issue in the country, of course, has been Jonathan's inability to
1812	control Boko Haram's Islamist insurrection in the north of the country.
1884	Buhari, a former general who ruled the country for a couple of years following
1963	a coup, campaigned on getting tough on corruption.
2023	As for the election results, the BBC's Abuja correspondent sounded a note of
2100	caution:
2118	"There are long faces in the PDP camp. It looks like Muhammadu Buhari's lead
2195	may well prove too wide to be bridged.
2243	"But this is Nigeria and predictions are dangerous. The biggest surprise would
2322	be if the result is not disputed by the losing side.
2384	"During the vote, the card readers experienced some technical glitches, but
2460	they could prove to be decisive in ensuring the numbers could not be cooked
2536	and the views of Nigerians could not be ignored."
