236	Iran Calls on Hezbollah to Kill Netanyahu's Sons
308	The sons of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu have been targeted for
385	assassination by Iran.
417	Photos of the two young men, viewed through sniper scopes with crosshairs
491	superimposed on them, were published on the Iranian news website Mashregh,
566	affiliated with the militant Revolutionary Guard Corps, with the warning, "We
644	must await the hunt of Hezbollah," The Free Beacon reports.
713	Netanyahu's sons, Avner and Yair, were chosen as assassination targets, the
789	website states, because of their affiliation with top Israeli leaders.
869	Iran's state-controlled Fars News Agency also ran the article and the photos.
956	The article, entitled, "The File of the Zionist Children," states, "It is
1030	worth mentioning that these excellences of Zionism were not directly involved
1108	in the war against the forces of resistance and they have not taken up arms,
1185	and some by account of their own words are against Zionist radicalism,” the
1261	Free Beacon reported.
1292	“However, they have three years of mandatory service in the army of this
1365	regime in their records."
1400	Latest News Update
1428	The threat is believed to have been issued in retaliation for a Jan. 18
1500	airstrike in the Golan Heights in Syria which killed prominent Hezbollah
1573	figures, including Jihad Mughniyeh, son of the late Hezbollah military
1644	commander Imad Mughniyeh, and an Iranian general, Mohammed Ali Allahdadi,
1718	Israel Hayom reported.
1750	Along with Netanyahu's sons, the article also called for the assassination of
1828	Gilad and Omri Sharon, sons of former Israeli Prime Minister Ariel Sharon, and
1907	Shaul Olmert, son of former Prime Minister Ehud Olmert, JNS reported.
1986	Behnam Ben Taleblu, an Iran expert at the Foundation for Defense of
2054	Democracies (FDD) told the Free Beacon, "All the outpouring and statements by
2132	Iran’s political and military elite is meant to establish the deterrent
2204	power of the Islamic Republic. Such power is designed to instill the fear of
2281	reprisal, without having to bear the costs of engaging in one.
2353	"Mashregh News has chosen to explicitly demonstrate that deterrent power in a
2431	sickening retaliatory fashion, weighing the perceived benefits of some of the
2509	assassinations from the perspective of the ‘resistance.'
2575	"In a not-so-subtle manner, the article attempts to force a linkage between
2651	the reported 'mandatory military service' of the children and becoming a
2724	target.
2741	"The question now becomes, will Hezbollah or Iran choose to escalate from this
2820	appalling form of psychological warfare?"
2871	Netanyahu recently blamed Iran for an attack on the Israel/Lebanon border
2945	which killed two Israeli soldiers and wounded seven, Fox News reported.
3026	"This is the same Iran that is now trying to achieve an agreement, via the
3101	major powers, that would leave it with the ability to develop nuclear weapons,
3180	and we strongly oppose this agreement," Netanyahu said.
3245	"We will continue to defend ourselves against all threats, near and far
3317	alike," he said.
