198	CFR Backgrounders: Al-Shabab
250	Introduction
272	Al-Shabab, or “the Youth,” is an al-Qaeda-linked militant group and
340	U.S.-designated Foreign Terrorist Organization fighting for the creation of a
418	fundamentalist Islamic state in Somalia. The group, also known as Harakat
492	al-Shabab al-Mujahideen, and its Islamist affiliates once held sway over
565	Mogadishu and major portions of the Somali countryside, but a sustained
637	African Union military campaign in recent years has weakened the group
708	considerably. Still, security analysts warn that the group remains the
779	principal threat in a politically volatile, war-torn state.
848	Al-Shabab's terrorist activities have mainly focused on targets within
919	Somalia, but it has also carried out deadly strikes in the region, including
996	coordinated suicide bombings in Uganda's capital in 2010 and a raid on a
1069	Nairobi mall in 2013 (PDF). Washington fears the group, which has successfully
1148	recruited members of the Somali diaspora in the United States, may strike on
1225	U.S. soil. However, many terrorism experts say al-Shabab's reach is limited to
1304	East Africa.
1326	What are the origins of al-Shabab?
1370	Somalia, one of the most impoverished countries in the world, has seen a
1443	number of radical Islamist groups come and go in its decades-long political
1519	upheaval. Analysts say the forerunner of al-Shabab, and the incubator for many
1598	of its leaders, was Al-Ittihad Al-Islami (AIAI, or “Unity of Islam”), a
1670	militant Salafi group that peaked in the 1990s after the fall of the Siad
1744	Barre military regime (1969–1991) and the outbreak of civil war.
1818	Washington fears the group, which has successfully recruited members of the
1894	Somali diaspora in the United States, may strike on U.S. soil.
1966	AIAI, which sought to establish an Islamist emirate in Somalia, sprang from a
2044	band of Middle Eastern-educated Somali extremists and was partly funded and
2120	armed by al-Qaeda chief Osama bin Laden. Many of its fighters, including
2193	current al-Shabab commanders, fled the country and fought in Afghanistan in
2269	the late 1990s after being pushed out by the Ethiopian army and its Somali
2344	supporters. The U.S. State Department designated the group a terrorist
2415	organization in the days after the 9/11 attacks.
2473	In 2003, a rift developed between AIAI's more moderate old guard, which had
2549	decided to create a new political front, and younger members who sought the
2625	establishment of a “Greater Somalia” under fundamental Islamic rule. The
2698	hardliners eventually joined forces with an alliance of sharia courts, known
2775	as the Islamic Courts Union (ICU), serving as its youth militia. Al-Shabab and
2854	the ICU wrested control of the capital in June 2006, a victory that stoked
2929	fears of spillover jihadist violence in neighboring Ethiopia, a majority
3002	Christian nation.
3029	What were the turning points for al-Shabab?
3082	Ethiopia invaded Somalia in December 2006 and ousted the ICU from Mogadishu
3158	with little resistance. The intervention, which came at the request of
3229	Somalia's transitional government (which was set up in 2004), had a
3297	radicalizing effect on al-Shabab, analysts say. After much of the ICU fled to
3375	neighboring countries, al-Shabab remained and retreated to the south, where it
3454	began organizing guerilla assaults, including bombings and assassinations, on
3532	Ethiopian forces. Some experts say it was during these years that the group
3608	morphed into a full-fledged guerilla movement and gained control over large
3684	pieces of territory in central and southern Somalia.
3746	The Ethiopian occupation (PDF) was responsible for “transforming the group
3821	from a small, relatively unimportant part of a more moderate Islamic movement
3899	into the most powerful and radical armed faction in the country,” writes Rob
3976	Wise, a counterterrorism expert at the Center for Strategic and International
4054	Studies.
4072	Addis Ababa says the intervention was a “reluctant response“ to calls by
4145	the ICU for jihad against Ethiopia and renewed territorial claims against both
4224	Ethiopia and Kenya. It has stressed that the intervention was supported by the
4303	United States and the African Union, among others.
4363	New Islamist-nationalist fighters swelled al-Shabab's ranks from around four
4440	hundred into the thousands between 2006 and 2008. This was also a period when
4518	the group's ties to al-Qaeda began to emerge. Al-Shabab leaders publicly
4591	praised the international terrorist network and condemned what they
4659	characterized as U.S. crimes against Muslims worldwide. The State Department
4736	designated al-Shabab a foreign terrorist organization in February 2008. Two
4812	years later, the group vowed to “connect the horn of Africa jihad to the one
4889	led by al-Qaeda and its leader Sheikh Osama bin Laden.” However, it was not
4965	until February 2012 that al-Shabab's leadership formally declared allegiance
5042	to al-Qaeda.
5064	In June 2010, al-Shabab seemed to make good on its promises of jihad with
5138	coordinated suicide bombings that killed seventy-four people who had gathered
5216	to watch the World Cup in the Ugandan capital of Kampala. It was the group's
5293	first terrorist attack outside of Somalia. “We are sending a message to
5365	every country who is willing to send troops to Somalia that they will face
5440	attacks on their territory,” said a spokesman at the time.
5508	Uganda was the first nation to send forces into Somalia in March 2007 under
5584	the African Union Mission in Somalia (AMISOM), which was charged with
5654	defending the transitional government. In late 2014, Kampala maintained the
5730	largest contingent in the UN-backed force with 6,220 personnel. Other AMISOM
5807	troops come from Burundi (5,338), Ethiopia (4,395), Kenya (3,664) Djibouti
5882	(1,000), and Sierra Leone (800).
5924	What are al-Shabab's objectives?
5966	Many analysts say the group is not monolithic and its objectives vary. Writing
6045	in 2012, former CFR fellow and Africa expert Bronwyn E. Bruton described some
6123	of the cleavages that divide al-Shabab's leadership, including competing clan
6201	loyalties and rifts between the group's nationalists intent on ousting AMISOM
6279	and the central government, and Gulf-sponsored radicals with transnational
6354	terror aims.
6376	The group continues to threaten neighboring countries as well as Western
6449	interests in Africa. In January 2013, Ethiopian authorities arrested more than
6528	a dozen al-Shabab-linked militants allegedly plotting attacks in eastern
6601	Ethiopia. And in September of that year, al-Shabab fighters claimed
6669	responsibility for a raid on a Nairobi mall, holding hostages for days and
6744	killing dozens. It was the deadliest terrorist attack in Kenya since
6813	al-Qaeda's East Africa affiliate bombed the U.S. Embassy in Nairobi in 1998
6889	(224 people were killed  in that attack). Al-Shabab attacks in Kenya escalated
6968	in 2014, with 173 people killed in Kenya, according to its police force.
7050	In areas it controls, al-Shabab enforces its own harsh interpretation of
7123	sharia, prohibiting various types of entertainment, such as movies and music,
7201	the sale of khat (a narcotic plant often chewed), smoking, the shaving of
7275	beards, and many other “un-Islamic” activities. Stonings and amputations
7348	have been meted out as punishment on suspected adulterers and thieves.
7419	International rights groups have reported that al-Shabab members have
7489	kidnapped young boys from schools and have forced them to fight for the group.
7577	Who are the group's leaders?
7615	Sheikh Hassan Dahir Aweys, who fought against Ethiopia as a colonel in the
7690	Siad Biarre regime in the 1970s, is reportedly al-Shabab's spiritual leader.
7767	He commanded the military arm of the AIAI, and then took over leadership of
7843	the ICU. In 2006, Aweys handed operational command of al-Shabab to a young
7918	Somali jihadi, Aden Hashi Ayro, who was killed in a U.S. missile strike in May
7997	2008.
8012	Ahmed Abdi Godane (aka Abu Zubayr), one of al-Shabab's founders, served as the
8091	group's top commander after Ayro's death. He was designated a global terrorist
8170	by the United States in November 2008.
8218	In June 2013, Godane loyalists reportedly killed two senior al-Shabab leaders,
8297	Ibrahim al-Afghani and Moalim Burhan, in a shoot-out that analysts attribute
8374	to internal dissension. Prior to his death, al-Afghani reportedly penned a
8449	letter to al-Qaeda chief Ayman al-Zawahiri condemning Godane's harsh
8518	leadership style. That same month, Aweys, al-Shabab's elder statesman,
8589	surrendered to federal authorities in Mogadishu after his relationship with
8665	Godane soured.
8689	In September 2014, the U.S. military confirmed it killed Godane in a targeted
8767	air strike on an al-Shabab encampment in Somalia. The White House stated that
8845	the successful counterterrorism operation marked “a major symbolic and
8916	operational loss to the largest al-Qaida affiliate in Africa.” Some
8984	terrorism experts believe the removal of al-Shabab's powerful, charismatic
9059	leader will prompt a power struggle within the militant group.
9131	Ahmed Umar, also known as Abu Ubaidah, is the current leader of al-Shabab.
9206	Experts say he lacks the charisma and strategic intelligence of his
9274	predecessor and is unlikely to maintain control of the fractious group.
9346	Al-Shabab's former intelligence chief surrendered in late 2014, and the
9418	militants continued to lose battles against African Union forces in 2015.
9501	How is al-Shabab funded?
9535	Counterterrorism experts say al-Shabab has benefited from several different
9611	sources of income over the years, including revenue from other terrorist
9684	groups, state sponsors, the Somali diaspora, charities, piracy, kidnapping,
9760	and the extortion of local businesses. The governments of Eritrea, Iran, Saudi
9839	Arabia, Syria, Qatar, and Yemen have been cited as financiers—although most
9915	officially deny these claims.
9954	Domestically, the group built up an extensive racketeering operation in
10026	Kismayo after seizing control of the southern port city and its economy in
10101	2008. The trade of charcoal, in particular, is essential to the city's
10172	commerce. However, a Kenya-led assault on Kismayo liberated the port of
10244	al-Shabab forces in October 2012—a victory that many experts say
10309	strategically crippled the jihadi group.
10359	However, an October 2014 UN Security Council report (PDF) says al-Shabab's
10434	illicit charcoal trading hasn't been interrupted by “the military offensive
10510	against the group” and continues in Kismayo and nearby Barawe. Charcoal
10582	exports are a component of a trade that includes al-Shabab's importation of
10658	sugar, much of which then makes its way into Kenya illegally. Roughly ten
10732	thousand bags of contraband sugar worth hundreds of thousands of dollars may
10809	be smuggled into Kenya every day, according to the UN. In April 2013, Kenyan
10886	officials complained that al-Shabab operatives were attempting to infiltrate
10963	the country's sugar trade.
10999	What areas does al-Shabab control?
11043	Despite strategic setbacks inflicted by AMISOM forces over the past several
11119	years, including the loss of the Barawe in October 2014, al-Shabab remains in
11197	control of most of southern and central Somalia. The U.S. State Department's
11274	2013 terrorism report estimates the group has several thousand members.
11346	Analysts say the group's resilience is likely the result of significant
11418	support from local clans and the perception among elders that it remains a
11493	plausible alternative to corrupt institutions in Mogadishu.
11562	Does al-Shabab recruit U.S. nationals?
11610	Al-Shabab has recruited members of the Somali-American diaspora in recent
11684	years, a trend the FBI has described as a top domestic terrorist threat. In
11760	particular, the group has attracted several volunteers from Minneapolis, MN,
11837	which is home to the largest Somali population in the country. Shirwa Ahmed
11913	and Farah Mohamad Beledi, the first two confirmed U.S. suicide bombers, both
11990	traveled from Minnesota, where they had grown up, to Somalia to receive
12062	al-Shabab training and wage jihad.
12106	Another prominent leader for al-Shabab was Omar Hammami (aka Abu Mansoor
12179	Al-Amriki), a native of Alabama, authorities say. However, Hammami reportedly
12257	fell out with the group and was killed in a firefight with al-Shabab militants
12336	in September 2013. Other Somali-American recruits have come from California,
12413	New Jersey, New York, Ohio, and Virginia, according to a list compiled by the
12491	Anti-Defamation League.
12524	What is U.S. policy in Somalia?
12565	Washington's primary interest in Somalia has been preventing it from becoming
12643	a refuge for terrorist groups like al-Shabab to plot attacks on the United
12718	States and potentially destabilize the strategically significant Horn of
12791	Africa, where longstanding disputes among  Eritrea, Ethiopia, and Somalia
12865	still fester. In recent years, U.S. officials have also been wary of
12934	collaboration between the militant Islamist organizations in the region,
13007	including al-Shabab, Boko Haram, al-Qaeda in the Islamic Maghreb, and al-Qaeda
13086	in the Arabian Peninsula.
13121	The United States, stung by the loss of eighteen U.S. servicemen in the Battle
13200	of Mogadishu in 1993 (aka the “Black Hawk Down” incident), has largely
13271	relied on the use of proxy forces in Somalia in recent years. Since 2007,
13345	analysts say Washington has provided more than half a billion dollars to train
13424	and equip African Union forces battling al-Shabab. Much of this indirect
13497	logistical support has been supplied on the ground by State Department-funded
13575	contractors, such as Bancroft Global Development and DynCorp.
13646	Drone strikes and special operations raids on al-Shabab and al-Qaeda targets
13723	have rounded out the U.S. strategy. Military analysts have characterized the
13800	Pentagon's approach in Somalia as “offshore balancing,” which emphasizes
13873	the use of U.S. air and sea assets in conjunction with support for local
13946	counterinsurgency forces, such as AMISOM.
13997	In January 2013, the United States formally recognized the Somali government
14074	after a hiatus of more than twenty years, and two years later President Barack
14153	Obama nominated Katherine Dhanani to be the first U.S. ambassador to Somalia
14230	since 1991. And while the U.S. has no embassy in Mogadishu (the U.S. mission
14307	to Somalia is based in the U.S. embassy in Nairobi), officials say Washington
14385	is likely to expand its diplomatic presence.
