250	Experts Say al-Shabab-Islamic State Linkup 'Unlikely'
327	Boko Haram's loyalty pledge to the Islamic State group has raised fears of
402	further Islamic State alliances in sub-Saharan Africa. Terrorism experts
475	however, say the continent's most powerful extremist force, Somalia's
545	al-Shabab, is unlikely to go down the same path.
603	Al-Shabab has deep ties to al-Qaida -- the Islamic State group's main rival --
682	going back to the 1990's, when the terrorist network trained some of
751	al-Shabab's most prominent leaders at camps in Afghanistan and Pakistan.
833	So far, there has been no direct contact between the leaders of al-Shabab and
911	the militant group, at least publicly. Observers believe supporters of the two
990	organizations are talking. Last week, a new video released by al-Shabab's
1064	media wing was first posted on an Islamic State-only file sharing site.
1145	Still, this is not firm evidence of collaboration. Experts like Abdiaziz Alas
1223	Artan, a Cairo-based scholar of militant organizations, have trouble
1292	envisioning an alliance between the groups.
1345	“At this time it’s not easy for Al-Shabab to join ISIS," Artan said.
1414	"First, al-Shabab has given allegiance to al-Qaida, the parent organization,
1491	and to throw that away will be difficult.
1542	"Secondly, al-Shabab feels it’s the older organization, the more senior one
1618	that has the priority, and if anyone has to move, [Islamic State] has to ...
1695	for them to downgrade and to join a group that, not just emerged just
1765	yesterday, but one that also disobeyed al-Qaida central, is going to be
1837	difficult.”
1858	In 2012, al-Shabab merged with al-Qaida. Somalia expert Roland Marchal of the
1936	National Center for Scientific Research in Paris said al-Shabab has forged
2011	deep links not only with al-Qaida central, but also to its powerful
2079	Yemen-based affiliate, al-Qaida in the Arabian Peninsula.
2146	“The linkage between the two has become more systemic or certainly deeper
2220	than it was any time before," Marchal said. "And it’s not only an issue of
2295	ideology or personal relations, it’s something that goes much deeper into
2369	the organization of both groups.”
2412	But at least one prominent al-Shabab supporter is pushing for a switch in
2486	alliances. In an audio message posted online this week, Kenyan cleric Sheikh
2563	Hassan Hussein, also known as "Abu Salman," said there are no religious
2635	grounds for opposing the leader of Islamic State.
2694	Salman hinted there is reluctance within al-Shabab to leave al-Qaida. "Those
2771	jihadists who want to recognize Mullah Omar as Amirul Mi'miniin (the Emir of
2848	Muslims) are avoiding recognizing Abu Bakr Al-Baghdadi instead," he said.
2931	The rise of the Islamic State group has lured militant organizations at a time
3010	when al-Qaida leaders are severely crippled by U.S. intelligence operations. 
3088	The group has attracted thousands of jihadists from around the world,
3158	including many from the Middle East, Europe and North America.
3230	In the lower militancy ranks, it’s becoming clearer that young fighters are
3306	excited by successes of the Islamic State group. Marchal said even though the
3384	al-Shabab leadership has affinity with al-Qaida, some members see Islamic
3458	State militants as more practical than al-Qaida.
3516	"They said what is nice with ISIS is the fact whatever area they take under
3592	control they try to build something, they try at least to build the first
3666	steps of an Islamic state, while with al-Qaida, we will be fighting for one
3742	century before we defeat all our enemies," said Marchal.
3808	"So for what I have been told, many in the military section of al-Shabab are
3885	keener towards ISIS while the Amniyat [the security force] and the political
3962	leadership is much closer to al-Qaida.”
4011	Unlike al-Shabab, Boko Haram was free of any allegiance before committing to
4088	the Islamic State group -- an important difference, experts said.
4163	Whatever decision al-Shabab takes will be a strategic one, not ideological,
4239	analysts argue. They say that's because al-Qaida and the Islamic State group
4316	come from the same side of the militancy spectrum -- both are violent
4386	extremist groups that want to set up a caliphate and impose a strict form of
4463	sharia.
4480	“The ideology is similar, the jihadi ideology is similar," Artan said. "The
4556	only difference is [Islamic State's] rise was driven by anti-Shi'ite
4625	[ideology] while the rest of al-Qaida is anti-West driven.”
4694	Then there is the issue of opportunism. Some observers believe Boko Haram may
4772	have taken the step to join the militants of the Islamic State because, in
4847	part, it saw an chance to increase recruitment and fundraising for their
4920	organization.
4943	One politician in Somalia -- former defense minister Abdihakim Haji Mohamud
5019	Fiqi -- thinks al-Shabab also may turn opportunistic after military setbacks
5096	at the hands of the African Union mission in Somalia [AMISOM] and the Somali
5173	government.
5194	"In my opinion it’s really possible," said Fiqi, "because al-Shabab is
5265	desperate ... they have no hope today that they can win this terrorism war,
5341	they can do anything they can to get support, such as [team up] with IS or
5416	Boko Haram, so it’s possible."
5456	Al-Shabab has lost most of its territory to AMISOM and many of its leaders to
5534	U.S. drone strikes over the past four years. One such strike killed the
5606	group's emir, Ahmed Godane, in September 2014.
5662	Another strike earlier this this month killed Adan Ahmed Isak, better known as
5741	Adan Garaar, who allegedly played a role in planning the deadly 2013 attack on
5820	Nairobi's Westgate shopping mall.
5863	Fiqi added, however, that he does not believe al-Shabab can get tangible help
5941	by switching its alliance.
5977	"We know the situation of ISIS. There are many nations that are in alliance
6053	against ISIS, and there is no hope they can support al-Shabab economically or
6131	militarily," he said.
6162	But even with the Islamic State group on the defensive, it still has secured
6239	alliances elsewhere in Africa, from Egypt to Libya, and now Nigeria.
