257	Hillary Clinton's Crystal Ball
311	Even while Hard Choices was still wafting its way across the Atlantic Ocean—
388	and long before it landed on my desk in central Europe, an entire twenty-four
466	hours after the official publication date—Hillary Clinton’s account of her
541	State Department years had already led several news cycles, inspired thousands
620	of megabytes of commentary, and left its subsequent reviewers with serious
695	literary and philosophical dilemmas.
741	Normally, the process of writing a book review begins after the reviewer has
818	read the book in question. The process of “reading” Hard Choices, by
887	contrast, begins not with the physical or even the electronic book, but rather
966	with the advance “leaks” in Politico, and the Fox News reports about the
1039	advance “leaks” in Politico, and The Wire’s report on the Fox News
1106	reporting on the advance “leaks” in Politico. To understand this book, one
1181	must be aware also of the Diane Sawyer interview with Hillary Clinton, and the
1260	Twitter rage about the Diane Sawyer interview with Hillary Clinton, and the
1336	Slate analysis of the Twitter rage about the Diane Sawyer interview with
1409	Hillary Clinton. And then there is the NPR interview, and so on.
1483	For this reason, Hard Choices presents the reviewer with an existential
1555	problem: is it actually a book? Is it even intended to be a thing that people
1633	sit down and read, cover to cover? Or is it rather a collection of carefully
1710	crafted messages, each designed to reach a particular person, or to deflect a
1788	particular criticism, or to inspire a certain kind of remark? When my husband,
1867	who happens to be the foreign minister of Poland, saw the book on my desk, he
1945	picked it up, flipped to the index, and checked to see if he is mentioned. (He
2024	is.) I have absolutely no doubt that over the past several weeks that same
2099	action was performed by dozens of people in dozens of capitals around the
2173	world.
2189	Of course Clinton and her team anticipated, and helped to arrange, the media
2266	frenzy, and they knew that many would read the index before the book. Each
2341	description therefore reads as if it had been vetted for that purpose. In Hard
2420	Choices, almost all of Clinton’s colleagues are admirable people who are a
2495	“living embodiment of the American Dream,” or a “terrific
2553	communicator” who works hard while always remaining decent, passionate, and
2629	unstoppable. If they are slightly difficult colleagues, they might be a
2701	“creative thinker” (Rahm Emanuel) or have a “bulldozer style” (Richard
2772	Holbrooke) with which the secretary nevertheless learned cheerfully to live.
2858	Her foreign partners are much the same. In general they are “consummate
2930	professionals” and “enjoyable company.” A few, such as ex–French
2995	President Sarkozy, can even be “fun.” And even with more challenging
3064	interlocutors, such as the Chinese official Dai Bingguo, Clinton usually
3137	manages to speak “deeply and personally about the need to put the U.
3206	S.-China relationship on a sound footing for the sake of future
3270	generations.” Do not read Hard Choices if you seek a nuanced analysis of the
3347	people who run the world’s foreign policy, let alone any juicy gossip. Even
3423	the “candid” photos look staged: Hillary, Bill, and Bono sitting at a
3493	piano, for example.
3522	Yet even if we accept that Hard Choices really is a book—it has a binding,
3597	after all, and has been produced by a printing press under the auspices of a
3674	publishing house—it isn’t that easy to say to which genre it belongs. It
3747	clearly is not a work of history: the book is constructed according to
3818	geography rather than chronology, and although Clinton does give accounts of
3895	her more important policy decisions, she refrains from setting them in any
3970	particular domestic or global context. Each one is told as a separate story,
4047	and most of the stories have happy endings, even if in real life they
4117	didn’t.
4134	Clinton’s chapter on Europe, for example, begins with the deterioration of
4209	the transatlantic alliance under George W. Bush, explains how she fixed the
4285	problem by renewing relationships with “invaluable” partners, and ends
4356	with a visit to Belfast where an “old friend” is now the lord mayor of
4427	Armagh. This latter event gives Clinton a moral for her Europe story: she
4501	hopes that children growing up now in Northern Ireland will “never turn back
4578	and that their peace and progress would be an inspiration for the rest of
4652	Europe and the world.” A scant, bland paragraph or two are devoted to the
4726	European economic crisis, which was by far the most important issue at the
4801	time. There is no mention of the European Union’s longstanding failure to
4875	come up with a coherent foreign policy, no sense that anything at all is wrong
4954	with an institution which has made “many contributions to peace and
5022	prosperity within and beyond its borders.”
5074	Clinton’s chapter on Burma is similarly glossy. It begins with a description
5151	of Aung San Suu Kyi—“frail, but with unmistakable inner strength”—and
5221	ends with Burma on the road to democracy, a story that she calls a “high
5294	point” of her term in office and “an affirmation of the unique role the
5366	United States can and should play in the world as a champion of dignity and
5442	democracy.” There is no hint that the Burmese army was just then beginning
5517	its vicious war against the Karen insurgency, that a brutal conflict between
5594	Buddhists and Muslims was already growing worse, or that Suu Kyi’s prestige
5670	was starting to plummet as she failed to exert any influence to stop either
5746	one of those outrages. Even Clinton’s portrayal of Haiti, where she and her
5822	husband have a long involvement, fails to note that their plan to “Build
5895	Back Better” after Haiti’s earthquake in 2010 is now widely perceived to
5968	have failed.
5990	On topics that she knew would be examined more exhaustively, Clinton is more
6067	careful to avoid overly sunny conclusions. Her account of her attempt to
6140	“reset” relations with Russia was clearly rewritten just before
6204	publication in order to include recent events in Ukraine. Here she draws what
6282	positive stories she can—there was some cooperation with Russia in central
6357	Asia, for example—but makes clear that she had low expectations for the
6429	Russian-American relationship from the beginning. As she left office in 2013,
6507	she advised the president that “difficult days lay ahead and that our
6577	relationship with Moscow would likely get worse before it got better.”
6648	Still, even this more realistic version of events is unsatisfying, for Clinton
6727	never digs very deeply. She offers no real analysis of Vladimir Putin’s
6799	motives, and never goes into the complex history of the Russian-American
6872	relationship. She acknowledges that Russia does present a very difficult
6945	problem: “Hard men present hard choices—none more so than Vladimir Putin,
7019	the President of Russia.” But she doesn’t tell us on what basis she or
7090	anyone else will solve it.
7126	For similar reasons, Hard Choices also cannot be called a work of political
7202	philosophy or political science. There is no overall argument in the book, no
7280	marshaling of evidence to make a particular case or to set forward a
7349	particular strategy or thesis. This is not an argument for “realism” or
7421	“idealism.” It is not an analysis of America’s priorities. There are
7490	admirable nods to human rights, a discussion of climate change, and some
7563	intelligent observations about diplomacy in the Internet age. But Clinton does
7642	not connect the dots into a larger view, clearly because does not see the need
7721	to. Early on, she does dismiss the “outdated” debate between “hard
7788	power”—military force—and the “soft power” of other kinds of
7849	influence. She prefers “smart power,” which she defines as “choosing the
7922	right combination of tools—diplomatic, economic, military, political, legal,
7999	and cultural” in order to advance “our core national security
8061	objectives.” Yet that is an argument about process, not about policy; about
8137	the means, not the ends. Most of the time Clinton prudently stays away from
8213	thorny debates about just what those core national interests should be.
8294	And although the words “a memoir” appear in tiny print on the cover, this
8368	is also not an autobiography, at least in the classic sense of the term. It
8444	actively avoids any language that might be construed as “literary,” or any
8519	psychological insights of any kind. By her own account Clinton never gets
8593	angry, although occasionally she admits that she is “exasperated.” She
8664	doesn’t get tired very often either—or if she does, she doesn’t
8728	complain: “I drank copious cups of coffee and tea, and sometimes dug the
8801	fingernails of one hand into the palm of the other.”
8863	Instead, her personal triumphs and tragedies, like her diplomatic triumphs and
8942	tragedies, are always converted into stories and more stories, usually with
9018	moral lessons for herself, for the reader, for the nation. Her mother’s
9090	death reminds her that you must “never rest on your laurels. Never quit.
9163	Never stop working to make the world a better place.” Chelsea’s wedding
9235	makes her think of her daughter’s “dreams and ambitions”: “This, I
9302	thought, is why Bill and I had worked so hard for so many years to help build
9380	a better world—so Chelsea could grow up safe and happy and one day have a
9454	family of her own, and so every other child would have the same chance.” The
9531	news of Chelsea’s pregnancy makes her recall “what Margaret Mead said,
9602	that children keep our imaginations fresh and our hearts young, and drive us
9679	to work for a better future.”
9718	Clinton carefully puts to rest any hint of conflict between herself and her
9794	husband, or herself and President Obama. Instead she includes a scene of
9867	herself sitting in East Timor, watching ex-President Clinton nominate
9937	President Obama for the second time: “Watching from some ten thousand miles
10013	away, I was full of pride for the former President I married, the current
10087	president I served, and the country we all loved.”
10147	Of course Hard Choices could be shelved alongside the memoirs of other
10218	statesmen— Henry Kissinger, say, or Margaret Thatcher. But those books,
10290	while also painting the world in colors designed to flatter the author, are
10366	generally composed by people who did not anticipate a further career in public
10445	life. Clinton’s book, by contrast, does not seek merely to establish the
10518	author’s place in the nation’s past; it is designed also to establish her
10592	place in the nation’s future. This is clear to the reader from the cultural
10668	context—from Diane Sawyer and NPR and Fox—but also from the volume’s
10737	enigmatic conclusion. After 593 pages of writing about foreign policy, Clinton
10816	suddenly shifts gear. “Our strength abroad depends on our resolve and
10886	resilience at home,” she declares in her epilogue. “Citizens and leaders
10959	alike have choices to make about the country we want to live in and leave to
11036	the next generation. ... We need more good jobs that reward hard work with
11111	rising wages, dignity, and a ladder to a better life.”
11175	We know why she has made this gear shift—and she knows that we know. But she
11252	tells us anyway: “Over the past year, as I’ve traveled around the country
11326	once again, the one question I’m asked more than any other is: Will I run
11400	for President in 2016?” And the answer? “I haven’t decided yet.” She
11469	explains:
11488	Whatever I decide, I will always be thankful for the chance to represent
11561	America around the world. I have learned anew the goodness of our people and
11638	the greatness of our nation. I feel blessed and grateful. Our future is so
11713	full of possibility. And for me and my family that includes looking forward to
11792	a new addition— another American who deserves the best possible future we
11866	can offer. ... There have been too few quiet moments like this over the years.
11945	And I want to savor them. The time for another hard choice will come soon
12019	enough.
12036	And thus, having spent 595 pages eschewing anything that might look remotely
12113	like a literary device, Clinton finally resorts to the oldest one of all: the
12191	cliffhanger.
12213	In the end Hard Choices is not history, and not political philosophy, and not
12291	auto-biography. It belongs to an altogether narrower genre. Like Mitt
12361	Romney’s No Apology: The Case for American Greatness, Barack Obama’s The
12434	Audacity of Hope: Thoughts on Reclaiming the American Dream, Newt Gingrich’s
12511	A Nation Like No Other: Why American Exceptionalism Matters, and John
12581	Kerry’s A Call to Service: My Vision for a Better America, Hard Choices is,
12657	quite simply, one of those books that people write when they are running for
12734	president. Since it calls itself a “memoir,” and focuses on her four years
12809	as secretary of state, and since it does not have the word “America” in
12881	the title, Clinton’s version is a little different from the others. But
12953	really there can be no doubt that this is a campaign book in an
13017	autobiographical and statesmanlike disguise.
13071	I am not sure when it became de rigueur for presidential candidates to publish
13150	a work between hard covers, but nobody now runs for high office without having
13229	written, or having arranged for the ghostwriting of, a very large book. The
13305	advantages are obvious. Such books provide some vignettes for voters to chew
13382	over, and some pre-approved quotes for the press. They offer a narrative about
13461	the candidate that is entirely of the candidate’s own construction, a story
13537	that Hillary or Mitt or Barack can control from start to finish. Above all,
13613	the publication of a book, if judiciously planned, can provide an excuse for
13690	interviews, a book tour, and quite a lot of highbrow media, and all of this
13766	many months or even years before the candidate begins the tedious process of
13843	running an actual campaign. If the candidate proves really adept at the
13915	writing/ghostwriting/marketing of the thing, he or she can even make some
13989	money.
14005	But once the reviewer understands that Hard Choices belongs to this genre,
14080	then its positive attributes become much clearer. If you leaf through this
14155	book, as I initially did, looking for insight into particular people or
14227	events, you will be disappointed. If you look for a grand strategy, you will
14304	be similarly let down. But if instead you peruse the book in search of clues
14381	as to how candidate Clinton is going to portray herself over the next two
14455	years, then it becomes somewhat interesting, even downright useful.
14532	It is impossible not to notice, for example, that throughout the book Clinton
14610	emphasizes very particular personality traits. She returns again and again to
14688	the ethic of service that her parents bequeathed to her. At one point she
14762	speaks of her “ ‘service gene,’ that voice telling me there is no higher
14835	calling or more noble purpose than serving your country.” Clinton also hints
14912	at personal sacrifices: “When I chose to leave a career as a young lawyer in
14989	Washington to move to Arkansas to marry Bill and start a family, my friends
15065	asked, ‘Are you out of your mind?’ I heard similar questions when I took
15138	on health care reform as First Lady, ran for office myself, and accepted
15211	President Barack Obama’s offer to represent our country as Secretary of
15283	State.”
15300	That is a clear message: Clinton is not enjoying all of this, and she is not
15377	going to pretend otherwise. She didn’t move to Arkansas or tackle health
15450	care reform or become secretary of state because those were pleasurable things
15529	to do. She was not seeking personal gratification—on the contrary. Unlike
15603	some of the men who have been or will be her competitors, she is not motivated
15682	by narcissism, arrogance, and egotism. She is animated entirely by her
15753	“service gene.”
15778	And also by her work ethic. She lets us know that she travels doggedly and
15853	works obsessively, almost to the point of making herself ill. She tells us
15928	more than once how many countries (112) she visited while secretary of state
16005	and how many miles (nearly a million) she clocked up. She says that she
16077	encouraged her staff to “do whatever they could to stay sane and healthy
16150	amid the rigors of a grueling schedule.” Diplomats who have dealt with her
16225	do indeed testify that she really was always well-briefed and well-prepared.
16302	Whichever of those 112 countries she happened to be in, she always knew what
16379	the issues were, and she always understood to whom she was talking. Unlike Joe
16458	Biden, she never mixed up the president and the prime minister.
16531	This necessarily meant that she relied on the State Department and its
16602	employees rather than on her own relatively narrow knowledge of foreign
16674	countries—and this, frankly, is a lot better than winging it. Indeed, there
16750	is more than a hint of the technocrat about Clinton. She doesn’t delve into
16826	policy debates much herself, at least not in this book, but she likes to
16899	surround herself (along with her retinue of loyalists and handlers) with
16972	people who know about things, and she has the technocrat’s desire to find
17046	the best solution to the problem, whatever its origin. She studiously avoids
17123	anything that could be misconstrued as “ideological,” or even as an
17191	“idea.” She admires experience, preferring the sage advice of Richard
17261	Holbrooke over the “younger White House aides” who rolled their eyes when
17335	he spoke. What she seems to mean by “smart power” is policies that work.
17417	From all of this, it is possible to make a few good guesses about what kind of
17496	candidate Clinton hopes to be: deeply non-ideological, a centrist. She intends
17575	to run as a hard-working, fact-oriented pragmatist—someone who finds ways to
17652	work with difficult opponents, and not only faces up to difficult problems but
17731	also makes the compromises needed to solve them. Again and again she portrays
17809	herself sitting across the table from Dai Bingguo or President Putin, working
17887	hard, searching for a way forward. Similar methods, presumably, can be applied
17966	to the Republican leadership.
18005	Though pretty stultifying to anyone who wants a bit of moral uplift from their
18084	presidential candidate, this might well be a brilliant campaign strategy. It
18161	might even be a brilliant presidential strategy. Clinton wants to be the
18234	politician who will rise above the partisanship that has hamstrung the Obama
18311	administration, end the gridlock in Washington, cut deals, and move forward.
18397	In order to do this, she will transform herself into a figure of benign
18469	neutrality. Unlike Obama, she will not inspire, but she will also not enrage.
18547	Perhaps she provoked angry passions as First Lady, but that is all behind us
18624	now. Hillary Clinton circa 2016 will promote not the left and not the right,
18701	she will promote America.
18736	To anyone whose memory stretches back beyond the two most recent presidential
18814	administrations, this may sound familiar. In the Bill Clinton years, this
18888	stance was called “triangulation,” and it meant that the president kept an
18963	equal distance from both the Republicans and the Democrats in Congress. Those
19041	who didn’t like it complained that, in practice, triangulation required a
19115	rejection of anything that looked like political principle or moral
19183	consistency in favor of whatever policies might be politically feasible. On
19259	the other hand, a decade’s worth of bitter partisanship hasn’t gotten us
19332	anywhere, either. After eight years of Bush and eight more of Obama, the
19405	nation might well be tired of Big Ideas, and might well prefer some
19473	old-fashioned wheeling and dealing instead.
19526	As for Clinton’s lack of emotion, and the reliance on stiff formulations and
19603	cliché— well, we might as well get used to it. For there is another message
19679	in Hard Choices: by writing the kind of book that she wrote, Clinton is
19751	indicating that she is not going to open up and reveal herself in some new
19826	way—ever. If there is more depth beneath the surface, if she is less stolid
19902	and lackluster than she appears to be, then we aren’t going to know about
19976	it. This is a woman who is aware that every outfit she wears, every hairstyle
20054	she adopts, every word she utters can create an international debate, and she
20132	intends to control as much of that conversation as she can. If, once upon a
20208	time, there ever was a spontaneous Hillary Clinton who said what she really
20284	thinks and did not worry about how the media would respond, that person was
20360	suppressed long ago.
20390	Maybe, if she really wants to be president, she was right to have done so. It
20468	really is true that one slip of the tongue could end Clinton’s career. It is
20545	also true that the stories with edifying morals, the glossy photographs, the
20622	promise of bipartisanship, the work ethic, the devotion to service and
20693	duty—all of this makes sense in the context of a national campaign: a lot of
20770	people who are only remotely, or not at all, interested in the nuances of the
20848	Russian-American relationship can identify with this package very easily.
20922	Those who do not want or do not need a grand strategy for America, at home and
21001	abroad, may find her “journey” very compelling. And many people will like
21075	the positive spin she puts on even the most negative world events: it is so
21151	cheerful, so upbeat.
21181	Hard Choices is not remotely a book for the ages. It does not belong on the
21257	same shelf as Dean Acheson’s memoir. But maybe it contains the winning
21328	formula—and for this author, winning is what counts.
