271	American Sniper' guitar to be auctioned for charity
346	Seeking to raise funds for veterans suffering from post traumatic stress
419	disorder, Nashville-based Gibson Guitars has produced a one-of-a-kind Les Paul
498	inspired by former Navy SEAL Chris Kyle.
548	The guitar will go up for auction Thursday at
594	www.charitybuzz.com/chriskyleguitar with a starting bid of $3,000. Proceeds
670	from the auction, which closes May 5, will benefit the Guardian for Heroes
745	Foundation, which provides an array of services to in-need veterans with
818	disabilities.
841	The guitar's design features the skull logo that Kyle's SEAL Team Three used
918	during tours in Iraq, and its control knobs were crafted with shells from the
996	same kind of ammunition Kyle used in combat.
1050	The project was the brainchild of Nashville country artist Tim Montana, whose
1128	friend was a Marine veteran from Franklin who battled PTSD. Tim Montana and
1204	The Shrednecks will perform at the Chris Kyle Memorial Benefit and Auction,
1280	which takes place May 1-3 in Texas.
1325	"The goal is obviously to raise awareness to PTSD and help raise money for
1400	such a worthy cause in honor of an American hero," Montana said.
1474	Montana inspired by friend's battle
1519	Shortly after arriving in Nashville eight years ago to pursue a career in
1593	music, Montana befriended Hunter Mitchell, a Marine from Franklin.
1669	Montana said he loaded music onto Mitchell's iPod for his deployment in the
1745	Middle East. After Mitchell returned, he shared his struggles with PTSD.
1827	After seeing "American Sniper," Montana contacted the Chris Kyle Foundation
1903	and reached out to Gibson with his idea to make a guitar to auction for
1975	charity. Mitchell died Feb. 6 while the instrument was in production.
2054	"I wrote a song about him and his experiences a couple years ago," Montana
2129	said. "In the midst of this whole thing, he passed away. He told me about (how
2208	PTSD affected him) and helped me see it firsthand."
2269	Montana's song "This Beard Came Here to Party" went viral in 2013 and even
2344	became the unofficial theme song during the Boston Red Sox' championship run.
2431	Guitar has custom paint job
2468	Producing the guitar was a labor of love at the Gibson plant on Massman Drive.
2547	Approximately seven people worked on producing the Les Paul, according to
2621	Frank Johns, Gibson's new product supervisor.
2676	"We created special knobs with the bullet shells," Johns said. "We also did
2752	the special paint job with many layers of paint and masking, not a sticker
2827	that's applied. We created a silk screen for the head stock to commemorate the
2906	event with the official logo."
2946	Alex Juskiewicz, Gibson's global director for entertainment relations, said
3022	such one-of-a-kind guitars typically sell for a pretty penny, especially an
3098	instrument with such a unique backstory.
3148	"We really do try to give back. We have a foundation set up to give back to a
3226	lot of charities. It's something really ingrained in our company's culture,"
3303	he said.
3321	"Gibson has always been made in America and always will be made in America,
3397	and Chris Kyle did a great thing for this country and we'd like to support
3472	that."
3488	Kyle helped veterans with PTSD
3528	Kyle rose to prominence as the most prolific sniper in American combat
3599	history. His memoir, which inspired the blockbuster Clint Eastwood film
3671	"American Sniper," documented his combat stories and the toll that war took on
3750	him and his family.
3779	In 2013 he was murdered at the age of 38 by another military veteran, who also
3858	reportedly suffered from PTSD. Before his death, Kyle was dedicated to helping
3937	veterans struggling with PTSD, and he helped launch Guardian for Heroes. PTSD
4015	is a condition attributed to witnessing traumatic life events and brings about
4094	depression, anxiety and suicidal thoughts.
4146	Former Navy SEAL Rob O'Neill, who was on the elite unit that killed terrorist
4224	Osama bin Laden, said music can be used to help veterans cope with PTSD.
4297	O'Neill recently joined FOX News as a contributor.
4357	"PTSD doesn't mean you're weak, it means you survived," O'Neill said in a
4431	prepared statement. "A mechanism for coping with anything in the past is great
4510	music. Verbal expressions of our feelings don't do justice to the emotion.
4585	Music gives us power over our demons."
