244	Analysis: So what if Sara Netanyahu did Bottlegate?
319	Legally, the Bottlegate allegation may be a dead end.
382	It is now quite possible that Sara Netanyahu did everything she has been
455	accused of in “Bottlegate” and may still be legally bulletproof without
527	ever having to deny anything, or call a witness.
585	Bottlegate refers to allegations that Sara Netanyahu, the prime minister’s
660	wife, and possibly others connected to her activities, may have improperly
735	pocketed NIS 4,000 cash from the collection of the deposit on recycled glass
812	bottles; though the bottles were bought with state funds.
879	In Bottlegate’s early stages, there was controversy about whether the media
955	was inventing or exaggerating the situation.
1009	But as of last week’s state comptroller report, the basic above story about
1085	Sara was confirmed.
1114	State Comptroller Joseph Shapira also added that the “misuse of state funds
1190	must be treated with full severity no matter how small the amount,” and made
1267	reference that something about Bottlegate and some other allegations “raised
1344	prima facie suspicions of ethics violations, which could even raise suspicions
1423	of criminal acts.”
1451	Maybe there is even more to Bottlegate than we know, maybe Shapira was
1522	referring to obstruction of justice related to covering-up Bottlegate, or
1596	maybe he was referring to a different piece of his report’s allegations
1668	against the Netanyahus.
1701	But having spoken to an array of experts about the Bottlegate allegations,
1776	there is a definite consensus that regarding the legal perspective to
1846	Bottlegate, Sara is “indictment proof” from any criminal offense,
1912	regardless of what Shapira says.
1954	Netanyahu’s lawyer, Jacob Weinroth, was the first to raise the defense that
2030	it can be irrelevant, under the law regarding returning bottles for receipt of
2109	funds, who bought the bottles – as both the bottle buyer and collector who
2184	turns them in are legally entitled to receipt of funds.
2249	Meaning Sara was due the money since she “collected” the bottles.
2324	Shmuel Saadia, a lawyer, author and expert in criminal law dealing with public
2403	officials, said this argument makes Sara’s actions and intent “free of any
2478	criminal aspects.”
2506	Saadia noted that “there is no obligation for individuals to return” the
2579	bottles in the first place, so there can be no crime related to who or how
2654	they are returned.
2682	In the worst case scenario, he said that even if someone made “an absurd
2755	interpretation” of the law to try to ensnare Sara, at worst she made or
2827	could claim to have “made a good faith mistake.”
2885	Further, Saadia said that both the minuscule funds and the actions in
2955	question, relating essentially to recycling would fall under the category of
3032	something where “there is no public interest” and of “too minute” an
3101	issue to prosecute.
3130	Dr. Yuval Karniel of the Interdisciplinary Center in Herzliya agreed with much
3209	of the thrust of Saadia’s argument, particularly that the issue was “too
3282	minute” to prosecute and waste the state’s time.
3340	Karniel did say that Weinroth’s arguments that Sara’s status could be
3410	viewed from the perspective of being a collector of the bottles, like any
3484	random bottle found by an individual on the street were “cynical.”
3560	He pointed out that most likely Sara not only used state money to buy the
3634	bottles herself, but that she may not even have personally been involved in
3710	their collection, instead ordering state employees to collect them for her.
3795	In contrast, Karniel said, the part of the law that entitles a collector to be
3874	rewarded without buying the bottle is designated to encourage recycling of
3949	bottles which have already been “left behind” by the original buyer.
4027	If Sara obtained the bottles using state funds, with a later intent to cash in
4106	on collecting them, she was not in the shoes of “Joe collector,” when he
4179	randomly collects a stray litter-bottle on the street, Karniel said.
4257	Still, at the end of the day, Karniel admitted that since the law is
4326	relatively new and there are no real clear court decisions on point, it would
4404	be very difficult to argue that Sara should have known that what she was doing
4483	could be viewed as criminal, as opposed to unethical.
4546	Since the standard regarding intent for convicting of a crime is so high, it
4623	is hard to imagine filing an indictment against Sara could be justified.
4705	If anything, Sara’s idea might have been so “creative” that she may have
4778	been the first to try it, and only future people who try the same thing might
4856	be able to be considered “on notice” of the full criminal possibilities.
4938	Saadia has also added that the timing of raising the allegations right before
5016	elections was problematic and would color any decision to file an indictment
5093	as political.
5116	All of the above is heavily reinforced by the fact that several experts who
5192	were consulted on the subject said that they viewed the issue as so minor and
5270	lacking substance, that they were not even interested in being interviewed on
5348	it.
5361	Finally, while the state has not expressed an opinion, the vibes it is putting
5440	out on this particular issue have not been enthusiastic.
5506	So maybe Sara did it and no one may like what she might have done, but
5577	legally, this particular allegation may be a dead end.
